Okay, we're going to make announcements.
Nobody told me there was going to be a lot of people here.
Good morning.
Yes, I am.
Good morning to all of you, and thank you for coming.
Some of your faces are very familiar to us, and some of you aren't,
but we are so glad to see all of you here today.
And we hope that you enjoy the lecture,
and Doc has been preparing for it for the last three weeks,
so you're going to be in for a treat.
Okay, I have a few announcements, so please go ahead and sit down,
and then I'll introduce Dave for you.
I need you to turn off all your cell phones,
and there's no recording or filming of the event,
so please don't turn on your cell phones to do so.
Also, I'd like to have the people that are from out of country.
Could you stand up?
Anyone that's here from out of country?
Thank you.
Thank you so much for coming.
I know that it's amazing.
It's a very difficult trip,
and it just shows that your spirituality is very important to you
because you've come such a long distance to hear us.
So now I'd like to introduce my husband,
Sir Dr. David R. Hawkins.
I don't have a pointer.
I forgot a pointer, sweetheart.
You got a pointer?
Nope?
Yep?
Okay, you got a pointer.
So, what is the lecture on today?
Success.
Success?
Now, who the heck is interested in success?
I had the secret of success to announce to the group,
and I forget what the hell it was now.
The secret of success, honey.
Do you remember what we...
We don't have a pointer.
Well, the secret of success, one, is to be prepared.
Think through your project in advance.
Step by step.
Some days are diamonds, and some days are dust.
Well, we just thought you would enjoy that little demonstration
of the importance of taking your Thrive Project through in advance.
Now, we have slides today,
and the purpose of these slides
is so I don't forget what we're talking about.
Where are the slides?
101 Ways to Success.
Well, we've had an interesting year so far.
We've had 101 days, 101 ways to happiness,
101 ways to peace,
and we finish up the year with 101 ways to success.
So, if you've got peace, happiness, and success,
you've pretty much depleted your earthly life of any challenges.
Yes.
And you've got nothing left but serenity, if you can handle that.
That's not too popular a thing anymore, but serenity.
All right.
Now, how many people are here for the first time?
First time.
Well, that's exciting.
All right.
So, we're going to discuss things that have come out of many years of research,
many years of research.
As well as 50 years of clinical experience.
I had the largest psychiatric practice in the United States for some 50 years.
And then we got into consciousness research.
And consciousness research really evolved because we discovered a basic truth
that is really devastating in its application.
And that is truth makes your body go strong.
Makes your body go strong.
And falsehood makes it go weak.
Well, that ought to be pretty handy to know, yeah?
So, if you've got a friend, you've got a friend, and I've got a friend here.
So, I'll say, if I ask something, you know, a question, and I'll say, okay,
there's over 700 people sitting out there, resist.
Over 800 people resist.
Over 850 resist.
So, there's between 800 and 850.
But you can instantly know the truth of anything in the universe,
which is so devastating that practically nobody gets that when I tell you that.
Approximately 15% of this audience will get it.
The other 85, I don't know what happens to them.
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
We can track back through biologic history.
Why truth would have an attractive, that which is good for the organism would have a positive response.
That which would be poisonous and therefore contribute to your downfall would have a negative effect.
You look at the forms of early life, how would a little protozoa or an amoeba know what's good to eat or what would kill them?
If you didn't know the difference, he died.
So, it was very important for...
The earliest life forms to know that which is pro and supportive of life and that which is negative and will kill you.
So, those that didn't learn the lesson, many of them died by the billions over the centuries.
So, we're left with an organism, intrinsically this organism.
Then the nervous system, which is controlled by the field of consciousness itself.
It's...
So, the answer that...
The answer that we get when we ask a question and press down on her arm is being answered by the field of consciousness itself and not by the person.
It has...
So, the answer has nothing to do with what this person here thinks the answer might be or this person here.
So, this is therefore called consciousness research.
The infinite field of consciousness, what other...
In other languaging...
In conceptualization would be that you might say the mind of God out of which arises all of creation with no beginning and no ending.
The field of consciousness is infinitely powerful.
It has no beginning and no ending.
And within the field of consciousness, there is neither here nor there, then or now, and all time is now.
In the infinite field of consciousness, which you might call the mind of God,
all time...
All times are now, everywhere is right here.
So, I can ask a question of the field of consciousness.
And the answer arises as though the event was...
It occurred right now.
I can ask, you know, what was the consciousness level of Napoleon, the Bonaparte?
It mattered before we met, before or after Waterloo.
So, we'll demonstrate it.
By the end of the day, we'll show you how to do it.
It's very simple.
When I say, you can see I'm not using any suggestion because what I'm holding in mind, she does not know.
And I can say to her, okay, I first ask this, the question I was asked right before this lecture, the answer is yes, resist.
The answer is yes, we were asked to do a favor for somebody, and the answer is yes, we should go along with it.
Now, if it were a negative response or something like that, we would have gotten a no.
If it was illegal or untruthful, etc.
All right, so, it's very handy to be able to know the difference between truth and falsehood about anything, anywhere, anytime.
And with it, I guarantee success.
Should I buy this car?
And her arm goes weak.
No, it's a clunker.
Did I buy this car?
Arm goes strong, yes.
Okay.
Should we hire this employee?
Yes or no.
The fact that you can know anything about anything is only grasped by 15% of the average audience.
That makes me sad.
So, I want the 85% who don't get it to listen carefully.
Okay.
I can ask, is what I'm holding in mind...
Is what I'm holding in mind truthful or not?
And press down on her arm, and if it's true, her arm goes strong, and if it's false, her arm goes weak.
How can that be when she doesn't even know what question I'm holding in my mind?
What connects the two of us when we're not physically connected at all?
Huh?
She doesn't know either.
Neither of us know.
No.
Yeah, we have...
I have hypothecated, of course, the infinite field of consciousness, but it's pragmatic value.
So, we're not here just for academic reasons.
We're here for...
It's of tremendous value.
Let's say you have a business, and you're thinking of opening a new branch in South America.
And so, you hold in mind this project, and you ask your partner,
this is a practical idea that would be good to do now.
And you'll get a...
A yes or a no.
If it says yes, you can go ahead with it.
If it says no, you can then ask further.
You can ask questions of why it wouldn't work now.
Because you're dumb and ugly.
Oh, yeah.
The reason you're a failure is because you're dumb and ugly.
Oh, okay.
There's nothing wrong with being dumb and ugly.
Well, you can make millions of dollars being dumb and ugly.
That's what people do.
Run for Congress.
All kinds of things you can do.
We always joke about politicians.
I mean, you know, when you're a politician, you expect it, you know.
All right.
So, this is a pointer.
Oh.
A laser.
You have to push it down.
A laser pointer.
You have to point it right there.
Oh, my God.
Is it safe?
No, it's not safe.
One shot of that little red dot, and you're done for.
All right.
We started out.
We evolved what is known as...
Is there an itch to this?
Oh, there it is.
I don't want to fall off in the middle of a lecture.
What we evolved is a map of consciousness.
A map of consciousness.
And discovering what makes you...
Truth makes you go strong.
We calibrated this field of consciousness,
which is inclusive of just about everything that's possible.
And it's extremely useful.
From this map of consciousness, you see,
we calibrated...
We calibrated the level of consciousness of anything that is now or ever was,
including all the people on the planet, et cetera.
You find on a scale of one to a thousand,
200 and over is truth.
200 and over is the level of truth and integrity, et cetera.
Below 200 are the levels of falsehood and the emotions that go with them.
You see, the emotions below 200 are scorn,
hate, cravingness, anxiety, regret, despair,
humiliation, and enslavement, withdrawal, despondency.
So when people go into a depression,
what happens is they fall to the bottom of this scale.
As we move up the scale of consciousness,
over the level of 200.
So many times when we calibrate something,
we really want to know, is it over 200 or not?
Is it true or is it false?
200 and up, you go into the positive mental states,
such as trust, optimism, forgiveness, understanding, reverence,
serenity, and eventually bliss.
So these are the higher states.
And of course, the highest states of all
are the advanced spiritual states leading to enlightenment.
And so the level of enlightenment, you go from being courageous.
You see, you let go of pride.
You let go of pride.
Pride is the big downfall.
Pride and anger and cravingness and fear and grief and guilt and shame
keep people in the bottom of the level.
Then when you face the truth about things and accept it,
you develop courage.
And then you move to a level, a consciousness level 250,
which is very comfortable, called neutrality.
In neutral, it's okay if it happens and it's okay if it doesn't.
Let's say, yeah.
It's okay if the audience gets it.
That's what I'm talking about.
And it's okay if they don't.
That gives you a certain independence, doesn't it?
However, beyond that is willingness.
Willingness is my will for the audience is that they get it all.
So I move from 250 up to 310.
Willingness is the willingness to explain it all.
And accepting that this is necessary takes me up to reason.
So I use reason to explain things.
Now, because I love this audience,
I wouldn't be here.
That moves you up to 500.
Then if I get that the audience is getting it,
I feel joy.
I move up to joy.
They got it.
Oh, then I end up at peace, 600.
And peace means that you're very happy how it all is.
Some get it and some don't.
And I'm at peace with that.
And it's okay if you don't get it.
If you don't understand the thing I'm saying today,
it's okay with me.
So you don't have to please me by getting it.
What a relief, huh?
Nobody's required to understand this at all.
Besides, you're going to get it primarily by osmosis anyway.
When you get home, you'll say, what did he say?
I don't know.
You get it by osmosis.
Yeah.
What does that mean?
It means that the field,
the field generated by all of us here together
for the purpose for which we're here,
the field itself is enormously powerful.
And groups such as AA, et cetera,
they'll say, don't bother trying to get it.
Just go there and go to the meetings.
You'll get it by osmosis.
So all of you who don't get what I'm saying intellectually,
don't worry about it.
You'll get it by osmosis.
Good old osmosis.
God counted on osmosis for the human condition.
He figures they're not going to get it.
They'll get it by osmosis.
So the presence of God then which prevails
has within it the power to bring understanding
to the human consciousness
without going through some linear logical sequence of thinking.
So they won't necessarily go through,
reason and logic,
although we'll put it in there for those who are obsessive compulsive
and want to know why.
It just is, okay?
That should take care of it.
All right, now today we're talking about,
I forgot what the subject was.
We're talking about,
what were we talking about?
Oh, success, yes.
I knew it was something important, yes.
All right, so I'm doing,
do a few remarks.
I'm going to give you a few review slides.
This is the energy of the field of consciousness.
And you see, as consciousness level moves higher and higher,
you reach a point where it escalates.
And these are the divine states.
We seek out the company of the avatar,
the great spiritual teacher,
because their aura radiates out this enormous energy.
The way you become enlightened,
is you pick up from the consciousness of an enlightened being,
the energy, this energy field right here.
Can you see a little red dot?
You can see that?
It's amazing.
Anyway,
energy fuels of enlightenment.
See, this is love.
Here we go.
This is reason.
This is reason in the 400s.
Love is in the 500s.
Enlightenment is about 600.
At 600, it's really a state of sort of bliss.
And then the very high advanced states of consciousness
are infinitely powerful.
And the way you reach the state yourself
is somewhere in your life or lives.
The presence of the enlightened spiritual master
irradiates out this energy field.
And you pick it up in your aura.
So, unfortunately,
you can't print it and can it and mail it.
And that's why people travel long distances.
Because the energy field of the aura of the teacher
illuminates through your aura.
So, the way the Buddha transmitted enlightenment
was in silence
when he handed the flower to his follower.
The flower was only symbolic.
The follower,
and then I think it was,
was picked up by the teacher.
So, he picked up the energy field of the Buddha.
And then from him,
that energy field was transmitted down
through the centuries,
through the thousands and thousands of years.
So, in a way,
we're all picking up the energy field of the Buddha.
God bless you, Buddha.
Buddha who?
Buddha, Hanson, Johnson?
No, Buddha.
So, we're all picking up that energy field
of originally released by the Buddha, yeah.
All right, so the next one.
These are the energy,
how do you turn this thing on?
Oh, okay.
Where's the consciousness level of mankind?
People say, well, where's mankind?
The consciousness level of mankind right now,
let's see if we have permission to do mankind.
Mankind overall, we have permission to do, resist,
is over 200.
Oh, 205, 210, 209.
208, 207.
Consciousness level of mankind is over 206, 205, 204.
Consciousness level of mankind right now is 204.
Truth is 200.
Mankind overall is at 204.
Okay, let's do America.
We have permission to do America.
Consciousness level of America is over 400, 405, 406.
America is about 405.
What did I say humankind was at, 204?
204.
Therefore, we are very fortunate indeed
to be living in a country
where the overall consciousness level
is much higher than mankind in general.
So this is a very advanced nation, you might say.
Especially California, anyway.
So 85% of the world's population,
85% of the world's population calibrates below 200.
200 is the level of truth and reality.
Truth and reality is at 200.
85% of mankind calibrates below the level of truth
and integrity, which explains and explains
why humanity is so fracture.
Okay.
the nature of the nightly news and the world in all of its expressions as war
and murder and suicide political corruption etc 85% of the world's
population is below the level of truth and integrity so let's move on to the
next just depressing fact this is mankind this is mankind this pyramid
demonstrates alright the dark is mankind 85% of 85% of mankind is here and 15% of
mankind it is above the level of 200 so how can that be
it's because
Because the 15% above 200 has so much power that they calibrate the total negativity of
the 85% below 200.
Therefore, you see how responsible you have to be as a very advanced consciousness.
The people in this room are of a very advanced consciousness.
They just, by the fact they breathe in and out, are counterbalancing 85% of humanity.
This group here counterbalances actually probably millions of people at the lower levels.
Okay, let's move up.
So this is how it works.
You see the balance.
This 15% above 200 counterbalances 85% of humanity that is below 200, and it gives you
an appreciation for a country in which education, etc., and integrity, and truth, are all valued.
Next one.
Next map.
Uh huh.
The evolution of consciousness over time shows you that consciousness evolved very practically
not at all for thousands and thousands of years.
And then all of a sudden it began to take off.
And you see right now.
it's in an upward so right now the consciousness level of mankind is in an up upward swing
okay next the uh what is this oh we don't need this one this is the evolution of consciousness
over archaeological times uh i thought the animal kingdom everybody likes the animal kingdom
everybody says what is my dog calibrate at that's an important question who cares what obama
calibrates and i want to know what my dog calibrates huh got plenty of room i just want
to make sure you're telling the truth now he calibrates over 200. what's fun is to look at
the animal kingdom you see the bacteria protozoa and the beginning of time they calibrate at one
that means that they're alive and fish are at 20. octopus is 20. uh the komodo dragon is at 40.
reptiles are at 40. predatory mammals such as the lion and the tiger calibrated 40.
and i always tell people not to play with lions and tigers even though they appear tame today
because they only calibrated 40. and in one instant they'll revert to native and then you
become you're part of the evening news great killed by the great white tiger or something
alligators 45
five uh dinosaur is 60. whale is 85. migratory birds are 105 so i think this is interesting to
calibrate the level of the animal kingdom uh the rhinoceros is 105. songbirds are 125.
polar bear is 160. water buffalo better watch them too 175. wolf is 190. hippopotamus is 190.
now you notice these are all below 200.
These are all the predators.
Any one of them will kill you if they get a chance.
A hippopotamus will kill you.
A jackal or a fox, a black bear, a water buffalo.
Water buffalo are very dangerous, you know.
They'll suddenly turn on you.
I knew somebody was attacked by a water buffalo.
No warning, just suddenly took off.
So below 200, then, you're with dangerous animals.
Now what happens at 200, you see, is we leave the carnivores.
The carnivore lives by the death of others.
They're below 200.
200 and up, you have the grazers.
They don't die by the death of others.
They eat grass.
So 200 and up are the peaceful animals.
The gazelle, the giraffe, the deer, domestic piggy,
the elk, dairy cow.
Yeah, isn't that interesting?
So there you got the predators.
And interestingly enough,
they calibrate below 200.
On our scale, where 200 is the differentiation
between truth and falsehood,
between that which is safe and that which is dangerous.
And so here you see the elephant at 235.
You see the cats at 240.
The family cat is 245.
You see doggies at 245.
Family dog is 250.
Anybody got a family dog out there?
250.
Kitty cats and doggies are 250.
Now, if you see, they're above 200.
So I tell people who are sick, lonely, and depressed,
do you have a cat at home?
No. Do you have a doggie?
No. And say, well, I'm not going to treat you
unless you get a doggie or a cat here, at least a canary.
You got to be interested in something besides just you,
you, you all the time.
So if you got at least a family dog, you're thinking about some
of them besides just yourself all the time, you've got to go
out and go wee-wee and everything else.
And monkeys, they're not.
Monkeys are fun at 250.
I used to have a pet monkey.
It was very funny.
A gorilla, I never had one at 275.
Now, there's some exceptions.
Remember Oscar the cat?
Oscar was very famous.
Wasn't he the one that predicted people dying within 24 hours?
If Oscar slept with somebody with a patient, he slept
with a patient, the patient was dead within 24 hours.
Oscar had some kind of way of knowingness.
The death was imminent.
And Oscar calibrated at 250.
Then there's the famous trained African gray parrot, Alex.
Alex is amazing.
Alex can actually think, calibrated at 401,
trained by a professor at some university.
There's a question, can animals think?
Well, this answers it.
The gray parrot can think.
She'll say, give me two orange squares.
He gets two orange squares.
Give me blue circle.
Give me a blue circle.
So this parrot can actually reason and think.
Coco, the trained gorilla at 405, I think is very interesting.
Coco, I've got a picture of Coco on my refrigerator at home.
And it shows Coco has got a kitten in her arms.
And Coco loves the kitty.
Coco, the trained gorilla, loves kitties.
Songbird's song is at 500.
And very interesting for all of us, you know.
A cat's purr calibrates at 500.
And a dog's wagging tail calibrates at 500.
500 is the energy field of love.
So when you see the dog's tail wagging like this, that's 500.
And our kitty goes, purr, purr, purr, purr, purr.
That's 500.
So the value of having pets, first of all,
you think about something other than yourself,
is that you're surrounding yourself by an energy which calibrates at 500.
500.
And they do this in hospices.
And hospices have learned this.
And many hospitals and nursing homes, you know,
have resident doggies and resident kitties for the patients to play with.
And they found that they get better quicker, faster, and more often.
Okay, so that's the background on it, just to give it some human interest.
We'll move to the next.
All right.
Here's a greater realm, the application of the levels of consciousness.
the great books of the western world
the intellectual basis
of the western world
of the audience here present
our intellectual basis here then
comes out
comes about to the great
books of the western world
vary from Thomas Aquinas
Aristotle
Sir Francis Bacon
Chaucer
Dante
here we have Darwin
at 450
Dostoevsky 465
Engels at 200
then we get to
Faraday you see
Immanuel Kant
Galen, Sigmund Freud is at
and
let's see 499
Galileo
at 485
Hegel at 470
Hippocrates
Hegel at 485
Immanuel Kant 460
Machiavelli 450
Karl Marx 130
that's one reason that the collective socialism hasn't done too well
is because Marx is only at 130
which has been
has had lamentable
consequences for mankind
if he was at 430
everything would be different in the world
if he was at 430 everything would be different in the world
so there we have the great minds of history
Shakespeare at 465
Sophocles 465
Tolstoy at 420
Virgil 445
I think this is a very interesting study
the great books of the western world
because this is the intellectual foundation
of our current society
we expect things to be reasonable
logical and to follow certain laws of logic
we expect things to be reasonable and to follow certain laws of logic
and just jump from two plus two equals six
so there's certain laws of reason
alright let's go to the next
we could spend the whole morning just on this one chart
move to the next one
where is the next chart
now the functions of the mind
I thought this would be somewhat interesting
for later on because we're going to be talking about success
the mind is really
there's really two levels of mind
there's what I call lower mind
lower mind
is somewhat limited
it's very personal
and
it's somewhat pedestrian
it has to do with physical and emotional
survival
and acquisition
we're going to be talking about success today
and so
part of lower mind is acquisition
some people conclude
that success is
represented by the accumulation
of things cars and houses
and money and
accumulation of things
that's compared to higher mind
higher mind is more general
and impersonal and unlimited
higher mind
is more detached
lower mind tends to take everything personally
and
they can't just criticize an idea
they have to attack the person
who has the idea
but higher mind
is more detached
it's really interested in whether
a thing is true or not
rather than attacking
the person who says it
okay let's move on
that's enough background on all that
that's all
so lower mind then
is based on
desiring and wanting
and
tends to be somewhat gullible
tends to exploit life
and we call it
we call them rather insensitive
people
the road to success
you have to awaken higher mind
higher mind is more intuitive
it's more expansive
it's interested in
aesthetics
art
how beautiful a thing is
it tends to serve life
lower mind tends to exploit life
higher mind tends to serve life
how can I serve you
how can I make something that mankind needs
so that's success
through adding to the value of human life
okay the next one
yeah next thing
alright so
this has to do with the higher and lower mind
we're talking about
brain physiology
the brain physiology
the left brain is the animal brain
and it's very emotional
it goes through the thalamus
which is the emotional
center of the brain
and you end up with an emotional
reaction
below
that's below 200
consciousness level above 200
is right brain
whereas left brain
releases adrenaline
and the emergency emotions
the right brain
releases endorphins
so
people that are spiritually oriented
then what happens
is the dominance of their brain
moves from the left side
which is the emotional emotion
greed, rage, hatred
getting even and vengefulness
moves to the right brain
and the right brain dominance
is non-linear
and positive emotion
and
people who are spiritually oriented
then have greater
greater immunity
have greater capacity for healing
they have a balanced acupuncture system
and
they give you a positive muscle test response
so when I ask her something that's true
her arm goes strong
and something that's false
her arm goes weak
okay what's the next one
alright
social problems are attributed
to all kinds of things in society
all kinds of things in society
are given the blame
that's the basis of
what's his name
I forgot his name
that's the basis of communism
is
everything is laid to blame
it sees cause and effect out there
Karl Marx
then
calibrates slow because
it creates a dichotomy
the cause is out there
now if the cause is out there
we examine that to see
where is the source of happiness
anyway
well we found that the level of
consciousness of an individual
or a country or a company
here's the
people in the world
who have a calibrated level of
100 to 200
the rate of unemployment is 50%
not due to local
socio-economic conditions
but due to the fact that
that's their level of consciousness
the rate of poverty
at that level is 22%
the happiness rate
people you say
people at this level of consciousness
are happy
15%
and we find that the rate of criminality
is 50%
so we see that
cultural phenomena
which we deplore
and
we imagine that they're caused by
something out there
we find out that what it's really
associated with is a level of
consciousness
I lived through all kinds of depressions
and eras when there was no jobs
there was no jobs at all
there was no jobs during the depression
my childhood
there was no jobs after World War II
when all the vets came home
there was no jobs anywhere
where there was no jobs
I always have two or three
how can I have two or three jobs
if the problem is in the world
and it's joblessness
I was a bartender in the afternoon
and a cab driver at night
what's the problem?
the level of consciousness
then is
more important than anything
so people's education
people's education
the quality of their
upbringing is of extreme
importance
the rate of criminality
as you can see
at the lowest levels of consciousness
is very close to 100%
they're let out of prison
and they commit a crime
within an hour
and
guys would go after
young children and all that
we'd let them out at 3 o'clock
and by 4 o'clock they'd been arrested
they went to the nearest park
what does a pedophile do
when you let them out of prison?
he heads to the nearest park
and grabs the first kid he can grab
takes him less than an hour
people are surprised
by the rate of recidivism
what does a pedophile
think about in jail?
what's the next little child
he's gonna grab in the park?
what do you think he's thinking about?
Plato?
alright, next move
levels of consciousness
and rate of happiness
you see if happiness was in the world
then we would see a correlation
but here what we see
is that the level of consciousness
is related to the rate of happiness
if the
the number of people
who calibrate at 30
what percent are happy?
4%
so the rate of happiness
is related to the level of consciousness
below 200
the rate of happiness is
small
as we move up
I don't know if you can see this pointer
it doesn't seem to do much pointing
but anyway
as you move up the level of consciousness
you see the percent of people who are happy
becomes
eventually predominant
if you're courageous
if you're in neutral
neutral is a nice place to be
uh
neutral at 250
it's okay if you get it
get the job and it's okay if you don't
willingness is
more positive
acceptance and then you're dominated by reason
and eventually you reach
a state of lovingness
and this is a possible state
for all of us within the world
uh
peace joy and enlightenment are
not necessarily available to everyone
but lovingness
lovingness which is really an inner decision
at consciousness level
the percent of people who reach 500
that are happy are about 90%
this is probably
the most important decision to make
is
lovingness
okay this is within
your capacity
to make a decision
you don't have to go away to school
you don't have to study it
you don't have to hear a lecture on it
there's a decision within yourself
to be loving
towards all of life
no matter what
the fact that you don't understand it
doesn't get you off the hook
the decision to be loving
lovingness
towards all of life
and all of its expressions
so as you walk along
you see a bug on the sidewalk
most of the people in this room
will walk over the bug
the people that were just
let out of jail half an hour ago
will stamp on the bug
that's a huge difference
whether you stamp on the bug
or you wish the bug happy life
and walk over it
so I want everybody here to pledge
no more bug stomping
after this lecture
when you see a little bug on the sidewalk
you say oh little bug
I'm glad that you're around
created by God
the universe is created by divinity
and divinity is now expressing itself
as a bug on the sidewalk
whose little life is up to you
his whole life is up to you
your life
his life is up to you
what kind of a human being you have become
to become as loving
as we can be towards everyone
to be loving means
that you tend to become forgiving
it means that you try to see everything
as the other person sees it
I can see that
I can understand why they're that way
because they were brought up in a certain way
and
the willingness to forgive
I remember after World War II
you know
here the Japanese were shooting us down here
I was out in the South Pacific
as soon as the war is over
we forgave each other like that
forgave each other instantly
I said
salute them
we used to salute each other
because they were very very brave
these kamikazes were very
they were terrifying
kamikaze would fly right into you
and blow up your ship and blow you up
didn't give a damn that it blew him up
he just went to heaven
that's scary
so it's funny
after the war was over
didn't take more than a couple of minutes
to let go of the whole thing
and after the war was over we'd shake the hands of the Jap aviators
and I'd say no you guys were really great
and we would shake hands
he was a great warrior
and I gave him respect
for his incredible courage
in the name of the Emperor
in the name of the Sun God
really
he was serving the Sun God as he understood him
and he flew right into us
and would blow us right up
and of course we were doing what we could do
and the other thing that
backed us all up
is that we risked our lives for our buddies
so out of love
out of love
you'd walk into a hail of bullets
you'd walk in
very dangerous places
some of the places we went
we must have been cuckoo
but anyway
you did it out of love for your fellow man
so love your fellow man
is a very very powerful force
and it's a lot different than
being ooh la la
what do they call them
the woo woos
in Sedona they call them the woo woos
talking about this
ooey gooey kind of
divine love and all sir
and
unless you bump into their
fender in the parking lot
and instantly all that goo goo ha ha
son of a bitch I'm going to call my lawyer
they revert to
what they really are
alright so
the person who's
at 500
if somebody bumps into your fender
and it's happened to me
he got backed right into my thing
in the parking lot
he backed in by mistake
and dented an offender
he got all upset
he expected me to holler and shriek at him
and I said look you can't help it
you drive a car enough miles
it's got to happen sooner or later
I was really interested in calming this person down
so he didn't feel upset
there's no point to feel upset I mean the dent is there already
I got insurance
don't worry about it
and I gave him a pat on the back
he was so relieved he almost fell over
he thought I was going to punch him in the nose or something
so love then is a very formidable
state
love will take you through all kinds of things
world wars and automobile accidents
family catastrophes
love at 500
is a very powerful energy
and as time goes on
the love becomes more progressively
more unconditional
unconditional
it means that you love things
initially you love things
without qualification
you don't have to know all about
whether it's worthy of love
deserving of love
just you love all of life
and all of its expressions
because it is
wow that doesn't take too much qualification
why should I love everybody in this audience
because you are
because you are here on top of me
you not only are
you are here
that makes it doubly neat
you love things
because they exist
so the source then
for your love of things
is strictly their existence
and their existence is up to the will of God
so
no matter what you love
you are loving some expression of God
and one day as you are walking down the street
the divinity of all things
shines forth
and you are never the same again
the divinity of all things
shines forth
and you can see its incredible beauty
this is arranged for the convenience
of those of us who are stupid
and can't see beauty unless it is
completely arranged for us
even the stupid can see the beauty
of God's rose
so nothing has to meet
any kind of a qualification
to justify
our lovingness for it
and therefore the downfallen
we can
love them without being
naively trusting towards them
the black mamba
will do you in
the minute it gets a chance
so
you can love the black mamba for what it is
but only an idiot
would let him out of the cage
which is a story I've told before
about a friend of mine
who had a pet black mamba
I think he was doing LSD
at the time but anyway
he had a pet mamba
so this black mamba
black mamba says to him
all of a sudden speaks to him
and says
you can let me out of here
I won't hurt you
please let me out
I don't like being in this cage
I promise you I won't hurt you
so this friend of mine
called all of his friends
and this black mamba says to me
if I let him out of the cage
he won't hurt me
so his friend says to him
don't believe him he's lying
I think it's so funny
alright
where are we now
so here's where the
levels of consciousness
and the rate of happiness
you can see that people who live
at 500
the chances of being happy
are about 90%
and the other 10%
may have specific reasons
within their personal lives
I don't know what the limitation is
when I used to see people in the office
I would know what the limitation was
and try and work them around that limitation
very often
a resentment from childhood
something their mother did
or their father did or said
and they are carrying this resentment
and forgiveness then
is very important
sooner or later
to forgive everybody and anything
how can you forgive people
who have done stupid ignorant cruel
and injurious things to you
you forgive them because you see them as limited
they didn't know any better
for the same reason then
that you forgive a dog who bites you
if you put your hand in the car
with a dog in it
the dog will bite you
that happened to somebody I knew
the dog was just doing his doggy thing
he was supposed to protect his car
and some idiot is trying to
invade his car as far as he was concerned
so in each case where there is an exception
to the rule you will find
that there is a particular reason
let's move to the next one
yes, ok
we use the calibrated levels of consciousness
to calibrate
spiritual teachers
throughout history
people are always calling
our office and sending us emails
about the calibration level
of various teachers
so we thought it was much easier
just to publish the best known
because they are very well represented
throughout time
and
spiritual literature of the world
so
when they ask about
a local teacher
a lot of times they will ask me
what about
Swami Bum Bum
he is about 80
probably rape you
if you didn't keep your eyes open
so anyway we thought
just for comparison
because there are a lot of pseudo gurus around
really bad actors to tell you the truth
and I don't know why they are so attracted
to pedophilia
you see pedophilia seems to be very big
amongst fallen spiritual teachers
I can never find anything sexually attractive
about a child
so there is something demented about them
alright we move on to the next one
spiritual teachers continued
we will move on from there
anyway all I want people to know
is that there are
over a hundred
if people are looking for a good teacher
there is over a hundred
who are calibrated very high
let's move to the next one
here you have today's world
laid out for you
here is today's world folks
there they are
trust me
trust me America
trust me voter
trust me investor
now so this is
the importance of this
is the difference between perception
and reality
perception is
what you think you see
so what you see out there
is what you think exists
so
the more spiritually sophisticated
person sees past appearance
and moves into essence
I don't care what the
appearance of a thing is
I want to know what the essence of it is
I don't know
I don't care that it's a sleek looking airplanes
I just want to make sure the wings hang on
until we land
so if I calibrate an airplane
and it comes out at 190
I want to take the next plane out
one time they used to have a shuttle
between Washington DC
and New York City
and I used to go to some meeting in Washington
I forget
and they guaranteed every hour on the hour
there would be a plane
so at midnight one time
I get there at midnight
and there was one person
me
in Washington DC
so the airline said if they had one passenger
they would fly it
so at midnight I'm the only passenger on this plane
they ran a whole plane from Washington DC
to New York City
because of me
so I hear I'm on this plane
all by myself
there's nobody on this plane but me
I guess the pilots up in front
but there's nobody around
they didn't have a stewardess for passenger one
so I'm flying all alone in the dark
and I'm looking down
I see the city's down below
and I get
you are the only person on this plane
the only one
uh oh
well God
is there some message I'm supposed to be getting?
so I quickly said my prayers
I figured there could be a reason
there was only just one of us
alright we'll move on
so here we're
talking about success
101 ways to success
the earlier lectures we did so far this year
101 ways to peace and to happiness
so peace and happiness
and then eventually
these bring you to success
people think that
peace and happiness
have to be sacrificed for success
uh no
peace and happiness
are part and parcel of success
true success means you're pleased
with how it's all going etc
so we're talking today
about success
and how simple it is
so we have to first define
what it is
well there's internal success
I'm very pleased with something
and then there's external success
as the world views it
I'm working on success
you mean within yourself
you can be very pleased
you know how you saw a piece of wood
or how you planted your garden
but the world wouldn't consider that success
so you have to decide
do you mean internal or external
which are you aiming at
are you aiming at being pleased
with your own self
the hardest critic
I have to deal with
is Dave
he's the only one I gotta please
and if it doesn't turn out right
no rest
go back to your desk
and work on it some more
internal so success then
is either within yourself
what you consider to be success
a resolution of a project
you've set up for yourself
and then there's external success
as the world views it
what the world views
as success
is a different animal
than what I consider to be success
success means to me
that if I sit down
to write 101 ways to success
I write 101 ways to success
yeah
so
I couldn't get away from the desk
until I had 101
that kept me busy for weeks
by success you mean
personal, spiritual, or worldly
you know worldly success
interestingly enough
there's a couple of new books
out on success
Gingrich's new book
Five Principles
for a Successful Life
another interesting one
just came out
George Foreman's Knockout Entrepreneur
everybody familiar
with George Foreman's success story
how many are familiar with it
yeah okay
well George Foreman of course
was a heavyweight champion of the world
and he lost it
or gave up on it I forget
and at age 45 I guess
he was broken
so I said George we're broke
you better go out and make some more money
George went back in the ring at age 45
and re-won the world's heavyweight title
at age 45
and then of course he went on to do
the Foreman Grill
which we have one at home
everybody has a Foreman Grill
and he became a multi-millionaire
selling the Foreman Grill
we love our Foreman Grill
you can't do hot dogs or anything
without your Foreman Grill
so
George Foreman's
Knockout Entrepreneur
to re-win the
title at age 45
which in boxing is middle age
is impressive
and then to go on to become
a millionaire
so there we're looking at success as winning
and there
he won the championship
and he won his wife's
return of her respect
that he wasn't a failure
he won the world's respect
everybody likes George Foreman
anybody here not like George Foreman?
so
likability and lovability
being very humanly human
so
to be successful we don't have to be
artificially perfect
very often the world loves us
for
our humanness and for our foibles
and our nuttiness
success then is
can be limited
described as goal achievement
to do this
project that I had here
I had to do
101 ways to success
so I
didn't achieve the goal
until I got to 101
and along the way
I got a couple dozen
that I thought about
and decided I didn't like too well
and threw them away
and went to the next
today's lecture is a success
in that I achieved
putting together 101 ways
and then I calibrated them all
with my arm etc
success is the world's view
as being prominent
this is the predominant
idea of success in today's world
is to be prominent
to be a media attraction
and to reach celebrity status
success
as prominence
and media attraction
and celebrity status
so
today the world is dominated
by the media
and you're successful
if all the programs want you on there
to be a guest on their program
and you feel like a success
you feel like a success
so there is a downward side
to media attention
it sucks you in
without you realizing it
people say oh it hasn't affected me
oh yes it does
being the big star on a TV show
does affect you
and
I've been on a number of them back in New York
there's a peculiarity to it
unless you've been a guest
on some big name
show you don't appreciate it
how many people have been a guest on a big time show
and many people here
not too many
well anyway somebody knows somebody
and you get invited to be
on a certain show
I forget the names of them all
they were all back in New York
so it's very interesting
you drive all the way to New York City
and then you go up
in these giant buildings
and you go up to the level where the studio is
and
the studio takes a whole level
of a huge building
probably covers half an acre
I think
and of course the makeup is waiting for you
so you get there and all of a sudden
everybody's flying around you
and they're fixing your face all up
and painting your ear lobes and all this
and you get all this attention
then you go on the talk show
I forget the name of them all
Barbara Walters
I was on hers a couple of times
a number of shows like that
so anyway you're the big star of the moment
and you're the focus of everybody
the wardrobe people are there
every little thing is absolutely perfect
the Klieg lights go on
and now you're Mr. Big
70 million people are watching you at this moment
70 million people
are watching every little twitch of your nose
and Barbara Walters
a couple of times
other big name shows but anyway
so for the moment you're somebody
makeup makes you somebody
and the Klieg lights go on
and these studios are huge
they're really giant places
and all of a sudden
the show comes to an end
all the lights go out
everybody leaves
and there you are all alone
in a half-acre studio
with nobody there but you
where the hell is the door
how do you get out of here
I could not find somebody
to let me out
I finally find a janitor
I said how do you get out of here
so here you are
charged up
the adrenaline
all the cortisol and all the kind of hormones
veins etc
you're Mr. Big for the moment
you come down this huge building
Rockefeller Center and there you are
you come down you get off the elevator
and you step out into the street
and there's this huge feeling of
loss, of drop
from being somebody
from being it
you're nobody
from being the ultimate it
you're no one
there aren't 70 million people
getting wrapped by you
so I understood why
why the
why the people in entertainment business
and certain aspects of the entertainment business
are so prone to drugs
because that drop is awful
imagine your cortisone
your adrenaline
everything is way up here
suddenly it pulls the rug out from under you
suddenly you're nothing
you're nobody
nobody cares about you
nobody even says hello
that sudden drop is sickening
I get why all the rock stars
and all them
get into drugs because
at the end of the program you can't get off that high
you want to keep the high going
so I had greater sympathy
for people in the media
who get into drugs because I can see
they can't stand that
adrenaline rush
the cortisone shooting out
the endorphins shooting out
and suddenly they pull the plug on you
suddenly you're nobody
you got nothing and all your hormones collapse
and
you're a nothing and a nobody
so I understood instantly
why they have to keep that high going
so typically in that particular culture
after the program is over
you meet over at somebody's house
and everybody is high
you stay high until 3 or 4 in the morning
so I got off being any
any kind of moral
being moral about it
I could just understand it
so one thing about the willingness
and the decision to be loving towards all of life
and all of its expressions
is you achieve a greater understanding
you find that you're not prone
to right and wrong
you're no longer subject to
criticizing people and putting them down
what you're interested in is
understanding them
when they come out of the prisons
and they continue the crime
the same as before they went in
instead of condemning them
you begin to understand them
for them there is no other life
there is no other life
except going back to mugging
and drugs and pedophilia
and whatever put them there in the first place
because that is their life
so we're looking more at success
as happiness
and one way
to achieve success
one attribute
is to build a good karma balance
what does that mean
it means you have like a deposit
in a savings account
everybody has a karma savings account
you ever know that
see that's true
everybody has a karma
savings account
the little bug that you didn't step on
it's a little bug
adds to your positive karma
savings account
and the next time
a pot falls off the top of a building
it'll miss you instead of hitting you
in the top of the head
it doesn't take great achievements
you don't have to save the life
of thousands of people
by inventing penicillin or something
all of life and all of its expressions
builds up a positive karma balance
and when you need it
it's there, it's like a savings account
and I've had a number of
many occurrences in my life
that cannot be explained
by any kind of logic whatsoever
being out in the middle of nowhere
I myself was lost
I didn't even know where the hell I was
and I pulled the truck over
in the middle of nowhere
and nobody I knew within hundreds of miles
I got a phone call
I had a flat tire
and I pulled the truck over by the side of the road
and all of a sudden
off the little road itself
a car pulls over
and pulls right over in front of my truck
and it's an old buddy from school
Dave look at you
you got a flat
can I help you
that happened to me a number of times
one time I was on one of these crazy
loop-de-loop things on the way to the airport
and the truck broke down
in the middle of all these loop-de-loops you know
I'm flat
I'm really in a bad way
and this guy pulls next to me
he says can I help you buddy
I got a flat
he says don't worry
this guy who was a complete stranger
took the tire off
threw it in the back of his pickup
went down to the loop-de-loop
went to a garage
got it fixed
went back through the curly Q8 loop-de-loops
and came back to my car
and put it on my car for me
no
that's positive karma balance
in other words
the goodness that you've radiated towards all of life
to the best of your ability
is not like a savings account
and when you need it
it's there to draw on
and you never know
when you're gonna need it
lightning strikes without warning
and
so
when your life is hanging in the balance
or something about your life is hanging in the balance
if you have a positive karma balance
it swings the result
in a favorable direction
and if you have a negative karma balance
it swings the
pendulum in a negative direction
so
my advice is to always keep a
positive karma balance
what do they call this
where you do a good favor for people
for no reason whatsoever
what do they call it
random acts of kindness
yes
the laws of random acts of kindness
that's really the operation
out of which it works
by constantly building a positive
karma bank account
you don't know when you're gonna need it
you may not need it
to the last five seconds of life
say I don't need it
wait till you get to the end
and then let me know
we've got three minutes
oh my god I better hurry up
oh my god
success is being important and famous
and a celebrity
success is happiness
I think success is if you're happy
what more can you ask than being happy
happy is
I'm happy to be happy
success is being happy
I'm happy my dog's happy my kitty's happy
my wife's happy my neighbors are happy
what more can you want
God's happy
I imagine God's happy all the time right
you can imagine the desired income
you begin to image it
you build a good karma balance
which is what we just got through talking about
so you've got a bank account to call on
you harness your desire and ambition
into a workable plan
and through self confidence
and dedication
next slide
then we move on
to slide
satisfaction with your progress
how is it going
and you develop a certain momentum
to override obstacles
you need supportive relationships
and build some
it's really a very very
enjoyable part of life
it's having good friends
how can you live without good friends
and people that you love
and you don't tell them that you love them
because that would make them nervous
you just love them but you don't say anything about it
I'm so glad to see you
I haven't seen somebody in months
just happy as hell
to see that person
a good friend that you love
you become flexible instead of rigid
what's the secret of success
of somebody like Donald Trump
you'll notice that
success is very common
in the level of the three hundreds
the consciousness level
of the three hundreds
not divine love
or intellectual
not intellectualism
but enthusiasm
Donald just keeps running around
buying one casino after another
and why does he do it
because he likes doing it
does he need more millions
he doesn't need any more millions
why does he keep doing that
he just loves doing it
ride his birds and go out
and play baseball once a week
because they love it
so I love Donald Trump
just because he loves doing what he does
and that's why he does what he does
because it's self rewarding
more
an advanced person
dedicates their life to the highest good
and we pray for awareness
of God's will
and however it turns out
we retain modesty
about it instead of
claiming personal credit
now should we take a break
we're going to take a 15 minute break
and
I expect you all to be successful
by the time you come back
from the break
I want all of you to give Kathy
and Wally Arnold
a thank you
because of them we're able to
put this whole program on for you
so if you could give them a hand
I would appreciate it
thank you
I don't know
everybody's not in anyway
we're waiting for everyone to come back in
where's Nick and Ted Arnold
I would like them up stage please
there they are
come here
where's your brother?
they're twins
hi sweetie
okay come up here
we're going to do happy birthday for them
okay so we're going to do
it's going to go Nick and Ted
alright here we go
happy birthday
to you
happy birthday dear
Nick and Ted
happy birthday
21 today
thank you
thank you guys
okay
alright thank you so much
they'll never forget this birthday
okay
that's enough frivolity for today
are we ready to resume
yep
everyone's back
well the good news is during the interim
we checked out using the arm
that everyone in this audience
is entitled to success
everyone in this room
wow
I guess there's no really bad karma
people here
if you had bad karma you wouldn't be here
they're here because they have good karma
oh I get it
they're successful because they already have good karma
alright
well that's good news
anybody upset
anybody want your money back
alright so
everyone in this audience is entitled to success
karmically speaking
there's lots of people who don't believe in karma
they don't last long
but they are around
the Buddha believed in karma
so that's good enough for me
and
you wouldn't need a savior
so because
we have a savior because of the Buddha
because of all the great spiritual masters
all of us
here are very fortunate
we have the value of the teaching
of the greatest spiritual masters
of all time
filtered down through time
through the energy
energy of the spiritual teachers
so through the energy
of the spiritual teachers
which are transmitted down through time
to this audience right here
so this audience right here
is benefiting by the aura
of all the great spiritual teachers
of all time
wow
the energy of the Buddha
all the great spiritual masters
that we looked at a big list of them today
have filtered down
and an audience like this
is automatically self-selected
because when people become interested
in spiritual reality
they are already
spiritually already quite advanced
that they are even interested
in such a thing
because when you're in the lower levels
you're just only interested
in physical survival
once you get past physical survival
then you're worried about
intellectual development
and you start reading the great books
of the western world and things like that
and then you become even more awakened
into spiritual reality
so this is an audience of people
who are spiritually awakened already
and therefore
makes an excellent
audience to talk to
very fortunate indeed
what's the next slide we have coming up today
yes
we're still on success
I knew we were on something interesting
I couldn't remember what it was
okay
so
people who are destined for
great futures etc
we tend to be thankful
rather than prideful
thank you
oh lord amen
all glory
be to thee oh lord
and honor be to thee oh lord
amen
so we dedicate our lives to God
and ask for God's guidance
in all of our decision making
and our way of being in the world
so we tend to be thankful
rather than prideful
and
we're pleased therefore
with incremental goals
you don't have to become the star of the show
tomorrow
the fact that you're making progress
is sufficient
we said that it's a way
success is a way of being in the world
it's a way in which you are
the way in which you are
tends to radiate a certain energy
and that certain energy tends to influence
things that are around you
so that spiritually advanced people
will experience the world differently
than people who are not
I can remember there was a phase in my life
that I went through a very high state
I don't know how I survived the body
and everywhere I went
people broke into
gleeful happiness
and I had an apartment in New York City
and I would make my rounds in the morning
the various doormen of the various buildings
and the various shops
everybody would light up
as you came
to their attention
they just became lit up
and not because of who you are personally
so it's got nothing to do with you as a person
but something about that energy
uplifted everyone
so all the doormen look forward
to seeing me make my
morning rounds
and the various stores
that I would go in
so you tended to uplift
all that come into contact with you
so success
is not what you do
but what you have become
aha
it isn't what you do
it isn't what you have
it's what you become
it's what you are
what you are
it transmits that energy
of other people
of feeling friendly and confident
and more entitled to
give you the truth than a falsehood
to be loving towards you
than unloving
so
that's something to be thankful for
it isn't what I do
it isn't what I have
it's what I've become
so what you are
is already a guarantee
of success
your functions then will follow
what you are
what you are will determine
what your judgments and your decisions are
and the answers you get about
certain things
and so
if in doubt
you can find somebody with whom
you can do the simple test
of truth versus falsehood
thankful rather than prideful
thank you God for all the gifts
of this life
so the very successful
people I've known
in this lifetime
have all been very modest
very modest people
you know worth enormous amounts of money
and etc etc
and very modest
modest as a person
so we are interested then
in incremental goals
you don't have to become a worldly success overnight
it's a result of basic attitudes
there is also
a certain determination
to achieve certain standards
determination to
give the best lecture I can give today
you know the determination
may not be the best lecture I can give today
but as far as my intention is
to get across certain basic things
in both the verbal
and the non-verbal
I also trust that the
non-verbal energy field
transmits itself
and then is acquired
by the listener
by virtue of the
listener's agreement
by your agreement
and you have agreed
to pick up from the energy field
of this consciousness
the radiance of that
which has been transmitted down
through the centuries
and which you will then transmit to others
so the thing to be happy about
is that you have become
an asset to the world
that you have
all the people in this room
have become an asset to the world
not everyone can say they are an asset
to this world
I can think of a few people right now
but what a gift that is
so as you can see
out of that you become thankful
you become that
which is a gift to your children
to your parents
to your society
to your neighborhood
just by the fact that you live there
the crime rate has gone down
would you believe that
the fact that you live where you live
accounts for the fact
of a reduction of the crime rate
where you live
the crime rate is already reduced
because of the radiance
that you emit from your aura
so that gives you great respect
for the aura
down through the millennia
down through the centuries
the great wisdom
which originates with divinity
has radiated down
through the great spiritual teachers
etc
and is now
characteristic of my aura
that which I am radiates peace
and success to the world
let's all say that
that which I am radiates peace and success to the world
that which I am
radiates peace
and success to the world
Amen
ok, you don't have to do anything
it's not what you do
there's all kinds of do-gooders
God help me
California is really bad for do-gooders
I think
they're lurking around every corner
eat this, don't eat that
don't smoke a cigarette
oh my God, geez
it's worse than murder
murder is ok, but smoking a cigarette
good God
the ultimate crime of mankind
World War II
was won by camel cigarettes
you didn't know that
every lifeboat had a carton of camels
in there
if we didn't see
we'd pretty soon run out of smoke
so we'd raid the lifeboats
and steal the carton of camels
they were 10 cents a pack
anyway, so that was a different generation
this generation of course
is more pure
when I go to California
they say
you're going amongst the pure
you get a little California halo
this is California
what happened to my slides?
oh
well
humor is one of the best teachers there is
so humor
you don't take yourself too seriously
it seemed like a good idea at the time
you say so
I bet all our money on a certain stock
and of course it collapsed within 72 hours
and we lost a million
oh well
on the other hand
you bet on it
and it went up and you made a million
you're thankful rather than prideful
you don't say well I made a good decision
no
you didn't make a good decision
the world made a decision
why a stock goes up
or a stock goes down
is due to millions of factors
so anyway
we're satisfied with progress
incremental goals
progress rather than perfection
and this progress is a result of
basic attitudes that we have
accumulated by good
and positive merit
one thing is determination
determination to do a good job
another thing we call is
willpower or grit
we visualize our goals
and chip away incrementally