Heat.
Oh, how wonderful to be here. Um our
lecture today is basically about peace
and um our ma our main um question that
we ask ourselves is is peace
external or is peace internal?
So I'm going to ask David to say just a
couple words on that right now.
Is peace external or is it internal?
>> Peace is an internal affair. Yeah.
Sometimes
it leaks out into the world.
Peace is an internal affair. Yes.
If they don't turn off that music now,
I'm going to kill them.
I want peace and I want it right now.
That's a good way to start the lecture.
On the way here uh today
the awareness came to mind that
mind thinks but spirit knows.
>> Oh that's good. The mind thinks but the
>> mind thinks yeah thinks about things you
know and the mind is really an
instrument of the ego endlessly discuss
things argue
and spirit just knows
silently
>> that's that's really great
>> spirit did that
now might talk about it but it was
spirit that grabbed
My sweetheart's arm.
Spirit is an instrument of God. So God
just grabbed your arm.
So you get in touch with your God
nature. Your spirit is your godly
nature.
And the mind is the ego's nature.
The human life is of course
the mind's spinning around but it's
really the spirit that accounts for your
existence.
The mind would like to convince you that
your survival is up to mind. Mind says
if you don't listen to me you won't make
it to the end etc.
Uh but spirit is the one that knows.
remember the time. Can you tell them
about the truck when you were down in
Patagonia and and um you know you had
broken down and the truck was smoking.
>> Oh,
>> tell them that story because that was
more of the spirit than it was your
mind.
>> Oh, that wasn't mind at all. No,
sometimes spirit uh uh
Well, no, I didn't hear thoughts. I just
knew I was in Patagonia, which is down
near the southern border, in my old
truck, 68 or 64, whatever it is, big
Willis truck.
And uh I was many miles, 150 miles
probably from the nearest civilization.
And I had parked the parked the truck.
And uh and I came back to start the
truck. I turned the key and smoke shot
out from under the hood.
I thought, "My god, the engine is on
fire." And here I am million miles of
nowhere.
And I already had heat exhaustion.
I did I had very little energy to begin
with.
And so here the engine is on fire and I
and I'd run out of water.
And uh I wasn't exactly an experienced
desert hiker, you know, run out of
water. So anyway, the smoke is pouring
out from under the hood.
Even if you open the hood, you wouldn't
be able to see where it was coming from.
And I thought, well, I guess you're
going to die here now.
So I sat back. I thought, well, it's
time to leave. I'll leave.
Every time I've been close to death, I
sit around waiting for it to happen
and the miraculous always occurs. So
anyway, I was all set to leave the
planet.
All of a sudden, an inner inner voice
said to me, "Well, I had a plastic cup
with about this much coffee still in the
bottom, maybe half inch of coffee."
So,
an inner knowingness,
the inner knowingness was take this cup,
plastic polyester cup,
and take a screwdriver and jam it
through the bottom of the glove
compartment.
So, I opened the glove compartment. I
took the screwdriver and I rammed it
through the bottom of the glove
compartment.
Well, the bottom of the glove
compartment in your car, you think it's
made of something solid, but it isn't.
It's just heavy duty cardboard. So, I
rammed it through this cardboard and I
took this cup and I put it in there and
I heard a sizzle and the fire went out.
So, that's one reason I'm still here.
But anyway,
a a knowingness
uh a nonverbal knowingness is the voice
of spirit. That's the voice of God.
And people complain they've never spoken
to God and God's been talking to him for
20 years and they don't even realize
what it is.
I always thought it was Susie.
It's God talking to her. So I listen
carefully when she speaks now
respectfully.
>> Okay, we're going to go ahead and start
this. I think we've got everyone in. And
um so the lecture today is on peace. We
want to welcome all of you. I know a lot
of you have come here from Canada,
different areas, and we want to thank
you for making that trip. And at this
time, I'd like to introduce Dr. David R.
Hawkins.
Gloria and Excelsius Dio. Glory be to
thee, O Lord most high.
Amen.
And uh what are we talking about today?
I forgot.
>> Peace.
>> Oh, peace. Right. Yes. I knew we were
talking about something important.
And we have some slides on the subject
of peace.
>> Do you have a pen?
>> I have a pen
>> in case they need to take notes.
>> That'll be a dollar.
>> Thank you.
that that I that'll be a dollar. I I've
told that story before. I was way up in
the Andes up near uh Machap Picchu. And
uh there wasn't anybody for miles and
miles around, maybe I forget how many
thousand feet it was, over 10,000 ft.
and and I go through this narrow
passageway and here's a a young girl
stand standing there and she's got a
llama
and uh
I said can I can I take your picture
with that llama? She said that'll be a
dollar.
So that's how I got into saying that'll
be a dollar.
That'll be a dollar.
So now where is the first slides? Here
you are at the map of consciousness.
>> Oh, the map of consciousness.
Uh, well, we use this thing as a
pointer, don't we?
It's good for small children and dogs.
Now, how many people are here for the
first time?
Oh, wow.
God bless all the people who are here
for the first time. The thing about
being here for the first time is you can
only be here for the first time once.
So this is indeed
a memorable occasion in your life.
I speak from humility.
In fact, I got more humility than
anybody I know.
Now you have to be able to read this.
Is this the right height for this
or is it supposed to come down a little?
>> No, that's it.
>> That's it.
Oh, I can jump. That's all right.
All right. This is the map of
consciousness.
extremely well known and uh really known
pretty much around the world. Now
uh these are the historic levels of
consciousness
the the ancient knowledge
uh well it's calibrated from 1 to a
thousand and uh over on the left hand
side you see uh uh the view of God
and uh your view of yourself
uh the level of enlightenment which
calibrates It's uh from 700 to a,000
and the emotion that goes with it and
the process that's going on in
consciousness
that is extremely comprehensive
includes just about everything that's
possible to know.
Uh last night they had a something on
Fox News about a famous murderer.
famous murderer
up right here. Here's where he
calibrates.
And you know where it calibrates without
even using the arm, but most serial
killers and all calibrate around 30. 30.
Yeah.
Uh, anything below 200 is false.
Anything below 200. So when we use the
arm to find out whether a thing is true
or false,
uh below 200 is falsehood and 200 and up
is truth.
Don't use it on politicians.
200 and up is truth. Uh and of course
the the quick way to find out is that in
in the presence of truth the body goes
strong.
In the presence of falsehood it goes
weak.
It's so simple even an idiot can get
that.
You get it?
This is a protoplasmic in my
understanding protoplasmic response
that for life to survive it had to be
able to discern poison from food.
So the little bacteria or little
organisms
had to have some way of knowing this
stuff here will kill you. This stuff
here will make you grow. Those that
didn't learn it are no longer with us.
So it's a basic
knowingness of life forms starting out
at the lowest forms of protoplasm
and going on up to the highest level.
But with it you're capable of knowing
anything.
Now, the thing that's the most
mind-boggling of all,
the most mind-boggling thing of all,
therefore, you won't get it.
Listen carefully.
>> Uhoh.
is within an instant you can tell the
truth about anything.
Anything with a capital A,
anything now or ever. Anything anywhere
in the universe.
Anything that ever occurred, anything
that's possible.
You can know the truth about anything in
an instant.
It takes one instant.
Let's see how it works.
We have permission to do this here. This
crowd here calibrates over 350, 400,
420. Holy cats. 440. Holy cats. 435.
430.
This cal, this group here calibrates
over 430.
Okay,
let's do the United The United States
Congress calibrates over 300
350.
You you calibrate higher than the United
States Congress. That's good enough for
starters.
That's because it's a spiritually
oriented group.
To be spiritually oriented tends to lift
your level of consciousness
and throw you in the company of others
that are like-minded.
Uh people who are spiritually oriented
tend to gravitate towards each other and
uh are attracted to each other and feel
comfortable and at home with each other.
All right. So this is very famous this
these levels of consciousness.
This is called the map of consciousness
and it's uh printed in all the languages
in the world 29 languages or 30
languages or something and is commonly
known now throughout the world actually
due to our own work and of course due to
it its practicality.
So you you don't have to read a whole
book to get that a thing could by using
the arm you can calibrate
It's either truthful or it's not
truthful. And if it is truthful, what
level of truth is it? Uh so this is
extremely useful. Now today what we're
talking about is peace
which as a state of consciousness
calibrates at 600.
Peace as a way of being in the world is
one thing.
Political peace is something else.
But peace as a level of consciousness is
an extremely high state.
It means you have to give up the
attraction to all the other things that
would pull you down.
As you see, shame and guilt, apathy,
grief, fear, cravingness, anger,
pridefulness
are all in the lower
lower levels of consciousness.
Courage is at 200.
If somebody's going to help me out, if
I'm in the armed forces,
who do I want to come and get me?
I'm laying there just been shot
about to get blown up. Who do I want?
I want somebody right here.
I don't want somebody at pride.
I don't want somebody who's going to
talk to me and reason about it.
If they love me, that's fine.
But that's just uh
flowery.
I want somebody with courage.
Courage. I want somebody with courage.
Somebody who says, "You're about to get
blown up. Now what?
And I always give the this thing when I
was in the Navy and this mine is right
next to the mine sweeper. We were
sweeping the East China Sea. Here's this
mine came up from the bottom and then
it's got these things sticking out of
it.
>> Horns.
>> Horns. Yeah. So anyway, the horn is
almost touching the side of the ship.
We're about about to get blown to bits
any second.
and we're holding this thing away with
boat boat uh boat poles to keep it away.
So this other guy is helping me and he
looks at me. He says, "What if it blows
up?" I said, "Well, then we die." He
said, "Oh, you're right."
I just told him the truth and the
sincerity of it was just what he needed
to hear.
And the reason I was so bland about
dying is I'd had near-death experiences
and been out of body and all that kind
of thing. And therefore, there really
wasn't anything to be afraid of. If you
leave the body,
and those of you who have had the
experience, when you look at the body,
it's laying there. You're the spirit and
you you're nowhere particular in space.
And the body is laying there and it
doesn't really look all that
interesting.
You wonder why you were ever so attached
to it in the first place.
All right. So, these are the levels of
consciousness. Today, we're going to be
talking about
uh peace, which is actually the highest
level of consciousness. You see, to let
go to reach the state of peace, you got
to let go of shaming yourself.
You got to get rid of attacking yourself
with guilt. You have to care enough
about life that you're no longer in
apathy. It's time to get over feeling
grief about things. You screwed up. So,
all right. You're screwed up. You're
scared to death. I mean, who cares?
I didn't ask if you were scared, boy. I
just told you to climb up that mast and
fix that goddamn thing.
That's what they told me. I'm up in the
mast and I have a fear of heights. And I
said, "Don't look down, Shorty." Like a
stupid idiot, from the top of the mask,
I looked down. Christ, the body just the
body went into involuntary spasm.
The Bosen's mate said, "I'm going to
have to come up and get you, Shorty." I
said, "Okay." I couldn't let go of the
mask.
He came up in a Bosen's chair. He was
the boxing champion of the Third Fleet.
And uh he said, "Jardy, I'm going to
have to coalcock you." I said, "Okay."
I could not let go of the mask. The
bodies were involuntary spasm.
He was the champion of the third FE
fleet. He was a ferocious boxer
and he had an incredible knockout punch.
So I I just I said, "Okay, okay, go
ahead." So I waited for the knot guy
punched and all of a sudden the body let
go. Involuntary just like knowing where
to pour that cup of coffee. The
involuntariness of it all.
So we have courage. Then we have
neutral. Neutral is it's okay if it goes
this way and it's okay if it goes that
way. Willingness
at 310, acceptance at 350.
that the high 300s are very very
powerful in the world. If you're a
worldly person, these are the levels you
want. The great multi-millionaires,
uh, who's the one that keeps buying
casinos and buying whole countries and
anyway, they all calibrate in high 300s.
uh
which is sort of a a way of being in the
world where acquisition and mastery
I is motivating just for its own sake to
own more gambling casinos than any other
person in the world is just the
gratification of it doesn't need money
got enough money but just to be that so
when you get to the 400s now you talk
about the intellect and reason thinking
this thinking this
these are the great books of the western
world everything of great note is in the
400s love is in the 500s
uh joy is 540 peace is 600
uh so these are all energizing as you go
up energizing and energizing
but peace is no longer energizing
when you go into a state of peace you
can sit sit on a rock all day
and people have to tell you you got to
go in now. You're going to get
sunstroke. You say, "Okay."
All right. So, peace is a divine state.
The beginning of the divine states. So,
okay. We'll go on. Is that enough of the
calibrated levels? These are the uh
enlightenment 600 and up.
uh supreme godhead, God manifests his
divinity, the archangels,
Christ, Buddhahood, Krishna, Brahman,
these are all a thousand. Those are
called avatars.
All right. So, we'll go on. We'll go on
next. The uh this is the energy field in
microwatts in microwatts. So you see the
energy field of the calibrated levels
translates into the physics of it all.
And you see that the amount of energy.
So you see down here these people don't
have much energy. That's where they're
in apathy
and they don't care enough about it.
Here it takes more brain energy for
brains. 500 is the level of love. 600 is
selfless love. And these are the levels
of enlightenment which go up to a
thousand. Okay.
Now the world's population, the reason
peace is so rare in the world, people
think peace is whatever that you call
that when there's no war.
Anyway, 85% of the world's population
calibrates below 200. 200 is the level
of truth. truth level of truth is 200.
85% of the world's population calibrates
below 200. Uh-huh. That explains the
nature of the world. So there's no point
in trying to make it wrong. It's just
that people have not reached the point
of consciousness.
People keep going back to jail for minor
crimes over and over and over again. And
you say, 'Well, after three or four
trips, they've been arrested for
stealing. Why do they go and do it all
over again? It's because they're down
here. It's because they don't get it.
Okay, so we'll move on next. Okay,
here's the world's population.
Here's the world's population.
You see, only 15% of the world's
population is above 200.
The implication of this is staggering.
This is all of mankind.
All below 200.
Only 15% of
human population calibrates above the
level of integrity 200.
Which means the average person will seal
you blind if you give them a chance.
As we know from the Congress and the
15% of the people
uh are above 200. So why doesn't mankind
then just fall off into the ocean and
drown
and it's because the 15% have so much
power that they totally counterbalance
the all of mankind.
85% would not even be able to survive on
its own. This 15% is what keeps mankind
uh alive. Okay. Next
um the evolution of consciousness over
time.
This is percent of elapsed time. And you
can see consciousness stayed way down
here and then only in the last few
minutes of human history uh did it rise
up to the current level. Yes, the
current level of consciousness of
mankind overall
is um let's see it's over 2025
206 207.
Overall mankind calibrates 206.
Okay. So now we'll move on. These are
the great evolutionary early epics and
their calibrations. You see life begins
as protozoa and bacteria calibrates at
one or two.
Then you see the marine the fish then
the animals the reptiles and then we
move up move up the scale of the animal
kingdom.
Next slide.
And we get to the animal kingdom. Now
here's one we're very familiar with. Uh
here we have bacteria,
insects, fish,
komodo, dragon, reptiles, snakes,
alligators.
Here's the dinosaurs, whale, dolphin,
migratory birds. Isn't that interesting?
I think that's just fascinating.
I love the animal kingdom and it's very
interesting. A dove calibrates at 145.
a grizzly bear at 160.
Don't fool around with grizzly bears. At
160, they have only one interest, and
that's to find out if you're good eating
or not.
We get to the hippopotamus,
we get to the deer.
You see, below level 200, that's the
great demarcation. Below level 200,
uh, animal life is predatory. They live
by the death of others. From 200 and up
arise the herbivores.
The herbivores survive without killing
anybody. They don't have to kill
anybody. Cow doesn't have to kill
anybody to eat. So here now you get to
the deer and the piggy and the elk dairy
cow
and we're moving up the scale.
Uh, the farm horse cats are at 240. The
family cat is at 245.
Dogs are at 240. The family dog is 250.
Then we go on up to gorilla. Oscar the
cat. Alex the train gray parrot. Coco
the trained gorilla. You see that Coco
the trained gorilla calibrates higher
than 95% of mankind.
You remember when that baby was dropped
in the gorilla pit
and the gorilla went over and picked up
the baby and set it over where the
keeper could come in the gate and get
it.
They don't do that in other parts of the
world.
They just kill you.
All right. So, Oscar the cat. Oscar's
the cat that knows when you're going to
die.
That's a famous cat. You know who Oscar
the cat is? If a if Oscar goes and
sleeps with you, you you're due to die
within 24 hours.
They he was in a nursing home and they
found out Oscar knew when somebody was
going to leave the world within 24 hours
and he would go and sleep with them and
sure enough within 24 hours they were
dead. All right. So here's the song
verse song. Now, here's the cat's purr.
A cat's purr is at 500, and a dog's
wagging tail is at 500.
So, when the cat is sleeping next to you
in the bed going
to me, it's like music.
The next happy thing is you get up in
the morning because the cat got you up
purring and there's the doggy and the
doggy's going
Dog wagging tails 500.
Unconditional love. Unconditional love.
I'm always interested in advertising.
And those those ads that show a dog with
a wagging tail calibrate much higher
than all the other ads.
If you want to sell more bush beans,
you have a dog with a wagging tail.
Purr.
I had a cat. I had to teach him how to
purr. He didn't know how to purr.
He's my $50 cat. I never thought I'd
spend $50 for a cat, but this cat was
unusual. And we brought him home and he
didn't know how to purr.
I waited for him to purr. I never had a
cat that didn't purr. He didn't know how
to purr. So, I had to show him how to
purr. I took him to bed and I'm
And I held him next to me so he could
feel the vibration in my chest.
Next thing you know, he's going.
So I had to teach He could do it on the
exhale and I had to teach him how to do
it on the inhale.
So I go,
next thing I know.
So
people who don't like cats or dogs,
beware of them.
Anybody who doesn't like a dog's wagging
tail or a kitty's fur
better carry a gun.
Okay, we'll move next.
Great books of the western world. This
is a profound importance. This is the
great the renaissance. The great books
of the western world. And uh here you
see all the great minds of history.
Charles Darwin, Dustfki,
uh,
all the great names, Hypocrates, Hegel,
you see all the great names.
Shakespeare, Adam Smith.
Here are all the great names of history.
And when you go to college, this is what
you don't know it, but when you go to
college, this is what you're supposed to
be learning.
You're supposed to become acquainted
with the great minds of history.
When you go to college to learn the
great minds of history, you do. Except
that now the far left has taken over.
And you see what's wrong with the far
left is that Karl Marx calibrates at
130.
Why is Karl Marx so low?
Does not teach the truth. Truth is at
200. Marxism is at 130. So the reason
the far-left calibrates low is because
it's based on the proposition of
perpetrator and victim. It's a dualistic
perception.
And this dualistic perception projects
onto the world victim and perpetrator.
If you're poor, it's got to be
somebody's fault that they caused you to
be poor. Not that you're lazy, didn't
pay any attention in class, and are
drunk all the time. That's got nothing
to do with it.
the halves are responsible for creating
the have nots etc. All right. Anyway,
that it's tried as a social system
hasn't worked out anywhere.
We have lots of politicians that's you
know keep trying to put it onto us even
though it hasn't worked anywhere. Hasn't
worked anywhere. Show me some place
where it's worked in the world and I'll
gain some enthusiasm.
Okay. Next.
Uh this is uh very sophisticated
uh this has to do with a situation.
Uh there seems to be an event.
Now the event however only takes place
within a certain field of context.
So an event is defined actually by the
field in which it seems to happen. It
seems to happen. We'll go to the next
one. I shouldn't have put this one in.
That's not too good one. Uh
here we have the difference between
lower mind and higher mind. Now as we go
evolve from the animal kingdom, you now
come to uh the lower lower mind and uh
the li the lower mind wants things. It's
insensitive. It's callous. These are the
people that go to jail all the time. all
the time beating up people. Uh their
indifference to the suffering of others,
totally insensitive,
completely selfish, you know, and they
depend on force
and uh higher mind is more
sophisticated. Higher mind, which is
more typical of this audience, you know,
is more sensitive. It tends to be
merciful. It tends to serve all of life.
It's intelligent. So this is power.
This is power. This side actually has
power. And this side here depends on
force. This depends on force.
So if I want somebody to follow me, I
don't use a something to beat them beat
them up. I try to persuade them that
this is the best way to go. Okay? We we
persuade people.
Uh
these are the levels of consciousness
in which form begins to register within
mind.
The first thing it runs into is that
which watches and experiences.
That's an aspect of awareness.
That's the observer, the witness which
doesn't think. The light of
consciousness
arises out of the godhead
out of
out of God as creator arises the light
of consciousness.
Though what we do is consciousness
research.
What we're really doing is constantly
researching what could otherwise be
called the mind of God which is
consciousness. Consciousness
is infinite
and uh has no beginning and has no end
and has no limitations
and it's infinitely powerful.
With spiritual evolution, you get low
let go of thinkingness and you reach an
inner state of quietude.
The one that's mo easiest and most
obvious to get to reach is the observer,
the witness. You observe and witness,
but you don't think anything about it or
say anything about it or argue anything
about it. I observe someone sitting at
the table. She looks peaceful.
She looks peaceful.
All right. So I don't need the observer
witness doesn't think about things.
So move on to the next. Then
we have to become acquainted because you
have to understand how you're going to
have peace in a world uh without
understanding the human condition.
The human brain left and right brain
as your animal brain. Then your animal
brain below 200 it sees something
happening
instantly it goes it bypasses the cortex
and goes directly to the emotions
goes to the emotion emotions.
All right. So that's the emotional side
of the brain. It's really uh the animal
side. Below 200,
you run by the animal brain which is
into fight or flight. The alarm reaction
disrupts the acupuncture meridians.
Negative muscle test response.
All right. The other side of the brain
is the spiritual side. The right brain
dominance is nonlinear.
It is the source of peace and we're
talking about peace today. So what we're
talking about is the release of
endorphins within your brain associated
with positive emotions.
the peaceful endorphins
spiritual side of your body
uh brings about healing, balances your
acupuncture system, and you get a
positive muscle test response.
So what we're talking about today then
is
serenity, peacefulness
as a way of being in the world because
that activates the condundalini energy,
the spiritual energy uh to rise up into
the right side of the brain and that
alters all your responses.
So a fearful person looks over there and
is frightened and a person who's more
into endorphins looks over there and is
interested.
So the endorphins support life.
Okay, next thing
levels of consciousness and social
problems.
As you see here's the level of
consciousness
uh over here uh people or a community or
a country or a
neighborhood let's say
what is the rate of unemployment seeing
as unemployment is very much in the news
today unemployment
the
>> yeah anyway the rate of unemployment as
you see increases the lower the level of
consciousness.
The rate of unemployment does not
decrease
in direct align with
the number of jobs available as everyone
presumes.
Everybody thinks the reason they're
unemployed is because there aren't any
jobs.
So you see that the power is given to is
given outside the person.
If I'm unemployed,
there's only one reason, and I've been
unemployed.
There's only one reason I'm unemployed.
Me.
Sole cause of unemployment is me.
After World War II, there was no jobs.
But whenever there was no jobs, I always
had three or four of them. I drove cab
at night. I drove
cabb during the day or the bartender at
night.
Uh if you're broke and you haven't got
any money, the quickest thing to do is
you go down any street. I'll tell nobody
can ever complain that they're
unemployed after what I say next.
You want to run out, put your fingers in
your ears.
If you want to listen to this, you can't
blame anybody anymore.
I'll tell you what you do.
It's a secret.
You go down any street.
You knock on doors.
Lady opens the door. You say, "You need
any windows washed today?"
I've never gone more than three houses
without somebody employing me right on
the spot.
dollar window.
20 minutes I made $10.
Go down the next house. By noon I've
made $95.
No income tax on it.
Don't let me know that.
It's impossible to be unemployed.
See, unless you're disabled, let's say,
if you're disabled like I am right now,
as you can see, I can barely walk
around.
When you can't barely walk around, what
do you do? You give lectures for God's
sake.
You write a book,
sing a song, dance, be funny, whatever.
So unemployment then is a lack of uh
creativity
uh a lack of awareness
and if you ask God dear God I need a job
please guide my guide my steps in the
right way then a job comes to you
uh and failing that you knock on doors
it's un it's not possible to be
unemployed
anyway the rate of unemployment down
below here is 97%.
It's always those people's fault. Those
people's fault.
The rate of unemployment here is based
on blame and projecting
projecting their power into the world.
Who has the power over your employment?
You or the world? If you project it into
the world, now you become a servant of
the world.
The rate of unemployment amongst people
of higher energy fields is practically
0% as you see it goes up and I certainly
must have been at least the 400s in
those days and uh unemployment there was
only 7%. The rate of poverty goes up uh
in the same way. The higher you go the
less the rate of poverty.
Poverty is one thing. Being broke is
another.
I've been broke a lot of times in my
life, but I didn't consider it poverty.
I considered it being broke.
How how is life happy or not happy? Down
here, these people, they're all unhappy.
So, you can see southernliness about
life.
Uh what happens is your your rate of
happiness decreases to almost 0%.
These people think they're getting away
with something, but as you can see,
they're all unhappy. All unhappy. And as
your consciousness level goes up, uh,
the rate of happiness becomes almost
100%.
And the rate of criminality shows the
reverse. Of course, the higher the level
of consciousness, the rate of
criminality is rather rather rare. And
as your consciousness level goes down,
the rate of criminality
is close to 100%. Close to 100%.
Every bum knows that if you go to sleep
on the street, you wake up, your shoes
are gone.
So always sleep on your shoes. Don't
leave them on your feet. They'll take
them off while you're asleep. Okay.
Remove next.
uh you see uh the uh susceptibility to
AIDS correlates with the levels of
consciousness.
The lower the level of consciousness,
the higher the rate of AIDS. Okay, we'll
go next.
Um
levels of consciousness and rate of
happiness. We did that already. We see
that
pridefulness
cuts your rate of happiness to 22%.
And arrogance, anger, fear, all these
things cut your rate of happiness.
Courage then from the level of truth on
up the percent of happiness increases
rapidly.
Okay. Next.
Uhhuh.
Uh these are the levels of consciousness
of great spiritual teachers. I just want
you to know they're in several of the
books. Uh all the great spiritual
teachers uh worldwide and in and
throughout history. Okay. Next.
Well, Socrates was at 540.
Uh
Socrates at 540. Uhhuh.
So anyway, I just wanted you to know
that they're all available and they're
written in the book. You don't have to
send us an email wanting to know about
somehow we've got all these people
listed and they always find somebody
who's not on the list and send us an
email about it.
Okay, next.
Um,
oh,
there is the difference between essence
and perception. The difference between
essence and perception. What a thing
looks like is perception.
And it consists of projections, what you
project onto a thing. Essence is what
the thing really is within itself.
So here you see the wolf in sheep's
clothing.
The wolf and sheep's clothing.
Inside is the predator
predator who will steal from all the
taxpayers
and buy themsel a couple of yachts and a
private plane and uh villas around the
world.
Let's see. Where are we on this list?
>> Are we gonna Okay, we're finally getting
to it.
Okay, I just wanted to cover the basics
uh for a common point of reference.
Uh
we're not supposed to be at 101. We're
supposed to speed at one, not 101. You
go from one to 101, you go from 101
backwards.
How can that be backwards? There we go.
Oh, shake it up. Shake it up, baby.
101 ways to happiness.
I thought we were talking about peace
today. I don't want anybody being happy
out there.
Give up happiness, man. Give me peace.
Oh.
Oh,
here's the saddest story I've ever
That's a great line.
It's good to write that right at some
place, secret place where you can look
at it and nobody can see.
Yours is the saddest story I ever heard.
I want everybody to make one. A little
sign.
You put it on your mirror at home in the
bathroom. You stick it in the corner of
the mirror. It is an experiment. Do it
for seven days.
If you do it for seven days, you become
a seven dayer.
And I know who they are.
Do it for six days. Cheat. No, I'll know
it.
You put a little sign there. It says,
"Yours is the saddest story I've ever
heard." And you put it in the corner of
your mirror. And you will find that your
life is brightens up instantly.
Won't cost you anything.
Won't even charge you a dollar for this.
Why? Because it's it it tilts your view
of life into a different direction. just
to see that yours is the, you know, that
kills self-pity.
It kills resentment, it kills blame, it
kills all the stuff that makes people
miserable and it gets you back to the
reality that the source of your own
happiness is solely within you.
Nobody can take it away from you. And
that's I was tell all the husband, I
said, "Listen, you got to do your job.
Don't let it bother you. I'm ready to
go. Go ahead. Chop my head off if you
like. I want him to have a good day.
It's his job to chop your head off. So
why complain?
101 ways to peace.
Number one.
Yeah. You got to keep track of the time
on it. Where are we going to break?
>> 15 minutes.
>> How much?
>> About 15 minutes.
>> 15 minutes. Oh, wow.
Boy, we can hit cover the history of the
world in 15 minutes.
101 ways to peace. Now, peacefulness
then has to be a decision that you make.
Peacefulness can can exist in the right
right in the middle of war and
devastation
and catastrophe.
The ways to become develop a peaceful
nature. Uh, the first thing to do is to
give up trying to change and control
other people.
Don't tell them how to vote.
Give up
questionable advertising. Let go of
trying to change and control others.
We always want other people to be
different than they are.
Why can't they be more like like me?
If I can't change them, if I'm stuck
with them, well, then at least I can
control them. I can control them. So,
you'll see how often your mind would
like to change people and make them
different.
The next big thing to have peace of mind
is to let go to get even.
You see that in the political arena,
things the previous administration did,
the new administration has to get into a
a make wrong and a get even because they
want to be right.
That's why you can't never see peace in
the political arena because they're all
up they're all up to proving others
wrong, proving they're right, and trying
to get even for what the previous
administration did 18 years ago or
something.
So let you have to let go wanting to get
even.
You can let go wanting to get even if
you understand divine justice.
If you understand divine justice, it
saves you the bother of getting even
because everything
take is taken care of by divine by the
presence of God.
All things then karmically
have their own karmic payoff and you
don't have to do anything. It's not
necessarily not necessary to bring down
your enemies because they will bring
themselves down by their own hand. By
their own hand, they will do themsel in
and then you're not stuck with the
karma. You see, the minute you get even
uh or get even with them or conquer
them, etc., uh you now have that the
karma of that. If somebody falls over,
it's better that they do it of their own
accord than you're putting a bullet in
them.
It's impolite to shoot people
without even asking their permission.
It's best to So, if you really want
peace above all else,
the mind thinks.
The mind thinks and the spirit knows.
The spirit knows. So the spirit knows.
Let go of wine to get even and let go
wine to be right. And this is extremely
difficult in the human condition. In our
society getting even and being right is
considered a
dre.
You have to do that. And the other thing
that
goes on is making other people wrong. So
if you're right, then other people must
be wrong.
The struggle for moral superiority
of being right is intense.
So we learn to practice discernment
rather than judgmentalism.
Discernment and judgmentalism.
Discernment then is interested in
finding out what is the essence of
something. Discernment is the essence.
Judgmentalism then is a more seeking the
moral high ground.
So we'll go to the next.
The way to make these things come about
in your own life is to silence
opinionation.
And it's not necessary to have an
opinion about everything.
In fact, it's not necessary to have an
opinion about anything.
You don't need an opinion about
anything.
If I said to you, what do you think of
such and such? You say, "Well, I really
don't have an opinion about it."
What? Got no opinion? Wishywashy, idiot.
What do you think of our new Supreme
Court justice?
I don't know.
It's the way things are going
in our society. This is the way things
are going. And such a thing is likely to
happen. But when the waves go this way,
they're not likely to happen. So you can
stand back from society
instead of being bobbled around by the
waves.
So we learn to be modest with our
opinions.
We learn to perfect diplomacy,
gentility.
They really people don't know what the
upper classes are. They think people the
upper classes are having jets and big
estates and lots of money. They don't
really know what the upper classes are.
The upper classes, everybody's got
money. It doesn't mean anything.
Everybody's got a title. Yeah.
The most important thing was the
capacity for diplomacy.
uh for diplomacy graciousness.
I was once put up for one of the
greatest probably the most exclusive
club in America whose name I I can't
even mention. And I got to meet all the
the really high people in the world in
the New York City area.
The president of this, the president of
that. If I told you all the titles,
you'd say you met them. I said, "Yeah."
There was one quality that they had.
100%. These are the top top people in
the world. Top top. The top of the top.
Every one of them was gracious.
To be one of the top people in the
world. Then the first thing to do is to
be gracious. That means considerate of
others. A sensitivity to others. That
they've been standing a long time.
Wouldn't you like a chair to sit? You've
been a long time without water. Could I
get you something to drink?
They have to put in another hour or two.
You say, "How about a cup of coffee?"
The one thing about the top people in
the world, it was just stunning. Was
extremely gracious.
Extremely gracious.
I met the richest, most powerful people
in the world. And I'd come into their
office and they'd say, "This is Dave
Hawkins who I want you to meet." Yes.
And he'd say, "Can I get your cup of
coffee or sit over here where the sun
won't shine in your eyes?
Here's the big big foo.
Make George Soros look like poor."
And they're
solicitous of your comfort.
be solicitus then of the comfort of
others. This means not just physical
comfort but their psychological comfort,
their spiritual comfort. If somebody
disagrees with with me, I tell them
that's very interesting. I think that's
great. Disagreeing with me is fine with
me. Why? Because I want the person to be
honest with who they are. All right. I
don't I'm buttering me up with false
false yes men.
Be modest with one's opinions. It would
seem you'll say, "It seems to me at this
time that this is the way it appears to
be." You see, that's flexible.
It seems to me a certain way. That
leaves room for you to move out of the
way. So, you become diplomatic and
gentile.
You become gracious and considerate of
others. People say, "What's all this got
to do with God?"
God is gracious and considerate.
When you get to heaven, he says, "Would
you like to float on this cloud here?
Would you like to float over the sea?
So God comes disguised.
God is disguised.
And you have to be spiritually advanced
to realize the God and everyone.
The God and everyone. So the person who
says to you, "Can I get you a cup of
coffee? Would you like to sit down? You
look like you've been on a long trip."
What's talking to you is not him. What's
talking to you is divinity.
That's divinity speaking to you.
Why? Because divinity is that quality of
consciousness.
It's not a personhood. It has no gender,
no age.
gentility, consideration for others.
It's also called unconditional love.
Unconditional lovingness is a concern
for the welfare of others,
putting them first that they have the
most comfortable seat. Huh? Be gracious
and considerate
and keep inner serenity as a goal.
Inner serenity as a goal.
What's the point of winning the argument
and then you can't sleep all night?
I guess I told him off.
Boy, did I ever tell him off. Dumbass.
So, you keep keep a sense of humor.
My secret weapon is a sense of humor.
Everything is comical when you look at
it a certain way. When you look at it
from really high space, everything is
comical. Uh here are people struggling
to achieve uh all these things, you
know. Anyway, be modest with your
opinions. Perfect diplom diplomatic
skills and gentility.
Be gracious and considerate.
Keep serenity as a goal.
It's okay to be wrong or to have no
opinion at all. People say, "What do you
think about that?" You say, "I don't
know. I just haven't thought about it. I
really can't tell you." People say,
"Well, that's being wishy-washy."
I love being wishy-washy.
Wish she was. She wish she w.
What do you think about so and so being
out on the Supreme Court? Oh, I think
that's fantastic. At least she ain't out
of a job.
Ain't collecting unemployment.
A lot of people where came come from
where she come from or un unemployment.
She ain't on unemployment.
Working for a living.
Uh,
another thing you can do and when you're
undecided is to calibrate the options
and be flexible.
And this is from an old friend of mine.
It is not necessary to have an opinion
on everything.
An old friend of mine that I came out
west with. And uh, that's his quote. I
put it in one of the books. Put his name
there. I won't give his name away now.
No, I'm not giving away his name.
Keeping it a secret.
You don't have to have an opinion on
everything or on anything. People say,
"What do you think about so and so?" And
you say, "Well, I don't know. I just
haven't given it much thought yet." I'm
going to think about it after dinner.
I'm going to think about it after dinner
tonight.
We got a lot of to go. I better move
along.
Next, these are all practical. If you
want to live a peaceful life and be
peaceful, the one of the first rules is
avoid peace demonstrations.
All peace demonstrations are violent.
They got dogs, water cannons,
shock machines.
They got police all over the place.
thugs.
Usually what goes on at a peace
demonstration is thugy.
I can start a riot anywhere
in less than 10 minutes for $50.
Anybody don't believe me?
They know better.
The communists learned how to do that,
perfected the art of it. For $50, you
can start a riot anywhere. I'll tell you
how. In case you want to start a riot,
don't have to be a commie.
You want to start a riot, you go to the
nearest lowass bar.
You see, I got 50 bucks here, fellas.
Now, what I want you to do, there's some
badass guys out there that stole my car
and my girlfriend, and I want you to
give them a good poke in the nose and
teach them a lesson. Any takers?
$10 a piece. I can get five guys to
leave any bar anytime.
And you have two shots in a beer when
you get back. Okay. Okay. SOP.
Next thing you know, there's a riot on
the street. Then the call call the
police. I can start a riot anywhere in
five minutes flat. The communists
perfected the technique of this
spontaneous demonstrations.
All spontaneous demonstrations are
staged.
If it wasn't staged, why would they all
be there?
Why would 50 people be on a street
corner?
How many people is there standing in the
average New York street cover corner?
One or two? Five maybe. Not 50. How do
you get 50 people on a street corner?
You get get it by organized
community organizing.
It's called barroom organizing. Nearest
barroom. We'll get you demonstrators in
two minutes. And demonstrators love
demonstrating. So they'll pull in more
demonstrators. Next thing you know, the
knuckles are going and the police are
there. It's wonderful excitement.
Everybody's adrenaline goes up.
Everybody's having a good time.
So if you want to be peaceful, avoid
peace demonstrations because they are
too violent.
They got police dogs, water cannons.
And here, this is useful. And I'll leave
you with this thought while we take a
break. We're going to take a break.
All of you who pine to be beautiful and
rich and all, remember that Socrates was
short and ugly.
It's okay to be short and ugly.
Socrates was short and ugly. He wasn't
tall and handsome.
Socrates became world famous for
centuries.
He was neither tall nor handsome nor
rich.
All right. So, we'll convene again. How
long?
>> Um about 11:30.
>> How soon is that?
>> 15 minutes.
Have one for the road.