Okay, there's your pen. Every set.
>> Okay.
All right.
We'll put this someplace.
>> That's for beating off children and
small dogs.
>> Hi.
>> Yes.
>> Is there a difference between energy and
consciousness?
Yes, consciousness is a realm. A realm
and within the realm, the realm is
dominated by the energy of
consciousness. Yeah. So the like there's
electricity and then there's the energy
of electricity.
So as I say it's electric, you're
qualifying the field, identifying the
field and then energy is a different
matter. Mhm.
Yes.
>> Thank you. May May I hold your hand for
a short time?
>> Yes.
>> Thank you.
>> God bless.
>> It's hard to explain consciousness. I
should take some time and go into
greater detail.
>> Hi. In your new book, you talked about
fear, overcoming anxiety. I was just
hoping if you could elaborate on the
process of deeply surrendering the fear.
>> Letting go, resisting it. Uh constantly
letting go, resisting. People are afraid
of fear.
Fear is just an emotion. And um what you
do is you let go being afraid of fear
and you let yourself you let fear swamp
you. You get swamped by fear. And if you
keep letting go, resisting fear, it
becomes intense. And then suddenly you
realize that it's all it's always the
fear of death. And as you let go your
fear of death, the fear dissolves.
Oh, you might say all fear is innately
fear of death
and therefore letting go of the fear of
death itself. You experience it out.
You experience it out. You let the fear
come up. quit resisting it.
That's how you get rid of pain as well.
You let go resisting it. You let go
resisting it and eventually it just you
disappear it.
>> Thank you. Doctor
>> Wernern used to call it a stack. Warner
called it a stack. Let go resisting the
stack. The stack is built up over
lifetimes.
All the suppressed emotional energy that
you didn't experience out. Can you do
okay?
>> Huh?
>> Can you hear? Okay.
>> Yes. Fine. Mhm. Seems very loud like
it's coming out of the table, but that's
right.
>> That's just
>> seems mystical.
I thought it was God talking to me at
first.
>> Okay. God.
>> Hello, Dave.
>> I want you.
I want you.
Yeah. Okay.
>> Go ahead.
>> Hi. Um, my name is Aldi and I have
problems with my liver. I've had I have
problems with my liver.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, I have hepatitis C and it's
it's
halfway to scerosis.
>> It's halfway what?
>> To scerosis.
And um I'm wondering one if I can just
get some healing
from you.
>> This is
>> healing.
What's unique about hepatitis C? Why
isn't it A or B? What's hepatitis C?
Huh?
>> I don't know. It's
>> How do you know you got it? How you say
you got hepatitis C? Where where'd you
find that out?
>> Well, the doctor's uh the doctors.
>> Oh. Oh. And where does that come from?
>> Um,
>> what is it? A virus?
>> Yeah, it's a virus.
>> And how do you catch this virus?
>> Um, there's it's a blood a blood virus.
It's a blood virus.
>> All right. So, what is the treatment for
it?
Um
there's u there's only one treatment
that the western world has and it's um
it's like a year-long treatment. It's
it's basically like
um
cancer treatment. What is what's that
called?
>> Radiation.
>> Radiation. It's like that. It's like
chemotherapy.
>> Oh. So it's a major
>> it's only like a 50% 40% type of thing.
So
>> yeah. So in a way you don't have any
choice about the matter. Huh?
>> Well, I I've I've tried it and I
couldn't handle it.
>> Oh, the treatment was worse than the
disease.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, I see. Okay. So, you pray to God for
it. A healing and the karmic
propensities will determine the outcome
anyway.
>> Mhm.
>> Can you say a prayer for him anyway? You
know, can you say some kind of prayer
for him anyway?
>> Oh, here. Wait, wait till I finish this.
Okay. I can only do three things at
once.
I need the arm. What I'm holding in mind
is okay.
Dear God, we pray for pray for your
healing of this thy servant, this thy
child that is seated before me, asking
for your healing. Amen.
There is up to your karmic
balance.
We'll get this settled down here sooner
or later.
Sooner or later,
we'll find out its secret.
>> Hello.
>> I um
thought of all these questions to ask
and then I read your books and you've
answered them and I just wanted to thank
you so much for
just for being here.
>> That's very kind of you. Where do you
want me to sign any? This is the wrong
page.
>> Sign it right there. Okay.
Okay.
I'm glad you got usefulness out of it.
It's meant to be informative and the
information itself then becomes
inspirational.
>> It's changed me just by reading it and
just by being here. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> May I?
>> Yes indeed.
>> Holy smokes.
to back.
>> Okay.
>> All right. Let's go this way.
What book is this? It looks familiar.
>> It's the Zen of Wang.
>> Oh, Wang Paul.
Yes.
>> Salut was a soldier.
>> Yes.
The you talk often of the greetings that
the pets give us at the very high levels
400 low levels of 500 and um can we
become that skillful to greet one
another at that level
>> and would there be a way of doing it as
soldiers salute one another or a child
comes into the world?
>> I didn't get the first part of his
question. Um he says is it is it in our
the can we ever become as high as say
you know the cat's purr and the doggy
where we can greet each other at that
calibration is it possible for
>> as high as what is what
>> in the 400s what the cat's purr is
>> oh the cat's purr now the cat's purr is
at 500
>> wait a second will ever be possible for
us to greet one another
>> oh in the same way
we do routinely
in in a spiritual group like this.
People hug each other, people love each
other. Uh they sort of bond for long
periods of time. They see each other at
other meetings.
No, we're uh we're as high as the dogs
are.
>> I'm glad to hear that.
>> I sometimes wonder
>> some members of society,
>> God bless you. Some members
>> some members
>> well we said the majority of mankind
calibrates below 200
and a dog's wagging tail is 500 and a
kitty's purr is 500.
So there are the majority of people on
the planet do not have the lovingness or
kindness of a dog or a cat.
That's why they kill each other in the
name of whatever
a cat won't kill you in the name of
chief dog
chief kitty
come over and cut your juggler in much
less slowly saw your head off.
No, dogs and cats are more benign.
>> Thank you.
>> Even mountain lions are benign. Did we
calibrate that mountain lion
behind the house?
>> I don't know.
>> All right.
We had a mountain lion walk by the house
not long ago. I'm looking out the window
and here's a mountain lion.
Boom.
>> I can't figure what is all this.
>> This is a journal of some sort.
>> Oh. Oh.
I thought we calibrated that mountain
line. No. Huh? We didn't. All right.
>> Thank you, Dr. Hawkins.
After a second near-death experience in
1995,
I began to have stories where I became
acutely aware of the one being of all.
>> Of the what?
>> The one being of all, the self.
>> Oh. Oh yes. Okay.
>> These can last minutes, hours, days, and
sometimes weeks.
>> Yes.
>> Two weeks seems to be my limit.
>> Though at the time it seems to be a
permanent change.
>> Yes.
>> My question is about maintaining a
balanced energy level.
After about two weeks, I begin to become
overloaded.
Do you have any suggestions on releasing
or coping with high energy? What do you
want to release it for?
>> What do you mean release it?
>> It seems to build up in the body and the
body becomes anxious and overwhelmed.
>> Yeah. And then what happens?
>> I what I do is I go to my psychiatrist
and I terminate it.
>> How does he terminate it? Was it mallet
or what?
>> Medication.
>> Oh, bonk.
>> Same thing.
>> You do whatever common sense and
intelligence would tell you to do
because you're a human being.
So, you do the the rational,
sensible thing, you know.
Here's the
>> the labyrinth right here. Picture the
labyrinth.
>> May I hold your hand for a moment?
>> So, there's some medication that
relieves this?
>> Yes.
>> Uh-huh. So, it's a curable condition.
I don't want it to be a curable
condition.
>> You go through periods where you let go
of everything, experience the self more
strongly.
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
>> But you have to have your knuckles
wrapped in order to do it.
>> That's all right. However it comes about
is fine. However it comes about.
>> Thank you, doctor.
Yes,
>> Dr. Harit. Uh, thank you. I have no
questions. I just thank you and ask for
your blessing and a chance for a
picture.
>> I perish the bless.
I bless you in the name of the infinite
love of the God Almighty God our
creator. Amen.
>> Thank you.
Hello, doctor.
>> Yes, indeed.
>> Like to have a picture with you and
Susan if I could.
>> Indeed.
>> Thank you.
>> Oh my goodness.
Oh my goodness.
>> That's what I see.
>> Oh my goodness.
>> This a good one.
>> Put your head on it.
Okay.
>> Hello.
>> First of all, I want to say thank you
both of you for everything.
Um my question is that sometimes it
seems to me that people on a spiritual
path get it's almost effervescent and
enthusiastic almost in love and I find
for me my experience is that I get
quieter and simpler and I have less and
less to say. I wonder if you could help
me understand that and I'd like to know
if I'm missing something.
>> No, everyone is different. And everyone
experiences it. And uh you know the
levels that the people reach are not
always the same. And they uh you also
have different karmic propensities.
And uh
certain states although they are
magnificent
cannot be really tolerated for great
lengths of time. Ecstasy has a
limitation. Yeah.
And I remember finally letting go of
ecstasy.
And then after ecstasy came a profound
peace, profound. There was nothing more
to seek, nothing more to gain. There
were no other spiritual exercises
necessary.
Everything was complete and total.
So when we talk about stages, you know,
we're using generalities.
You can calibrate the levels of the
various states and that sometimes gives
you an idea where you are you know on
the on the path. Uhhuh.
Let God worry about it. You know
people try to define it and calibrate it
instead of just doing it.
>> I'm not inclined to calibrate it. I'm
inclined to just see what happens.
>> People say I surrender everything to
God. Now how much do I calibrate?
Oh boy, those are pretty looking things.
What What are those things?
>> Thank you both again very much. We love
you very much.
>> Thank you very much. What is this honey?
What is that?
>> Just saying.
>> Oh, I didn't know what it is.
Okay.
You surrender all things to God as they
arise.
Uhhuh.
>> Hello.
Um, my question is, what do you do when
you feel you need to make a decision and
been praying on it for quite some time
and asking for a miracle and no answer
seems to be coming?
>> What do you expect? Did it come in
skyriting or a voice out of the woods or
how many possibilities are there?
>> I don't know.
There only two, isn't there?
>> You mean either yes or no?
>> So, what if I don't feel I'm getting
either yes or no?
>> Then forget it.
>> Okay.
>> But you have spaghetti or goulash for
dinner isn't really important, is it?
>> No.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Can I touch your hand?
>> You don't have to be enlighten
enlightened by next Wednesday at noon,
you know.
>> Thank you. Can I touch your
>> People worry too much about such things.
>> Okay.
>> I was worrying where am I, you know?
>> Yeah.
>> It's like a vanity. Am I beautiful
today? Mirror, mirror on the wall. Tell
me, am I the f greatest of them all?
>> Thank you. I'm going to take a picture.
Ah,
it's best when you're worrying about
calibrated levels of yourself to just
try and get the general range. You know,
get the general range. If you're over
400, it doesn't make any difference
whether you're 422 or 427 or 418.
you know, you're generally in the 400s
or if you're in the 500s, what you
really want to know is the general range
of it all.
>> Yep. That's a natural curiosity.
>> Good afternoon.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you for coming
being here. I appreciate that. I um was
fixiated more or less on the inner
innocent inner child.
>> Yes.
>> And I run on emotions
right and wrong.
And I would like to
stop. And
>> why do you want to stop?
>> The feeling is not good.
>> Huh?
>> The feeling is not good of be making
somebody making myself right or making
somebody wrong.
>> Oh, right and wrong. That's not Yeah.
Okay. And also
>> that you mean judgmentalism.
>> That also
>> that's what right and wrong is all
about.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And and I don't know when my innocent
inner child because I know immediately
that I'm doing this.
>> I wouldn't I wouldn't label it. Don't
worry about it.
>> Okay.
>> You know, you either have to have apple
pie or pumpkin pie. That's all it
amounts to.
>> Uhhuh. There's no point in calibrating
pumpkin pie and calibrating apple pie.
At one time, one thing will be more
attractive and more important than at
other times
because it's not only the item itself,
but the context in which it's coming up.
The important thing about the spiritual
pathway,
I'll tell you one thing about it. The
important thing about the spiritual
pathway is that you're on the spiritual
pathway. That's the only thing that's
important about it.
That's all that's important
is you're you're oriented this way to
the wind and as the wind comes around
like a windmill, you're you'll turn with
the wind. So the speed of the windmill
is not what's important, but the fact
that you're turned to the wind.
I have a windmill at home and sometimes
it spins fast, sometimes it spins slow.
When it spins fast, it doesn't mean it's
a better windmill.
So, your orientation is what you want to
stay oriented to the wind. So,
spiritual impetus and suggestions and
occasions
uh you're like open open to them.
All right. Yeah.
You see, it's a good thing Marco Polo
didn't ask how many miles have I got to
go yet.
>> Thank you.
>> Um, hi. Good day. Um, I brought you a
present. Thank you.
>> Um, I just want to say thank you for the
work you do and thank you Susan for just
being you.
>> Thank you.
>> And I just want you to bless me and my
country, please.
>> What?
>> Where are you from?
>> South Africa.
>> Yeah.
>> He's one of them that are from South
Africa. I want you to bless him and his
country
>> and he's been studying our
>> Oh, yes. Yes. We have quite a few people
in South Africa. Yes. Okay. I have
permission to do as he asks. I have
permission to do as he asks. Okay. What
do you want me to do?
>> Just bless me and my country, please.
>> What did he say?
>> Bless bless him and his country.
>> Oh, God bless you and your country.
>> Thank you.
>> A very exciting country.
>> Yes.
>> Can I touch your hand?
>> A very exciting country.
>> There you go. Thank you very much. Thank
you very much.
>> Oh, nice. Wonderful. Oh, wow. Oh, boy.
Oh, boy.
That's lovely.
>> It's a shirt like
>> Oh, it is
>> the South African one.
>> This is a shirt that the South African
elders wear.
>> Elders.
>> Huh? What?
>> Thank you. It may be a bit big. Oh,
el elders.
>> He thought you were taller.
>> I'm recovering from the shock of elders,
not taller.
>> I thought you would be taller.
No, I am glad to announce I've been
reelected president of the octagenarian
society.
>> Octagenarian?
>> Yes.
>> I don't have a question, but I would
just like to touch your hand if I may.
>> Yes.
>> And um have a photo taken.
>> What did she say?
>> And have a photo taken.
>> Just and just say thank you for
everything. Not not the least you're
here.
>> Yes. Uhhuh. Thank you.
The thing about the Octagenarian Society
is you don't have to be elected. There's
no meetings and there's no dues or fees.
>> Hello. Can I shake your hand?
>> Yes.
>> Thanks.
I wrote my question down on a piece of
paper because I thought I'd forget it.
For the past three years, I've been
having trouble finding consistent work
and yet at the same time
>> finding what? Finding what?
>> Consistent work.
>> Consistent work and yet at the same time
trying to evolve spiritually. I believe
my parents want me to get out and
support myself.
Where do you live?
>> Brook Brooklyn, New York.
>> Brooklyn.
>> Yeah. Do you have
>> you can't You're not allowed to stay
home with your parents in Brooklyn
beyond a certain age.
>> Yeah, I'm turning 25. Uh I turned 25
today.
>> You're actually 25.
>> 25.
>> Yes, indeed. You're going to be an
embarrassment to your parents that
you're still living with your parents.
>> You going to say, "Is your son still
living with you?" No. No. He uh
>> I've been having a lot of trouble. Can
you
>> give me some advice?
>> It's a hard time to find.
>> Don't make up excuses for this idiot.
You got thing you got things cushy at
home, don't you?
>> I guess so. Yes.
>> You got it all cushy cushy cushy.
And you don't have to get out in the
cold bad world and stand on your own two
feet. Oh,
>> I think you hit home.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you.
>> I'll tell you, stand up straight. March
straight forward ahead. Walk walk over
to where there's a job and say, "I'm
ready to work. Sign me up.
>> Okay.
>> And ask what is the work later? You
know,
>> shoveling poo poo
>> thank you for the opportunity.
>> Yes.
>> I've been thinking a lot about keeping
holy company
>> and you just said that uh we are as high
as it goes here,
>> this group. and I haven't been to a
lecture in a while and I am very taken
back by the kindness and generosity of
the people here. And my question is I
keep thinking about a a beautiful place,
a retreat maybe where people can go for
a week or a month and study. Um maybe
there's people there that are mentors.
Um
>> yes
>> I guess my question is how can I be a
part of establishing such a place a
retreat study
>> you would have to find people with a
common interest
any monastery would be able to give you
at least some connections
okay
>> you know there's retreat houses of all
the denominations you know Roman
Catholic and Buddhist is
>> I was thinking about this group uh in
particular.
>> Yeah, it's a it's it's it's a thought
that is recurrent,
>> is it?
>> And it really needs somebody with
organizational skills plus some
financial capital to get it going,
>> right?
>> Mhm.
>> Okay.
May I uh shake your hand and take a
picture?
>> Yes, indeed.
again. Thank you.
>> Yes.
Uh,
I've been having some blocks from
receiving in my life.
>> Some what?
>> Blocks from receiving in my life. And
when I go inside, it seems there's some
beliefs of not uh being unworthy and not
deserving.
>> Yeah.
>> I don't know how to get past them.
Well, maybe it's right.
>> If you're unwilling to receive, then
you're not deserving, are you?
>> Sometimes it feels unconscious, like I'm
not even aware. It feels unconscious.
>> That's not possible.
>> Okay.
>> If it's unconscious, you wouldn't be
aware that that's operative.
When I go inside
>> unconscious means you would have no idea
what it is,
>> right?
>> So you consciously
wonder what is it you wonder about
yourself?
>> Whether she deserves certain
>> uh not deserving or unworthy.
>> You're too hard on yourself.
>> Well, it's misconceiving how events come
about.
Sometimes things uh occur because of
your own hard work, not because you're
deserving as a gift from God.
Okay.
Thank you. Can I hold your hand for a
minute?
>> Sometimes you get things because you
earned them. You earned them. Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> So God's gift is that he gives you the
opportunity to earn it.
The impetus to earn it.
That's enough.
Yes.
My question is about I feel like I have
a difficult time um allowing myself and
accepting myself to be loved and I feel
like that's a hindrance to knowing get
moving on to knowing the love of God.
>> All right. So when people are loving
towards you, what do you reject them or
what?
>> Um I don't believe them.
>> You don't believe them?
>> No. No. And I I kind of it's
>> well there's a lot of nonverbal things.
There's nothing to believe.
>> Okay. I don't understand what you just
said.
>> Okay.
>> What did you say?
>> There there was nonverbal things.
>> Yes. The way people are with you tells
you how you're regarded.
>> There's nothing to accept or reject.
And it also represents of course uh
their capacity for lovingness. You see?
Yes.
>> So if they're unloving towards you, it
doesn't mean that you are unlovable
and it takes a while to sort out.
Uh your your willingness to give love is
what uh determines your capacity to
receive it.
Yeah. Don't worry about being loved.
Just be loving towards all of life and
all of its expressions.
Every little toad, every tree,
everything
regard it with
dignity and wonder.
And that will bring me to know the love
of God.
>> God is all that exists.
>> Thank you.
So when you appreciate the beauty of a
tree, the beauty of a flower,
the magnificent of a bird,
then you see you witness God.
There's the famous story of the hunter
who shoot goes duck hunting and he
shoots down this duck. The duck comes
flying down like this, lands on the
ground, and then its mate comes down and
lays over the duck and covers its mate
with its wings.
50,000 hunters quit hunting after they
witnessed that.
Nothing was said,
but you get the essence of that which is
50,000 hunters gave up hunting.
My father was they tried to teach him
how to hunt
and he had a a dough right in his sights
and he looked through the the site and
he saw this the magnificence of this
beautiful deer and he couldn't pull the
trigger. He said I realized that was not
a hunter.
How could you kill something so
beautiful and stunning?
Unless you're hungry and you have to.
It's too much of a leftover macho game.
You know, it was macho back in the 1920s
during the depression to go out and get
a deer and bring it home proudly over
the fender.
Yeah. Doesn't mean that anymore.
I can go to any store and buy venison
for God's sake.
So the significance and the meaning
depends on the context, the cultural
context, the time and the setting. You
know,
in the 20s, uh, bringing home a deer was
a worthwhile endeavor.
Nowadays, you can just go to Walmart and
they got it right in the counter.
>> Yep. Better to pray to Walmart.
You know, I love Walmart.
>> Yep.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Yeah.
>> There we are.
>> Yes.
>> You want to help me with it?
>> What?
>> Anything you want to add?
>> No.
>> Okay. If I miss something, you call it
to my attention
because I got to deal with the lights
and the sounds and all this.
>> Yes.
Could you share with me the essence of
the teaching on transcending
um the duality of existence and
non-existence?
There's experiential and then there's
conceptual.
There's experiential
and then there's intellectual
and then there's experiential.
And the answer arises of itself by
contemplating
the problem.
And the answer is nonverbal.
There is neither existence nor
non-existence. Those are all concepts.
What is is
so the mind says well if it is then it
exists.
And the mind that said that the mind
said that what does the mind know about
it? It doesn't know anything about it.
It wouldn't even try to answer the
question if it understood it.
If the existence had no reality, there
would be nothing to ask the question.
So it answers itself by contemplation.
I faced that conundrum. I remember at
age three.
I was suddenly stunningly hit by the
fact that I exist.
The minute I realized that I exist, a
tremendous fear came up. If I exist, it
might have come about uh that I would
not have existed.
So then I thought which is reality
existence or non-existence.
All this was done with knowingness and
not a mental verbalization.
that I am came as a terrible shock
because I came out of non-existence
nonawareness of existence into awareness
of existence
and it was like suddenly the cleague
lights were turned on it was blinding
and shattering. Mhm.
So those are just moments in the
evolution of a certain consciousness as
>> Thank you. And I have these two crosses
that I bought. Um I wondered if you
would bless them for my children.
>> I have permission to bless these
crosses. Just I bless these crosses in
thy name, O Lord.
Yes.
I bless these crutches in thy name, oh
Lord. Okay, they're blessed.
So, we have only one hour to answer.
>> Oh, yes. Okay, we'll just move right
along.
We'll move along as fast as we can move
which is the snail space.
What do you want, honey?
>> Just go ahead.
>> Oh, go ahead. What What is on your mind?
>> A lot of anxiety.
>> Yes.
>> I'm willing I'm willing to surrender.
>> Huh? I'm willing to surrender. I'm
willing to surrender. I'm trying.
>> Anxiety is a fancy name for fear.
>> Is that right?
>> I don't know.
>> Huh?
>> What is he saying?
>> I don't know.
>> Anxiety is a label. Please tell me what
it is you experience. You don't
experience anxiety.
That's a con abstract concept. What is
it you experience?
>> Fear. Fear.
>> Fear. That's simple. Yeah. Okay. Fear.
So then you let go of resisting the
fear.
>> Okay.
>> And the fear comes up about what?
>> Suicide. Committing suicide because
>> Uhuh. Well, if you commit suicide, then
it's over. That cures your
>> Yeah, I know. I've tried to tell myself
that, but it doesn't count because
>> that cures the fear.
>> That I'm sorry.
>> If you're dead, you won't be afraid
anymore.
and then I'll be worse off. That's what
that's what this is.
>> There's psychiatrists.
>> There's psychiatrists. There's
tranquilizers.
All kinds of things. You can drink and
become a drunk and then join aa all
kinds of things.
>> But I I want to surrender. I want to
serve the Lord. I want to do the will of
God. I want to
>> Yeah, that's an abstract. Tell me how
I'm going to do the will of God. Tell me
how I should do the will of God right
now. Should I get up, take my clothes
off? I mean, what do you want me to do
to do the will of God right now? Dance
the jig?
People will get these uh spiritual
concepts and they turned into some kind
of verbalized magic.
You're looking for some kind of magic.
Spiritual evolution is a very human
experience. It's energized by divinity,
but it's a very, very human experience.
It's here and now. It's Suzie. It's this
audience. It's you, you know, it's not
an abstract thing out there someplace.
So, just live life where it is right
now.
Live life where it is,
not in some abstract questioning realm
which your mind conjures up.
Okay.
Everything is fine. Yes.
There's nothing wrong with you at all.
It's all in your head.
If you're nuttier than a fruit cake,
turn it over to God. Says, "God, I'm
nuttier than a fruitcake. Straighten me
out. Go see Doc Hawkins." for
>> people get lost in the abstract.
>> That's what it is. The nonlinear
abstract.
>> Yes.
>> I just want a blessing and uh to thank
you.
>> Mhm.
>> And that's it.
>> Thank you. Thank you very much.
>> And touch Doug's hand.
>> That's very neat. You bet.
>> Thanks, Doug.
>> Yeah.
See, he didn't die.
>> Never mind.
>> Oh, another guy.
>> Huh?
>> It was for the other guy.
>> Yeah. Okay.
Very good.
>> Thanks.
>> Is that you there, honey? I don't know
what that is there.
Oh
>> yes,
>> I've had moments of awakening and
revelation and I would love to ask for
your blessings and support on living in
a more constant state of remembrance of
my true nature.
>> That's a long question. What?
>> Say it one more time.
>> I'd like to ask for your blessings and
support
>> of what?
>> For me to live in a constant state of
remembrance of my true nature.
remembrance won't do you much good
then what will
>> being in that state don't remembering
the state
I don't want remember when I was full I
want to eat a sandwich and be full
remembrance of that sandwich isn't going
to help you
now that's spiritual lingo that's just
lingo
>> yes then could I ask for your blessings
for me to be in in a constant.
>> There you go. Be it live it.
That's fancy languaging. Yeah.
>> Yes. I'm nervous.
>> You see what an oddity it is to say
remember to remember who you are.
Just be what you are. Yep.
Don't even bother being a who.
You what?
>> Thank you.
>> Where did the Who live? I forget in that
Christmas story.
>> He lives in a cave.
>> No, no. The Who?
>> The Who's live in Whoville.
>> They live in Whoville. Yeah. Sorry.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
>> The Who's live in Whoville.
>> Hello. First, I'd like to say thank you.
Um, about two and a half years ago, I
erupted my condolini and over this past
year, I emailed Veraritoss two times in
an emergency and you answered that and
helped me and I'm very grateful for
that.
>> Oh, good.
>> And um I wrote a poem for you.
>> Oh,
>> and thank you. Shall I read it or would
you like to read it later or read it
later?
>> Read it later.
>> I don't want to know. It might scare the
people or something.
Condolini who they'll say
>> it's a thank you poem. It's a poem of
gratitude toward to you.
>> Oh, thank you sweetheart. We'll put it
on the wall. Thank you very much.
>> The whole poem
>> I have so many to answer today or
that's fine. Um my question is you had
mentioned numerous times that one should
be prepared in the event of um advanced
sudden jumps in in consciousness and the
I guess the repercussions of that. Um
and I guess in not functioning, not
being able to function. How does one
prepare for something like that? What
does
>> just to know about it?
>> There's no um places or people that you
>> when the time comes.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. Just to be aware that it could be.
>> And if it happens, it's unmistakable. So
you won't have any problem realizing it.
>> Okay.
>> All right. Thank you.
>> Comes unexpected anyway. Okay.
Okay. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Reading about is one thing, experiencing
is something completely totally
different.
>> Hello.
My question. Um, as an analogy, we tune
up our cars. we, you know, we get them
realigned. I'm looking for a guidance to
be sure I'm my spiritual
track is my car is in alignment. That um
the best way to notice when I'm a little
bit off, stay out of the lion's den. You
know this.
Am I making sense? Well, you want to
know where you are on the spiritual
pathway. The various levels of
consciousness are there. No,
>> I want to avoid I want to avoid the
pitfalls that I' I've heard about, but I
want to I'm looking for a best way to to
um selfch check.
>> There are 10,000 ways to God. You want
to know which is the best one?
>> No.
>> The one that you're on is the best one.
>> Yeah. The path is Yeah, it's set. But I
just feel out of I don't want to go way
off track. That's That's what I'm
looking for.
>> You're not going to go way off track.
Your intention is to evolve spiritually.
>> Okay, that's sounds good to me.
>> Only a person who's spiritual would be
worried that they're going off the track
spiritually.
>> That being so serious.
Thank you.
>> You're doing fine.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Hi.
>> Hi, Susan.
>> Thank you for the biggest laughs I've
had in my entire life, Dr. Hawkins, and
for being my dear teacher. Thank you,
Doc.
Thank you, Susan.
>> Oh, thank you.
>> You bet.
>> What is that?
>> That's the Buddha water. Can you sign
that?
>> Oh, I can't sign Buddha water deepers.
The Buddha doesn't want me signing
Buddha water.
>> Okay. No Buddha water signing.
behind the table.
>> Okay.
>> Good evening or whatever time it is. Dr.
Hawkins, it's an honor to be in your
presence. My question is uh I'm an actor
in this lifetime and um my question is I
was wondering if you know of any actors
whose work calibrates above 540 that I
could study and emulate and
>> No, I haven't calibrated actors in
general.
>> Okay. Could I ask another question?
>> Yeah.
>> Uh I don't remember my backup. Um
>> my back
only asked what
>> I know. So uh yeah. Okay. Thank you. Oh.
Oh, yes. That's the other thing. Um I um
I got into uh your work my senior year
of college and everybody in my class
kind of thought I'd gone off the deep
end, of course. Um but um the last thing
I did is I created this oneman show. It
was based on your life's work. I kind of
got to silence my my naysayers and I'd
love to give it to you. It's about 18
minutes long.
>> Oh, thank you.
>> It's based on your work.
>> Is your name on here?
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you very much. So, you're in the
theatrical business?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Okay.
>> Let's see you dance.
That's going to be good on YouTube
tomorrow.
>> I love to dance.
>> He does.
I should have been a dancer in this
lifetime, but I couldn't afford it.
Couldn't afford the frivolity of being a
dancer.
Had more serious things to do.
I can't follow that.
I just wanted to uh gently shake your
hand, look you in the eye, and say thank
you.
>> Thank you for thanking me.
>> Thank you.
>> Thanks for putting us at the beginning.
Oh, thank you.
>> Okay, come on. Let's move it fast.
>> Let's move it, buddy.
>> We have a lot of people who want to ask
questions. And
>> thank you very much, David.
>> Yeah,
>> appreciate it.
>> Yes.
>> Um, my question is what exactly is the
mind and how is it related to the human
brain?
>> Well, the mind is a I mean, the brain is
obviously a series of neurons. One side
of the brain is spiritually oriented.
The other one is ego oriented.
The energy field of knowingness and mind
is a a nonlinear energy field. And this
energy field is what activates the
neurons. The mind is actually
non-physical.
It's an energy field.
This energy field then energizes the
dendrites in the brain where it goes
from the atheric body to the physical
body.
And the mechanics of that are very
similar to Maxwell's
uh
to Maxwellian
physics of magnetism creates electricity
in a wire or vice versa.
Uh electricity
in a wire creates magnetism.
So electricity and magnetism are fields
that can be switched back and forth. So
the atheric body, this is what all the
students of consciousness, the
professors and all can't figure out is
how does the atheric body which is
non-physical
activate the physical body which is
physical.
And if they use Maxwell's theorem, they
have the obvious answer. The energy is
in the atheric body and the atheric body
activates the neuronal physical body
just like so the brain is the wires and
this is the electrical field that
activates the neurons. So the answer is
very simple although they fool around
with it decade after decade you know.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Now did you understand that
>> kind of
I'll figure it out later probably. Thank
you very much, Susan. Thank you, doctor.
>> You understand the relationship between
magnetism and electricity?
>> Oh, yes.
>> Okay, that's all it is.
>> It's going to take a while to get that.
>> So, the energy activates the neurons.
>> Yeah. Okay. Simple.
>> Great.
>> Mhm.
>> And if you're brainless, don't have a
brain, then the energy field doesn't get
transmitted to the human domain. Yes.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah. I'm asking this question on behalf
of a number of people who are using
methadone maintenance as a part of their
recovery
>> that are using what?
>> Methadone maintenance maintenance.
>> Oh yes yes yes.
>> And the question is can being on
methadone maintenance of itself
limit or somehow negatively affect one's
level of consciousness and if so in what
way?
>> Uh it would be it would be holding you
back. The methadone serves for a period,
but it's only a crutch. So, you can't
live forever on methadone. And sooner or
later, you have to face the withdrawal.
And you have to face the uh living it
through. You follow the 12step program
and you follow it through. So, you know,
great numbers of people have gone from
very addicting drugs to less addicting
drugs to dependency on a 12step program
and eventually drug-free. Yeah.
>> So, it may hold them back on the level
of consciousness until
>> well the the dependency on methadone
itself has to be overcome sooner or
later
and it's the fear of a relapse. You feel
you get dependent on the methadone. But
what you do is progressively very small
increments reduce the methadone.
>> Thank you for everything.
>> Yeah.
>> Hi.
>> Mhm.
>> I just want to thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Yes, indeed.
>> I brought you a puppy.
>> Oh boy.
>> And it's a special puppy. He's got a
third eye here.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Then he also has a voice.
>> And you've got the tail. And this is the
tail wagging the dog.
>> Oh, that is funny. Oh my god. My
>> toys.
>> Kelsey will go crazy over that. Yeah,
>> Kelsey will go crazy over that. That is
adorable.
>> Kelsey is going to study that thing for
days before she touches it.
My dog's just going to look at it and
good god can't imagine what that is.
>> Our bird's going to start laughing like
it.
>> Yeah. And our uh
>> our parrot will study its noises. And
that's adorable.
>> He's got a third eye. A
>> he's cute.
>> Very cute.
>> He's going to a good home.
>> Give me that dog. That's my dog.
>> Adorable.
>> Yeah, that's cute.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins and Susan. and thank you
for your work because uh the Albuquerque
Hawkins group would have nothing to talk
about
>> if we didn't have your teachings.
>> Yeah,
>> we're very I'm I'm here with a with a
question from my minister whose wife is
in hospice right now.
>> His wife is in hospice.
>> Hospice. She's been in hospice for a
while.
>> Yes.
>> So you may get the framing of this
question.
Um, can one person somehow take on
another person's karma as a favor to the
devote?
>> Not really.
>> Hypothetically, there's ways that it is
said to happen. I myself am dubious.
>> Thank you. Can we take a picture with
you?
>> Yes. Mhm.
>> Albuquerque.
You cannot really take on another
person's karma or
>> Yeah. You cannot really take it on
>> part in it, but you couldn't take it on.
>> You can't really take it on.
>> But you could take part
>> because you owe the money. Yeah.
>> Yeah. But you could take part in their
karma. Like if they needed help.
>> Oh yeah. Be part and parcel of the
solution. Yeah.
>> Thank you. Thank you very much.
>> Oh, thank you.
Is this Did someone leave your book?
Someone left the book.
Who dropped the book? Oh, the guy with
the dog.
>> The guy with the dog who lifted you.
>> Yes.
>> Um, firstly, I would like to thank you
for telling me the truth, the whole
truth, and nothing but the truth.
it.
I've been looking for that all my life.
>> Uhhuh.
Good for you.
And I I would like to could you say more
about
our guardian angels?
The guardian angels are
uh you can communicate with them.
They themselves are on this pathway of
spiritual evolution.
And their task is to be available as
counsel.
That's correct. I guess.
And then someday you'll have a chance to
become a guardian angel or advisory
angel. They have different ranks.
Are they linked with us karmically as
individuals?
>> Oh, I don't know. I don't know.
>> Thank you.
>> But they're very available.
Guardian angels are very available.
And I think when you ask for a a
miracle, you know, they become
activated.
You know, I know now you're really
seeing it as they see it from a higher
level.
Mhm.
>> Thank you.
>> I remember when Guardian Angels lifted
my the etheric body out of my physical
body when I went through surgery without
anesthesia.
Yeah.
I was like lifted out of the body into a
beatotific space. The place space was
sootific
and I had to go back to an ordinary
state of consciousness.
>> Yeah.
>> Hello.
Uh over the past few months, I've
started having spiritual experiences
where my mind was just clear and I
didn't feel the need to to make opinions
or to think about anything.
>> Yeah.
>> And so I was trying to think of a
question to ask you and the only thing
that I could come that could bring to my
mind was just that I love you and I love
everyone and I love the Lord so much.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Thank you.
So you transcended discursive mind
that you transcended the discursive mind
and when became only the witness mind
>> and I was wondering whether I could
receive your blessing.
The idea is yes. Yes indeed you do have
my blessing and I wish you well on your
way.
>> Thank you.
>> Uhhuh.
Hello.
>> Do you want me to sign this?
>> Yes, please. I came from Korea and I'm
translating Jesus word and lecture into
Korean and I'm translating occurs
miracles walk book into Korean and also
I'm translating this book can you
calibrate this book
>> divine healing
>> divine healing of mind and body
mind and
>> McDonald
pain.
>> Let me see. Let me see. Let me see.
Oh, I see. Divine healing of mind and
body.
>> Yes.
>> What does that say there?
>> That's the author.
>> What is the author's name?
>> It's Mand Mundone. MC McDonald Bane.
>> Bane.
>> Bane. B A Y N E
>> Fang.
>> Yes.
We have permission to calibrate this
book. It's over 550.
580.
555.
It's over 550. It's about 550.
>> 55 550.
>> 550.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you.
and hand please.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you. Thank you so much.
>> Okay.
So, it's written lovingly 550 is
love is 500 and up.
>> Thank you.
Hey Doc.
>> Hey Susan.
>> Um,
>> thanks a lot for everything. Your work
has transformed my whole life.
>> Good.
>> And um,
>> for the better, I hope.
>> Much for the better. Yeah. Big time.
>> Thank you.
>> Um, I love you so much. And I love you
too, Susan. And you have your work has
taught me the the real meaning of
unconditional love
>> and that is what I live by now.
>> Good. Good.
>> You love the trees. You love the
flowers. You love the grass.
>> I I go to school for botany and I
definitely love the
>> You love all the people in the street.
>> You love the bums on the sidewalk.
>> Oh yeah. Oh yeah. I sit down and talk
with them whenever I can.
>> Very good.
>> Um could I just shake your hand?
>> Yes. And um I wanted to ask if maybe I
could hold something in mind and uh you
could tell me whether it's true or not.
I'll just hold it in mind. I don't have
to
say it unless you want me to.
>> I don't get his question.
>> He wants to hold some in mind. I don't
>> Okay.
>> Uh his question is answerable. Resist.
Okay. What he's holding in mind, I have
permission to ask if it's true or false.
Resist.
What he's holding in mind is true.
What he's holding in mind is false.
Resist.
>> Score.
I love you. I really do.
>> You got dancer. That's why.
Well, to be honest, I I really believe
that I see the the effects of angels all
all throughout nature and in the clouds.
And
>> yeah,
>> I really see the artwork that they leave
afterwards.
>> That's right. Everything is God's
artwork.
>> The clouds in the sky, the grass, the
trees.
>> Yep.
>> Even ugly people like Socrates.
Uh, I have to go back and meet with
Socrates again when I leave here.
>> God bless you.
>> And then he's going to say, "I hear you
calling me short and ugly.
Actually,
>> I can hardly understand English at all."
But I am here to see you.
Please bless me and my problems.
>> Do you know what he said?
>> Um,
let me see. I think I'm a picky,
sensitive person and I have a lot of
fear about many things. How can I
translate transcend these tendencies?
>> Fear. He wants to let go of fear.
You can only do it by trusting God and
asking God for guidance. And then you
have to take a leap of faith. You have
to make the leap of faith.
Yeah. Mhm. Then you have to you still
have to make a leap of faith. People
think that well if God's helping them
they won't feel any anxiety or
uncertainty. No. With God's help, you'll
do it. Even though you have anxiety and
uncertainty and fear,
it's stronger than the fear. Yes.
Actually,
I have no question. I just want to look
into your eyes and hold your hands.
>> Okay. You want me to sign this?
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
In that case, we'll sign it.
Yes, ma'am. Hello.
Where are you from?
Huh?
>> Korea.
>> Oh, Korea. Oh, yes. Oh, yes. Yes. It's a
wonderful place. Korea.
>> Yeah. I love Korea.
People that are very special.
Very special. I don't know why,
but they are. Uhhuh.
Mhm.
Yes,
>> thank you for your teaching.
>> In my spiritual work over the years,
when I've asked questions, I've always
had some nonverbal
knowing
that's come from the question, that's
given me the insight. And over the
years, it's been more accompanied with a
loving energy. And I've used that for my
discernment in my path.
And when I started working with your
teaching and was exposed to kinesiology,
I've come across a resistance to it that
I've worked worked on for for several
years now. But I still notice that
there's a resistance.
>> Resistance to what?
>> To doing kinesiology rather than just
asking question.
>> Well, then don't do it. Yeah.
>> Okay. It doesn't matter. It just seemed
like to me that part of what my
knowingness showed was that in some
cases it would be useful and yet I still
have some resistance.
>> Yeah,
>> don't worry about it.
>> It just works for us and other people.
But if this is going to work for you,
it's fine.
>> It works on it own.
>> I have a blessing
>> in indeed. I have permission to give him
my blessing or resist. Okay. Yes, you
have my blessing and God bless your
sincerity.
Mhm.
>> Hello.
>> I lack boundaries.
>> Okay.
>> What?
>> She likes boundaries.
>> No, no, no. I don't like them.
>> Oh, you don't like them?
>> I lack them.
>> Oh, you lack boundaries.
>> She lacks boundaries. Lacks.
>> I don't know what she means.
>> I don't either. Um, let's see.
In the process of being me, I have no
boundaries
and it gets me into trouble in my
personal life and in my professional
life. Do you have any advice?
Well, you the boundaries have to do with
uh the the child and you refusing to
accept adult rules.
You just want to, you know, indulge in
being the
irresponsible child
who has everything its own way
and refusing to become an adult. That's
all.
If you say within yourself there's the
child and the adult and the parent. Yes.
>> Sometimes what happens is the child
wants to defy the parent and then they
miss being an adult.
>> Even though I work very hard and I give.
>> Work very hard and what?
>> Even though she works very hard and
she's very giving. Would that would she
still fall into those lines? Yes.
>> Yeah. Oh, that's not the question. The
question is you you don't recognize
boundaries. Is that correct?
>> Yes.
>> You jump in bed with everybody.
>> Not those boundaries.
>> Oh, you steal things in the store.
>> No, I just I I give. If someone asks me
something, I always say yes. And then I
feel resentful because I give and give
and give and then there's nothing left
for me. So
>> yeah, that's a different problem. Yes.
So in other words, you don't respect
uh sensible balance,
>> right?
>> And what is socially appropriate,
>> All right. So if I say to you, I want
you to go walk on all fours, your elbows
and knees to the edge of the stage, you
would do it.
>> No, actually.
>> No. So you have limitations.
>> I suppose I guess I do.
>> You do have limitations. You see?
>> Yeah.
>> A person with no limitations is really
quite, you know, it's called a
psychotic.
>> Well, thank goodness I'm not that.
>> No, you know, you can't fly off the
stage. You know, you go like this and
run, you won't take off. Right.
>> Right.
>> No. So, you know, you have the you have
respect for limitations and uh you know,
you'd have to be more clear about in
what area of life you're talking about,
>> right?
>> If you mean buying things, you spend too
much money. You mean indulging yourself
too much? I mean, what is it you're
talking about?
You're too vague. In general,
>> I think people talk into things that
they want done for them.
>> Yes.
>> And uh
>> Yeah. Yeah, that's what it is. She
agrees to do things that are going to
benefit other people.
>> Doing favors. Yeah.
>> She's not pulling.
>> Oh yeah. Why did I do that? Yeah.
>> Right. Exactly.
>> So, uh, in a way it's sort of being
ingratiating in a way.
>> Ingratiating.
>> Mhm. Kind of curry favor by being
obsequious.
>> Uhhuh.
People
don't necessarily respect you because
you're so compliant and obsequious.
>> Exactly.
>> They secretly think you're sort of an
idiot.
>> So, what's the solution?
>> Don't give everybody your last Kleenex.
>> Okay.
>> You have to say learn to say no,
>> right?
>> Yeah. You have to watch out for
yourself. So the adult and you have to
take charge a little bit of the child.
>> Just say uh I'm sorry but that just is
not going to work for my schedule.
>> Yeah. Can't do that at that time. I have
other commitments that I
>> You can't let the child rule. Mhm.
>> Thank you.
>> And it's great. You have to go into
detail.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> For your cure, you could wash the car on
the way out.
Thank you, Dr. Hawkins and Susan. I uh I
wrote a book called Food and
Forgiveness, and I wanted to gift it to
you, too. My friend Stephen helped me
write it, and our friend Lou Marzel
edited it.
>> So, that's a gift.
>> All right. Thank you.
>> And I signed it.
>> Oh, thank you very much.
Thank you.
>> Yeah,
>> thank you.
>> Thanks. And I my my work is to get more
local organic and sustainable food to
>> get what
>> local organic sustainable food uh into
schools and into businesses in general.
>> What does sustainable mean?
>> That means that we're not using
chemicals with the animals and we're not
confining the animals. Uh and that means
we're not pouring pesticides on the
vegetables and the fruit like that. You
mean organ? Pure organic. Organic. Yeah.
Okay.
>> Sustainable means that uh future
generations the planet will still be uh
healthy or healthy.
>> Oh, you're worried about the planet. I
thought you were worrying about the
kids.
>> I am worried about the kids.
>> Well, you got your choice. Kids or
planet?
>> Uh the kids.
>> Oh, okay.
>> Yeah. And I'm wondering if you have
permission to bless that work.
bless
>> the work that I do.
>> Pure organic foods for children. That
doesn't need being blessed.
>> Well, right now they're not eating it.
So, I'm trying to
So, I'm trying to get them.
>> Yeah. Maybe you're carried away with
doooderism.
>> I hope I'm not.
>> There was an article in the uh Arizona
Republic about um organically growing
pork. There's a down in I think
somewhere in Phoenix that's doing it and
um you know what they were saying the
restaurants are just craving for there's
a whole network out there that is
organically grown food and these um
different farmers are bringing it to the
restaurants
>> I don't know if you know anything about
that
>> uh not about that no maybe I'll simplify
it and can I have a blessing
>> we have permission to bless this young
Man,
>> you look pure and organic to me.
>> God bless you and Amen.
>> God bless.
>> God bless you. Thanks.
>> Wasn't for chemicals, we'd all be dead.
>> Hi, Dr.
I get his intention. His intention is
>> I've been trying to meet you, Dr.
Hawkins, since 2003 and I finally made
it.
>> Yes.
>> You came from the moon or where?
>> Oh, yeah. I did. That's Yeah, I'm a
loony.
I It seems to me that any question I ask
you once asked and answered by you will
only lead to another question. So my
only question to you is may I hold your
hand for about five seconds?
>> Indeed.
Fear.
>> Amen.
>> Thank you both. Pleasure.
>> Hello.
>> This is my first time here and I just
want to thank you very much for your
love, teaching and inspiration.
>> Thank you. Thank you for thanking me.
>> Yes, indeed.
>> Hi, Susan. Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Hello.
>> Actually, I'm coming from Germany and I
just would like to thank you very much
and ask for your blessings.
>> What did he say?
>> Germany.
>> After I
>> Yes.
>> Oh, yeah. Okay.
>> Can I just get your own blessings on
your hand?
>> Okay. We have permission to give him our
blessing. Yeah. Uhhuh. You got to give
thanks for this gentleman's approach and
his request for thy blessing, oh Lord.
Amen.
>> Thank you very much.
>> I took 12 years of German.
>> 12 yard.
>> Yeah, I love German.
>> He actually speak it pretty well.
>> I was speaking it last week. Yeah.
Actually,
we have quite a following,
>> you know, Sama. What's her name? Sama.
She's translating all of our books into
German.
>> When I grew up, the guys took German and
the girls took French.
>> Maybe
>> real guys didn't take French.
I don't have any questions for you. I
just wanted to um
>> thank you for the many many gifts I've
received through you and
>> very very appreciative. So, thank you so
much.
>> I'm glad and thank you. Yes.
>> I wanted to know if it'd be possible to
receive a blessing.
>> We have permission to bless this young
man. We just I bless you in the name of
the Lord. Amen.
Yeah. Mhm.
>> Hi.
>> I don't have a question. I just want to
say God bless you. You have changed my
life. You have. It's just incredible.
Can I hold your hand?
>> Thank you so much for thanking me. Yes.
>> Thank you for your blessing.
Yes.
>> Hello.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you. The question I have is for
several people. Is there no depth of
separation from God that one cannot
surrender from?
Is there no depth uh from God that one
cannot surrender?
>> I don't understand the question.
>> Well,
it's like how low do you go before
>> can you can you can you completely be
separated from God say in levels of hell
or separateness and not
>> it's possible to come out very deep
levels of hell.
>> Yes. And uh by appropriate uh prayer and
inner spiritual work,
it's possible to come up from pretty low
regions of hell
out of God's forgiveness.
You pray for forgiveness for your
ignorance and willfulness.
>> Yes.
Shake it.
>> Yep.
>> Thank you.
Hello Dr.
>> with the exception of blasphemy.
I have permission to ask this
for blasphemy there is no forgiveness
resist. Oh that's scary.
Lord David, I would like to ask you a
question about NLP and how conducive is
NLP or neural linguistic programming in
someone's spiritual uh
>> I have forgotten what I used to know
about NLP.
I really can't answer anymore. I don't
remember it anymore. It's too many years
ago, decades ago. I'm saying that
because at this point in time I feel
that nothing in this world of form ever
satisfy me anymore.
>> Yes.
>> Everything is just fleeting and it's
like I'm playing a game of
meaningless. I mean
>> there is nothing there besides your work
and spirituality and meditation.
>> Yes. And I'm trying to the experiencer
as you put it tries to juice life a
little bit more. So that's why tries to
juice life.
>> He's trying to
>> to juice life to have more u love and um
compassion and passion and all these
great qualities.
>> Oh yes. Yes. Okay. Mhm. Do you listen to
beautiful music?
>> Yes, I do. Yes. That's very
>> every day.
>> Yeah. Good.
>> Then you're you're safely on your way
because that's the field that you move
into the field of infinite beauty.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you very much. I appreciate it.
>> Thank you, Susan.
>> Mhm.
V or is this
>> Huh?
>> This one.
>> Hello.
>> Hi.
>> Yes.
>> When the Buddha taught the mystic law of
the Lotus Sutra, what was he referring
to?
>> When the Buddha taught what?
>> The mystic law of the Lotus Sutra.
I'd have to recall the lotus sutra.
>> Those are the chants.
>> What?
>> Those are the chants. You know,
>> I I can't recall let you right now.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> I've read so many spiritual works by so
many spiritual masters that
>> I'm getting too old to remember who
wrote what.
>> Thank you very much for both of your
work. Thank you.
I calibrated the Lotus Sutra. Let's see.
The Lotus Sutra calibrates over 700 750
around remember it was around 720 7 over
700.
Mhm.
Yes.
Yes,
>> I have no questions. Uh
>> I I just want to hold your hands
with the look into your eyes.
>> Oh yes. Thank you.
>> God bless you.
>> Beautiful child of God.
Maybe
it says I want to find my true vocation.
I'm a Korean trans and dental med
medicine doctor. I am I am
satisfied with my job at the current in
a certain degree but I always that
something is missing. Uh, do I have a
talent to be a doctor? Um, I think I
might be
>> She's not asking a lot of questions.
Let's take them apart one at a time.
What's the first question?
>> Um, her true vocation is um is a
transcendental medicine doctor. I don't
know what trans.
>> Oh, that's TM. Okay. Okay. Right now
being a TM uh teacher is is sufficient
adequate.
Being a teacher a TM teacher right now
is very very good. Yes. Mhm.
>> But she also feels something is missing.
>> Oh yeah. Well, she wants to go higher.
Okay. She wants to go higher than just
TM. Yeah. TM is limited.
>> Okay.
>> Mhm.
>> And so she says, "Do I have the talent
to become a doctor?"
>> Medical doctor. Yeah.
Uh we have permission to ask this. She
has the adequate intellectual apparatus
or the the overall talents to become a
medical doctor. Is this?
>> Yes.
>> So we got we we got that um to become a
medical doctor would be good.
>> All right. Um but you are good as the
transcendental med medical doctor too.
TM TM
>> because you want to go higher,
>> go be more successful and go higher. So,
we got yes on both answers.
>> That's good.
Look happy. Please look happy.
>> I don't know. Is there someone that can
speak Korean so that she can Is there
anyone here that translates that knows
English?
The answer is yes and yes.
>> Yes and yes.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> Uhhuh.
>> These are all of our books in Korean.
>> Yes.
>> I have no question. I just want to hold
your hand.
>> Yes.
There you go.
>> God bless. God bless. God bless.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you.
And
um I think we're going to start the uh
shaking hands now and you're going to
have to sign some books online because
we didn't get them all signed.
>> All right. So do I what do you want me
to do?
Um, do you want to say something to end
the lecture?
>> Well, we didn't end the lecture. We're
just shaking hands.
>> All right, we'll do it at the very end.
>> Okay, we're going to we're going to
shake everyone's hand that we can. We
try to do that at every lecture because
there's so many at this lecture today.
It may take us a little longer. Um,
please go to the back of the theater and
come around so that we do don't have a
clog up here in the front. So, if you
could go to the back of the theater and
then come around the front. You You
cannot line up here. You'll have to go
to the back of the theater so that we
have a a pathway so people can come back
around. So, if you'll go to the back of
the theater, please go to the back of
the theater.
Yeah. And then we'll we'll bless
everybody. Hi, sweetheart.
How are you?
That's the end of the lecture and I'm
not taking it anymore.
>> Yeah. So, because people are going to
walk by here. So, if you could go to the
back so that we have a line here so they
can walk around.
>> Okay. Good.
>> God bless you.
>> Do you want to hang on to the mic or do
you want me to take it?
>> I mean, do you think you're done?
>> Smile.
>> Well, we're gonna have it here. You
broke the camera now.
>> Hi, I'm Andrew. I'm Scott Jeffy's
research partner.
>> I'm Scott.
>> Oh, Scott. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And what's
your name?
>> Andrew Collier.
>> Oh, yes. Yes. Yes. I know who you are.
Yeah. Yeah.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, wait. Can we Sorry.
>> Oh, you betcha. You betcha.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you, sir.
>> God bless you. God bless you for your
work. Hello dog. Thank you back from
Australia.
>> Oh, thank you.
>> Very much
pleasure. Thank you.
>> Thank you all.
>> The divine within me honors the divine
within you.
>> Thank you.
>> Yes, indeed.
>> Hold it down. Hold it down.
There you go.
>> Thank you.
>> No, it isn't as easy as it looks. You're
doing this fine.
>> Okay. Yes, indeed. God bless you.
>> God bless you. God bless you.
Hey, God bless you. God bless you.
Double bless you.
>> Uhhuh. God bless, sweetheart.
>> Ah, God bless you. Yes, indeed. I Well,
I know all these people, you know.
>> Ah, hello. Hello.
Hi. Hi.
Hello. Yes, indeed.
>> Hello.
>> Bless you.
>> Yeah. God bless you.
>> God bless you. Yes, indeed.
>> Hi, buddy.
Hi.
God bless you.
>> God bless you.
>> It's kind of like convocation.
You see, I've become a bobblehead.
God bless you. See, you watch how he
goes. See how the bobblehead shakes
hands.
>> Another beautiful lecture.
Bye.
>> God bless you. Thank you.
>> Bye.
>> Bless you. We'll see you again soon.
>> God bless you.
>> God bless.
>> God bless you, sweetheart. Yes.
>> God bless you.
>> Hi. Hi.
>> It's great to see you.
>> Yeah. Great to see you.
>> If you want a photo, go ahead. Turn.
>> Can I get a photo with you, Don?
>> Yes.
>> I don't know.
>> Please.
>> The air is free.
>> You just had one.
>> That was it.
afterwards.
>> Yeah. Hello. Hello.
>> Hello indeed.
>> Delivered.
>> Hello, sweethearts. Look at there. Cute
little kid.
>> You like a blessing for a daughter, Doc.
Bless.
God bless you, sweetheart.
>> Hi. Hi.
Ho ho ho ho ho ho. Yes indeed.
>> Oh, hello sweetheart. Hello, sweetheart.
Hello, sweetheart.
>> God bless you.
>> He won't mind.
>> Oh, God bless you. God bless you.
>> Doc, you're going to get fiddled with as
far as your microphone.
>> Oh, okay.
>> People are fiddling with my phone.
>> Phone fiddler.
>> Keep Let's move the line there along.
drag your feet
>> this way to the omnibus
Australia.
>> Let's wait to the eress.
>> Good to see you.
PT bar
this way to the egress.
>> Yes.
>> Oh, I just got the
>> way to the egress.
Hello.
>> Thank you.
>> Thanks for being a proponent.
>> God bless you.
>> Thank you again.
>> This way to the egress.
>> Thank you. And we'll take a picture.
Nobody's going to think he's 6'4.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you for all your work.
>> Yeah.
>> Some people think
jewelry. I think
>> God bless you.
Yeah.
>> Oh, look at all the people running
through here. Willy
>> God bless you,
>> sweetheart.
President of the Elders Club.
>> Okay.
>> Hi.
>> One more. One more.
>> There we go.
>> Hey.
Yes.
>> Hello.
>> Hey, doc. This is
my dog.
>> Yeah. I was wondering if you could bless
my family. This is my wife and this is
my dog. Can you bless my family?
>> Yeah. God bless you.
>> Okay. God bless.
>> Thank you, Dr. Hawkins. I enjoyed your
lecture very much, sir. That's great.
>> God bless you.
>> Yep.
>> They made this for you. It's an octopus.
>> What is that?
>> A little octopus.
>> Oh, an octopus.
>> Yeah. Thank you.
>> Little octopus. That's great.
>> Thank you.
Thank you from Philadelphia. Love you.
>> Really
bless you for everything you do for us.
Thank you.
Thank you so much for everything.
>> Thank you.
>> God bless you.
There you go.
>> Thank you, Andrea. You changed my life.
>> I'd like to take it home, but can I take
a picture of you?
>> You can take a picture.
>> Okay. One, two, three.
>> Home.
>> Thank you so much. Thank you.
>> Hi, Doc.
>> Hi, bro. Good to see you again. Good to
see you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thanks. Take care, Doc.
Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thank you. I'm all healthy
and normal again. Hey Doc, I love you.
God bless you.
>> Terra, you're in our prayers every
night.
>> Neighbors. I'm buying Jack's house. Jack
in the book.
>> Hello. You take his picture, please.
>> Now what?
Thank you. Thank you. There we go.
broken up. Yeah.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu