I didn't know where we were until I realized we were here.
Hi. We have 10 people that are from Korea that are in the audience.
If you could please stand up. Stand up for us.
They came all the way from Korea to be with us today.
Who are the 10 people? What?
We have 10 people from Korea that are here today.
Oh! Oh!
Yeah.
Yes. We appreciate you traveling such a long way.
We also have a lot of people here from Canada.
Who are the Canadians?
Okay. Stand up.
I wanted to acknowledge them because they have come from such a long way.
And we have a terrific following in Korea.
And these people, you know, we really appreciate it.
They were one of the first people that David and I did a seminar for, was in Korea.
And we went all the way over there.
That was, I think it was 1999.
In 1999, we started it.
Now Dr. Moon has an ashram there who is continuing with our teachings.
And she is translating all the work into Korean for those people.
So I just wanted to acknowledge you and thank you so much for coming.
Anybody here from Dubai today?
Dubai. Anybody here from Dubai?
Ask.
Do we have our Dubai people here today?
Dubai-ers?
I think she's coming till October, honey.
We have a couple of people that come over from Dubai also.
And I think they said they were coming to the October lecture.
Or India. Or India.
How about our Indian people?
Is anyone here from India?
Yes. Come on. Stand up.
Australia. Australia, India.
Australia.
So I just wanted to acknowledge everybody.
I could have everyone standing.
Oh, there's going to be no recording of the lecture.
I don't know if any of you are doing that.
But we cannot have you record the lecture.
It's all copyrighted.
And so if any of you are recording it, we'd ask you to please refrain from that.
Thank you.
Okay. We'll resume.
We have exactly one hour?
Okay.
We got up to number 14.
We better move along.
And I think we're going to have to go back to the lecture.
We're going to have to go back to the lecture.
So let's go back to the lecture.
And I think you're going to have to go back to the lecture.
I think you're going to have to go back to the lecture.
Okay.
All right.
So the question is, how do you evaluate wisdom over being right?
It's not necessary to be right unless you're a – you feel that you have to fight for your image.
You know, the image is that you have to be right.
It's of greater value to be understanding.
One thing that people ignore in our current society,
and I think that's something that we all need to be aware of,
is that you don't have to solve everything all by yourself without discussing it with anybody.
Everybody should have somebody, a mentor, that they look up to, that they respect,
can be just a very good friend.
But instead of keeping everything to yourself and sweating it out,
you can talk to people that you respect because you get feedback.
There's a reason for it other than just the practicality.
The practicality is you don't get so egotistic about whatever your conclusion is.
I mean, you didn't conclude to do that all by yourself.
You discussed it with a friend, and the two of you decided that.
Well, if the two of you decided that, then you don't say,
well, I'm the one that picked the winning ticket.
You know what I mean?
I picked the winning ticket.
If you discuss the winning ticket to buy with somebody else,
it's a shared, joint decision,
and that, you know, protects you from egotistical inflation.
So we're looking for ways to transcend the ego and allow the spirit to take over,
and this is one of the ways.
In all my years in psychiatry and psychoanalysis,
it was another rule to always have a colleague to discuss things with,
even though I'd had 50 years' experience as a psychiatrist.
One time I had, for many years, the largest practice in the entire United States.
I still had somebody that I saw periodically to discuss things with.
So you get feedback from other people, and they have other ways of looking at it.
And so sometimes my counsel would say,
well, that sounds good, but you could look at it this way.
Well, I hadn't thought of that.
So it's good to have a confessor,
confessor, a counselor, a therapist.
Everybody should have a psychotherapist, everybody.
I don't know anybody that doesn't need a psychotherapist.
People who think they don't need a therapist are the most gone of all.
No, I can do it on my own.
Okay, good luck.
Have a good spouse.
Have somebody that you can confide in,
share in reaching decisions,
and it serves your highest good.
To always have somebody to share with serves your highest good.
That's true.
I got you, babe.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Of course, it was wise counsel that led to me sharing things with you.
Me.
I'm so smart.
I don't know.
Talk with Susie and then make up your mind.
Yeah.
Okay.
Realize that you influence others by what you are,
not just by what you do.
We subtly or constantly influencing actually all of mankind by what we are.
So what you are is more important than what you do
because what you are radiates out an energy that influences everyone.
What you are, what you have become is more powerful.
People can say, what can I do to help mankind?
And I tell them, become the most loving, evolved person that you can.
Love all of life and all of its expressions.
Be respectful of nature and beauty.
Esteem beauty and nature.
Realize that you influence others by what you are,
not what you do.
So this group here right now is influencing mankind.
This group is influencing mankind.
We're not doing anything.
We don't have any flags to wave.
We don't have any slogans.
We're not shouting into the TV reporter's microphone.
This group right here is influencing all of mankind right now.
Resist.
There you see.
You radiate out an energy into the field of consciousness
which influences everyone.
So that the best thing you can do for the world
is to sit down and shut up.
The kind thoughts that you have towards others,
the kindly thoughts, the kindly intention that you have towards others,
tends to influence all of mankind,
the whole field of consciousness of mankind.
Realize that you are influencing others right now.
Not by what you say, but what you are.
And that's why I am not an enthusiast of activism.
Activism, everybody, you know, they get on TV
and they have a thing around their thing.
They're a blogger activist.
I salute all blogger activists.
That's my blogger activist salute.
I salute you.
They actually get on TV.
And they're being interviewed by the chair of the thing.
And that's what they're, underneath it says blogger activist.
You ask them, what have they blogged lately?
Screw you.
Oh, yes, okay.
All right.
Avoid activism and pedantry.
People say, well, isn't that the American way?
It's the American way of certain people in America at certain times.
But it's not a way of being in the world.
And once you choose spirituality as a lifestyle,
you can give up the activist signs and the parades,
most of which is egoistic display.
Most activism is egocentricity.
Look at me, how important I am.
And listen to me because what I have to say is so important.
It's not important to anybody except you, but anyway.
Sounds good on active.
So you'll see on TV, you'll see it's interesting.
It says activist, blogger and activist.
That was on this week.
I said a blogger activist.
Boy, oh, boy.
There's only 150 million of them in the United States.
Be grateful for your assets.
Be glad that you're. . .
smart and good looking.
And that you're tolerant.
And your biggest asset is that you have become interested
in spiritual evolution and spirituality
and serving God and your fellow man.
It is helpful to your ego to remind yourself
that mankind has survived millions of years without your help.
I don't know how mankind got along without me all these years.
So intrinsic to spiritual evolution is humility.
And therefore, yours is the saddest story I've ever heard is a good one.
And you can also add to it as another sentence,
mankind has survived without you so far.
That way you don't take yourself so seriously.
Take yourself so seriously.
By doing these things,
you become your own best friend.
Putting a little thing on your mirror that says
yours is the saddest story I've ever heard
and mankind has survived all millions of years without you,
you're already being your best friend.
You're bringing your ego in. . .
You're putting a leash on your ego,
reminding yourself of the reality
that you are of benefit to mankind.
To the degree that you radiate God's love.
The degree that you radiate love.
Unconditional love to the world.
You are being your own best friend
and you are doing everything you can to the world.
The world is full of do-gooders.
And the history of do-gooders is rather catastrophic.
There's always a do-gooder,
and they like politics.
They like to control other people.
That for your own good,
we're going to reduce the so-and-so and peanut butter.
They're after one thing or another.
Candy, peanut butter, booze, smoking,
you know, chewing tobacco and whatever you want.
There's always a do-gooder
going to do something do-good for you.
Do-good for you, meaning control you.
What they mean is they want to control you in a certain way.
It's for your own health.
Why not let me worry about my health?
The longer I live, the more it costs the taxpayer.
I don't want people to quit smoking, quit drinking,
and driving fast while they're blind drunk.
There's an interesting book on do-gooders by Mona Chiron.
Real do-gooders.
I got to experience some of it in great detail.
At one time I had the largest psychiatric practice
in the United States for many years
and the greatest hospital practice.
And I was also in charge of many hospitals, state hospitals.
Where there was 3,000, 5,000, even up to 9,000 patients
all in a giant hospital.
So the do-gooders came along and said,
well, there is no such thing as mental illness.
That's just a myth.
I forget the idiot who said that, but there he was.
I invite him to have one of them live with him.
We'll see how long he thinks it's...
After he burns down your house and stabs your wife to death
and rapes your daughter,
we'll see whether it's a myth or not.
Anyway, do-gooders was...
Mental illness was a myth.
I forget the idiot.
Some psychiatrist who really...
He's probably on the other side.
I don't mean to say anything mean about this,
but it was stupid.
Mental illness was just a myth.
So they opened the doors of the state hospitals
and let these poor victims out.
You see, victimology pictured these poor souls
as being the victims of the system,
and that the hospital was like incarcerating.
Well, the reality was that these people were not capable
of taking care of themselves on the outside.
In fact, that's the main reason they're there.
Not that they were mentally ill or emotionally ill,
but they frankly couldn't take care of themselves.
So they closed the doors of the state hospital,
and all these people went out into the street,
and they became today's street people.
The street people you see in any big city years back
were in a mental hospital.
In the mental hospital, you got three good meals a day
balanced by dieticians.
You got free medical treatment.
You got legal protection, medical protection.
You got all kinds of protection, and things were done for you.
You never...
How often do those people go to the dentist
laying on the street?
Their teeth fall out.
In a mental hospital, you see the dentist, etc.
Anyway, Mona Shirin details that.
Oh, do-gooders always have something wonderful
they think will be good for you.
Another thing that's wonderful is to let other people win.
Letting others win is very gratifying,
and it makes them very happy.
So letting other people win arguments,
and say, you're right, honey.
You're right. You're right, dear.
She does it with me.
She says, well, we'll do as you say.
We'll do as you say. Yeah.
The reason we do is I say because I let her win
by saying, we'll do what you say.
That puts her on top.
Now I got to think of a way to count her
to be on top of that one.
Beware of unintended consequences.
This is very well known in society.
You intend for a thing to go in a certain direction,
and there are other factors
involved that you're unaware of.
Realize that in trying to develop compassion for people
and their propensity to make grave errors,
the grave errors is the innocent child
is present in everyone.
So the innocent child in all of us reads
a book like Do-Gooders and says,
let's go and save the mentally ill.
They're being imprisoned against their will,
and mental illness is just a myth anyway.
Who believes that?
The innocent child is present in everyone.
You could also call it the idiot child.
The child is innocent, innocent,
and is present in everyone.
The reason you believe what you believe
is because the innocent child in you believes it.
Within us is the child, the adult and the parent,
is a good designation.
And so the child within you,
tends to believe the adult,
and especially the parent.
So the parent within you says,
well, I read it in the paper,
or I saw it on television,
or I read a good book on it.
Well, that's enough to impress the child.
The innocent child is present in everyone.
Who makes the mistake when you screw up?
Who is it that really screws up?
It's the innocent child.
So if you're going to blame somebody,
who are you going to blame?
Are you going to blame the parent, the superego?
No.
You tend to blame the adult,
but it wasn't the adult that fell for it.
It was the innocent child.
The innocent child, then,
is what's gullible.
And all the political discussions
that you hear so heatedly on Fox News and others
is appealing to the innocent child and other people.
This one must know what they're talking about.
Oh, okay, because they got this title.
I'm the czar of something.
They must know what they're talking about.
The innocent child believes that.
The government believes it.
The voters believe it.
Who would even suspect the innocent child
doesn't know his ass from a hot rock?
How can a czar not know his what from a hot rock?
He didn't even pay his own income taxes yet.
All right.
If you see things differently,
it brings up the whole reframe and recontextualize.
What does a thing mean?
Means...
What does it mean?
It means if you frame it this way,
this is the way it looks,
but if you frame it differently,
it looks different.
It's the same thing.
The only thing you've changed is the frame.
If I take an idiot and he babbles idiocy,
I say, he's a dumb nut.
If I give him a title,
Congressman from someplace, rather,
I've recontextualized him,
and now he's a politician.
A minute ago, he was a dumb nut,
but now I've reframed him.
Critics are a dime a dozen,
except that the majority of people calibrate below 200.
All right, so you won't be disappointed.
Your peace will not be disturbed
because your expectation of people
is if they survive and are pleasant,
that in itself is fantastic.
The fact that they're surviving
and they still got a job
or they're still taking care of the kids, whatever,
the majority of people calibrate below 200.
Now, we showed that with the graph before.
So mankind is not anywhere near as evolved
as you think it is.
A lot of the criticism that we have of others,
politics or anything else in our society,
is the expectation of a higher level of consciousness
than the people are capable of.
The majority of people cannot tell truth from falsehood.
Isn't that a shock?
Boy, oh, boy.
Hmm.
I have permission to ask this.
That is a fact.
Resist.
Does that reframe your understanding
of the human condition?
The human mind,
humanity, people,
whole nations,
whole civilizations
are unable to tell truth from falsehood.
Whole societies,
whole civilizations,
whole generations.
Let's take a whole generation of Germans
fired in World War II.
Mein Kampf.
Millions of people worshiping this guy
who's going to be the savior
of right the wrongs of World War I
and all this.
Lead mankind to new,
a pure race and all.
You say,
how can millions of people
follow a guy who calibrates about 170?
Well, you see in other countries right now,
dictators around the world
all calibrate about 170.
You want a brain surgeon
who calibrates at 170?
I don't even want a cook
that calibrates at 170.
So we tailor our expectations of the world.
We become more forgiving
because we realize that error
is due to ignorance,
and it's due to the child,
the inner child within oneself.
If you can impress anyone's inner child,
that's what convinces people.
And that's what the media do constantly.
They try to impress the inner child.
We'll give somebody a fantastic title,
Czar.
The Czar of something.
Oh boy,
the Czar must know something about something.
The Czar doesn't know anything.
Except the majority of people
calibrate below 200.
All right.
Now those who are spiritually oriented,
judge not lest ye be judged.
Okay.
So that does not mean to go to sleep
and be unaware of reality
and the essence of things.
But what does it mean?
What it means is
they realize that people cannot help themselves
because of their own inner limitation.
Therefore, everyone is intrinsically innocent.
If they could be better than they are,
they would be.
To say they could be better
is a hypothetical egotism.
In reality,
you cannot be better than you are.
Judge not lest ye be judged.
Uh-huh.
Therefore,
the motives in whose eyes
judge none.
It doesn't mean to be blind
to the reality of what people are.
To recognize that somebody is a crook
who's on the take
is merely a recognition of truth.
That's different than judgmentalism.
Judgmentalism says he shouldn't be that way.
Well, if he could be different than he is,
he would be.
All viewpoints are arbitrary.
Why?
Because they all represent a positionality
and the result of framing.
Looked at from this viewpoint,
it looks like this.
So,
all viewpoints are arbitrary
and therefore,
you judge not.
So,
realize that any judgment you can make
represents a viewpoint
and that viewpoint itself
is arbitrary.
So, that
saves us the problem
of getting into fixed
fixed positionalities of rigidity.
A spiritually evolved person
avoids rigidity.
Doesn't mean they have
they lose certainty about the reality
as they have known it.
But it's no longer an arbitrary position.
There are lots of people
who don't believe in God
and I understand them completely.
And they get on
and they rant and rave
and they're creative about the evil of
religion and
Godness and all that.
And I myself was a devout
atheist for 20 years or something.
No, I wasn't an atheist.
I was a non-believer.
I was extremely religious,
very religious.
And then,
due to a very major inner psychic event,
I switched from being
very religious to the point of
hyper-religiosity
and instantly became an agnostic.
Became an atheist actually
and later on an agnostic.
I think I've told that before.
I was walking through the woods one day.
You know, I had a very religious upbringing.
I was a boat boy for the bishop.
I was an acolyte.
I sang in the church choir.
I was a boy soloist at the cathedral.
I was about as religious as you could get.
My family was religious.
And one day I was walking through the woods
not thinking about religion
or God or anything.
All of a sudden out of nowhere
arose
a vision of the
suffering of all of mankind
throughout all of time.
It was like a revelation.
Suddenly the curtain was pulled aside
and I saw
the enormity and gravity
of the suffering
of all of mankind.
And in that instant
I became an atheist.
I said I can't believe in a God
who would allow that.
So I blamed the suffering
of mankind
on God.
What I didn't realize
that would have been revealed to me
was not divinity but the ego.
What I was looking at
is the profound destruction
and the massive agony and suffering
that the ego has brought
man over time.
That which is demonic,
the devil, whatever you want to call it.
That which is evil, etc.
So
it took me a good 20 years
to discover the mistake I had made.
It wasn't God
responsible for all that
but mankind himself.
Greediness is not taught by God.
So
the suffering of mankind
is then brought about
by the ego.
We can't even blame the ego
because it's the
innocence of the inner child
that believes the ego.
So man's
suffering then really arises
out of his lack of
spiritual evolution
and the ignorance that accompanies
being deaf, dumb, and blind
through the presence of divinity.
And therefore
God was reborn.
God was happy about it.
Geez, Dave, thank God you made that.
Except that the majority
of people calibrate below 200.
There's the source of
man's suffering.
All viewpoints are arbitrary.
Therefore we renew thankfulness
and gratitude.
Every day we say
our Father who art in heaven
may we see you again.
God bless you.
Amen.
Alaska. Very impressive. I don't know. He's very impressive, his simplicity. All right. So we
renew our thankfulness and gratitude. And now a really, really liberating understanding.
The mind, which you consider yourself, is not you. It's an it. The mind is what talks all the time.
What talks is not the spirit, but the ego. The spirit doesn't talk. The mind is an it.
It's not who you are. In the enlightened state, you realize you're not the body.
You're not the mind. You are something that goes beyond and encompasses both of them.
The mind is an it. It's not a you. So when you listen to the mind, you can refer to it as it.
What is it thinking about taking this driveway home? Huh? That's what it is thinking. Not you.
The real I, the real I, the self with a capital S, is the presence of divinity within.
The radiance of consciousness itself, without which you wouldn't even know that you exist.
The source of all awareness is the self with a capital S, which is not different than
consciousness itself.
Consciousness, then, is the radiance of divinity as all that exists. The radiance of all that
exists. Out of consciousness arises the universe. Out of consciousness arises the universe and all
that exists. The mind is an it, is not a you. And critics are a dime a dozen. People will say,
well, that's the American way to get up and speak your piece.
I think that's wonderful that people do that and, then, they should sit down.
Oh would you sign up, yeah, I hear what you have to say, and then I say, thank you!
Moving on,
All right,
Well, okay, now accepting that the people, the majority of people below 200
is a little more difficult.
To help you with this review,
extraordinary popular delusions and the madness of focus.
crowds. I refer to this book very often because all of mankind or the majority
of mankind can be seriously wrong about basic facts of life and the fact that
it's held generally by the populace makes it true. Right now we have
earthwarming challenging as number one belief system and we'll get to that
later. Review extraordinary popular delusions in the madness of crowds. So
the fact that everybody believes the thing is interesting should be taken
into account but it should not be persuasive. Keep a sense of humor. Oh you
know they're gonna tax people the government gonna
tax people for cattle. Every cow is gonna cost you a $15 federal tax
the reason is because cattle emit methane. Methane is a cause of
earthwarming. Cattle you-know-whats are what's causing the earth to warm. Just
think what went on when there were 70 million bison running across the face of
the United States. 70 million bison all doing you-know-what. Must have made quite
a noise. The earth would have gone into a fiery ball. 70 million bison emitting
methane at the same time. Oh so earthwarming is today's major delusion
and madness of the crowd and it's so politicized you know it's so politicized
everybody gets out there about earthwarming and becomes very fervent
very fervent.
Certain politicians whose names I won't mention aren't going to allow something or other
because that's going to save the earth. Oh you're going to save the earth yeah okay.
Everyone assumes that they are right and others are wrong. So when you hear an argument going
on put yourself in the other person's place and say to their hearing what I'm saying is
wrong. So when they discuss maybe an alternate view of what's causing earthwarming
I'm aware that the other person has been thoroughly brainwashed and is not
believing is what I say at all. I don't even know why I'm talking to them except
that you have to be polite and make conversations. I say well an alternate
view is that earthwarming has to do with the magnetic activity on the surface of
the Sun and sunspots as ice core drillings back through 10 million years
have demonstrated. That's just an alternate view. So I don't care if they
believe it or not. I mean, it doesn't hurt me if they want to tax cows. Seek to
understand others and change them. So it's not necessary to change people to
see things your way. Serve God rather than the narcissistic ego. To serve God
means to spiritually send forth love and goodwill towards people, send forth
goodwill, goodwill towards all of life.
in all its expressions so the rule of life that i think i recommend is to serve all of life and
have reverence for all of life and all its expressions and therefore all you have to do
is participate rather than dominate you don't have to win every argument you can put a thought
in the other person's mind and say so i have heard wasn't it the buddha that said that all the time
as i have heard as i have heard so i i like to say i have heard and then you can give them an
alternate view uh and it's okay to have false i have false it wasn't a yogi bear that said
i have false but being wrong ain't one of them
i got false but being wrong ain't one of them he had described the yogi bear i don't know
yeah
i got false but being wrong ain't one of them
uh now we we reach the peak of our current society and that's the struggle for the moral
high ground who's right who's morally therefore a superior support others to find good about
themselves even though they're a psychotic raving idiot they're kind to their mother
you are very kind to your mother yeah find something good and you can really cook you can
really cook you know
fry bacon really good
concede therefore to what is versus what you think things ought to be all right so you got to watch
out when your mind starts telling you things ought to be such in such a way be very suspicious of
ought the things that ought to be different people ought to be smarter no why people ought to agree
with you no people ought to pay their taxes honestly
what do you mean ought
human nature it's human nature to chisel a little bit if you can get away with it
it's human nature to chisel if they can get away with it and the majority of people calibrate under
200 therefore the majority of people would cheat on their income tax if they can get away with it
they get away with it
hipparisha national
is true
p
what do you know about that
pr
i call it creative tax reporting
as medical treatment
pict
i
there is shots deductin is medical treatment
the
fifth
to what is. So there's no point in making people wrong
about that. Everybody's into survival and
therefore they do what they think will bring about
increase the likelihood and value of their survival.
So we can just presume that people will do what they
consider best for their survival.
Okay. It's okay to just be rather than to do or have.
The other levels of consciousness
were what you have or what you do
is what makes you important. Your title, what you do,
what you do, what you have, cars, Cadillacs,
private planes, whatever. And in the
end it's what you have become. It's what you are.
Surrender your will to God and therefore you can let
bygones be bygones.
My grandmother used to say on the maternal side,
she'd say she was saintly. In fact, she was considered for sainthood.
If you don't have anything good to say about a person,
then don't say anything at all.
Well, you'll see the mind really likes to
say things that are not too complimentary about people.
That's what gossip is all about. And when I was
young in the church,
the women's organizations in the church,
their main problem, their main character defect that they all worked on
was the attractiveness of gossip.
And I worked in a, I worked in a,
something about gardening, I forget the name of it,
greenhouse one time. And there was five or six women and me.
Yeah. And all they did all day was gossip.
That's all they did. They didn't have TV.
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
So look at gossip, obviously, as a source of amusement.
I'm sure if they had television, they would have turned it on.
But the conversation went, did you see the way Gertrude looked at him?
And did you see what she was wearing?
She wore the same thing last time, you know,
that's the way the whole thing went.
And I listened to that for eight hours as I stuck these seedlings in.
So I got an enormous education in gossip.
If you don't have anything good to say about a person, then say nothing at all.
You know, otherwise, the first negative thing you can see people run,
did you hear that so-and-so got a ticket for so-and-so?
Uh-huh. He got a ticket for driving drunk, I hear.
Yeah. No wonder his wife is saying, you know, I didn't say anything.
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
It's important to realize that mankind has been at war
93% of recorded history.
93% of time, man has been at war.
Right now, I don't remember how many wars we got going on in the world.
The United States has two of them.
But since I've been in the world,
when I first was born, World War I wasn't quite, it was just over.
And the shell-shocked war veterans were wandering around looking for jobs, etc.
And then since I've been around, I've lived through, I don't know, six or seven wars.
It's been one war after another.
If you count little wars,
Africa and various places,
I guess it's been, there's been a war all the time I've been alive this lifetime.
So for 82 years, at least I know,
man has been at war.
Usually several wars at the same time.
So what do you think of that?
So there you are.
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
Mankind has been at war almost all the time.
The only time...
The only time he wasn't at war, he was probably sick with the plague
and too sick to be at war.
Or too impoverished, he couldn't even afford to buy a Tommy Hawk.
I share this with Brock once in a while.
He would say, so there you are.
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
The news in the morning is that something other happened, you know.
And I'd say, well, so there you are.
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
In a way, that's being fatalistic.
So there you are means that's the way the world runs.
That's the way things are in the world.
That infuriates the gooders who feel that they shouldn't be that way.
It shouldn't be that way.
I accept the fact that there will be lots of people in the world
who say it shouldn't be that way.
But it is that way.
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
So there you are.
Another way to explain it is what will be will be.
And what will be will be is not just chance.
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
What will be will be is very hard to describe verbally.
It has to do with the influence of karmic influences.
Now, karmic influence, it's like we're all little magnetic,
we're all little like pieces of iron filings
with a magnetic north pole and south pole.
And the infinite field of consciousness, which is the mind of God,
is an infinite magnetic field.
Now,
what you have become
determines where you are within that field.
So you've got to picture yourself as an iron filing.
You've got a north pole and a south pole.
Here's this big, powerful electromagnetic field,
the mind of God, called consciousness.
Now, where you are within the field
depends on the decisions that you make.
So as you say, well, I'll forgive that person,
you move up here higher in the field.
And if you say, I'm going to get even with that son of a bitch,
you move down in the field.
See, you can't blame it on God.
See, what historical religions do is blame it on God.
This creates a lot of atheists in the world.
Now, what happens to you is solely up to you alone.
I forgive him, I hate him.
Oh, overlook it.
No, get even.
You can see how a little electromagnetic iron filing,
how you move,
and the infinite magnetic field,
the infinite power of consciousness itself.
The power of consciousness is beyond man's imagination.
We've quoted a scientific explanation.
The energy, the power,
one cubic centimeter of consciousness
is greater than its equivalent as weight of the entire universe.
One cubic inch of the infinite field of consciousness
is equivalent to the power of consciousness.
One is greater than the total mass of the entire universe.
The entire mass of the universe is less than the power
of a tiny bit of consciousness.
Why?
Because consciousness is the field of God's will.
And the power of God's will is infinite,
has no beginning, has no end, and is infinite.
Acceptance.
So there you are.
That's how it is.
Oh, okay.
Develop a peaceful nature.
Be aware of the power of nature.
Love nature and develop yourself a peaceful nature.
See the beauty of all that exists.
Okay.
Value quietude.
You don't have to turn the radio on
the instant you walk into the house.
The enemy is really the inner child,
the innocence of the inner child,
and the inner child's willfulness,
as spiritual beings, we practice the virtues.
We don't claim perfection.
We claim progress.
We try our best to forgive people,
even though they seem to be evil or wrong or whatever.
We practice the virtues.
It doesn't say we master the virtues.
It says we practice them.
So we're admitting that we are evolutionary,
that the degree of our fulfillment,
of our human potential,
is not the same as the degree
of our spiritual fulfillment.
So we're admitting that we are evolutionary,
that the degree of our fulfillment, of our human potential,
is constantly growing.
Recall when you,
this is a very good one,
because very often,
the power of this arises in childhood.
Recall peace on earth,
goodwill towards men,
the angels who announce
the coming of Christ
on Christmas Eve.
Strive to be angelic
rather than Luciferic.
Practice no attractions and no aversions.
The Buddha said,
neither attractions nor aversions.
What?
I'm going to quit.
People are afraid of death.
Actually, the near-death experience
is one of absolute and total peace.
So the goal,
the lecture for today
has to do with peace
and peacefulness.
And although people fear death,
the actual experience
is one of infinite peace.
So we'll stop there for now.
God bless you all.
We purposely came back a little late
so you wouldn't feel guilty
about getting back late.
We want everybody to be happy.
102 ways to happiness.
Oh dear.
No attractions and no aversions.
That requires some discipline.
You can do it by asking yourself,
could I let go
wanting to be attracted by that?
And you begin to see
that the attraction
is something you project
onto things.
That famous book that I've mentioned
a number of times
called Glamour says
the thing is not attractive at all.
Its attraction is due to an energy
that you project onto it.
Now that's quite a surprise, isn't it?
You think the attraction
is in the thing.
The attraction is in you.
Well, you're very attracted
to a doughnut
if you're hungry
and you like doughnuts.
You don't think doughnuts
are attractive.
You think they're ugly.
Ugly doughnuts.
How to be one up
in a conversation.
You're going to have an argument.
I'll tell you an inner secret.
You're going to have an argument
with somebody, see?
They're a debater.
So the debater gets up with you
and you say,
you got something on your chin.
Is that mayonnaise?
You're going to get some time.
In an innocuous,
in a harmless situation.
Just say,
is that something on your chin?
Is that ketchup?
No.
Is that lettuce?
Is that mayonnaise on your chin?
So that completely throws
the other person off their mindset.
Throws them off their mindset.
And then you swoop in.
Waiting for them
like a hawk on the edge of the field.
Is that mayonnaise
on your chin?
They've lost
the game.
You throw them off
their cool.
I learned that in boxing.
How to pretend.
It's called the feint.
And of course
that was a formidable mosquito weight.
They didn't have mosquito weight.
They invented mosquito weight for me.
Except the social roles of others.
In other words,
people are fulfilling
what they see as their social role.
It's not really actually
who they are.
They're acting out a social role
in their definition
of the understanding of
how they're supposed to be
and what they're supposed to be
and how they're supposed to look
and how they're supposed to talk.
Their behavior
and appearance
and everything should be like.
So that's the value
of trying to understand others.
To understand what runs them
and out of that
comes compassion.
Out of that arises compassion.
Understanding others
brings compassion.
The near-death experience
is one of total peace.
Which is hard to explain.
But the peace of God
that goes beyond understanding
is a peace of
great profundity.
Transforms
the appearance of the world
and takes you out of all
possible suffering.
Okay, next.
We've got 101 of these.
We better move along.
Only the ego is vulnerable.
The real self is eternal.
The real self is invisible
to other people.
And therefore, if your feelings are hurt
or you've got to have something
or win something
or you're lamenting losing something
remind yourself
it's only the ego
creating this experience.
It's only the ego creating this experience.
It's because of your relationship
to the object
that you mourn it when it's lost.
So, again
it's always going back to the ego
to understand the ego
and therefore
not be its victim.
Live in each instant
which is innately peaceful.
This comes about
through spiritual work also.
To live not one day at a time
not one hour at a time
one instant at a time.
We were either going to make it
back here in time
or we weren't.
What can I do?
I'm not driving.
The traffic is there
and helping or not helping.
Live in each instant.
If you live in each instant
you are always in peace
because suffering is created
by writing a scenario
writing a story.
I lost
poor so-and-so
and he got run over by a so-and-so
and then my cat drowned
and then the next thing you know
I had a flat tire
and then I got a ticket.
I mean you got a whole long story.
Now actually
the cop giving you a ticket
you could say
anytime I got a ticket
I always thanked him
and I said thank you for
helping to save my life.
Then he'd say
well I was going to write you a ticket.
I said I realize you're actually
trying to save my life
and I'm so stupid I don't realize it.
The cop would say
well thank you
watch it from now on.
Detach from control.
This observer.
This is a little more sophisticated.
It means that if you constantly
let go wanting to control things
change them being on top of them
what happens is the
chatter of the ego stops
and you then become
merely the observer
the witness.
Now this is a high spiritual state
in which you relinquish the personal self
to the field of consciousness itself.
Witnessing and observing
you think there's a you doing that
there is no you
witnessing or observing
there isn't any person there at all
the idea that there's a person
there comes in after you've
observed and witnessed.
Observing and witnessing goes on
autonomously of its own
it doesn't need a personal self
doesn't need a personal self
consciousness is
aware and you don't have
to interject yourself and say
I'm aware. You say the edge of the
stage is there
the edge of the stage is there
I don't know where the hell is the edge of the stage
come
it's there someplace
the edge of the stair is there
the witness observer then
is
a higher state
because the ego is not making
conclusions, judgments
doesn't want to control anything
it merely wants to witness
and
when you go out of body
at least
one out of body
there was only the witness observer there
didn't have any particular
intention about anything
it was just aware
of it
like people who leave the body
in surgery and go up to the ceiling
and witness the surgery
the witness observer
doesn't want to do anything
but watches everything
just watches
say what did you do when you were up near the ceiling
didn't do anything but I was aware
of what was going on
be the witness observer
that's a state you can achieve
by constant surrender
and by
contemplation
the contemplative state
puts you in the witness observer
practice meditation
and contemplation
as you do that
the witness observer
becomes predominant
and becomes
more or less one's normal state
and
the only trouble with that is
you're asking people questions all the time
what day is it
differentiate wants from needs
what you want
is one thing and what you need is another
people convince themselves
that their wants are their needs
they always have to have a raise
everybody has to have more money
that's universal
no matter how much you make
you need more money
if you ask any multi-billionaire
what's your problem
he says well I just need more
capital
I could buy the whole United States
instead of just the eastern seaboard
you know
and Jesus Christ said
wear the world like a light garment
in other words
participate
see that it's there
but it's not central
the ego is not central
wear the world like a light garment
so you're the witness observer
you observe the world
and differentiate appearance from essence
that's what
we do when we use the arm
to calibrate something
the appearance of a thing is one thing
the essence is another
the ego cannot tell
essence from appearance
it just sees the wolf in sheep's clothing
and
sheep in wolf's clothing
the wolf in sheep's clothing
differentiate appearance from essence
be kind to all of life
why
for its own sake
because of your own reverence for life
you try to be kind
to all of life
in all of its expressions
no matter whether it's a toad
or a bunny or a squirrel
whether it's another human being
whether it's a tree
I never hurt a tree
I try to be kind to trees
you see some people take an axe
a hand axe
and they're going by a tree
they slam it into the tree
and then walk on
pull it out and walk on
what do you think the tree didn't know
you just hit it with an axe
if you ask the tree
how was that
the tree will go
all of life then
is aware of the nature
of the other life
in an advanced state of consciousness
you'll see
that the tree
is aware of the divinity of yourself
the self with a capital s
as you walk by a tree
its consciousness
which any scientist
would poo poo
is aware of the divinity
of that which is walking by
that's true
even a tree
is aware of the divinity
the godness within you
the tree is aware
that an emissary of god
is walking by
let's try it again
even a tree is aware
that you are an emissary of god
all of nature
knows
that that which is of divine origin
is walking by
all the more reason
to be kind to it
if consciousness expresses life
is aware of the divinity
of your essence
out of respect for that life
you return the favor
and therefore
I love the trees
I love the kitties
I love all living things
because their essence
is also that of divinity
this is god appearing as a kitty cat
this is god appearing as a mole
this is god appearing as a toad
you see the little toad
don't you see
the toad loves life
he loves
like a toad
so to take a hammer
and hit the toad
as you can see
the extreme ungodliness of that
because that is denying
the divinity
of all that exists
all that exists
is worthy of reverence
so as we grow
we begin to revere
all of life
and all of its expressions
even the mad dog
even the raving maniac
who can't help but be a raving maniac
they cannot help themselves
so out of benevolence
then
you send unconditional love
to all of life
and wish it well
differentiate appearance from essence
be kind to all of life
and
so you can practice with this
it's very beneficial
to have pets
and a garden spot
the pet could be anything
the pet could be cockroaches
in a little box
the pet could be anything
my mother used to make me let them go
don't keep them in the box
those are cockroaches
alright
decrease your expectations of others
nobody is going to ever reach
the level
at which you would wish them
so
the expectation has to be
and you can see
that everybody has been programmed
by our society
so few are the people
who escape the programming
of our human world
it's very good
for your peace of mind
to mind your own business
mind your own business
oh dear
make a list of your worries
if you can't get rid of your worries
it's important to make a list of them
has everybody here got any worries
anybody here
who doesn't have any worries
alright the mental ward is that way
one way to get on top of your worries
is to make a list of them
and prioritize them
because when you identify them
you can deal with them
otherwise they're just sort of
a vague, vague thing
worrying about money, worrying about old age
worrying about
your business collapsing, whatever it is
if you sit down
and make a list of worries
they lose a good deal of power
over you
because you're defining them
when you define them
you confine them
and you see how small they actually are
I mean if you go flat broke
you go into county
so what's wrong with being in the county
you're flat broke
got no money, no place to go
what better place to be
chocolate versus vanilla
is simply a choice
alright what the world does
it says
the people on this side are chocolate
and the people on this side are vanilla
and
they don't have to be seen
as adversaries
you can see
you can choose chocolate
doesn't mean you have to
hate vanilla
you can choose vanilla doesn't mean
you have to hate chocolate
if you watch the political news
you would think the only way you can be vanilla
is you gotta hate chocolate or vice versa
actually you're just picking
one of two choices
differentiate your emotional
from your spiritual viewpoints
people will use an excuse
well I feel this way
they use the emotional
outlet
why did you do that
well I felt like that
that's the big excuse
what was your emotional viewpoint
and what was your spiritual viewpoint
well my spiritual viewpoint
is somewhat different
so you don't want to be the slave
of the ego and its emotions
and don't forget that the ego
the basis of the mind
is the child
so when you're talking about emotions
very often you're talking about
the inner child
and not the inner adult
and in fighting your way out of
some corner
the emotional corner
use logic instead of emotion
a lot of people try emotion
instead of just logic
if you use logic
you can see there's nothing to be afraid of
when life is over
they bury you and that's the end of the problem
so what's the problem
when it's over it's over
no more suffering
ask for a miracle
those of you who have done the course of miracles
know that this
in itself is a miracle
that asking for a miracle
very often
produces the miracle
I cannot find the thing
I have no idea where it is
it's a complete blank
and I'll ask the Holy Spirit
where is so and so
and then I forget it
I walk in the other room
and then out of nowhere
not out of logic
out of nowhere
it comes to my mind you're left in the bathroom on the shelf
I've got it
everything I ever lose is in the bathroom
in the shelf
or the kitchen on the shelf
ask for a miracle
people feel they're not entitled to miracles
or that they don't believe it
people don't know what a miracle is
very often a miracle is
merely the reframing
the thing has been reframed
especially in time
it wasn't expected in time
today is tomorrow as yesterday
today
is tomorrow as yesterday
good God it's yesterday already
and here I'm worrying about it
I was worrying about getting back here on time
and tomorrow
that's going to be yesterday
today's going to be yesterday
and we'll say we were worried about getting back on time
yesterday
aside from having a mentor
talking things over with friends
is really
very important
because an isolated person
ends up pretty crazy
and who was it
whatchamacallit
a killer
lived by himself in an 8x10
terrified all of industry
and all
he didn't have any friends to talk it over with
I forget his name now
huh
the unibomber
that's it
the unibomber had nobody to talk it over with
if he talked it over with friends
he might have been dissuaded
now
he wanted to be all by himself
in an 8x10
space
I understand he is now all by himself
in a 10x12 space
he probably feels
he's rattling around in that big cell
as you can see
the person with schizophrenia
and delusions
is unable to help himself
so even though he was
the unibomber
you can't hate him
you can't want to get even with him
how can you see the unibomber
except as a person
who was spiritually lost
he was spiritually lost
spiritually lost
completely egocentric
yeah
so not having friends to talk it over with
another way to
down your fears and worries
is to accept the worst possible scenario
worst possible scenario
picture it in your mind
well the worst thing that can happen
is I get a flat tire on the parkway
and it's raining
and I forgot my drivers license
that's the worst possible scenario
then you say
well now what if all that happened
well I'd catch hell from the cop
and I'd have to pay the fine
that's true
well if that's the worst possible scenario
you don't have to be frightened
one time I left Phoenix
to go up to
where is it we live
wherever it is we live
and
it's two hours away
a couple hours north of Phoenix
and I started to leave Phoenix
and my headlights went out
the battery went dead
so here I am 110 or whatever it is
miles
and it's midnight
pitch black out and I've got no headlights
well wouldn't do me much good
to pull over the side of the road
so what I did is I followed the car
ahead of me
and I very carefully did everything he did
when he went this way I went that way
I knew that sooner or later
the driver is going to see some guy with his lights out
is behind me
and he will conclude that this guy is following me home
because he's got no lights
so I followed him for two hours
150 miles
or whatever the distance is
and I was
worried that I was frightening the guy
so I asked God
I said please don't let him be frightened
I just need him to guide me home
and the guy I think
he did understand it
he eventually did understand it
and he got that I was a man in distress
and let's
I have permission to ask this
he finally got it
yeah he got it
I was praying that he would get it
I said dear God please let him just get that
I got to get up the highway
and I got no headlights
so that worked out
that was the worst possible scenario
I like this one
this is the movie that should have won the best film ever
Scarlett O'Hara
they named some other movie
I couldn't understand why they picked the movie they did
when obviously
this is the greatest movie ever made
yeah
and Scarlett would say
I'll think about it tomorrow
well in the modern world
that would be criticized wouldn't it
think about it tomorrow
this that and the other
but there's a certain wisdom to that
because if you think about it tomorrow
it doesn't look the same
for one thing you start a process
going in your unconscious mind
and so when you say
I can't think of how I'm going to make any money
I haven't got any assets
and I've got no income
and I've been cut off now
and you say well I'll think about it tomorrow
I'll think about it tomorrow
then suddenly
in the morning you get up
you're self boiling an egg
and all of a sudden
you remind yourself
well I could take this to a hock shop
and probably get a couple hundred bucks
right yesterday you didn't think of that
today it's obvious
everybody's got something in your house
you can hock
everybody got something you can hock
hockables
anybody so poor they haven't even got a hockable
nobody's that poor
you may have to sleep on the floor
but you've got something to hock
there's a new program on that called hock
what is it hock shop or something
about the same night as ice road triggers
pawn shop yeah
is peace
is everywhere
existent
peace is existent all the time
even in the midst of war
you know
we were about to explode
this mine was about to go off
and he says well we might get killed
and then what happens if we go off
and I said to him well then we die
he said you're right
you're right
and his fear went away
and just the
peace in the middle of war
there was peace
in that you were doing exactly
what your duty was
you're supposed to man this particular gun
you're supposed to watch for strange ships
you're supposed to be on guard
report anything
and so
you're standing out there
I was on a very small ship
not one of these big battleships
I was on a minesweeper
and so we stood watch for four hours
at night you see
and when you stood watch you wear the gun belt
with a loaded 45
loaded 45
and anything that moved you shot it
see something moving over the fantail
anyway things could be worse
life is transitory
so that's another thing
the ego thinks that
it's eternal that it's life
is going to be forever
once you accept the fact that life
is transitory at best
we're all going to go
uh oh you didn't expect
to hear that today
we're all going to go
anybody thinks they're not
going to go
anybody planning not to go
laughter
in the infinite
dimensions of time
we're all living together
you would think a couple of years here and there
is different in time
but in compared
to infinite time
in the few decades or whatever it is
it'll take for all of us to go around the other side
is all about the same time
so frankly we're all going over
about the same time
some people went ahead and got parking
places for us
laughter
and is over and found us parking places
so we get to heaven
we will have parking places
and uh
a sign telling us where to go
laughter
life is transitory
the acceptance of that then
decreases a great deal of fear
life and all
experience of life is transitory
the knowledge that
you were created by God
it then gives us
certain solemnity
certain profundity
lets see if we have permission to ask that
we have permission to ask this question
we were all created
by God resist
we were created by God
wow
here you thought it was a sperm and an egg
laughter
a biologic accident
life is transitory
that which you really are
was created by God
so not the ego but the self
with a capital S
is the essence of who you are
and when you leave the body
those of you who have left
the experience of leaving the body
the witness observer witnesses
and observes the body but feels no attraction
to it at all
it seems meaningless
boring
not even attractive
you would think you're trying to get back in that body
and reactivate it
but strangely enough it just lays there
it has no attraction
you go on a worry diet
we said we were going to make a list of worries
so then you begin to pick off
your worry diet
the things that you're going to let
be willing to let go of
I will stop worrying about money
what's going to happen to you if you don't have any money
if you're poor
well I've been poor
when you're poor there's lots of things you can't have
can't have a new Cadillac
so you go on a diet
and you start letting things go
could I be happy without a new Cadillac
yep
could I be happy
if I didn't have a new pair of shoes
yep
I've got them on so I know
give up on a worry diet
give up trying to be happy
just
you have an ongoing acceptance
now this acceptance
is not the human will
this acceptance
is being the
witness observer
it's a contemplative position
not meditative but contemplative
so that as we walk
through the day today
the stage
is here where it is
the flowers are where they are
Susan is sitting there
doing fine
there's some mysterious person
in the dark over there
I don't have to know who that mysterious
person is
I said well I can
just control my curiosity
do I have to know who's sitting there
in the dark
no don't have to
do I know who's sitting there
no
I presume it's a friend
well if it's not a friend
it could be an enemy
if it's an enemy
it could kill you right now
so here I am
do you want to kill me
kill me
nobody killed me oh well
and you can let go of your worries
if you're motivated
by God
you can let go of your worries
one by one
by total acceptance
give up trying to be happy
don't try to be happy
just be happy
that's simpler than trying to be happy
you can see that trying to be happy
is like a mouse chasing its tail
stop trying to be happy
should be happy because you are. You are. Fantastic. From nothingness to somethingness,
give up trying to be happy. Give up being rich and famous. Oh, everybody's dream in America.
I can't go to Hollywood and get on the television interview shows. Give up being rich and famous.
You see what happens to the most rich and famous people.
Oh, it's rather grisly when you study the truth of their life, their life stories.
Give up being rich and famous. What people do to be rich and famous. Have 18 children at once. God
knows what people will do. Walk the tightrope over stretches. Who was that great gymnast that
finally fell to his death? Famous circus family.
Anyway.
Italian name. He was the greatest in the world. And he fell to his death anyway.
So being rich and famous eggs you on to the edge. People with any sense, you know,
stand back a little. You see, every year about nine people fall over the edge of the Grand Canyon.
How do they manage that? I'm scared to get within 20 feet of the edge of the Grand Canyon.
I've gotten better. I used to be 50 feet from the edge of the Grand Canyon.
Now I've gotten, I'm up to 20 feet within the Grand Canyon. How do they get over there
where they fall off? Every year about nine people fall into the Grand Canyon. Anybody
who's dumb enough to fall in the Grand Canyon deserves falling in the Grand Canyon.
I think they actually, they're just daredevils. You know, these people that want to parachute
out of strange things at strange heights with both legs bound together and a gag in their
mouth or something.
It's what I call vainglorious. What a lot of people think is heroics is nothing but
vainglory. They want to be on the headlines. They jumped all the way from, you know, 30,000
feet and didn't open their parachute until they got to 600 feet down here. So they must
have had an exciting ride. Anyway, more spiritual ways are to walk the labyrinth. And you know,
walking the labyrinth,
what cathedral was that, Ernie? What cathedral was that? The labyrinth, chart. Anyway, walking
the labyrinth, which is very famous. Our church back home has a copy of the labyrinth in the
parking lot. The effect of walking the labyrinth is the same if you trace it with a pencil.
If you have a diagram of the labyrinth and you take a pencil point, you start from the
starting point and you do with the pencil point, you follow the labyrinth where it goes.
The effect on your consciousness is the same as if you walked it. Isn't that strange? Okay,
that's mystical. That is a mystical truth. Nobody knows the reason for it. Nobody knows
the reason for it. It's just a fact. So you can, if you're really worried and cannot get
off of it, you find some place that has the labyrinth in the parking lot or something,
or you get a copy of the labyrinth and you trace it slowly.
You trace it with the tip of a pencil and you follow. It says go this way, go this way,
now go this way, now go this way. There's something about this mysterious pattern that
brings a profound sense of peace, a profound sense of peace from merely following a diagram
with your eye or your pencil, or if it's large, walking it. Walk the labyrinth. Something
similar is to do the rosary.
Do the rosary. Something similar is spinning the prayer wheel. Yes. All right, let's ask
if those all work. Doing the rosary brings about greater inner peace. Spinning the prayer
wheel brings about greater inner peace. Resist. So whether you're Christian, Buddhist, or
whatever, it doesn't say you have to be a Christian or a believer to do these things.
It just says do them. It doesn't say only Christians.
The buddhists benefit from the labyrinth. Only buddhists benefit from the prayer wheel.
Says anybody, anybody. So there's something beyond belief systems. There's some other
power and energy and patterning in the universe, which nobody has discovered as yet. In my
perusal of the world's spiritual literature over decades, I've never come across any explanation
why such a geometric pattern.
have such a profound effect.
There is some recent
research on the Taurus,
T-O-R-U-S,
shape, and
in the mathematics
thereof, could be
perhaps a plausible explanation,
a partial explanation.
Okay.
Do the rosary, walk the labyrinth,
and spin the prayer wheel.
Another thing that will calm your nerves is to
write your will.
And take out life insurance.
Anybody here
lacks life insurance?
Uh-oh, uh-oh, uh-oh, uh-oh.
Anybody here hasn't written a will?
The fact that you're mortal
and the acceptance
of your mortality,
therefore, to not
have a will, et cetera, no life
insurance, means
a loss of sense of reality.
In reality,
you're going to come to an end.
I hate to tell you that, but
is this news to anybody?
A few arms go up, yep.
It does come to an end, yes.
Somebody you might as well benefit.
You're going to croak anyway.
You watch on TV, you can get
life insurance pretty darn cheap nowadays.
Kick out a friend,
a relative, leave it
to the humane society.
If you don't have any friends,
your relatives, what about
all the little doggies and kitties
that have no home?
You can make out a will and leave
a life insurance policy to the humane society.
Yes?
What's the importance of those things?
Because there's a certain generosity,
a lovingness,
that your death
will serve some positive benefit
to life in its various forms.
The humane society
could use the insurance money
so it can,
find more homes for more homeless pets, et cetera.
Write a will, take out life insurance.
Watch television's Animal Channel.
Animal Channel has very interesting things on it, yep.
And bury the hatchet.
Bury the hatchet.
I went to a camp, and when the boys
were getting to scrabble with each other,
at midnight, they'd all get off to get up.
You had to go out and dig a hole.
And you had to put your hatchet in there,
and then bury it.
That was a new thing.
Who wants to get up at midnight
and go dig a hole in the dark?
We were all scared of the dark anyway,
because we were all about 12 or something.
So we learned how to avoid
needing to bury the hatchet.
Give up being an adrenaline junkie.
That's a hard one.
You see all these speeders, you know,
they're caught going 110 on the parkway.
They're always in Los Angeles,
and they're always going 100.
And you see the helicopter
following them hour after hour.
Finally, you get so bored
of watching this stupid driver,
I'm ready to punch him in the mouth
when he gets out of his car.
Shat three hours of my life on television.
I couldn't quit until I found out
whether this guy was caught.
And it's almost a psychopath.
The last time, I think, it was a woman.
People think, oh, women don't do that.
Yeah, they're women psychopaths, too.
On dope and an adrenaline junkie.
Yeah, one thing of importance
is to keep your head up.
One thing of importance
is to quit when you're ahead.
Quit when you're ahead.
People push the greed button to the point
100,000 a year isn't enough.
Gotta push, push, push, push.
Push to 105, push to 110.
Of course, then they get fired.
Quit when you're ahead.
Let go of greed.
That's the hard one.
And greed is that rapacious
wantingness.
Woke your Buddha nature.
And cleverly live in the space
beneath thoughts.
People say, how can I get the mind
to stop?
You don't have to get the mind to stop.
Just pay no attention to it.
You'll notice that thoughts are like
the surface of the sea.
And beneath the surface of the sea
is the stillness of the deep.
Beneath thoughts, there is absolute silence.
Right now, this voice
is talking.
With spiritual advancement,
I'm aware that everything is happening
autonomously of its own.
I don't have to talk.
The talkingness is happening, isn't it?
The talkingness is happening
of its own.
I don't need a me that's talking.
I just witness that talkingness
is happening of its own.
So most of the things
we worry about and take blame for
and feel guilty over
are frankly autonomous.
Autonomous.
They happen of their own nature.
Just like a seed opens up
in sprouts of its own nature
when it's time for it to do so.
So there's no point of hovering over it,
trying to hurry it up,
or trying to slow it down.
In its own due time,
which is karmically determined,
including when you leave
this world.
And when you leave this world,
we've done this before,
let's just do it again.
From the moment of birth on,
of when you leave this world,
it's already preset.
We're worrying about dying
because it's already certified,
signed, sealed, delivered, and stamped.
Does that mean
you should be careless,
go out and get drunk,
and drive at 150 miles an hour
down the speedway,
trying to disprove it?
No, because it was destined
that you would get drunk,
drive 150 miles down the speedway,
and turn your car over.
Once in a while,
I get an inquiry by email.
If the time of your leaving is preset,
why bother with caution?
Why bother with safety
if it's all set?
That's fatalism,
something different.
Anyway,
stop trying to make it logical.
All we know is that
every time we pass this over the years,
the wind of your leaving
is preset.
It's been preset
since the beginning of time.
Wow.
Preset since the beginning of time.
The time you leave this earth
is preset since the beginning of time.
Resist.
Therefore,
it's because each one of us
is part of God's creation.
From the beginning of all time,
the beginning of creation,
there's not a then and a now.
In the infinite world
of consciousness,
all places are here.
All time is now.
There is nothing like then
and now.
Everything is now.
In an infinite field of consciousness,
there's no here or there.
Every place is equally the center.
Every place is equally here.
Any point in time
is now.
As you can see,
when you're dealing with infinity,
all the usual logic of thought
is thrown out the window.
All time is now.
When you get crazy,
and everybody gets crazy,
anybody here thinks they don't get crazy
periodically?
Come on.
Gotta be a nut job out there somewhere.
Hiding in your seat will do no good.
I know you're out there.
Speak sanely to yourself
in the mirror.
I look at myself in the mirror.
I can vaguely see myself anymore.
I see some older, I say,
God, you're looking like,
you're starting to look like an old duck or something.
My hair's getting thin on top, for God's sake.
That's all I can see.
It's this fuzzy grayness.
It seems to be getting bald up here.
I couldn't see it before.
There's one bathroom that has light over it.
The first time I looked at it,
I said, my God, he's losing his hair
on the top of his bloody head.
I was shocked to see that.
I still had the image
of when I was in the 30s or something.
Big mop of hair, you know.
Everybody had moppy hair in those days.
Speak sanely to yourself
in the mirror.
Give yourself a lecture
and be kind to yourself
and realize that you are crazier
than a loon
and stupider than hell.
The truth, buddy,
is that you are a nut job
and you're not too bright
and how God tolerates your existence
in the universe
is simply the consequence
that he created you.
I know God can't throw me out the window
because I'm his handiwork.
Right about face, right about face.
Oh, in the winning circle,
there I am in the winning circle
talking to myself in the mirror.
And the other thing,
as I've said earlier in these things,
always have a counselor,
a confidant,
a therapist,
a psychologist,
a best friend,
people that you can rely on,
a great spouse.
A great spouse.
As you notice,
I'm a great person.
Okay, what happens next
because I turned it over to you
at this point.