Well, I suppose I should be happy that I'm back again, but the one thing that you got
to be happy about is something else, one damn happy thing after another.
Can't even be miserable anymore.
People say, how can I get over being miserable?
I say, don't get over it, just be happy, learn how to love being miserable.
Lots of people do.
Oh, it's just horrible.
Then you agree with them, you're right.
You're right.
It is horrible.
All right, so we're talking about the roads to happiness.
If you stop and examine yourself, you begin to wonder what are your goals.
If you don't know what your goals are, it's fun to just sit down and write them down.
What are my goals in this life?
How many people here know what their goals are in this life?
How many people have written them down?
Written them down?
Oh boy, oh boy.
Just to make them more conscious, you actually write them down.
My goal in this life is, boom, and then you can prioritize them.
Of course, one good goal is to be happy no matter what happens.
Then if you win, you say, hooray, I won, and then if you lose, you say, thank God, I lost.
We'll come up with some of the reasons for that later in this list.
Sometimes it's much better.
Sometimes it's much better to lose.
Anyway, being rich and famous seems to be an obsession with the television industry.
Rich and famous is what they feed on.
Rich and famous.
So how to differentiate the flimsy ones such as rich and famous from mature goals?
Be pleased with the direction you're going instead of where you are with it.
Be pleased with the direction, your alignment.
So instead of saying, I won't be happy until I reach there,
or I won't be happy until I have $84,000 saved up,
just be happy that you are in the direction of trying to be thrifty
and think about your older age and provide for it, whatever.
So be happy that you are in a certain direction.
And of course, spiritual work, that is very much so,
because there's no way you can actually really tell where you're at
in your spiritual evolution.
But to be happy with the fact that your direction is to achieve enlightenment
or salvation, to bring about good for others and happiness to others.
So be happy with the things that you have assigned a value to,
to be friendlies.
To be friendly and cheerful, to be uplifting to others.
And I've always tried to be uplifting to others.
When people are depressed, I clown around them and get them to laugh
and make life as easy as you can for other people.
And so be pleased with the direction that you have chosen for yourself.
It's the direction you're in and not how far you are along the path.
The fact that you're on the path is what's significant.
How far you are.
Of course, as anybody's guess.
So we're talking about practical reality versus fantasy.
And of course, we know that these symbols of Hollywood success
and TV star success are, you know, symbolic.
And that it actually has to do with we project value onto it.
And that energy, as described by Alice Bailey, is called glamour.
So it isn't that that person...
has that.
It's that you have projected desirability onto that.
You have projected desirability onto that.
In and of itself, it has no attraction.
You say, is that true?
Yeah.
Nothing in this world has any attraction
unless you project attractiveness to it.
It's that attribute that you have projected onto it
that...
that makes it desirable.
So you're like a dog chasing its tail.
You're like a dog...
So most people in the world are like dogs chasing their tails.
They have decided that that is success.
My dog does it all the time.
It's so funny.
She starts to chase her tail.
She all of a sudden, you see her go...
I said, why are you chasing your tail?
She goes, Kelsey, stop chasing your tail.
For a minute, she thought it was something out there.
But it's not out there.
It's just me I'm chasing.
Oh, it was more fun when I thought
it was something out there.
It's not out there.
It's in you.
So chasing your tail, then, is because you've
projected wonderment upon that.
Thing is to pursue a thing because that is what you are.
If you're studious, then being a studious person
is what you are.
What you are.
And the thing is to enjoy.
Enjoy the process.
Enjoy the process of life.
Enjoy the various stages of life.
It's fun to be a kid.
It's exciting to be an adolescent.
It's great to be a young adult.
Middle age has a lot of wonderful things about it.
Older age is self-rewarding.
You're too old to give a rap about it anymore.
But other people worry about it.
I'm dying for you.
Say, yep, I remember when I used to think that way.
Yep, yep.
So you joined the yep generation.
Yep.
Having a million bucks.
Yep, I remember when that was a big deal.
OK.
So in other words, what's happening
is due to your own choice and your own decision.
That puts you back in control.
Puts you back in control to realize that where you are is
the result of your own decision.
It's not just an accident.
You choose and decide.
You've chosen and decided to go in this direction.
That way you don't end up blaming it on other people.
Because no matter which way you go, there are risks involved.
Is that not so?
Even if you decide to stay home and sit in your chair
and not go anywhere, you will then become decrepit.
Decrepit, right.
All right, move on to the next.
We've got 101.
We've got to move along.
To be flexible versus rigid.
To be flexible, like the reed that bends in the wind.
The reed, the current.
So the reed that bends with the current is flexible.
The one which is stiff and inflexible
is broken by the current.
So that's an old Taoist teaching.
That's an old Taoist teaching.
To be flexible and to bend with the wind
and to bend with the current rather than break.
To be able to change, to switch roles.
You can also see your life as a sequence of roles.
You are not only what you are, but you
are fulfilling a certain social role.
The parent or the child, those are all roles.
And then we learn not to be flexible.
We have to put happiness dependent on anything.
I'll be happy if I get an A in this thing.
All right, so you have to cancel and then I'll be happy.
And so that your happiness is not
provisional about anything, except the direction
that you're going.
You see, I'm going in this direction.
I'm choosing spiritual evolution as a lifestyle.
It gives my life meaning and greater significance
in serving God in every way that I can.
One way to serve God is by being happy.
God's will for you is happiness.
And therefore, to be happy,
it's sort of just a style of languaging,
is pleasing to God.
There's this.
Oh!
So God's demand is that you be happy.
Anybody here refuse to be happy?
Nobody wants to go to the lower places?
So being happy is fulfilling your human potential.
And we're created in that style by Almighty God.
So make the happiness independent of phenomena.
Therefore, you don't have to clutch and grasp at things.
Clutching and grasping at things, then,
is a good way to lose them.
Clarify your goals and your ideals.
And I'm surprised how many people here
raised their hands that they have actually sat down
and listed what their goals are and prioritized them.
And, of course, in actual life,
we're doing that all the time, but it's unconscious.
We're choosing and choosing one goal over another,
constantly.
But to make them conscious and intellectually aware
is of great value.
Realize that all value that you attribute to anything
is arbitrary.
Because you value it doesn't mean that it is.
It just means that you value it.
The only value that I would say is independent of personal opinion
is the scale of consciousness.
The scale of consciousness indicates
on a mathematical, arithmetic level,
value when looked at from the viewpoint of consciousness itself.
But many people would disregard that as of any value.
So even that which is a confirmatory value
would not be valuable in another person's eyes.
Honesty and integrity.
Well, in our culture, honesty and integrity are virtues.
There are other cultures in which honesty,
and integrity is idiotic and stupid.
On the other side of the world,
if the price of this object is $6,
and you sell it for $6,
they can see you an idiot.
Honesty and integrity,
in a different culture,
is considered stupidity.
Now, how do you accommodate yourself to a culture
that thinks that truth, honesty, etc.
is a defect?
Ha, ha, ha.
It's a little hard to figure how you're going to accommodate
to something that is diametrically opposed
to your own set of values.
Mm-hmm.
Clarify goals and ideals.
Realize that all value is arbitrary.
There are huge cultures in which
honesty is considered stupidity.
Ha, ha, ha.
Honesty is stupidity.
Yes.
Happiness is,
uh, a nap on a train or a plane.
Oh, ha, ha, ha, ha.
I just thought I'd put some quickies in there.
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
Ha, ha, ha.
You put up your feet and have a quick nap,
and you're happy no matter where you are.
Okay.
Yeah, okay.
All right.
We've got 101 to go.
We better move along.
Live one day at a time.
So, the 12-step,
the 12-step program
is one of the greatest sources of happiness.
People who practice the 12-step program
are happier than other people,
and you can even calibrate them
that they are actually happier.
They actually live in the 500s.
And one of the axioms
is to live one day at a time.
Is that rational?
Well, yesterday's gone forever,
so it has no reality.
Tomorrow isn't here yet,
So, the only thing that's really real
is what's right now.
So, living one day at a time,
is a very important part
of the 12-step program.
So, the 12-step program
calibrates around 570,
and it's higher than any other
pathway currently available.
So, be lucky if,
you're lucky if you have something
that requires you to go to
and join the 12-step program.
If you haven't got a problem,
you better go get one
so you can go there.
So, you can live one day at a time.
No matter what comes up,
I say, well, that was yesterday.
And yesterday, I thought,
what will I talk about tomorrow
at the lecture?
And I said, well, I'll worry about that
when tomorrow gets here.
Happiness is a cat's purr
or a dog's wagging tail.
We calibrated them at 500 and something.
A cat's purr.
It's hard to be angry, upset,
and self-pity
when a kitty's purring in your arm.
You get this kitty,
and she's going,
purr, purr, purr, purr.
I have a cat at home.
I paid 50 bucks for this cat.
It's my $50 cat.
Named Bootsy.
So, no matter what I do,
Bootsy wants to participate.
Well, I have to do the checkbook,
balance the checkbook at home.
And he loves the checkbook.
The minute I get it out,
he claims the checkbook to be his.
It's hard to feel unhappy.
I say, give me back my checkbook.
Happiness is a cat's purr.
There's nothing nicer than hearing kitties purring.
And sometimes I come home,
and there's all three kitties sitting around.
All three of them are purring.
Purr, purr, purr, purr, purr, purr, purr.
No, no, no.
It's like you get,
all three of them purring.
And when the three of them are there purring,
in the meantime,
down on the kitchen floor,
the dog's tail is wagging.
Now, it's very hard to be unhappy.
Three kitties purring at once,
and the dog wagging his tail.
The only thing that makes you happy,
is your wife's voice comes over and says,
dinner's ready.
Now you've got the ultimate happiness.
Dinner's ready,
the cats are purring,
and the dog's tail is wagging.
Who could want for anything more, right?
Another source of happiness,
is faith versus skepticism.
Skepticism is a narcissistic position,
and faith is a much higher position.
So, faith, of course the person who is a skeptic,
at the same time, idiotically doesn't realize,
it isn't his skepticism,
it's his faith in his skepticism that's keeping him alive.
He thinks skepticism will lead me to the truth and happiness,
and that's why he's a skeptic.
But it's his faith in his skepticism,
that gives him that feeling.
Isn't that paradoxically funny?
Now, if he was skeptical about his skepticism,
he'd be making progress.
I don't think too much of skepticism is the road to happiness.
I'm skeptical about it.
And I have faith that my skepticism,
a lot of skepticism,
will lead me to happiness.
So we learn to be grateful for what we have and what we have become.
Grateful for what we have and for what we have become.
You know, people say,
are you grateful that you're older?
Well, I'm not.
I'm grateful for my family.
I'm grateful for my friends.
And I say, well, considering the alternative,
very good indeed.
Yeah.
Maurice Chevalier.
Gratitude for what one has and what you have become.
What we've learned is a result of all the effort we put in.
We've traveled all those miles through life
to become what we are at this moment.
So we're the product of the past.
So we can build upon the past,
and we're also attracted by the future.
So here we are in no man's land between the past,
which is over,
and the future,
which isn't here yet.
Don't you see?
You live in a complete vacuum.
The past is over.
The future isn't here yet.
Though the only place you can exist is in this present moment.
So the only thing you have to worry about
is this present moment.
This present moment.
Detached versus craving.
It means if it happens, it's terrific,
and if it doesn't, it's okay.
The capacity to become detached is a learned technique.
Everybody should practice becoming detached
from something you think you just have to have to be happy.
Pick something arbitrarily and start becoming detached from it.
You say, well,
if I become detached from it,
then I won't get it, will I?
So the person wants to become detached
and still be attached.
That's a sneaky trick,
and I won't let you get away with it.
Detached means if it happens, great,
and if it doesn't happen, fine.
One way or the other, it's all the same.
Why?
Because that which I am in reality
is not going to be affected one way or the other.
I've either learned how to derive happiness
from my own existence, or I haven't.
And if I haven't learned how to derive happiness
from my own existence,
then what could possibly make me happier?
If I can't be happy worth this much,
how will I be happier if I'm worth twice as much?
So gratitude for what one has and is,
what you have become.
Anybody sitting in this audience
is obviously in a good place.
They should be grateful for what one has,
for what they have become.
Because the searching after truth
and all of its expressions
is one of the most advanced states of consciousness there is.
To seek truth for its own sake
and to go wherever one has to go
to learn truth is therefore a great goal.
Gratitude that you're even interested
in integrity and truth.
You realize that about 98% of the world
is not interested in truth.
One time we did an arm on that.
The number of people who are interested in enlightenment,
if you stop them on the street,
it's less than 1 in 10 million.
If you stop everybody on the street,
after 10 million people you'll find one person.
My ultimate goal in this lifetime is enlightenment.
Let's see if that's changed.
That's still the same.
Resist.
Desiring enlightenment
are 1 in 10 million on the street.
The Buddha said,
rare it is,
great good karma
to have heard of enlightenment.
The first great good karma
is that you have heard of enlightenment.
The second is that you decide to pursue it.
Having heard of it,
you decide to pursue it.
And rarest of all
is to pursue it
and achieve it.
So the Buddha said, therefore,
that you in this audience
are rare indeed
in good karma.
Everybody in this audience
has good karma.
Resist.
Okay.
Oh, happy, happy Buddha.
Buddha says, my God, they heard me.
Oh, fortunate is the Buddha
who has followers to listen to him.
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
Isn't that, this is like,
it's the Buddha that's happy.
It's that Buddha that's lucky.
How many Buddhas have people
who pay any attention to him?
That's what I always say.
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
Yeah, I like the Buddha.
Gratitude for what one has and is.
Detachment versus craving.
So to become enlightenment,
enlightenment is the releasing
of attachments and aversions
and therefore of cravings.
So the entrapment into the body
which initiates through the senses
in the beginning.
Enlightenment means becoming detached
to letting go of craving.
To letting go.
If it happens, it happens
and I will enjoy it.
And if it doesn't,
then I'll be doing something else.
If I'm not doing this this morning,
then I would be doing something else this morning.
I could be home,
and the kitties could be purring,
and the dog wagging his tail.
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
Detached versus craving.
Craving is always putting a desiringness.
Craving is always wanting something
that you have glamorized
and said,
that will make me happy.
The whole attitude of life is,
is the glass half full
or is it half empty?
Optimism or pessimism?
Optimism.
Optimism and pessimism.
Is the glass half full
or half empty?
So there we're saying how
your perception of life,
how you contextualize it.
Is it half full or half empty?
Oh,
it's half full because it's half empty.
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
I got it both ways.
First time in history
anybody won that one conundrum.
It's half full because
it's half empty, idiot.
It's half empty because it's half full.
Isn't that easy?
It took me to come along and solve
that conundrum.
I don't know how the world survived without it.
Ha, ha, ha.
Detached means if I find the answer
to something that's terrific
and I have to let go of the craving
for knowing the answer.
When you start getting,
investigating, researching truth
and its various expressions,
this can be for you
where you begin to
uh,
you have to know the answer
to this one.
And you drive your spouse crazy.
In the morning
I'll come in the other end
and she can tell I'm coming.
I'll say, honey, could I have your arm one second?
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
I just have to know
what such and such calibrates that.
I just have to know, you know.
I just have to know.
Of course I don't have to know.
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
All right, so I realize
it's not a have to, it's a want to.
Want to. Intellectual curiosity.
Of course, intellectual curiosity
is what drove the whole renaissance.
The great books of the Western world.
So a great deal of wisdom
comes out of that.
Uh, it's sort of
a positive curiosity.
The optimist thinks
that increasing one's
consciousness level will increase
one's happiness.
And that's optimistic
but also fulfillable.
And in order to do that
we choose spiritual versus
material goals.
Why? Because spiritual goals are
cannot be lost.
Spiritual goals are
valuable beyond all time.
And beyond the physical.
Material goals come and go.
The morning you get up and you turn on
the Rasmussen Report
or what is that one?
Something report. Tells you
where you lost money yesterday.
Well yesterday it had all these famous people
that are multi-millionaires.
And how much they lost.
They all lost 25% of their money.
And anyway, that won't affect
their happiness because the capacity
to make more money is there.
So it's the capacity then,
the capacity and not the thing itself.
Spiritual versus material goals.
Now these are the things
of the world.
The things that we surrender
to the world.
And these are the things
that we surrender to God.
Surrender those things of the world
to mammon
and that which is
of spiritual to God.
And not confuse the two.
Surrender that which is God's
to God and that which is material
to mammon.
The Bible says.
Okay, next thing.
The surrendering
to God's will
is a sophisticated
understanding that
really evolves
with your own level of consciousness.
As your own level
of consciousness evolves,
the understanding of God's
will becomes
progressive.
And can't really be described
verbatim as it progresses.
And when you're a kid
you think God's will is that you go to church.
You don't use
certain bad words
and various things.
So your understanding of what is God's will
evolves
over the decades.
And finally becomes almost
you can't really explain it.
It's more contextualized.
A contextualized knowingness.
A knowingness
that at this moment
in this instant
in this evolution
that this is the way to go
rather than this way.
So a certain knowingness
evolves
and we call it wisdom.
A certain spiritual wisdom.
To surrender to God's will
then brings about
an evolution of one's wisdom.
Is it God's will that I
take up arms and fight?
Or is it God's will that I surrender?
Whether to take up arms
against the slings and arrows
of outrageous fortune
or battle them.
So this is really
a conflict of
not a conflict but a conundrum
which is permanent.
In all the evolutionary phases
of life
what does it mean to surrender to God's will
at that point?
For some people to surrender to God's will
means to obey
the command and shoot
the enemy.
For another person to surrender to God's will
means I cannot kill another human
under any circumstance.
So what is God's will?
If you're 18
and you're in the Navy
and they say shoot them
God's will is that you shoot them.
If you're 82
and they say shoot them
you say I'm not going to shoot them.
So what is God's will?
It means for you
at this time in this context
so truth cannot be
defined unless
you define it within the context.
In what circumstances
is it?
Is it evil to do this
or not to do that?
To retrospectively make things
that were done under threat of war
illegal
is like an outrage to
this violation
of God's will
because what's truth
and what's God's will
truth is dependent
on circumstance
on context.
What's true in this context
is a lie in this context.
And fulfilling your obligation
to mankind and God here
is a violation of it there.
So this is
where spiritual evolution
leads to progressive
sophistication.
What is God's will for you
at this moment
in these circumstances?
If you were older then
it would be different.
If you were younger it would be different.
But you're not older and you're not younger
you're who you are right at this moment.
What is the highest
thing that you can do?
Serve your country
or become a conscientious
objector.
You know I practiced psychiatry
for many years, 50 years
and I forget what war it was, Vietnam I guess.
Lots of people wanted to
had to be seen by me and
whether they were
capable, etc.
And the question I always
was run up against was
if you don't want to go
to Vietnam and kill anybody
I'd say well you can
you got two options.
You can move to Canada
or you can just become a conscientious objector.
Just be a conscientious objector.
And that solved it.
So you don't have to be
anti something.
You can find a livable
space in which you can live.
You can serve your country
and be a conscientious objector
and you can work in the stock room
you don't have to shoot people
so right now I'd say
no I can't shoot people now
it's just don't work out for me.
Can't stand all the noise.
I'll lead a prayer group
in the back while you folks
go ahead and do the shooting part.
When you're done shooting
let me know.
The capacity to let go then
is freedom.
Capacity to surrender to God's will
increases the capacity
to let go.
To let go is
progressively more and more easy.
Can you let go of anything?
Eventually you reach the point
where you can really let go of anything.
I mean let go seriously.
You can overlook things
you can skip things
but a very serious let go
meaning really let go
becomes progressively easier.
Which is
very nice
that it is that way.
Surrender to God's will then
is the capacity to let go
and when we
is
we surrender our love
our self to God
out of love for God
and therefore the capacity to let go
is almost infinite.
If people say I can't do a thing
I'd say
you can't let go of it.
I'd say now if I hold the gun to your head
and if you don't let go
I'm going to blow your brains out.
Suddenly they can let go.
So you understand letting go
anything you think you're caught with
and you can't let go of it
you picture a gun at your head
and ask yourself
now can you let go of it?
Anybody stuck on something
they can't let go of?
Honey did I bring the gun this morning or not?
If we hold the gun to your head
it's amazing you can let go of anything.
Alright so
you be pleased with your own progress
the capacity to let go is there
it isn't can you
it's will you.
So it's a matter of the human will.
You say I can't let go of it
the minute you hear yourself saying
I can't let go of that
tell yourself the truth is
I won't let go of it.
Okay you won't let go of it
that puts it in a different domain
because something you can't let go of today
you may be able to a week from now
a year from now or a decade
a decade from now
it's easy to let go.
Being a movie star is hard to let go of
as an adolescent fantasy.
But by 80 you've gotten over it.
So I'm pleased with my progress
I don't have to want to be Clark Gable anymore.
Clark Gable was our hero
when I grew up you know
if you could only be Clark Gable
so you don't have to be Clark Gable now
to be happy.
And you avoid self-judgment
now we said the self-judgment
is the internalized parent
you see there's the child in you
there's the child
and then judgmentalism
is the inner parent
the super ego
is constantly judging everything you do
how to handle that inner judge
all the time
so the child
if you want to enjoy life
the child has to stay alive
you have to have a child
it's handy
child come here
I have to sit on my child all the time
the child wants to take over everything
they're not going to take you seriously
if you're so childish
you're right you're right yes
I must be serious
and dignified
I did it
whew
that takes care of the kids
having your inner kid alive and well
is part of happiness
so that you can sit on the kid
periodically
when he's in the street car
or something
I used to go with my younger sister
and I'd have to be with her
on the street car
I was like 10 or 11
and she was like 7 or something
so I'd say now you sit next to your brother
so she'd be very good
and we'd get on the street car
and she'd be sitting next to me
and next thing you know
she'd start wandering down the aisle
of the street car
then she's running up and down the aisle
laughing and giggling and running up and down
and I'd pretend I didn't know her
I would shrink down with shame and embarrassment
laughs
yeah
so she was being bad
and I was being good
so to me
being good was the way to happiness
and for her doing
what the hell she wanted
was her way to happiness
laughs
see I can't wait to see my sister again
on the other side
she was adorable
just loved her to pieces
but she loved being bad
laughs
why was it bad
because it was on the street car
and my mother said
you're supposed to sit in your seats
and not run up and down the aisle
in the street car
made it good or bad
alright therefore
our human values
to win is provisional
what do you mean by win
you know many times we see people
seeing something that to them is a win
and we see it as a loss
or vice versa
so what is a win
is how you define it
how you contextualize it
whether it's a win or a loss
is dependent upon the circumstances
simplicity versus
complexity
that which is really super complex
is harder to achieve
than that which is simple
therefore one way
to make life behave better
is to take something
that is staggeringly complex
and boil it down to its inner
inner principles
simplicity out of complexity
if a thing is too complex
it just can't be handled
and it gets discarded
discarded
that's all
and that's why
I'm constantly
thinking about
the language
algebra
a good friend of mine
is struggling through
college algebra
and he's like
oh god
it's your karma
well
you know
struggling through
college algebra
I gotta say
that is really
maybe one of the maximum
things you gotta live through
but it's sort of
a rite of passage
it isn't until you complete
There isn't anything good to know
that algebra can serve you in today's life.
You've got a computer that'll do it that fast.
You haven't even written it down to start figuring it out,
and the computer's got it already.
What are you going to do with college algebra?
Well, it's a rite of passage.
It's a rite of passage.
You just can't get there without doing college algebra.
And instantly you get sympathy from everybody.
Say, what are you doing tonight?
He said, I'm studying college algebra.
And you all go, oh, geez.
Let me give you a piece of pie to take home something
to make up for having to study college algebra all night.
It's a rite of passage,
and of course it's out in the limits of usefulness.
Any computer can do it in a one-thousandth of a second.
What takes you all?
Well, the evening computer can do it in no time at all.
So life moves on from complexity to simplicity.
So that which was undoable through complexity
is now doable through simplicity.
So we try to simplify life's problems.
Okay, let's move on to the next.
Realistic expectations of life and of others and of events.
What can you realistically expect?
If you're going to be interested in politics,
you've got to modify your expectations.
If you expect honesty and integrity and all that, forget it.
Just get realistic.
You're in a different world with different values.
Now, the thing is you cannot judge their world by your world.
And I've had to struggle through that myself.
Their world is not your world.
In their world, making it happen,
and if it takes a few bucks here and a few bucks there,
it's not your world.
It's not your world.
If it takes a few bucks there and lying here and testifying falsely,
that's what their game is about.
You can't use your rules and put it in their domain
because in their domain, you would be an idiot.
So values then are contextual,
depend on who you are and where you are in life.
And therefore, we can't judge others.
Value is in the eye of the beholder.
What you think of is the eye of the beholder.
What you think is valuable is what's valuable.
You have to give up your skepticism.
As we said, you can be skeptical about anything except you're skeptical.
Your skepticism, in a sense.
And a sense of humor serves you in all of these.
101 ways to be happy.
All of them are enhanced by a sense of humor.
A sense of humor.
Accept karmic propensity.
Many things are karmic.
This means a propensity, a tendency.
It's not cause and effect, but a likelihood.
And when we investigated it with consciousness research,
there is a high likelihood.
If you have a lot of negative karma,
it isn't that the negative karma causes the earthquake to happen just where you live,
but because you have that karma, you happen to be there.
So it's a propensity, not a causality.
Karma doesn't cause.
It doesn't cause anything.
But the likelihood of certain things happening is certainly being enhanced.
See essence rather than perception.
That was the wolf in sheep's clothing.
Be jocular instead of morose.
Jocular instead of morose.
What's 41?
Good will regarding all of life.
And this is the one that pays off the most.
Good will regarding all of life makes all of us happy.
Good will regarding all of life makes all of the rest of these easier.
All you need is that one and a hundred other ways to be happy come about.
If somebody ate your hamburger when you went to the man's room,
you'd say, well, I guess he was hungry and didn't have any money.
Good will regarding all of life makes all of them easier.
To be easygoing, uplifting, easygoing versus rigid.
And you can do that by reducing expectations of others.
If you don't expect anything of them at all, you're never disappointed.
If somebody's integrous, honest, intelligent, and educated, I fall over.
Oh.
Reduce your expectations of others.
And I've mentioned before that if you have good will towards all of life,
you'll see what a...
an effect you have on people.
And I always say, when you're in a store and they ring you up on the cash register,
you thank them very much.
You say, thank you a lot for racking that all up.
And they'll go, huh?
They do it hundreds of times before somebody says, thank you for ringing that up.
Reduce your expectations of others.
Be generous instead of stingy.
Generous with what?
Generous with yourself.
Not generous with...
one thing or another.
Generosity is an attitude towards life.
A givingness.
A nurturance.
You're generous towards all of life.
You walk through the woods and you say,
my God, these trees are magnificent and beautiful.
Now, I love the trees in the woods.
I adore them.
Now, let's see.
Our person asks this.
The trees in the woods are...
know that I'm glad and love them.
The trees...
in the woods know that you love them.
All of life falls down before that which is loving and reflects God's love.
Okay, the woods, the trees are literally aware of your lovingness of them.
Resist.
All of life then responds to what you...
not what you have, not what you do, not what you say,
but what you have become.
What affects?
The whole world.
People say, what can I do to save the world?
I say, stay out of the way.
Stay home.
Stay out of the way.
Keep away from parades and demonstrations.
You have...
So, all of us affect the consciousness level of the world.
What can you do to bring about world peace?
I say, avoid peace marches.
Instead, become as generous and loving as you can towards all of life in all its regard.
So, as you step over the little bug, instead of stomping it,
you have not done more for the world than parading around with banners.
What you...
The way you affect what all of life is about
is by the virtue of what you are.
What you are.
What you have become.
Not what you say, not what you do.
All of that's trivial.
Okay, I'm getting threats.
Uh, uh, could I have a hand on that, Loewen?
Do we stop here for now?
Tell them what, what, how long.
We'll resume at two o'clock.
You tell them that.
We'll be taking a lunch break and we'll be resuming at two o'clock.
That's good.
I can hear it now.
All good things come to he who waits.
I'm sure waiting.
Are we ready to resume?
Yes.
Okay, then what we need is the excitement of the upcoming slides.
Uh, you'll have to wait a minute because I don't know if Janice is here.
All right.
In that case, we'll talk about a good karma savings account.
Now, everyone needs a good karma savings account.
So, when you do something that the world considers good,
uh, you don't expect an immediate reward.
You can be, uh, saintly and have all kinds of horrible things happen to you.
Because, uh, because of the goodness,
you, you've brought up the privilege of, um, owning the negative, the bad karma.
You can see that you rise above your good karma and then that brings up the bad karma.
So, if bad things are happening to you, you thank God that I've got the good karma,
to bring up that bad karma, to work it through.
That's right.
My thumb karma is settled.
Everybody needs a good karma savings account.
A good karma savings account.
And when you need it, it's there for you.
Let's ask the arm.
That's a fact.
Resist.
Many, uh, things that were totally beyond the expectation or even possible,
or even a possibility, happened under very strange circumstances in my life.
I can remember being a million miles from nowhere in a strange country where I didn't know a soul.
And I got my old truck and the truck, all of a sudden, it broke down.
There I'm a million miles, nobody, uh, within sight.
And I'm sitting there with this truck and I think there was something missing.
I couldn't take the tire off anyway.
Anyway, so I sat there.
Hmm.
What should I do?
All of a sudden, the car peers out of the distance and it was an old buddy from back east.
An old buddy from back east just happened to drive on this deserted highway
and find me, the only person along this way for miles,
broken down with the need for help with my truck.
Another time, I broke down on a clover leaf.
And I was due at the airport, I think, someplace important.
And the car, and, and,
and it drove, you know, it was the same old truck, broke down on a clover leaf.
My good karma truck.
So, it broke down on a clover leaf.
So, here's all these cars whizzing by you like this.
And here I'm in this old truck stuck over to the side, you know.
All of a sudden, the car pulled over.
I think it was a pickup truck.
Guy gets out and he says to me, I see you're broken down and you got a spare.
I said, no, I'll have to get this one fixed.
He says, I'll help you.
He took the, he did the thing, took the tire off, put it in the back of his pickup truck.
He says, I'll be back.
He went down this clover leaf all the way up and all the way down and all the way back around again.
And went off down and got, oh, here, went to a filling station and got the, got the tire fixed.
Then he came all the way back through the clover leaf and all the way back, all the way back this way.
And all the way back, and he pulled up next to me and he put it on the truck for me.
Complete, total stranger.
I thought, my God, what is that?
And he says, thanks, thanks.
And I said, thank you.
God bless you.
And that was the end of it.
All right.
That was my good karma savings account.
And then I learned something else too.
There are angels in bodies.
Some residents of this domain are angelic, are actually angels and have taken on a human energy fuel for purpose.
I don't know if you've heard of it.
Okay.
Anyway, those things, those are things that having a positive karma savings account, I mean, it was unthinkable.
A million miles from nowhere and nobody even knew I was in Arizona.
And here's an old friend from back, he pulls right up, right next to my car and says, can I help you and takes the tire off for me.
In the middle of a clover leaf with all these millions of cars going by, this guy comes in, picks it up, takes it down, goes all the way around.
As it's fixed, comes over.
the way back around and picks me up again. I mean, that's inexplicable by logic, by any kind
of logic. So the good that you do to others, don't look for a reward. Just give this as a gift to
God. So what I do, I do for you out of my love for God. And then later on, it comes back to you
in some unforeseen and non-logical connection, you know. And so we serve others to the best of
our ability, and we surrender that to God. Yes. All right. Now, are we going to show the slides?
Are they going to? I put a quarter in the slot before. There it is. Okay.
I had a thingy here. Here it is. All right. What was on that card? I didn't want to forget.
Yeah. Oh, no. Okay. All right. So I just wanted to put that one in there. That wasn't on the list.
Accumulate good karma. All right. Goodwill regarding all of life. To be of goodwill to
all of life, then is noticed by all of life. You think it's not noticed, it's noticed.
And that builds up your positive karma bank. To be loving towards all the trees,
to be loving.
towards the bugs, to be of goodwill towards all that exists, to have an easygoing attitude
instead of rigid. It doesn't have to be your way or no way. It's just easygoing means being
flexible, and things are not always going to go the way you go, so you'd be willing to
change. To be generous instead of stingy. Generous of what? Generosity is an attitude. It's not
monetary. It can take a monetary expression, but generosity is an attitude. Generous towards all
of life. Generous in your expectations. Thanking people for being of service
at the church.
Checkout counter at the supermarket. You say, thank you for running that up. Thank you for
running that. A lot of times, if you do that, you'll see their mouth drops. They say, what?
Thank you for totaling that all up. Oh, okay. Generous instead of stingy.
Modify the inner voice so that it reflects your spiritual attitudes. You know, you go inside to
your inner thoughts, and you talk to your inner thoughts until you've gotten,
your inner voice to be reflective of your spiritual commitment and intention. To be
gracious to self and others. Be gracious. That's part of generosity. To be gracious to yourself
and others. Well, we often remember to be gracious to others, but here's where we, most of us,
be gracious to yourself. I thank you, Lord, for my existence and all the wondrous and
wonderful things that have happened to me and the wonderful people I've met. So you be gracious to
yourself. Gracious to others. That, everybody learns sooner or later. But gracious to yourself
takes quite a while to learn because the self tends to be critical. The inner parent says to
you, naughty, naughty, bad, bad, you were no good. How can you be gracious to yourself, then,
is to have a more easygoing conscience.
More easygoing conscience that understands your humanness. Your humanness. If you were perfect,
you wouldn't be here. So part of perfection is correcting an overly strict superego. The
first thing, it's one of the first things my psychoanalyst said to me, you know, is laying on the couch.
He says, number one, you've got to have thicker skin. Not be so sensitive to what others say. And secondly,
you've got to be more forgiving to yourself, because I had a very rigid superego.
Rigid superego. What do they call that? Scrupulosity. So the reason I went in, one of the
reasons I went into psychoanalysis was scrupulosity. And as a child, I had counseling for
scrupulosity. The sleigh, I lived in fear of the sin, that I might have committed a sin. And I was
scared to death that my skin would be broken. And so I had to have more forgiveness. And I had to have
own mind that it would think of sinful thoughts my mother would ask me to do something and i
would feel anger come up and i lived in dread of that because to be angry at your mother was a sin
so how do we have a more forgiving inner conscience that one way to have a more
forgiving inner conscience is to be aware that it's intention so the intention is what you end up
looking at not the act but the intention behind the act because an act can go wrong even though
your intention is good so you develop a more flexible easygoing loving and forgiving
so love everyone and don't forget to include yourself in that as well surrender the need
to control others the need to control and surrendering that is not necessary to control
everything that happens to you
in the world it's not necessary to control it so it's the feeling that you have to change things
that you have to control them that you have to be on top of them and you become much more easygoing
it's not necessary to control everything that happens in life because there's positive karma
that will correct many a thing yeah all you need to do is hold what you desire and value in mind
and it tends to manifest within your life
and all the places i've lived over many decades now each one of them was really the realization of
something that i'd held in mind where i live now is that i want to be near a near running water of
some kind out in the desert but also have water running trees and there i am right there i've
dropped trees and water and i'm out in the desert let go of the desire for applause
do i hear a clapping for me
oh god i have to really control this audience
you don't have to have applause for everything you do in life you don't have to have recognition
and uh doing uh good things unexpectedly for other people is so pleasing that you don't need applause
you don't need applause
and i was going to say i'm going to say i'm going to say i'm going to say i'm going to say
a kick out to somebody who stopped for a hamburger and paid for paid for the hamburgers of all the
people in cars behind them paid in advance for all of them and they all fell over when they got there
and they said somebody said it's all paid for already let go of the desire for applause okay
thank you we got to move along be glad instead of mad
some people are glad that they're mad some people are mad that they're glad
be glad instead of mad you want acceptance of what of the phenomena of life instead of resisting them
and that's the uh the reed that bends in the in the current instead of resisting it and breaking it
being flexible be generous instead of stingy generosity is its own reward it it's a comfortable
place to be so all the things that we recommend that we recommend to people that we recommend to
are subjectively experientially very comfortable each thing is its own reward that you've been
generous is pleasing and it leaves you with a higher self-esteem and be honest with yourself
and others candid meaning honest with yourself and others if you don't like them diced and you
like them sliced you know and say i really like them diced better than sliced all right
in the meantime you silence the thinking mind by my this mind mind with a small m silence the thinking mind
well that takes some decades of spiritual work before generally before the mind stops talking
the silencing the mind that's the whole course we could do just on how to silence the mind
first of all you withdraw interest from it i don't care what the mind thinks you stop calling it my
mind
i'm calling it my mind that's grandiose isn't your mind what do you think you're the first
mind that got invented on the planet it's the mind everybody's got a mind so what
the current the current uh thing in the media is everybody has to speak their mind
and they think that's a great step forward in the evolution of consciousness now this is a
right, constitutional right. So those people who live in a certain political domain think
that their duty is to express their mind. That's only a very rudimentary understanding.
Anybody can babble away and talk, and when they go and listen to the man on the street,
I don't care what the man on the street thinks. I'm the slightest interest in what the man on the
street thinks. What do I care what he thinks? He's an idiot as far as I'm concerned. He's going to
think whatever TV told him to think today. That's what he's going to think. Whatever he says, he
heard it on television yesterday. Okay, everybody feels they have to express themselves, and they
don't realize that's just, you know, narcissistic egotism. I mean, why should the world give a rap
way? Why should the world give a rap way? Why should the world give a rap way? Why should the
world give a rap way? Why should the world give a rap what you think? I don't give a rap what you
think. I don't even give a rap what I think. Why? Because the mind is autonomous, and it jumbles
along and blabbers all day long. You climb into bed, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah. You get up in
the morning, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah. You look at your teeth, blah, blah. In the meantime,
your mind's going, blah, blah, blah, blah, and you're brushing your teeth.
The mind is an idiot. Knowingness comes about non-verbally in a non-linear dimensional. Knowingness
is annoyingness without thinking about it. Knowingness is a certainty that the direction
you're going is the edge of the stage. Yes, it is. The way to silence the mind is to stop giving it
egotistical, narcissistic egosensitivity. The way to silence the mind is to stop giving it
eccentric energy. Oh, wonderful mind, I wonder what you think about this. I don't know what you
think about it. I don't want to know about it, you idiot. They go around with it. You can see
them on television. The man on the street, what does the man on the street think of this? I don't
care what the man on the street thinks. If the man on the street is thinking it, it's not worth
thinking, obviously, or the man on the street wouldn't be thinking it. Silence the mind. Give
up thinkingness.
Well, thinkingness is a whole thing in itself. And we've talked about it before, and we'll be
talking about it again in other lectures. But it is the egoistic, narcissistic, egocentric idea
that what you think is important, that you have to have a voice in everything.
How would this world get along without your advice?
How would I get through the day without knowing?
What that man on the street is thinking. I'm from Fox News. What do you think about?
Give up thinkingness. Thinkingness is a narcissistic, egocentric, naive, naive investment
in this is an energy field. Thinkingness is an energy field which can be transcended.
All right. Forgiving versus vindictive. It is a, it is,
to forgive, not defenders of grace, Rama does not have λέҡ Shopify .
it's gracious to forgive, not that it's virtuous. See,
people give in and forgiven right now because they figure it is virtuous.
So, people are giving in a forgiving I figure that it's virtuous.
The more they forgive, Am I ever a big forgiver .
the more egotistic they get? You know, boy am I ever a big forgiver
versus….
Is this is rage slash
well?
getting even. Well, it's true. There are cru았습니다 Vannmas.
that's true. It's better than getting even. Well, I shorter not talk just saying.'
that's not even that.
you don't have to get even. Don't just think like like there.
Because Karma is automatic. Karma is automatic, Rly?
So if that? That, which is evil, which is να
So that which is evil will bring about its own downfall
by virtue of its own evility.
Evilism.
You don't have to make yourself an energy field out there
to go out and correct the world.
Work on your inner traits instead of your external ones.
People work on their outer traits.
It's the inner ones that save you all the work.
You don't have to work on your external ones.
You automatically say thank you when somebody serves you with something
because you feel gratitude.
So it becomes automatic.
The small things of life.
It only takes a bone to make a dog happy.
Therefore, you can see the simplest small things of life
are really what makes the difference, isn't it?
Yeah.
The small things of life,
we think that we're not really accomplishing anything
unless it's a big deal.
Unless it's a big deal.
Unless it's a major project.
Unless you've, you know, saved the unwed mothers
or saved the poverty-stricken in India or done something.
It's the small things of life
that accumulate into a positive karmic field.
The small things of life.
And it's true.
It only takes a bone to make a dog happy.
So what does it take to make you happy?
Ask yourself, what does it take to make me happy?
Well, all it takes is a bone to make a dog happy.
Well, all it takes is a sip of soda.
A sip of soda.
It only takes a bone.
Now, there's a nice song you need to know.
Don't worry.
Be happy.
And you sing that little song in your mind.
That actually was a recorded song many years ago, I think, wasn't it?
Huh?
How does it go?
It's that little toy that was the bath that you hung on the wall, you know.
Yeah.
Here's a little song.
That's cute.
That is cute.
I didn't know that.
Don't worry.
Be happy.
It comes as a toy.
We have one.
Okay.
I won't worry.
I'll just be happy.
We have a toy that says, Don't worry.
Be happy.
Prioritize your goals.
And if you've been, if you've had a day of feeling goodwill towards all of life
and the people you've encountered and the phenomena of your life,
and you feel gratitude.
Sometimes I say,
I say, here I am in a nice warm house on a cold night.
I've got doggies.
I've got kitties.
I've got TV in the other room.
I've got my sweetheart here.
What more could I want?
Nothing.
Completely and 100% satisfied.
Spiritual values and goals.
It's the energy that they put out that they stand for.
It's their lovingness, their lovableness,
their presence.
It isn't that any of these things have to do any special thing,
but just the fact that they are.
To love and appreciate that you are,
it's what you are that contributes to the world.
It's what the doggie is that makes you feel happy.
You see a dog's wagging tail, how do you feel happy?
The dog's not really doing anything for you.
He just is.
The kitty purrs.
And what is it doing?
It just is.
What is it?
It's a kitty purring.
And you feel an inner gladness about the goodness of life.
So with spiritual evolution,
you become more and more aware of the goodness of life.
I get the intention of this audience.
I get the intention of the people who designed this auditorium.
I get the intention of the people backstage.
I get intention.
I get the intention of this wonderful lady with me.
I get the intention of the gift of these beautiful flowers.
And I get the intention of the Kleenex.
And all the things you could possibly want are here for you.
What more could you ask?
This whole world, what's the purpose of the world?
It's here for you.
That sounds egocentric.
Why is the world here?
It's here for you.
Why is this lecture going on?
It's going on for you.
Why is this auditorium here?
It's here for your comfort.
Isn't that wonderful?
The whole world is here just for you.
Now, you have to see beyond the egocentric what that means,
that it's here for you.
Out of divine intention, that which is here is here for you.
Because the divinity of all that exists shines forth.
With the constant spiritual work, you see the divinity,
the essence of all that exists,
is divinity itself.
All you're seeing is divinity in its expression as this stage,
in its expression as this talking body here,
divinity in its expression as the flowers,
divinity as a Diet Pepsi,
divinity as a wonderful wife,
divinity as a Kleenex.
Why do you have a Kleenex available?
Because God wants you to have a Kleenex available.
Why else?
If God didn't want you to have a Kleenex,
there wouldn't be any Kleenexes.
Didn't pass the Kleenex test.
Happiness is therefore a goal.
What?
Oh, spiritual friends and groups.
The alignment with spiritual friends and groups itself
has a positive karmic effect.
The effect of a spiritual group is very powerful.
People don't realize.
They don't realize how powerful it is.
That's well known in certain circles,
such as, for instance, Alcoholics Anonymous.
A person does very well in the energy field of AA,
which of course is 570 and over.
They do very well.
And so they say,
well, I don't need AA anymore.
I'll just go out on my own.
And next thing you know,
they're back in the bar saying,
poor me, poor me.
So the field supports you.
The field supports you.
A group like this,
as a very powerful energy field,
its intention is extremely powerful.
And the collective intention is overwhelming.
So a group like this literally affects
the consciousness level of mankind,
which sounds egoistic to the ego.
But when you realize the power of a group like this,
you see that it extends and benefits all of mankind.
This group here benefits all of mankind.
Will you have permission to ask this question?
The spiritual energy of this group here present
is positively affecting all of mankind.
So just what you have become,
what you are,
not what you do or what you have or what you own,
that which you are.
So how do you influence all of mankind
by becoming the most advanced,
spiritually advanced and aware creature that you can be?
You serve all of mankind.
Including God by being as spiritually evolved
as you are capable of being.
Yes.
And all of mankind benefits.
So you don't see yourself as wanting,
lacking or incomplete.
That which you are now is complete.
So you don't move from incomplete to complete.
You move from complete to complete to complete.
I'm completely all that I am right now.
I'm completely all that I am now right now.
I am all that I can be.
So you move from complete to complete to complete
to be sweeter, more loving,
more generous, more adoring
than I am right now.
I would be so.
Give me keys.
Give me keys, baby, yeah.
And the winner is...
From complete to complete.
Because when you have all that you could possibly want,
you don't go from incomplete to complete.
You're completely all that you can be right now.
And then maybe next year
you'll be completely all that you can be next year
with a new car.
But that's just what completion is there.
That's not what it is here
and it's not where it'll be 10 years from now.
That's part of being complete
is having what you need,
what you'd like, etc.
Go from complete to complete.
So you don't go from lack to fulfillment.
You go from fulfillment to fulfillment.
If I could be taller, handsomer, and richer,
I would be.
I'm pretty good.
Tall, dark, and handsome. Okay.
So in doing this,
you end up identifying with the self,
the large self.
Now the large self
is infinite and perfect
and beyond all time.
And it is beyond imperfection.
So you identify that this is my reality.
This is my reality.
The self with a capital S.
And this is only my temporary expression
in this domain.
The self is complete and needs nothing.
It's beyond time.
Self-fulfilling.
The presence of God
has love itself.
Without the presence of God within you,
you wouldn't exist.
Therefore,
this owes its existence
to this.
And humility is when this
self begins to acknowledge
that this is its source.
This is its source.
The infinite self
with no beginning and no end.
I remember when I fell into that state
in a snowbank once
in Wisconsin,
a million miles from nowhere in a storm.
And I shoveled the snow out of the way
to get out of the wind,
and I climbed in this hole
just to get out of the wind.
And then an infinite presence
of infinite love
with no beginning and no end
was no different than that which I am.
That which I am always existed,
will always exist.
It has no beginning and no end.
And then I began to realize
that love was eternal,
and that love was what I was.
Eternal love was my identity.
That came as a revelation
all of its own
without a single thought.
Without a single thought.
And also in that state,
you have permission to leave the world.
So I've had,
every time that's recurred,
I've had permission to leave the world
goes with it.
There is no reason further to continue
on a physical existence.
You can leave if you wish.
You have complete permission to expire.
Yeah.
Each time there was something that I was,
for the sake of the love of someone,
I declined the offer.
But it's recurred over and over.
You have permission to leave the world,
and the knowingness of the reality
of that which you are
is the presence of God within you,
complete to complete.
The Self with a capital S.
Being happy to be here
when you realize that, you know,
you could actually leave if you wanted to,
except the limitations of humanness.
Humanness.
Your protoplasm.
You've chosen to learn what can be learned
only in the world of protoplasm.
So humanness has a protoplasmic,
the karma of protoplasm.
Therefore,
humanness is a temporary condition
of protoplasmic awareness,
things that can only be learned
within the limited domain.
The word I want for it is...
Hello?
Except the limitations of humanness.
It's okay to be a human.
It's okay to be human.
And the limitations of humanness.
It's okay
to be human.
What is going on?
What's going on?
Don't pay any attention
to the man behind the screen.
Happiness is an intention.
It's an intention
that you wish to be happy
and not make it dependent on happiness.
I'll be happy if I get that car.
I'll be happy if I get that promotion.
I'll be happy if I get
a fried egg sandwich.
Happiness is an overall intention.
One way to get there
is reflection versus impulsivity.
Meditation is a wonderful
spiritual technique,
but it's limited.
It's limited.
You can't drive your car
and also be in a meditative state.
So being reflective.
Reflect versus impulsive.
So as you move through the world
and make decisions,
you become increasingly reflective
of all the nuances and the implications
and the overall spiritual context.
Thoughtful rather than critical.
You can always find something to criticize.
I had a good time criticizing the snow
and criticizing the wind.
Gee, this place is windy.
My God, it's blowing my hair off.
Critical of the weather.
I figure that's a good thing
for a human being to do.
Complain about the weather.
Too hot, it's too cold, it's too windy,
it's too breezy.
So you can enjoy the downside
of being a human
and then realize
it's not really a downside.
Any good human being
should complain about
wind blowing your hat off all the time.
Stand up for being a human.
I have come here to complain.
Brave, courageous, and honest.
I am here to complain about the weather,
here to complain about taxes.
We need a protest group for something.
Reflective rather than impulsive.
Thoughtful rather than critical.
Be content instead of complaining.
I say be content with complaining.
Why shouldn't I be complaining?
Be content.
I'm going to cross out instead of
and put with complaining.
Any human worth his soul
is going to complain.
Tell you who doesn't complain
isn't worth the bother.
If you care about life,
you'll complain about it.
One reason for complaining
is because you care about life.
If you didn't care about life,
you wouldn't complain.
You wouldn't complain about the neighborhood
if you don't live there.
So be content instead of complaining
is a goal.
And realize that life is a learning curve.
You're someplace on the curve.
You're not perfect,
nor are you completely an idiot.
Life is a learning curve.
So be willing to accept
that you are where you are.
Move on to the next.
Before I get angry and have a fit.
Hurry up.
Why aren't they moving?
What the hell is wrong with this world?
Attention, please.
Uh-oh.
Happiness is a destination and a direction.
Reflective versus impulsive.
Thoughtful rather than critical.
Be content instead of complaining.
And realize life is a learning curve.
I thank all of you who quickly prayed.
These are the spiritual techniques
that we have used.
We pray for help.
And you ask yourself,
does praying do any good?
Am I just talking to myself?
There's a gnome.
A tall gnome.
Six foot, over six foot high gnome.
He's actually a midget,
but he's a tall,
the tallest midget on the planet.
I am the shortest giant on the planet.
He's the tallest midget.
I'm the shortest giant.
Ha, ha, ha.
Praying helps a lot.
Let's see, is praying wishful thinking?
Is it, you know, grade school,
kindergarten stuff?
Let me have permission to...
Praying is beneficial.
Benefits yourself.
Benefits loved ones.
Benefits the world.
Benefits all of humanity.
Resist. Wow.
So praying is not just a
grade school exercise.
That you do.
But it's a, you know,
praying actually is an expression
of what you have become.
You've become gracious.
I think that you thank the Lord
for all the gifts of this day,
both seen and unseen.
And you ask for God's direction
in your life.
And dedicate all your actions
towards divinity
and all of its expressions.
One of its expressions is creation.
And part of creation is human,
humankind.
So pray kind of played.
Affirm God is my source.
Both my source and my inspiration
and my solution.
And you sing an inner song.
Don't worry, be happy.
Sing an inner song.
You hear a child sitting there.
Happily in their high chair.
They got mush all over their face.
Mush all over their lap.
And they're just going.
Now inside of you there is still
the inner child.
So one way to be happy is to speak
to your inner child.
And parent it.
So you go.
Hum hum.
Hum hum hum hum.
arm fout
Hum hum hum
hum hum hum hum.
They didn't get good at it.
You can teach your inner child
to hum all the time then of course the inner mother says don't be humming out like like that
in church and in the grocery store you say you learn how to hum quietly even finally your mother
says stop that people are going to think you're mental or something so you learn how to hum to
yourself without making any noise i'm still humming even when i'm talking in the back of my mind
there i'm humming firm god is my source and my solution and sing an inner song
and when if you're feeling down this is what you need you can put this on your
mirror where you put yourself together in the morning and it says yours is the saddest story
i've ever heard
you
self-pity people love self-pity instead of criticizing yourself for self-pity
enjoy it yours is the saddest story you've gone and lost your thumb for christ's sake
i'm not even ready to leave this world and the thumb is going ahead of me
i go to heaven there's the thumb waiting for me saying where have you been for god's sake i've
been waiting here for
15 minutes
45 years for you to get here that is sad poor old thumb oh yeah darn it so i can have a temper
tantrum temper tantrum and self-pity are good insist on being miserable and gloomy oh happiness
is not going to do any good anyway what what good is happiness you can be happy and get run over the
next day
you can be happy you don't pay your income tax they put you away you can be happy you go over
the speed limit they give you a ticket what's there to be happy about it's better to be miserable
and gloomy nobody will interfere with you however when things get bad number 75 now number 75 i do
with myself at home i don't see very well in here i don't see very well in here i don't see very well in
here i don't see very well in here i don't see very well in here so i
you
well okay
so that's sort of movies i just got out of honeymoon and got out of
i with my business and i got out of home to west bend um so i was heading south just to go awカ
me west bend um so i figured for about three weeks i was like oh my god oh my god who should i hear to
David. Oh, poor drapey boy. Whoa. You, you have a sad, sad story. Every year you're a year older.
Jesus Christ, what more can I say? Creeping, old age is creeping up on you. Creeping. I hear you.
I heard you creeping. All right. Make faces at yourself in the mirror. That is a very good one.
You stop taking yourself so seriously. You see all the options that open up to you,
and it's a wonderful spiritual practice. It's a spiritual technique. The holy church of the
giggles. The holy church of giggledom. The way to God through giggles. If you practice all these
things, you'll be grateful for the gift of life. Why? Because you really enjoy life. It's easy to
be grateful if you enjoy it. It's easy to be grateful if you enjoy it.
If you let your inner kid loose, if you are fearless and spontaneous, and you're loving
towards everything that you encounter throughout the day, you end up feeling grateful for the gift
of life. How else could I express my love for everyone present in this audience except by being
here? It's only by being here and jabbering away and enjoying your presence. What a wonderful time.
So to be all that you can be to everyone all the time, either physically present or not
necessarily physically present, to be all that you can be to life. If nothing else, you reflect
back to life, its beauty, that life knows that you are recognizing its beauty. And when you walk
through the woods, the woods, the trees, realize that you are recognizing the beauty of life.
The divinity of your essence. The trees actually know it. The trees are actually aware in a
non-verbal, contextual knowingness. Resist. Hmm? Huh? Oh, then I'll finish it up in a hurry.
Okay, that's the most important one. Make face in the mirror. Be grateful. Live one day at a time.
Yesterday's gone forever, and tomorrow never gets here, because tomorrow is going to be tomorrow
tomorrow.
So live only today. Be your own best friend. Expansion versus diminution of problems.
Diminished problems, they're all nothing. Clarify confusion of self with social role.
Play the role of martyr. Am I playing the role of martyr? Am I an injustice corrector? Oh,
how the world loves injustice corrector. Oh, look how they do me wrong. The moral high ground.
Oh, the moral high ground. Oh, look how the world is mistreating me.
Because of everything. My age, my sex, my color, my religion, my country I live in. Oh, look how the world is
treating me unjustly. Okay, do we play the role of the hero or the role of the victim? Play the role
of morally superior. The competition for moral superiority in this world is intense. You think
it's money? No, it's moral superiority to make somebody wrong. Yep.
They say you don't, say you believe in heterosexual marriage. Now you can hate them and curse them.
What did they, who do they think their parents were?
If it wasn't for heterosexual marriage, you wouldn't be here, idiot. Let go of the role of being an
injustice collector. Let go of the role of being provocative. Stop pushing your luck. Avoid catastrophe.
Now,
here's some lessons. Do not buy a house in the floodplain. Do not buy a house on the edge of a
mud cliff. What is it? US 1 on California, the cliffs keep falling down. And they keep buying
houses right on the edge of the cliff. Sooner or later, it rains for a week and your mud in your
house goes sliding down. Do not buy one there. Do not win the lottery. Next one. You're all aware of
stop being approachable.
Protester. Obey the law. Be polite to police. Oh, my God. Stop demonstrating. Give up saving the world and mind your own business.
Next slide. Give up being important. Improve yourself instead of others. For God's sake, pay your income taxes. Even the head of the United States Tax Department doesn't pay his goddamn income taxes. Smile and the world smiles with you.
Dedicate all actions to God. 101 ways to be happy.
What do we do next, sweetheart?
What?
Oh, we're going to go on a break. First, before we go on a break, you're going to make an announcement?
Yes.
Please make an announcement.
All right. We have a 15-minute break. If you want to ask a question, please line up on this side of the room. If you have books that you want signed, line up on this side.
And we'll take a 15-minute break and be right back.
Yes, honey.
Thank you.