Can you hear me now? Can you hear me now? Can you hear me now? Somebody in the
group made me this wonderful cane and today is it's a major initiation. It's
good for keeping away small children and dogs. I wasn't attacked by any small
children or dogs. I said in the making of this movie no small dogs or
children were hurt. I forgot to bring a pen. I forgot to bring a pen. Well any
kind of a pen's good. I don't know.
how can i sign books with no pen yes come in how could i have forgotten my pen
we got a pen any place or a felt-tip pen well any kind is fine uh i'm frantic frantic frantically
looking for a pen frantic thank you thank you very much now can you hear me well it's the sound man
will have to turn the volume i can't yell any louder hello you got it okay sweetheart speak
dr hawkins i wanted to say that i'm filled with happiness by just by being here and it's my very
first time but it doesn't feel like the first time because i've watched a lot of your dvds
with my friend and it just felt as i've stepped into it it just felt very strange it felt that
i'd been here before and i just want to ask for your blessing i don't know if this is working
it's barely working uh that pen doesn't work very well we need a good pen okay they're coming
you'll have to try it again try it again is that sure yeah okay what is the question um well i just
wanted to say i'm filled with happiness at being here yes and i just wanted to ask for your
blessing it's the first time i'm here but it doesn't feel like the first time thank you doctor
you
may i uh
to touch your feet and shake your hands yes if you wish i still have to this is
it's working so just sign come on and we're getting a pen it's coming
all right my inner infant is having an intern fit i know what i want what i want and i want it right
now thank you so much can i touch your feet yes madam yes oh god bless you god bless you love
you
god bless you yes
hello hi first of all i'm very happy being here this is my first time but i watched your dvds
i've been watching for three years and my question is i want total freedom i want to be totally free
of all dependence on earthly anxieties worries and you want to hang on to the body at the same
time
i don't think so any method i know some methods you know i have been meditating i am you know i
want to be one with god just a non-duality you you just evolve and uh work on your spiritual
techniques and lessons and programs and don't worry about it okay thank you can i shake your
hand do it for its own sake okay for its own sake yes
yes yes yes yes thank you hello doctor there we go okay good yes uh you have spoken about
the styles of meditation in the discovery of the presence of god and you have recommended
style number three silent contemplation is that what you're saying no the meditation aspect
meditation yes and you speak of
all meditation is silent
you don't have to say silent meditation
I didn't say silent meditation
I can't understand
she didn't say silent meditation
what did she say
you recommended three styles of meditation
three styles of meditation
of which the third one
you recommended more than the others
and you talk of
seeing false genes
when you close your eyes
false genes
the little lights
phosphines
so you also talk about
entering
the depth of the silence
of diving into the silence
I don't understand what she's asking
she said talk about diving into the silence
yes
without looking
for what we are looking for
so then the false genes
wouldn't be there at that time would they
how do I know
I just said you wouldn't know
what's happening
if you were beyond that state
you wouldn't say
oh my those are phosphines
okay got the answer
all right
thank you
may I touch your feet please
yes
yes I understand
God bless
yes
God bless you love
ah yes
I get the fun of shaking you
our group says
sends us
sends you lots of love
we have two groups in Dubai
that study your teachings
oh Dubai yes
and we send you lots of love
and we pray for your longevity
yes you're from Dubai yes
yes
she comes all the way to Dubai
to hear Dr. Hawkins about once a year
yes yes
this time I'm coming twice a year
she's coming twice this year
you got some gifts for me
oh thank you
can I have something to sign
yes I signed all those
yeah
is there anything
nothing
oh thank you so much
thank you
God bless you
you've come such a long way
we appreciate you
love you
it's good to see you again
it's unbelievable to see you again
Dubai is that outside of Cincinnati
yeah it's wonderful to see everything
it's wonderful to see everything
it was a long trip
thank you
hi Dr. Hawkins
hello
greetings from Canada
yes
and we thank you for your happy teachings
and uh
we ask you for your blessing please
yes indeed you have my blessing Amen
thank you
and I have one question
you were mentioning that you had permission to leave the world
yes
earlier but you refused declined
I
how does it tie in
I merely declined it
yes
I didn't refuse
decline
how does it tie in with the earlier teachings you had?
the earlier lectures where you were mentioning that the time of death is predetermined at birth
that would have been then karmically given that you would have declined or the same with suicides
or or the soldiers dying in iraq and so on it's all predetermined or or isn't it it says it's
predetermined yes all right thank you maybe we have a picture now maybe take a picture
victor but it's predetermined for the majority of mankind but not for everybody all the time
let's have the arm on that it's uh predetermined for the majority of mankind most of the time
exists but it is not predetermined for the enlightened being exists see enlightenment
is beyond karmic beyond karma so you're not subject to karma you're in the karma is linear
in the
enlightenment is non-linear so the non-linear is not dominated by the linear
what did you bring a whole library here
oh my goodness signs of a misspent youth huh other people are playing bocce ball and i'm writing books
yes dr hawkins thank you for being my spiritual teacher my question is how do i transcend
my thinkingness that is a whole course of study in itself today i mentioned it and i also said
that it is the whole course within itself and uh to let it first of all you can view it as a
narcissistic linear egocentric and go beyond it nobody cares what you're thinking why should you
it's all worthless the only thing's worth knowing are things that you know that you're not aware of
you become aware of no of because of knowing this knowing this is non-verbal it's more diffuse
and global closer to animal instinct you might say animal instinct in a way the animal instinct
tells that this is not a good place to be right now he doesn't hear the leopard he doesn't smell
the leopard but he knows this is not a good place to be so he doesn't hang out there yes thank you
thank you yep ah yes hi dr hawkins i want to thank you for being for changing my life
and um i prayed to god many years for the words that jesus was trying to teach us
and he sent me you and i want to thank you i'm glad that you found what you were looking for
i certainly did in you thank you may i have a picture
a picture hello
hello um sometimes in quiet and um personal moments um i hear a sound in the room that
seems to have an energy to it and i've yes i would like celestial music no no not like that no it's
more it's victoria playing it's more kind of menacing it's a little bit menacing to me i mean
uncomfortable it's menacing oh a menacing sound yeah it seems to have a an energy to it though
but in terms of its original characteristics it's more of a sound and it's moreама feel
like that sorry a real sound or can you might you know feel like more quiet or more like a
little quiet and more feel more comfortable
um that's that, abel, I understand
yeah
uh
I get that
well
you know
I mean
who's that
boy
girl
so
spirit in the name of my lord jesus christ savior and i demand that i demand that you leave you have
the right to demand that an evil spirit leave you and if it keeps coming back or if the sound keeps
coming back does it just even what if the sound keeps coming back then what is it you demand that
it leave you you demand to leave you you demand that it leave you insist that it leave you yeah
oh yeah sure because okay so yeah once won't do it forever oh once won't do no negative spirits
will hang out testing you to see if you're going to give up and let them have their way or whatever
thank you you demand it's called the something or other of spirits the uh christianity calls it the
what the verification of spirits or no the something or other of spirits you demand if jesus
if you consider jesus christ your lord and if not you order them to leave it's the something
or other of spirits thank you
something
well
we need a good christian around here what is it there's some what is it the what the testing
hello there's a specific word for it i just can't think of it discernment yeah it's discernment but
it's called the something or other of spirits it'll come to me later well i really didn't have
a question i just wanted to sit in your presence for a minute oh yes thank you so much and now i'm
sitting here
i realize in my life
i'm busy with
clients but when i'm not i don't really want to
talk much
or or hear talk
and also i'm having a problem with hearing in the last few years
so it'll solve itself huh yeah yeah it did
except that i do a training program and so i get hearing aids so i can hear
but i wonder if i stop
the training program I wouldn't have to wear the hearing aids you can get it pretty expensively
now I know how much was that uh what do you call it the bug ear or something
it's a bug ear or something that's cute and it works
yeah so I just wonder if I'm supposed to kind of stop what I'm doing and
wait for the next I don't know the next uh direction what's the matter with what you're
doing now nothing then why are you looking for something to change when there's nothing wrong
with what you're doing I guess because I get um I practiced psychiatry for 50 years
yeah every January 1st I didn't say dear god what do you want me to do this year
50 years I practiced
psychiatry for 50 years
psychiatry right okay you just follow your momentum and do what's obvious you know what I mean
yes yeah okay thank you thank you if you're if you're ugly you go out and scare little children
good afternoon today's seminar is on happiness and it would make me very happy if I could undo
some of my negative karma and I'm wondering if that's possible no what you do is you uh
uncomplainingly
go through whatever life offers and don't worry about the negative karma just continue your
spiritual work and and do good in all the all of its forms and it automatically takes care of itself
thank you eventually the negative karma wears out and uh you rise above it and don't forget karma
part of the karma is really propensities propensities they're not absolute they're not
absolute
deterministic the fact you cut off somebody's head in some lifetime doesn't mean necessarily
that your head has to be cut off in this life in other words it doesn't have to be verbatim
it's correct it does not have to be verbatim resist yeah okay thank you yes please give me
your blessing he said something that's a sad story I've never heard oh blessing oh
you said that was enough just go see the teacher get their blessing and go that's true it is god bless you yes
you can show that to saint peter at the gate you know my saint peter story this guy dies he's going
to heaven there's a big long line like leading up to saint peter's office where you go through
like a turnstile this long line of people who've died recently well oh yeah you know i'm not going to
carry over the hill way off the distances you got to go all this way to get to saint peter and he
hears this murmur coming down from down the line and as it gets closer and closer and closer
he knows everybody's happy everybody's jumping up and down and they finally he gets it it says
sex doesn't count
i brought you some hello there hi i brought you some coffee syrup from rhode island
thank you and if you like that i'll keep you in it as much as you want yes i have a question which
i wrote down my question is about migraine headaches that is mine okay thank you what
migraine headaches yes um i get them often and i'm doing my best to welcome the pain as a gift
sometimes i can go back and discover unconscious guilt from which is causing it but in the majority
of them i eventually take
medication in order to function in the world
yes my question is is what effect does taking the medication on have on releasing the stack
is that considered resistance
oh i would take if you take like imatrix or something that works
uh... i would do so
and uh...
if you give up eating sugar and sweets make sure the functional hypoglycemia is not causing it
then there's various foods you
do uh...
high in purines can trigger it
so by writing down what you ate everyday and then checking with you if you have a headache
or not you may eventually see a correlation
okay thank you
also you tend to grow out of migraines
soon i hope
imatrix works extremely well
and there's others now even better i guess
so by taking medication does that have anything to do with that sort of thing singleton figured meow
to do with releasing the stack and holding that back and I need no it doesn't because the pain
is just a physiologic reaction there's nothing blessed about it you know okay it doesn't feel
blessed thank you like a picture please hypnosis works for it acupuncture works for it dietary
observation of what may be causing it yes thank you certain people in your life could be causing it
hi um I just want to say out loud that I thank you and I love you thank you yeah there could be
toxic persons in your life in your life you'd be better without them wow you bet god bless yes
Dr. Hawkins thank you so much for that infusion of happiness that you gave us all today
I
want to know what my highest spiritual
response is
to a situation where my 12 year old grandson
is
my 12 year old
grandson
is being given
these meds
they're 19 pills a day
that he is being given
to control his hyperactivity
oh yes
and on these
medications his tongue
is thick
it's
It's difficult for him to form a simple sentence.
And we moved close last year
so that I could homeschool him for a year.
And occasionally, I would be able to get him
without his medications.
Night and day difference in his learning.
My heart is melting for this child,
and I want to know what my highest spiritual response is.
Well, who's in charge of the meds?
The father.
And the father gets them from a doctor?
Yes, a licensed psychiatrist.
All right, so what you do is you share with the father your observation.
I have done that, and I was met with resentment and anger.
Anger about what?
The father believes the child is totally out of control
if he doesn't have this regimen.
At our house, during the school year,
we never saw that.
Yeah.
What do I need to do spiritually?
You're saying two people have two different observations.
One is a nutty, you're in a fruitcake, needs all the meds,
and you say there's nothing wrong with a kid
who doesn't need any meds?
One of you is out of this world.
I believe he's hyperactive,
but I believe this regimen is zapping his little developing brain.
Well, that's your program.
I can't help you with that one.
Oh, okay. Okay.
So, don't worry, be happy.
Yeah.
You get the best experts you can get,
and you share with these experts your observations,
and you can do a trial where you discontinue one or the other meds
and see if there's a difference, you know.
So, you need just the therapist that you can work with, you know.
It's all a matter of parental control.
So, thank you very much, Dr. Hawkins.
Dr. Hawkins.
Dr. Hawkins, first I'd like to say that this today
has been better than the night at the comedy showcase.
And also I want to acknowledge how much your teachings have meant to me
and my spiritual evolution and to thank you for it.
Thank you.
I may have your blessing.
Yes, God bless you.
There was some, I think he was a public figure
that had curable disease, cancer, and he took the laughing cure.
He wrote books on laughing and humor.
And did nothing but laugh for a couple of years
and eventually the tumor disappeared.
You wrote a book about it, yeah.
It was public information maybe five to ten years ago.
Yes.
We don't have any questions, Dr. Hawkins.
Your blessing.
Okay.
And I would like to come down there.
Yes.
All right.
As you will.
Yeah, you wrote a book about it.
You got every kind of a humorous book you could find.
And he just kept laughing all the time and eventually it cured it.
Norman Cousins?
Okay, I wanted it for your reference.
That's sufficient.
Yes.
God bless.
God bless you.
Amen.
Norman Cousins, yes.
I couldn't think of the name at the time.
Mm-hmm.
Howdy.
I'm nervous.
I just simply wanted to do something that my ego didn't want.
Want me to do?
May I just touch your feet and ask for a blessing?
Yes.
Easy question.
We'll put that in the donation basket.
Thank you.
God bless you.
Put this with donations.
Right here.
Give it to me.
Otherwise I'll lose it.
Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
Yes.
I don't have a question either.
I just wanted to take a moment to express my gratitude to you and your teachings and
let you know that they've really helped me find God in my life.
I'm just so grateful that I could be here today to feel your energy.
I thank you and ask for your blessing.
Thank you for thanking me.
Mm-hmm.
Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
A few years ago, I was briefly under the influence of a false guru.
When I came out of it a couple of weeks later, I started hearing voices.
I believed that I was being counseled by the white brotherhood.
It took several months before I realized the error I made and refused to listen anymore.
It took—wait a minute.
You're going too fast.
Sorry.
I was under the influence of what I thought was the white brotherhood, but I think from
reading your books that it was actually astral entities.
Oh, okay.
Mm-hmm.
It keeps coming up again and again, and I wondered if there's something that needs
to be cleared from my aura or something I need to do.
What's coming up again and again?
For several months, I was under the influence.
I was directed to do things, told to do things, and I thought that I was working in the service
of God, but I wasn't.
How did you get here?
Did you hear these?
Was it auditory or what?
Messages would appear in my mind, and initially, they were written down.
They told me—I thought I was mad.
I thought I was making it up.
But several of the things that occurred, I later found out through your readings, were
actually true.
It was a difficult period, and I don't know how else to explain it.
But I've heard you say before that if you've been involved with astral entities, that you
have to have your aura cleared.
Well, if that makes you happy, yes.
Oh.
I followed the guidance I was given, and I seem to be all right, but I keep worrying
about it, which is why I'm here.
Oh, you grow beyond it.
Just—
These things come in phases.
There'll be a couple of years where all kinds of weird things happen.
Then there'll be a year or two where weird gurus show up out of the woodwork, you know,
and say, bonky, bonky.
Stick to the tried and true.
Yes, I know that now.
All right.
In books I've written, we calibrate the level of spiritual teachers.
Mm-hmm.
Pick one that appeals to you and follow it strictly.
Okay.
And eventually it'll go away.
It'll go away.
Okay.
So I don't have to worry about it?
Yeah, it'll go away.
Yeah.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
Thank you, Susan.
Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
Yes.
It's very nice to be here.
I see light in dark things or energies, and I need help in knowing what they are, and
is it necessary that I do know what they are?
Lights in what?
In what?
Is this light up here?
I don't know.
No, like light and dark things in the, I guess the atmosphere.
Are they tiny or large?
They can be tiny and they can be large.
They can be bright white lights popping around.
Sometimes they're wispy and then sometimes they're dark.
Sometimes they will appear around people.
Mm-hmm.
And depending on the situation that I'm in or the group, they can be more so, more present
than others.
Mm-hmm.
And I'm not for sure exactly what they are.
It's not modified by anything you're doing or saying or state you're in?
No.
They come and go of their own?
Mm-hmm.
Do they seem to have a message?
Sometimes if I ask questions in my mind, they will happen to appear more quickly.
What do you think they are?
Angels.
What she's seeing is angels resist.
What she's seeing is phosphenes resist.
Yeah.
You're seeing little illuminations that are concomitant to the neuronal activity of the
brain's neurons.
Uh-huh.
Okay.
So just accept that it's normal and enjoy them.
Just accept it's normal.
If I close my eyes right now, there's a million tiny specks of light.
Right.
Because they're there all the time, I don't pay attention to them.
I just ignore them.
Okay.
And one more.
Would you come to Nashville and speak?
I can't do that.
Thank you.
No.
I've got a question about time.
You talk about time and you talk today about getting older.
Yeah.
But then sometimes you talk about how there's no such thing as time.
That it's a superimposition upon phenomena that are happening simultaneously.
Yeah.
You're mixing levels of truth.
Okay.
You're mixing levels.
So what do you do?
What do you do?
What.
So what, well that's, I guess that's because I can't figure it out.
What, there's no such thing as time, but we see ourselves growing older.
Yeah.
But is it.
We call that time.
Yes, we call it time.
Is it because if you try to figure out time over all of the universe you can't do that
because of multiple dimensions?
But could time be local for purpose?
What do you want to know this for?
I was just, yeah.
I just wondered about.
You don't have any reason to know it.
It's a connection.
Okay.
you've made up to confuse yourself.
Oh, okay.
The answers to it are very,
the actual answers to it are in advanced quantum mechanics
and advanced theoretical physics.
Whether time is limited to a certain dimension,
whether it's all-inclusive,
whether there's forward time and backward time.
It's, to me, games people play with
in advanced theoretical physics
with no actual application to their life at all, you know?
Okay.
Are you gonna stop making love because of it,
or are you gonna eat nothing but grapefruit,
or, I mean, you know what I mean?
I guess when you say there's no such thing as time,
but then you say don't waste time.
It's you referring to it.
I was just trying to figure out.
Yeah, but we're talking about different contextualizations.
Okay.
What you see is sequence.
That sequence is delineated as time, measurable time.
Yeah?
And then beyond that is the timeless.
So time is like a subdivision underneath,
let's say, the sky, you know what I'm saying?
How big is the sky?
Well, it's as big as you want to define it,
you know what I'm saying?
It doesn't, there isn't any beginning of the sky
and ending of the sky.
It's a point of observation.
All right, thanks.
The actual,
the actual fulfillment of this understanding,
you could try whatchamacallit, mindful universe.
You read that?
I've heard of it, yeah.
No, you gotta read it, not heard of it.
Okay.
Mindful universe is a good place to start.
Professor of physics at Berkeley.
It's readable.
All right, thanks.
Yeah, I'm just gonna do what's humanly possible.
.
Is that writing?
I can't tell if it's writing or not.
No, this pen's dead.
I don't know, you can't get a pen that, yeah, unbelievable.
.
Here, I'll use this one.
There was another one laying here.
I don't have it today.
There's another pen there.
This pen doesn't write at all.
.
You got three for the price of one.
You've got a lot of them.
I don't know, I don't know what to do with this.
Endless requests.
That's better.
Yep. They bring you books.
They bring you a book with no pen.
.
Thank you.
How many of these?
What does this thing say?
It's for everybody back in the day.
Oh, I see, yes.
.
I just firstly wanted to say thank you.
I can't possibly say that enough.
.
Yes.
My question is, we have a study group back in Maryland, and we help each other through testing different situations in our life.
.
I can't sign all these.
That's okay.
.
Thank you.
So my question is, we test through the situations in our life, and sometimes we test, is this a karmic issue, and we actually get no.
But from what I've learned, everything is, we are our karma.
Our karma is everything that's happened to us.
So how can we test that the situation is not related to our karma?
.
Sometimes what you mean by karma is historic karma.
Okay.
.
Everything is karma, yeah.
What generally people mean is historic karma, past lives and past decisions.
.
So when we ask the question if it's related to our karma, then that is our. .
When you ask what question?
.
If we ask if it is a karmic issue, then we are implicitly asking from a previous life, not this one.
That's what you're really asking, yeah.
.
Okay, thank you.
Is this a pen?
.
No, it's a pen.
Okay, thank you.
.
Is it for the highest good that she moves to the U.S.?
Okay, let's ask.
We have permission to ask this.
It would serve her highest good to move to the U.S., resist.
That's the answer we got.
And the second one was,
it is for the highest good that I remain in Luxembourg,
where I currently live.
But I guess that's redundant because the first one is yes.
Let's see.
It would serve her highest good to move to the United States.
Yes.
But it's also okay that she stay in Luxembourg.
Either one.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
Why is there such a profusion of these?
Because it's for the whole study group, so you have to do this.
Yeah.
I see, okay.
Okay, all right, okay.
Okay, those were the only two statements that I had.
Thank you so much.
Thank you both.
It's either way, yes.
It's okay either way, yeah.
But it's been a dilemma for three years,
and each time I ask myself what I should do,
I keep thinking that I'm listening to my ego.
Okay, so why don't you ask for guidance?
I've done that too.
And then I thought that the only possible answer I had
was to come here and ask you to calibrate that.
Maybe that's why you're not getting the answers.
Either one is all right.
Yeah, it could be that.
It could be that.
Yeah, it sounds like it's come see, come saw.
Either or.
You speak French.
Fantastic.
Merci beaucoup.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Yeah, you bet.
That's a profusion.
I don't know whose pens these are.
I know.
We can look at everybody's pens.
Yes.
I just wanted to thank you for being my teacher
and for saving me lifetimes and lifetimes
of inquiry and reading.
And my...
My inner song is happy, and my outer song is happy too.
Good, good, good.
Thank you so much.
She sounds happy.
Yes.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
First of all, it's just a pleasure to be here
and to be in your presence
and to be able to be around someone
that's given so much to humanity.
And I thank you as well as I know all of us.
Thank you for that.
I have a question.
I've been studying A Course in Miracles
and as well as your teachings for about the past eight years.
And through this,
I've gone through a lot of
what feels like an undoing process.
I've gotten to a point now
where it feels as if I'm at a place
where I almost have had experiences
where I felt I had to surrender my existence,
like my...
like not my existence, but existence itself.
I felt I had to surrender that.
And it was too scary for me to go through.
And I felt like I was being sucked into a vortex.
Yeah.
Of energy that I would...
You'd never be able to come back out of
once you make it through there.
And it was too scary.
And the couple times when this has come up,
I've pulled out of it because of fear.
And I wonder if you could tell me
if you think that's safe to do that
or if my instincts...
Well, I've walked through that door
and I've described that door.
That's why I came here to ask you this.
I've described that door.
Did it feel like demons were pulling at you?
I mean, did it feel demonic?
Like what?
Like fearful and demonic and...
Was it scary?
Terrifying.
It's safe for her to surrender
what she's contemplating surrendering.
All fear is illusion.
Okay.
And I'd like to ask
if you could calibrate an organization for me
that I've considered joining,
if it would be in the highest and best good
of the service to humanity
for me to join this organization.
All right.
Just hold the organization in your mind.
I don't want to know the name of it.
All right.
We have permission to ask this.
In the name of the highest good,
the organization that she wants to join
is ethical and of the highest order.
What is this?
It is not of the highest order.
Okay.
I wanted to ask if you would bless my wee ones,
especially Keiko.
Huh?
What?
These are her little sugar babies.
Oh, God bless you, cute little boogers.
Are those for dinner tonight?
Are we having them for dinner?
Susan, there are seven.
There are seven sugar babies that are just wonderful.
You'll have to take one out and show everyone
because they're just adorable.
Thank you.
I love these things.
What?
Take one out now?
If you can't eat it, we'll go to the...
I know.
Pick out one that's going to be to a man, get to a man.
Yep.
Teeny wincy.
They don't like the light.
They're nocturnal, so they don't like this much light.
Thank you.
God bless you.
Bless you.
Thank you.
Appreciate you.
Yeah.
Nothing more fun than pets.
Yes.
Great teacher.
My question is simple.
Is enlightenment basically easy or is it difficult?
It only takes a couple dozen lifetimes.
At minimum?
This is my basic question.
That's kind of oversimplified, but is it a simpler truth?
Do we make it difficult?
By simply saying, no.
Are we just striving for it and thinking about it and trying to get there, or is it ...
It's difficult, and it's because we're making it difficult, but it's difficult to let go
of making it difficult.
It makes perfect sense.
Thank you so much.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
I don't have a question.
I just wanted to draw near and just sit in your presence and hopefully just hold your
hand just for a few seconds.
Yes.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
God bless you.
Thank you.
I would just like to ask for forgiveness, and I pray to surrender to the love of Jesus
Christ and to accept the gift of the resurrection.
I don't know what you're saying.
I ask for forgiveness, and I pray to surrender to the love of Jesus Christ and to accept
the gift of the resurrection.
I don't know what you're asking.
What is she talking about?
She's just—
What about it?
What is the question?
I just pray—I ask for forgiveness.
She wants you to bless her.
Yeah.
I would like a blessing.
She's asking you for—
Thank you.
It's—the blessing is suitable.
All right.
So, I bless your search for the Lord Jesus Christ, your Savior.
We'll speak to you later.
Thank you.
Amen.
All right.
So, you need to learn how to speak before the Father for you in heaven.
Yes?
Thank you.
.
He is a hard time—it is a feedback.
He is a hard time hearing.
If you're a Christian, then Jesus Christ
will be your advocate before the Father.
Yes.
You want to work together.
You're an advocate before the Father.
Yes.
He will speak for you before the Father.
I want to say I love you and I thank you for the work that you're doing.
Yes.
and your presence in my life.
Thank you.
And I have a question
that I have a physical thing
that happens to me
that I can't explain
that I have a moment
of going faint
and then my heart starts racing.
Yes.
And I don't eat sugar.
And I don't know,
and it's unrelated.
It's been going on for a few years.
It's atrial fibrillation.
Resist.
Atrial fibrillation.
You can cure it
with a half a tablet of,
what the hell is it?
No, no.
Atrial.
Huh?
No.
Atrial fib,
it'll come to me in a second.
It's easily curable,
cardiologists.
Okay.
Well, when I went to
had an EKG and all that
and they said
there was no problem
with my heart.
Well, then you're not having
what you're saying
you're having.
Right.
Well, I don't know what it is.
I just know that
unexpectedly,
my heart will just start racing
and then it will stop.
Well, they did a cardiogram
and said that it's not doing that.
Right.
So, I don't know.
Are they lying or what?
I don't know.
All right.
Okay.
It's simple.
She has atrial fib.
Yes.
Okay.
You got paroxysmal
atrial fibrillation,
which is relatively benign.
However, your heart will stop
and then it may race
and then stop.
There's a simple medication
inexpensive generic
that stops it.
I can't think of the name
of it at the moment.
Let me see.
Yeah.
Beta blocker.
Yep.
It'll come to me later.
Any doctors who stop
what stops atrial fib?
It's a
well, I can't prescribe
for you under the present
circumstances.
Okay.
Anyway, it's obviously
atrial fibrillation.
Okay.
That doctor that comes on
Fox News every Sunday morning
talked about it
about a month ago.
He devoted the whole program
to atrial fib.
Okay.
You might write Fox News
and ask him,
who is that doctor
and get a copy of that CD.
Yeah, I can research it.
What's his name?
Dr. Bloomberg or something?
No.
He talked, anyway,
he talked about atrial fib
about a month ago.
Okay.
Thank you.
In great detail.
And may I shake your hand?
Yes.
Now, if I think of the name
of the med,
I'll just holler it out.
Yeah.
How can you not remember
that thing?
That's because we're
in a spiritual setting
and they ask you
medical questions.
They ask a linear question
in a non-linear dimension.
Thank you very much
for today.
It's been a wonderful day,
wonderful experience.
And my question is,
can we,
do we sometimes,
come into this lifetime
with a karmically,
pre-karmically agreed,
what you might call
divine mission?
I think so.
Yep.
Would it be possible
if I held it in mind
to calibrate
what I think mine is,
what I'm pretty sure mine is?
What do you think
your divine mission is?
It's getting involved
with orphanage work
in Costa Rica.
And it's very, very diamond.
Uh-huh.
Okay.
That would be a fulfillment
of his karmic mission.
Yeah.
It's like propensity
to help children.
Yes.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
Thank you.
That was all I wanted to know.
Thank you very much.
Is it okay to shake your hand, sir?
Yes.
Yes, God.
What's the name of the man?
Doctor,
to get his,
what is it?
He wrote a whole term
on how to do
clinics down in Costa Rica.
Okay.
Oh, yes.
I wrote a paper,
low-cost
psychiatric
and addiction clinics.
Clinics.
Clinics for Central and South America,
which I wrote for some organization.
When he was knighted.
Okay.
Yes.
And he wrote that.
Low-cost clinics
for the disadvantaged
in Central and South America.
I wrote a paper on the subject, yes,
for which I received some honor.
When he was knighted into the state.
Order of, yeah.
The Order of St. John of Jerusalem.
Yeah.
The Order of St. John of the,
the Order of the Hospitalliers of St. John of Jerusalem,
which were one of the first crusades,
Christian crusades to the Holy Land, yeah.
Yes.
Mm-hmm.
And it was in that lifetime there
that we killed each other.
He killed me for Allah,
and I killed him for Jesus.
Had a lifetime there.
And I've met,
he's been,
a working partner of mine
throughout many centuries.
Anyway,
it was during the crusades,
and I killed him for Jesus,
and he killed me for Allah.
We both went out of body at the same time,
looked at each other,
and split up laughing.
I said, this is too much.
He was out of,
both in our third bodies.
We both split laughing.
I killed him for Jesus,
he killed me for Allah.
Hysterical.
The world is still doing it.
But we saw that back in the year,
I forget, 12 something.
Yes, go ahead.
I've enjoyed your sweet presence today.
Thank you.
Yes.
And I just wanted to spend
a little bit more time closer,
and a handshake.
What'd she say?
She said, one.
Oh, handshake.
And more presence.
Yes.
You bet.
What's the name of that,
that I take every morning
when I cry this thing?
How could you take it every morning
and not remember it?
I mean, it's unbelievable.
Yes, go ahead.
I wanna thank you, Dr. Hawkins,
from the bottom of my heart.
Yes.
And ask for your blessing.
And these two young men are here
from London to see you.
Yes.
And they wanted also to shake your hand.
They're from London?
Yes.
Oh, yes.
We're in London.
Central and East town.
From South London.
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
I just wanted to say that
it's not a big deal to us to come here,
and we're really thankful to be in your presence.
Thank you.
Love you very much.
Thank you for coming here.
We love London.
I've been there two or three times.
We both love London a lot.
Thank you, Doctor.
Where is it where they have Poet's Corner?
Is that what's on the other?
The Abbey.
Westminster Abbey, yes.
I always go to Westminster Abbey.
It's been under construction for over 1,000 years.
That's impressive.
They've been working on it for over 1,000 years
and haven't finished it yet.
That's dragging your feet.
Sister taught Coco.
That's the woman that taught Coco.
It could be her.
It was his sister who taught her.
Yes.
Thank you.
Doctor, I bring you greetings from Eastern Canada.
Yes.
I come from New Brunswick.
Oh, yes.
Which is even further east than Maine,
as you know.
Yes.
I had a question,
and at about 12 minutes after 10 this morning,
it was answered.
Yes.
That question, of course,
was whether I should be using compact fluorescent lights or not.
Whether I should be using what?
Compact fluorescent lights.
And then you answered that about 10 o'clock this morning.
Oh.
So I've just enjoyed the day.
All right.
It is so very validating.
Yes.
To read your books over and over and over.
To watch your DVDs.
Yes.
And to have been here 28 months ago.
Oh.
In December of 2006.
When you told us the story of the snake.
Oh.
At that time, my oldest son and his wife was with us.
He, at the present time,
is suffering from a seven-millimeter kidney stone
and wasn't able to make the trip.
Oh.
However, this child, my adult,
and my two parents would like to have a picture.
Could we do that?
They have a way of blasting those things now
and disintegrating them.
That's what he's waiting for.
That's right.
The urologists are all on conference until Wednesday.
Yeah.
They disintegrate it now.
So we would like a picture with the family if I could.
Yes.
They disintegrate it now.
Yeah.
What?
Did you talk or something?
Digoxin.
Yeah.
That's for, like, heart problems.
Who gets this?
No.
Yes.
Can you do one more, please?
This is for the older boy.
That is so painful to have kidney stones.
I feel so sorry for him.
Yeah.
Let me see.
Love you.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you.
Yes, indeed.
Thank you very much.
Yes.
She went to Al-Anon and took step one.
Oh, yeah.
For that lady that had the heart circulation, is that the drug?
Oh, hell no.
It's better than the one.
I don't know who it is.
No.
That's not the one.
All right.
Hi.
Dr. Hopkins.
Thank you very much for your teachings.
I'm a physician, and I'm trying to incorporate many of your teachings in working with my
patients.
Yes.
I've used different healing practices or sent them to different types of healers.
In Truth Versus Falsehood, you calibrated different healing practices, whether it be
homeopathy, acupuncture, Reiki.
You said energy medicine calibrated quite high, and I was trying to discern what energy
medicine is compared to acupuncture or Reiki.
Well, acupuncture is a form of energy medicine.
Yes.
So I didn't understand what the difference was.
Well, energy medicine is just a general classification, kinesiology, acupuncture, things that are not
within the tight scientific discipline of traditional medicine.
So it's a general classification that you're giving it.
Yes.
Okay.
Well, thank you.
If I may have a blessing and a picture?
You can have a blessing, indeed.
God bless you.
Yeah.
Amen.
God bless you.
Now, the person that asked me about that cardiac med for atrial fibrillation will pester me
until I answer it.
If you call the office, the office will tell you.
What day is today?
Saturday.
Saturday, all right.
Monday.
Today's Monday?
No.
If you call the office on Monday and ask, what is the med to take for atrial fibrillation,
the girl will tell you.
When I'm in the nonlinear, it's very hard to jump back into the nonlinear.
You have to jump back into the linear and think of something definitively.
Hello.
Hi.
I just wanted to say hello and have a moment.
Yes.
Thank you.
METOPROLOL.
That's it.
METO, M-E-T-O-P-R-O-L-O-L.
It's for rhythmic disorders.
It's cheap, and it's generic.
Okay.
Thank you.
METOPROLOL is generic, and half a tablet of METOPROLOL a day stops atrial fib.
It came out of nowhere.
That's was not the result of a .
I asked the field.
Hello, doc.
Hello, Susan.
It's lovely to be back again from Australia.
Oh, my goodness.
Just a little something to say, thank you.
I'm just kinkすごい.
Australia?
Yes.
Open the way.
I don't think I can.
I'd like to ask for blessings again for Down Under and the family and I suppose myself as well, if that's possible.
It's great to be back again.
Well, God bless you.
And I see my blessing worked because Australia did not drop off the planet.
This is where Australia is down here.
It should fall down via gravity, but it stays there.
Well, thank you.
Thank you.
I thought you'd appreciate it.
Your blessings worked.
Yeah, yeah.
Yes.
And I was wondering, I had my mother's jewelry made up into a pendant to wear.
I was wondering if you would bless that for me, please.
Hold it and bless it.
Oh, dear.
What a lovely, lovely thing to have the blessing of.
Yes.
Yeah.
Well, thank you.
And I'd just like to shake hands.
Yes.
Thank you, Doc, very much for all your help in my life.
Uh-huh.
And all of us.
We're so grateful.
We're so grateful for your tape.
It's done.
Where abouts are you in Australia?
Near Byron Bay.
Byron Bay.
And also, I have family in Sydney, so I go backwards and forwards a bit.
Yes.
And Byron Bay's got that high vortex of energy like here.
Dermot, behind you, he used to live in Australia.
Oh, really?
Yes.
Right.
Oh, well, there's a couple of us.
The next lady is as well from Australia.
So we're very, very grateful for all you've done for us.
Uh-huh.
Yes.
Thank you.
Okay.
Yeah.
We have a lot of course.
We have a lot of correspondence in Australia.
Yes.
Someday, I hope.
Yeah.
Well, we'd love you to come, but...
Actually, it's not that long, the flight.
Oh, no.
It's only a couple of days on the plane and in the airport.
A couple of days in the airport floors and...
Yes.
Yeah.
Well.
Maybe next time.
You see, they got these supersonic airliners, and when they get them perfected,
you know, you bounce off.
They bounce off the atmosphere, and I'm going to try and get some big country like China
interested in producing them so it's profit-making, but it will only take, you know, maybe two
hours to get to Australia.
Oh, that'd be amazing.
So a bit like a hovercraft on the sea.
No, no.
They're supersonic, and they go beyond the atmosphere, and then they come down, and the
resistance of the atmosphere, they bounce off the atmosphere again.
And then that gives them a bounce like a kangaroo.
Oh.
So you can bounce from here to Australia in a matter of a couple hours.
I'm sure some big country will take it on.
And you've looked at all the procedure for this, the invention, and...
It's already a perfected thing.
It's just, you know, make it commercially worthwhile to pursue.
Yes.
You know, you need a couple billion dollars.
You need a couple billion dollars to invest.
Yes.
I'm figuring the Chinese or somebody will run in there and grab it, because it's a very
open...
Think of all the people that, you know, haven't got three or four days to get someplace.
Yes, exactly.
Yes.
Right.
You get from New York to London in, you know, a half hour.
Oh, fantastic.
And from London to India in maybe two or three hours.
Another hour or two, and you're over in Australia, so you can circumvent the globe in a matter
of hours.
It's amazing.
I think that it is...
That's so profitable, potentially.
Somebody with big bucks will go into it.
And there they were going around the world in 80 days.
Yeah.
Yes.
All right.
Thank you, Doc.
Yeah.
Could I take a...
I have a photo.
Yes.
Very quickly.
All right.
We have 10 minutes left, you know.
Okay.
Your time is my time.
We'll move along faster.
Run.
Run, rabbit.
Thank you.
Run.
Thank you, sweetheart.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Also from Australia.
I think that'll work, that one.
Okay.
Oh, great.
And if possible, that one.
And...
Okay.
And what would you like?
If you have any advice, please, for heavy metal toxicity?
They usually chelate them out.
What heavy metal are you talking about?
Mercury and lead, mainly.
And if you...
Well, heavy metals are usually chelated out with very high doses of ascorbic acid.
Okay.
The equivalent of...
Yes.
The chelate, C-H-E-L-A-T-E.
Okay.
Chelated out with high doses of ascorbic acid.
Alright.
The only cases I had in my years in clinical work, I chelated them out.
I think I told you I had one guy who was as mad as a hatter.
Anyway, he was a patient who was dragged around to see 50 doctors, all the chiefs of psychiatry
here and there and there, and he was hopeless, so he specialized in hopeless cases.
So they bring this guy in.
He's been everywhere, and he's crazy as a loon.
I mean, nuts, nuts, nuts.
My mind said, he's as mad as a hatter.
I said, oh, he's got mercury poisoning.
Right.
Turned out the previous summer he'd been out spraying stuff in some orchard,
a mercury-containing orchard spray,
and he was as mad as a hatter.
So we chelated the mercury out with high doses of ascorbic acid,
including intravenous, and he recovered completely.
Thank you very much.
And I'll get you to sign that you're coming to Australia
as soon as that plane's invented.
As soon as they get that bouncer off the atmosphere.
It bounces on the atmosphere.
Yeah. Yes.
I wanted to say thank you to both of you.
I really had a lot of fun today,
and I wanted to ask for a blessing for me and for my home.
God bless you and your home, lovely lady.
And a picture.
Thank you.
Yes.
I have a question.
At what consciousness level are you at when you have self-realization,
when you realize that you're a soul?
Is that 500?
Saintliness is around 570.
Enlightenment begins at 600.
And then there are various levels of enlightenment.
Okay?
Yes.
And salvation, as mentioned,
in the Course in Miracles, what level would that be?
Salvation is not a level of consciousness.
Okay.
All right.
Can I take your picture?
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
The workbook in Course in Miracles is at 600.
The textbook is at 550.
Thank you.
Hello, Dr. Huggins.
Hello, Susan.
Thank you very much.
In our devotion and duality group in Sedona, we use a prayer.
We pray.
I am a servant of you, my Lord, and I ask for your divine will to be revealed to me.
And the question is, how in the midst of...
I'm not understanding.
I am.
All right.
Go ahead.
In the midst of imagination and some thoughts, to learn to recognize the voice of the God.
To recognize the God.
How we can, yes, learn to recognize the voice of the higher.
How do you recognize the voice of God?
When...
If you question it, it's not the voice of God,
because the voice of God is self-revealing
that it is the voice of God.
It's a prayer. It's a prayer for God,
especially in moments when you're in a difficult decision
and then you ask the divine,
what would be the good for me, for my evolution?
What?
In moments of questioning,
which direction to turn,
you ask for, with this prayer, you ask for guidance.
Yes.
So how do you know that it's answering you?
It comes as a knowingness.
If there's any question, then that's not the answer.
The voice for God is accompanied by certainty.
Certainty.
If there's still a question,
it's because your mind is playing with it.
So if all of a sudden you get an answer to a dilemma
that you've been...
and you get this answer...
It comes as a clarification.
Yeah.
All of a sudden, you know...
It's simple and obvious.
Thank you.
May I ask you a blessing?
God bless you.
This is the man from Russia, honey, that came here.
Oh, okay.
Oh, wonderful.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
My question maybe is similar to his.
I have been questioning that I was...
focused too much on others' needs.
And I've been trying to get clear on my needs and meet them.
But then I start questioning if that's laziness and self-centeredness.
How can there be a conflict between the needs of others and your own?
It's how you're defining it.
There is no difference.
Taking care of children and their needs is taking care of myself.
Isn't it?
My need to be the father, the mother, the parent, the helper.
To fulfill my potentiality.
So you can't differentiate.
I'm doing this for this person and not myself.
Or I'm just doing it for myself and not this person.
They're both the same.
Okay.
What you sacrifice for others, you're also sacrificing for yourself.
And what you sacrifice for yourself, you're also sacrificing for others.
Because the less egoistic you are, the more you can serve others.
So you're just artificially dividing it as though they're two different things.
They're not two different things.
And then maybe just let daily tasks go to the side if they need to, to be more.
And then what?
Let daily tasks go to the side, you know, in order to be more what?
In service to the other or?
Well, sometimes things happen.
Daily tasks are service to the other, aren't they?
You're creating an artificial this or that versus that.
They're all the same.
You're giving service to life, to life.
Dusting the house, feeding the chickens, making the children dinner,
taking care of your aged mother.
It's all the same.
It's all service to life in all of life's expressions.
They're not different things.
They're all the same thing, but it's applied to different things.
That's helpful, service to life.
Yeah, thank you.
Yeah.
Okay.
Thank you.
Yeah, yeah.
Yes.
Thank you for all of the work that you've done.
I'm very grateful to be here.
When I am studying your work, I find it difficult to apply to myself in a very loving way.
I wonder how to truly forgive myself, how to accept my humanness as I am trying to progress.
Well, you could do it piecemeal.
In you is the child, the adult, and the parent.
Start maybe forgiving the child.
Then move on to the parent.
I mean, to the adult, then move on to the parent.
I would work the other way.
I would work with the child, and then the parent, and then the adult.
Thank you.
May I have a blessing?
Yes.
You know, identify the child within you.
Forgive and love the child.
And then the child always leads right to the adult, the parent.
And then you heal the parent, and then that leads to the adult.
By that time, the adult's relatively easy to heal.
It's different in each person.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
Yes.
Hi, Susan.
I'm using the calibration technique in my work.
I'm a doctor, so I calibrate lectures.
I calibrate journals and medical articles, really to find out, should I read this?
Many times I find I don't need to read a lot of the medical articles.
Many times she finds out what?
She doesn't need to read the medical articles.
Oh, oh.
Yeah.
Uh-huh.
Science is, well, it's not very powerful.
Yeah.
Now, I find it difficult to use the finger and loop technique, so I have been using the
pendulum, so is that acceptable?
Yes.
The pendulum should give you the same results.
Okay.
Yeah.
It should be accurate.
Thank you.
The only thing about the pendulum, don't try calibrating things that are obviously evil.
Right.
Yes.
I understand that.
Don't try calibrating Lucifer or something.
Right.
Quantum mechanics, you've said, is in the science, in the intellect level, and then
I came across a body of work by Dr. William Tiller, and he's written Psycho-Energetic Science,
and that calibrates over 500.
Can that be correct?
I'm not catching what you're saying.
She's talking too fast.
She came across this book.
Yes.
By Tiller.
Oh, Tiller.
Yes.
Tiller.
And she felt it was in the 500.
She felt that it was ...
I can't read his name.
What does that say?
William Tiller?
Bill?
William Tiller.
Bill Tiller.
Yes.
I know Bill.
I've met Bill Tiller.
Okay.
You want to calibrate this Bill Tiller book?
Yes, please.
This Bill Tiller book is over 540, 580, 575, 560, 565.
Around 560.
Yeah.
I got it right.
I met Bill Tiller.
Yes.
Bill Tiller.
I had dinner with him two nights ago, and I said, Dr. Tiller, this needs to be put in
a format that it's not esoteric, and he said, it's your job, and he gave it to me.
Okay.
All right.
Yeah.
Yes.
Bill Tiller.
Yeah.
Bill Tiller is well-loved and well-respected and well-known.
First off, I just want to say that I'm honored to be here, and thank you for your wonderful
speech today.
Okay.
My question is ...
I've learned from you that the mind cannot differentiate between truth and falsehood.
Right.
Okay.
Unaided.
Yeah.
Well, there are things that I know to be true.
How do I know that?
Well, you're talking about abstract things, concrete things?
Well, no, like ...
Like what kind of a thing?
Like, if I run and jump off this stage, I'm going to hit the ground.
Yeah.
That's a linear knowingness of the intellect.
So, if my mind doesn't know that, how do ...
No, your mind is knowing that.
Your intellect is knowing that.
Yeah.
The mind is greater than the intellect.
The intellect is just an instrument, a linear instrument, like an editing machine or a computer.
Uh-huh.
Okay.
Well, thank you.
May I shake your hand, and I'll get a picture, please?
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
Can I just ask, when you just said 180, were you saying that I calibrated 180?
Okay.
Just making sure.
No.
I didn't say 180.
No, I didn't say 180.
We were calibrating Bill Tiller.
Okay.
I must have been mistaken.
It was fine.
Okay.
We did Bill Tiller, yeah.
Yeah.
Now, you're safe.
If you're a nut job, I'd find a way to avoid you.
Yes?
Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
Yes.
Here's a gift for you that is a gift that's coming to you.
I'm going to give it to you.
You're going to give it to me.
is from Ramana Maharshi's cave
and I'd like you to accept it.
It's what?
Ramana Maharshi's cave
and I'd like you to accept it.
It's from what?
Maharshi?
Cave?
Yes, cave.
It's some Vibhuti
from some holy ash.
Now I know what you're saying.
Yes, from Ramana Maharshi's cave.
Yes, yes.
I'd like to thank you so much
for what you've done in my life.
It's been just amazing.
I have a conundrum
and it's regarding the turban.
I've been using the turban
as a source of protection
for the last 18 months
dealing with addictions
and mostly stemming from the gay scene.
Mostly stemming from what?
The gay scene.
Oh, G-A-Y?
Gay.
Oh, oh, oh, yeah.
The gay scene.
And I'm questioning from your teachings
and from my own ego dramas
whether,
whether it's necessary anymore
and whether I should continue or not,
although it's been very helpful.
And I'm wondering.
To wear the turban,
is that the question?
Yes.
It's helpful for him to continue
to wear the turban.
Yes, it's a reminder of your commitment.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
May I touch your feet, please?
Yes.
Thank you.
Yes, it's a reminder of your commitment.
And it's a difficult one you've made
to transcend that kind of a lifestyle.
Very hard, yeah.
It's a hard one to make.
So, you need all the help you can get.
Thank you, Dr.
Mm-hmm.
Well, it's someone's purse.
I don't like their purse.
Me aqua tasen.
And it means all my relations, we are all related.
And so, I thank you.
Yes.
For this time.
I walk a very strong spiritual walk.
And I had a great deal of resistance coming here.
This is my first time I've ever saw you.
I've read your book, Power Versus Force.
And I had resistance coming here because I
walk directly with spirit as its guide.
Spirit said, you must go.
It's imperative that you go.
And so, I want to thank you.
I'm full of gratitude.
Yes.
What you spoke about today, spirit
has taught me many, many years of this.
And so, it's a great confirmation for me.
And so, I'm very grateful to you and full of gratitude.
Thank you, yes.
Now, the question, which I have great resistance of asking.
Oh, you don't have to ask it.
I do.
They keep insisting.
I ask.
And the question is, how do you walk the strings of time?
How do you what?
How do you walk the strings of time?
And do you understand this?
There aren't any strings of time.
Thank you.
OK, I needed to know that.
It's all in your head.
OK.
I needed to know that.
Thank you.
And then, how do you learn?
And there's been several times, three times in my life
that I've disappeared in front of people.
Don't know how I did that.
What's that about?
I have no idea.
Like, I swear, physically, they were standing right in front of me,
and they didn't see me.
So, I don't understand that.
You don't understand that?
No, but I could with a little research, yeah.
Could you?
Are you teasing me?
They didn't notice you.
They didn't notice her.
I was standing right in front of them.
They were interested in something else.
You were boring, so they looked elsewhere.
Oh.
Thank you.
You're a blessing to me.
No explanation.
Yeah.
It's happened three times, and it was really befuddling to me,
and I wasn't quite sure what that was about.
Oh, yeah.
I can see what you mean.
Yes.
Thank you.
You're a blessing.
You wondered if you became invisible for a few minutes.
What was happening?
Yeah.
We'll take one more, and then we'll continue.
Hello, Doc.
You want something signed?
And Susan.
Hello.
Yes.
Gosh.
Thank you so much.
Yes, indeed.
And please may I have your blessing?
Yes.
Yes, yes.
God bless you.
Coming from this side.
Dubai.
OK.
Everybody and his brother's in Dubai nowadays.
Next thing you know, we'll have to go to Dubai, for God's sake.
OK.
I think that's exactly it.
One more?
Is that it?
Run.
Run, Rabbit.
You told us we were the last ones.
All right.
Hi.
I was going to ask, I work in the medical field, and I was wondering how, as a medical
professional yourself, you were able to do self-healing, because you commented in your
office series about giving lectures on hypoglycemia, and then you fell back into it, and you had
to stop giving the lectures.
So how are you able to handle that?
Or should I change my occupation?
I don't know if you understood what I wrote or not.
Well, I don't know what the question is.
Well, she said you conquered hypoglycemia.
Yes.
I functioned on hypoglycemia.
I gave up sugar and sweets.
Right.
Yes.
OK.
So that helped with that.
Yes.
But he didn't really conquer it.
Well, you said that after you started giving lectures again on hypoglycemia, you couldn't
split your mind.
So I was wondering, as working, like, in a hospital, would I be able to do my own self-healing,
but also work in a hospital?
Or would that be the same as splitting?
Just stay off sugar and sweets, and that's all, is the whole thing.
Well, it's not a big deal.
It's not a big deal.
It's not about that.
That was your example.
Mine's like with a heart issue.
So I'm like a cardiac nurse in that setting.
Would I be able to still do self-healing with a heart issue and work as a nurse?
Oh.
Would you be able to release it as a belief system and at the same time cater to the world
which gives it reality?
Exactly.
Yes, you could do that.
Oh.
You have to understand that heart patients have their own clients.
Yes.
They're not just their own karma, but you're there to help with their karma.
Anyway, no, you can split the two.
Okay.
You can cater to what the world believes and not believe it yourself.
Cool.
You know, you're playing a part in their karma.
Especially in the medical field, you have to pretty much go with what the program calls
for.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
I just wanted to thank you for your teachings and a bit of blessing.
Thank you.
I want a picture also.
Yes.
You have your own medical field back there.
And being a nurse and helping others, you devoted yourself to help others.
So, you know, in a way, you're playing a part in their karma.
Just like I don't wear glasses anymore.
The only problem is I can't see very well.
Life is funny.
Life is hilarious.
All right.
That's been very good.
Anybody else?
Yeah?
Are we done?
Someone has left their purse up here on stage.
Okay.
Thank you.
Bye.
Okay.
Thank you.
You want to hold it up?
Someone has left their purse up here on stage.
I don't know who it belongs to.
Okay.
Do want to calibrate the lecture?
Oh, if you want.
To calibrate the lecture, would you have permission to calibrate the lecture.
It's over 500, 520, 540, 560, 565, 570, 565?
Yeah.
565.
Someone has asked us to do an omni.
All right.
to do an um they want you to do it no no we're not going to do it okay we're not going to do
the um but we will shake hands so if you want to lighten up we'll do the hand shaking oh that'll
do you baby yeah okay we got to get up and move a little bit you notice we say om and not um look at
this little guy look at this little guy i think this may be somebody else's cup not ours what what
do we do now honey um you're gonna go down here this way i better take it with me my right foot
is killing me today for no reason out of the blue we're gonna we're gonna clear this and you better
behave too everybody's gonna go this way go that way come down this way please it's gonna be clear
in just a minute this is this is for beating off dogs
small children and devotees yeah okay give me your hand love
god bless you that's your sweetheart i miss her
oh i've been seeing you all the time yeah yeah you love it okay can't help but love her
hi hi god bless you thank you god bless you oh look who's here
he snuck
surreptitiously into line how did he get in there
god bless you god bless you god bless you love god bless you god bless you love god bless you love
hey god bless you god bless you sweetheart yes god bless you god bless you hey god bless you
oh god bless you and god bless you and god bless you and god bless you and god bless you
And God bless you. God bless you, love. God bless you, sir. Yes. God bless you, sweetheart. God bless you, love. God bless you. Oh, God bless you. Sweet talk will get you nowhere. God bless you. Yeah, God bless you.
Ah, God bless you, Lord. God bless you, love. Hi. How are you? God bless. God bless you. God bless you. God bless you, sweetheart. Oh, yes. Oh, yes. Hi. God bless you.
There was somebody else from Dubai. We have more Dubai-ers here today. Several in a row. We'll open a branch office in Dubai. When you leave Dubai, you can say goodbye Dubai.
That's right. Goodbye. Sweetheart, yeah.