Hello. Hello. Thank you.
Some of you have been asking if we have a bookstore,
and if you go right out here,
you'll see the sign on the door that says bookstore.
So anyway, it's off here to the left, my left, your right, whatever.
Anyway, it's right up there. It says bookstore.
So we do have a bookstore, and all the material are available there.
Must be time for a joke.
So I'll have to tell you the black mamba story.
Did I ever tell you the black mamba story?
A friend of mine that liked to collect exotic animals,
he had a dog.
It was a guard dog, and when he let it out of the car,
he would say to me, stand still, don't move.
Anyway, so he had a, as I say, he liked exotic animals.
People get to throw all those things.
So he had a black mamba.
And the black mamba lived in a big cage, you know.
And those were the days when LSD was around, you know.
So anyway, this friend of mine did LSD,
and all of a sudden, the black mamba starts talking to him.
And the black mamba says, I'm friendly.
You don't have to keep me locked in this cage.
If you let me out.
I will be very gentle with you.
So, no, no, he said, I'm not letting you out.
The black mamba gets very disappointed and says,
well, you don't even trust me.
I mean, what kind of a friend are you and all this kind of stuff?
So he thinks about it again.
So he calls a friend of his.
He tells the friend of his, this black mamba says, it's safe.
You can let me out.
What should I do?
And this friend of him says, don't believe me, he's lying.
Where's the light?
Where's the projection?
Okay.
That's a true story, a true story.
Good friend of mine.
Very good friend of mine.
Yeah.
So we see that one teaching of the Buddha is that you should be grateful that you're born a human
because of the karmic opportunity to undo negative karma,
and acquire good karma.
So being born a human is rare, fortunate, and the consequence of good karma.
So instead of cursing your human existence, say, oh, why was I born, and all that kind of stuff,
you say, well, this is a world of great opportunity because I can choose to condemn
or I can choose to forgive.
So the fact that we have freedom of choice then means we can understand that there's a lot
of good and bad in this world, and we can undo the negative and gain positive karma.
Therefore, the best spiritual advice is to be kind and loving towards all of life and
all of its expressions.
And so if you're going to be beheaded, you say to the headsman, thank you so much for
doing a very good job.
And bless him at his work.
All right.
Then there's another viewpoint.
Okay.
The world is a trap of illusion.
Therefore, salvation depends on non-attachment to its linear and emotional qualities.
Now that's only at 230.
The world is a trap of illusions.
So that's sort of a negative view of it, isn't it?
It's not really a trap.
The only one who's trapped is your belief that you're trapped.
Actually, you're completely free, and you don't have to follow.
Okay.
So that's the trap of illusions.
But you see that from the wolf in sheep's clothing and what you see depends on what
you project into the world.
So the perceived world is the result of the projection of human consciousness and therefore
akin to a Rorschach card.
As a psychiatrist, that's the way I used to think of it very often.
One person would see everything as hateful.
another person would see everybody as trustable, and so people seem to project onto the world
their own inner state of mind. So how can you transcend this situation where you're either
trapped in your own illusions? How do you know that you're perceiving reality at all?
And I just got through telling you about the chimpanzee and the white tiger and the friendly
lion. They look friendly and trustable, and each one of them ended up savaging or killing a person.
So how can you find out what the truth of it is? Frankly, without calibrating it, you can't.
We hate to tell you that, but that's a fact.
Yeah, the true reality of the world is unknowable only to the ego, but to the spirit,
it's quite knowable. The world is really a rare opportunity for maximum spiritual growth,
so the best thing to do is be thankful and give thanks to the Lord for this lifetime,
because in this lifetime I can undo the negative and gain the positive. The world is a rare
opportunity for maximum spiritual growth. Undo the bad and the earning of the new. That calibrates
at 510.
that's a very trustable teaching. 510 is a very trustable teaching then. Let's move on to the
next slide. The world is, one of the last books we published, we give about 40 different ways of
seeing the world, I think 35 or 40, but we didn't calibrate any of them. So I thought it'd be
interesting to go back and pick up a number of them that tend to be prevailing and calibrate
them. So although some of them are stated in the book, there are no calibrations given in the book,
it just says there's, you know, at least 35 different ways that you can choose to view the
world. So I thought it would be interesting then to calibrate them. So to say the world is a
meaningless kaleidoscope of sensations, and that all meaning is fairly projection, calibrates only
at 250. In other words, it's true to a certain extent, it's kaleidoscopic.
And sensations, the fact that it's meaningless means that all meaning is projected onto the
world by yourself. In and of itself, it lacks any intrinsic meaning. This is also true only
on a certain level. On another level, it is not true. The world is not really essentially
meaningless unless you understand by what we mean by meaning.
All meaning is something you impose upon the world. The world in and of itself
has no intrinsic meaning to the average mind. The more advanced mind, with the meaning of the world,
is the presence of divinity as the perfection of all that is. But by that time, a person is
very advanced to see that the world is an expression of divinity.
The world is the theatrical stage for the comedy of the absurd.
This is a common presumption. Often it's part of humor, you know. Absurdity is part of humor.
The world and human life are the consequence of the fall of Adam and Eve due to disobedience
and succumbing to the temptation of curiosity. Life is therefore penitential
for the absurd. The world is the theatrical stage for the comedy of the absurd. The world is the
original sin. Calibrates at 190. So that's a certain interpretation then of the Bible, is it not?
That Eve fell for the temptation of the serpent and pulled Adam down with her. Did she do that?
Oh, blame it on Eve. No, blame it on the serpent. Blame it on the serpent. Blame it on Eve.
and leave the guys alone, you know.
It's interpreted, interpreted then
as punishment for disobedience.
I have never agreed with that viewpoint.
I always thought that intrinsic to consciousness
is the nature of human consciousness itself.
Within everyone's consciousness
is really the consciousness of the child.
The reason you believe anything is that within you,
without its layers of sophistication,
is still actually basically the consciousness of the child.
Not different than the child's, but just not elaborated.
So basic to everyone within oneself
is there's still the innate, pure consciousness of the child.
So my interpretation of that story
is that the serpent was aware
that the consciousness of the child
still resided in Eve.
And so he appealed not to her disobedience,
but to her curiosity.
Trust me, I won't hurt you.
You can trust me, you can trust me.
And so I feel that she was the victim
of her own innocence, inner innocence.
Because of her innocence, she did not suspect
that anything other than innocence prevailed anywhere.
So I saw it like she was sinless.
I see it as sinless, like a sophistication,
like a being aware.
That the innermost layer of the mind
is childhood innocence prevails in everyone.
And it can be manipulated by evil.
We know that by Bernie Merkhardt.
What's his name?
Bernie, the super billionaire ripoff?
Madoff, yeah.
Yeah, Mr. Madoff.
Madoff with what, $500 billion?
Trusting people's money, see?
So how did they get away with it?
Because within each one, there was the child
that wants to believe in the goodness of the world
and is trusting.
And the child within us is trusting.
So we have to be careful.
It's not just the evil of the world,
but the innocent trustingness within our own inner child.
So it's our own inner child that gets us into trouble
a good deal of the time.
First of all, the inner child is curious.
Secondly, it doesn't know anything about evil yet,
hasn't lived long enough.
And therefore, it doesn't think to be on guard.
It would not even guess that a good friend
would rip you off for millions of dollars.
It would not suspect it.
So some of us have a hard time getting over
that intrinsic innocence of the child.
And we have the tendency to be overly trusting
and trust others who are not really trustworthy.
What is the world?
The world and humanity were created by God
and are therefore divinely inspired and intrinsically holy.
Wow.
That is certainly a more positive view of God.
Than viewing creation as punishment for original sin.
So I'd rather pick this view.
Plus the caliber is a lot higher than the original one.
545 is a lot better than 190 or whatever the other one.
The world and humanity were created by God
and therefore divinely inspired and intrinsically holy.
When the ego subsides,
the intrinsic beauty and purposefulness
and perfection and holiness of all that exists
shines forth like a radiance.
It shines forth from the world itself.
It's like you witness it.
It's like the world is illuminated
and the energy of luminosity
shines out of everything that exists.
And when you first perceive of it,
you have to pull your car over to the side.
That's what you saw that day, right?
And I remember when I first saw it too.
It stopped everything.
And I really wasn't able to function for a period of time.
The intrinsic beauty and perfection of all that exists
shines forth because all that exists is God.
All that exists.
There's nothing that exists that is not God.
But the divinity of his essence does not shine forth
because we tend to reject onto it
our own perceptions and belief systems.
Our own perceptions about the world.
A more limited view then.
The world is merely a physical product
of the physical universe.
This is the pedestrian scientific viewpoint.
And there are professional atheists.
Some of them I suppose are humorous too.
And they're professional atheists
and they poo-poo anything,
any other depiction of the universe
that the world is merely a physical product
of the physical universe.
That the world is merely a physical product
And God is an illusion.
God is an illusion.
And the professional atheist feels sorry for us.
Who's that comedian that comes out
and ridicules God all the time?
You remember his name, Gabe.
What's his name, do you remember?
Huh?
Oh.
That world's an illusion.
You think you see.
Huh?
Philmar?
Phil.
Billmar.
Billmaher.
That's it.
Yeah.
He's a funny guy.
But, you know,
he likes to ridicule anything
that is not just strictly
the most pedestrian physical view
of the world, you know.
So his view of the world,
his view of the world,
I have permission to do this,
the view that he presents,
I have permission to not calculate this,
calibrates at 190 resist.
All right.
So the view that he pervades to the world
is 190,
that it's just a physical phenomena
and that God is just an illusion.
Yeah.
All right.
So there's quite a big difference
between seeing the world at 545
and seeing the world as pedestrian materialism.
So this is what we call, you know,
the materialistic view of the world,
mechanical materialistic, 190.
Next we have life and humanity
are purely accidental products
of Darwinian biologic evolution.
So this view that he pervades,
projects,
and this particular view
is called mechanistic reductionism.
It calibrates at 190.
This is a physical universe.
It's a physical universe.
It's nothing but a product of physicality,
an expression of physicality.
So that's Darwinian mechanistic reductionism.
So in the schools,
we have now a conflict
between the different explanations of evolution,
between creationism, creationism,
and Darwinian, Darwinian biologic evolution.
All right.
So then we have a more,
a more sophisticated view.
Survival is due to natural selection
by the survival of the fittest.
Intellectually, that's true.
The survival of the fittest.
If you got bigger teeth than the rabbit,
you survive and the rabbit does not.
Yeah.
Some of these are such comical views.
I just love them.
The world and the universe
are merely passing illusions
created by the ego
to keep itself separate from God.
220.
That's it, 220.
In other words,
it's sort of true,
but not really totally true
or overwhelmingly true.
But this is sort of a spinoff
from some spiritual teachings.
The world and the universe
are merely passing illusions.
What it should say is
how you see them
are merely passing illusions
created by the ego
to keep itself separate from God.
I've never agreed that the ego,
the ego does these things
merely to keep itself separate from God.
The ego does itself
because that's the biologic nature of the ego.
Can I have your arm?
The ego does that
because that's its biologic nature, resist.
It doesn't know anything about God,
so how could it do what it does
in order to keep itself separate from God
when it doesn't even know anything about God?
So that's a presumption
which I've never agreed with.
I think it's part of the course of miracles, too.
Anyway, I've never agreed
with it
because, first of all,
it would have to know the answer
to the whole conundrum
in order to have created the conundrum.
You would have to know about God
to keep yourself separate from God,
and if you knew about God,
then you wouldn't be just a secularist,
so you see it's a self-defeating conundrum.
It's a fact
that the ego does
then maintain
its separation from God,
but not,
not because that's its purpose,
but because that's the consequent of a fallacy,
but its purpose is not the fallacy.
The fallacy is a fallacy
because it's a fallacy.
Otherwise, you'd have to know the answer of it
to deny it.
You understand what I'm saying?
Yeah.
Human life is an expression of God's will
by which the Godhead fulfills
the actualization of infinite potentiality,
calibrates at 560.
All that is,
is,
all that is
is not only created by God,
all that is,
is God.
All that is,
How it is perceived, then,
would be a positionality,
but it's reality.
So we see that
the intrinsic divinity of all things
shines forth.
When the ego collapses,
the radiance of divinity
shines as the essence of all that exists
shines forth
like a blinding light.
You almost step back from it like this,
because suddenly the awareness opens up to you
and you have to pull your car over
to the side of the road.
The intrinsic beauty and perfection
of all that exists.
You say,
certainly this box of Kleenex
cannot be an example of divine perfection.
Is this divine perfection?
Walgreens?
Walmarts.
Oh, Walmarts.
Well, that's different.
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
What strikes you at first
when this phenomena begins to unveil itself
is the stunning realization
that it is.
That it is.
That anything is.
It's the stunning realization of existence.
To exist as this,
or exist as this,
doesn't really make that much difference.
Like, these are flowers,
and these are flowers,
and these are flowers.
What's stunning is that they exist at all.
That anything has existence
is the first stunning thing.
So, as I look at these flowers,
I can't let myself look at them too long
because the divinity of their beauty
begins to shine forth
and you end up,
you stop talking
because you're, like,
unable to speak at the splendor
of the revelation of such incredible beauty.
So, after a certain degree
of divinity,
a development of inner awareness,
you go past a certain stage,
to function in the world,
you have to pull back to a certain degree.
In the state that you were driving
around the side of the mountain,
you can't, you know,
drive into the city
and drive through Phoenix
in that particular level of consciousness.
You'd have to get off the road.
So, these states of consciousness
tend to come
and then they recede
because if they continue,
it's almost impossible to function.
In a state of divine illumination,
it's almost impossible
to function in the world.
In fact, it is impossible
In fact, it's hard to even stay in the world
because in that level,
you have permission to leave
and you see you're not a physical body,
so you're not going to die anyway.
It's just that you depart
from the physicality.
All right.
Human life is an expression of God's body.
It's an expression of God's will
by which the Godhead fulfills
the actualization of infinite potentiality.
The infinite potentiality of divinity
is to be anything and everything.
To be a flower
or to be a thing that you wave in the air.
I like this next one.
It's a fun one.
Man descended from the stars
and fell from the heavens.
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
Ooh.
Ha, ha, ha.
Man fell from the stars
and descended from the heavens.
So that's a descent.
And then we have the next one,
Darwinian biologic certitude
that man descended from the monkeys.
Man descended from the monkeys.
Ah, poor monkeys.
They always got to blame for it.
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
A monkey once said to me,
don't blame me.
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
Don't blame me.
I had a monkey.
I had a monkey for years.
It was funny.
A macaque monkey.
And I also had a kinkajou.
A kinkajou is a South American honey bear.
Well, I lived alone then.
And so I got this kinkajou.
And the kinkajou is a South American honey bear
with a long tail.
And he hung on a cage over my bathtub.
And I would be gone.
I forget whether I was going to school
or working, what I was doing then.
Anyway, and the kinkajou
was sort of,
his fur got more dull.
And his eyes didn't have the shine.
And he sort of lost his appetite quite a bit.
Just sort of lethargic.
So I thought,
well, he's lonely probably.
That's what it is.
So I went out
and I bought him a macaque monkey.
So I got him a monkey for a friend.
So the monkey hung in a cage
on another big hook over the bathtub.
So here was the macaque monkey
and here was the kinkajou.
So the monkey didn't like the kinkajou at all.
And would start throwing things
at the kinkajou.
Anything he could get hold of,
he would throw it.
Throw it.
And the kinkajou instantly came to life.
His fur got nice and shiny.
And his eyes were bright.
And he was very happy.
So I guess, right,
he missed companionship.
Well, one day,
to finish the stories on the kinkajou,
the kinkajou is a South American honey bear.
And he's got a long tail.
And they're friendly and nice and fun.
And they climb all over you.
Well, I didn't know it,
but they're basically alcoholic.
So those were my drinking days.
I had a bottle of whiskey,
a decanter with wine or whiskey,
I forget,
sitting in the window.
And one day,
he got the lock off his cage
and he got out.
And when I came home,
he was laying on the floor drunk.
I looked him up in the encyclopedia
and various things,
and it said that they are naturally alcoholic.
And they will find fermented fruit
and get drunk on it.
So they grow in the jungle
and there's fermented bananas
and they get kooked on bananas
and then kooked on the next thing.
So anyway,
he got drunk and I came over.
He was just passed out.
And I picked him up
and put him back in his cage
and he slowly came back with a hangover.
Funny thing about six,
nine months later,
he got out of the cage again.
The Kinkajou figured out
how to open the cage again.
And when I got home,
he was lying on the carpet drunk.
No, he was lying,
no, he was,
he had knocked the bottle,
the decanter over
that I had the whiskey in before
was now empty.
But he'd gone over
and knocked over that decanter.
So he was going right back
to where he'd gotten the whiskey before
and knocked the decanter over.
He had a decanter rope only.
This time there wasn't any in it,
so he wasn't drunk.
But I thought it was so interesting
how one life form
energizes another life form
just by virtue of their existence,
just by virtue of the fact that we are.
So one of the,
you say,
what good am I?
What good can I serve the world?
Of what worth am I?
The first worth you have
is that you are.
Wow.
Is that nice to think of?
Everybody agrees,
nice to realize that you are?
Anybody here doesn't want to be?
It's nice that everybody wants to be.
It's nice because you already are.
You see how screwed up you'd,
it would be if you didn't want to be
and you actually you are.
Of course, later on you could look back
and say, well, at least I was.
Or the next thing,
can I ask our nation,
at least I will be again.
All right.
The world and earthly life
are the optimum avenue.
For the evolution of consciousness
and human form.
From its animal origins
to its spiritual enlightenment
and salvation.
Man is therefore the crossover
from the animal to the angelic.
So it says,
although it's true,
it's not a truth of a highest nature.
It's only 255.
The world and its human life
are only one dimension of existence
among many other possible dimensions
and that's 450.
So you can see that
there is a degree then of election.
Each one of us has elected.
Let's verify that.
We never verified that one.
Each one of us has elected
to choose this human existence.
Each one of us is elected.
We've chosen.
Okay.
Each one of us,
our own free will has chosen to be here.
Wow.
Goodbye alibis.
Alibis.
Each one of us may not remember it.
We don't remember that moment
in spiritual evolution
that we agreed and chose to reincarnate.
Is that okay with everybody?
Anybody protest?
No protesters?
Unfair to humans?
I was like,
whatever happens on this planet,
there's always protesters.
God bless the protesters.
They had a certain,
aliveness to everything.
If you have a carnival for goodness
and giving away free money,
there'd be protesters.
There's always protesters.
That's why I never go to a peace meeting
because of the protesters.
It's so violent that I'm afraid to go to them.
All right.
The world represents the fusion
of the linear and the nonlinear
and the actuality exists
outside the domain of time,
and causality.
All right.
So we were sort of saying that before.
Causality is a projection
from the human mind.
Everything is happening of its own
autonomously and spontaneously,
and nothing is being caused
by anything else.
What's happening is potentiality
manifests as actuality.
So the potentiality
of everyone in this room
is to become enlightened.
Potentiality.
For everyone in this room
is enlightenment.
Resist.
No excuses.
Everyone has chosen to be here.
So the next time you feel down
and discouraged
and everything is going wrong,
you ask yourself,
now why did I choose to be here then?
If everything is so screwed up
and I'm so hopeless
and the world is so screwed up,
why am I here?
Why am I here?
To ask yourself that periodically
is the basis of wisdom.
What is the basis of wisdom?
What is the meaning of my existence?
What is the truth of my existence
to the degree that I can know it?
And then one day comes an understanding.
But the understanding is nonverbal.
It's just an awareness of how
that which could have been is.
At the same time, that which is
originates that which could be.
It's not a one-way street.
It goes in both.
It goes in both ways.
It goes in both directions simultaneously.
The world offers the gift of life itself
via beingness and existence,
whereby consciousness is made experiential
and thus reified as the ultimate reality
out of which arises a capacity
for existence awareness.
Wow, that is a mouthful.
What in the world does that mean?
It means we're here.
We're here to discover the spiritual reality
behind our sense of existence
and discover that it is the reality of God
that has become manifest
and that it's experienced as the self.
So we have the self with a small s.
That's the one that we beat ourself up about.
And then there's the self with a large s.
The infinite self with a capital S
is the source of consciousness itself.
Consciousness doesn't identify in and of itself,
does not identify itself as separate
or an individual in the first place.
It's the human, the introduction of the humanness
that makes the mind assume that that which is is me.
That which is is called me.
And I've given you the story of the cat before.
You know, the story about the cat.
And you tell the cat, the cat says, who am I?
And then you tell him, you're a cat.
How many of you have heard this story before?
Anyway, anyway, the cat's, you tell,
I can't see anything out there,
so I presume some ants went up.
So you tell the cat what a cat is
and you get the encyclopedia
and you read them all four or five pages on the feeling.
And you get a little bit of a sense of who's a cat.
The cat says, I don't know why this story is going on.
And you help me find animal world, et cetera.
And the cat listens respectfully,
and then at the end he says, but that's not who I am.
And you say, well who are you?
And the cat says, I'm just me.
The thing I like about the story
is it crystallizes all of this into sort of a comical story.
That what each one of us really experiences,
The only thing you're experiencing is that you're experiencing.
What you're experiencing of is irrelevant.
Whether you're experiencing your hand here or your hand there,
or this is a Kleenex box, that's all irrelevant.
What's of interest and what's significant in value
is that you're experiencing, period, that you are experiencing.
So therefore, by reductionism, you can get back to the point
that which I am is not different than experiencing.
Therefore, that which I am, in reality,
is always experiencing and experiencing.
You experienced it that way when I was a kid.
You experienced it that way when I was rich, when I was poor.
When I was sick, I was well.
That which you are is experiences your own existence.
To experience your own existence.
Eventually, we say, how do I experience?
Experience that I experience.
How can I know that I know?
The spiritual reality of the self is due to the reality of God.
Experienced as the self.
God imminent.
So it's because of the self with a capital S
that the self with a small s presumes that it is me.
It is because of the presence of God within.
Were it not for the presence of God within,
you would not have consciousness.
Without consciousness, you would not know that you are.
Everyone presumes that their consciousness is innate to their existence.
Everyone presumes that everyone knows that they are.
Many things are, but don't know that they are.
Let's see if that's true.
Many things are, but do not know that they are.
In fact, there are many humans who are,
but are not conscious that they are.
That would always be fuddled with people.
People would say,
how can that be?
How can you be and not know that you are?
Because they are without being aware of their own existence as existence.
That's a lower level of consciousness, below 200.
They are, but are not aware that they are.
If you look at it, you can understand that later.
All contextualizations of the world are conjectural orientations
as life is lived solely by subjective experience.
That's true.
To a certain extent, 225.
It means it's true.
It's not overwhelmingly true.
It's not spiritually true.
What is the world?
Man is just a highly evolved hominid,
and therefore merely a biologic species and genus.
And spirituality is a product of imagination.
That's about 160.
All spirit.
The Skeptic's Bible.
What is the Skeptic's?
What do they write?
The Skeptic's Bible?
Is that the name of that book?
The Skeptic's Dictionary.
The Skeptic's Dictionary, yes.
All right.
The Skeptic's Dictionary.
Gallup reads about 160 or 170.
And that's the kind of where they come from.
Merely a biologic spirituality is a product of imagination.
That's a very interesting book
because everything that is spiritual gets ridiculed in that particular book.
Because from that particular book,
only pedestrians,
and physicality is real.
And anything beyond the most mundane consciousness level 170 or so is unreal.
Man is an environmental disaster.
And the sooner he self-destructs and returns the world to nature,
the better.
We saw that this morning on television.
This is the sort of crazy environmentalist.
The crazy environmentalist is worried about,
this morning on TV,
was worried about,
the sheep in New Zealand are belching and passing intestinal gas
and emitting methane into the environment.
So help me God, this is true.
The environmentalist says we should all become vegetarians
because to eat animals, you got to have animals.
And the animals pass gas.
I could laugh into a vulgar joke right now, but I won't.
That was this morning's television, right?
Environmentalist.
Sheep are belching.
They said belching.
Or come out the other end, he said.
So anyway, either way.
Contaminating the environment with methane.
So these people think that the environment is God
and that God is vulnerable.
So anyway,
the extremes to which people can go are really quite interesting.
You know,
there's some people who say,
I forget what they're in India.
I think they put a cloth over their face
so that they won't accidentally inhale bacteria
and thereby kill the bacteria.
They do.
They wear a thing over their face so they won't inhale bacteria
because they don't want to harm the bacteria.
So these are people that have not accepted something within themselves
that is profoundly human, humor.
I mean, human.
And they have demons.
They've demonized it.
So this is what in psychiatry is called a reaction formation.
The fact that you are so far over on this side
means that you're really over on the other side, you see.
All right.
Man is just a highly evolved hominid
and therefore merely a biologic species
and spirituality is a product of imagination.
That is a current political positionality.
Sooner he self-destructs and returns to worldliness,
the nature, the better, calibrates at 120.
Mankind is on a learning curve of biologic social evolution,
calibrates at 450.
So we're on a learning curve.
We're on a learning curve.
So that would explain many of the phenomena.
We can certainly see different regions.
If you calibrate the different regions of the world
and the different countries in the world,
you'll see extreme, extreme differences.
There are whole...
huge sections of the world
that live at consciousness level 160, 170.
They live by death and terrorism
and beheading people and torture
and belittling of children, women and animals, etc.
Then you live...
then there are people that live on the highest level.
They wish no harm to any living being
and they are benign in their viewpoint.
So meaning is a semantic linguistic construction
where no one has the right to say,
well, I'm a person, I'm a person,
and I'm not a person.
So we live in a very coherent reality.
Therefore, any and all statements are equally valid
as part of the current political collapse
of the intellectual basis of the country.
It is...
meaning is more than just a semantic,
although it is on a superficial level,
something that can be superimposed.
Meaning radiates forth when you see...
can differentiate appearance from essence.
When you can see the difference between...
and essence meaning shines forth from the essence so it differentiates
perception perception is what you think a thing is from essence so all the
consciousness work we've done really constantly approaches the same question
it what is the difference between the essence of this and its appearance so
consciousness calibration cuts through appearance and what we calibrate is
essence because we can't all of us discern the wolf in the sheep's clothing
therefore consciousness calibration is incredibly unique it's the first time
actually in man's history other than by divine revelation that man has had the
capacity to discern truth the essence of truth from falsehood that is a fact that
is a fact that
is a fact that so I have great respect for it it's like you've you
so I have great respect for it it's like you've you
so I have great respect for it it's like you've you accidentally fell into something of
accidentally fell into something of
accidentally fell into something of profound significance and application
profound significance and application
profound significance and application which the world doesn't even know about
which the world doesn't even know about
which the world doesn't even know about and which the majority of the people in
and which the majority of the people in
and which the majority of the people in the world wouldn't begin to understand
the world wouldn't begin to understand
the world wouldn't begin to understand even if you explained it to him need to
even if you explained it to him need to
even if you explained it to him need to tell me without even going to where's
tell me without even going to where's
is that place in Cuba? Yes. Without even going there, I can look at the name or a picture of
somebody. I can ask specific questions, where he was, what he did, what he decided, what he said,
what he said yes to, who he served, and what his intentions are when he leaves. I can know it was
certitude. What he tells the questioner could be anything that comes into his mind that he thinks
the questioner will fall for. But what he's really up to, what he's really up to, she doesn't even
have to know. I hold this guy's picture in mind. I say the person I'm picturing in my mind
calibrates under 200. The person I picture in my mind calibrates under 200. He wishes no good to
the United States of America. Resist. He will commit violence the minute he gets a chance to.
Resist. He feels that's his
spiritual demand. He's planning on killing right now. He's going to kill as soon as he can.
All right. How safe is that person to release that I just looked at? He doesn't even know I
looked at him. I got the truth of him. Sometimes even more than the person will acknowledge to
themselves. Without touching him, without torturing him, without waterboarding him,
without threatening him, without impairing his legal rights,
I already know.
I know what he's up to. All I have to do is calibrate him. I can do the same with an animal in the zoo.
I can say this Komodo dragon calibrates that. What does the Komodo dragon calibrate? 160?
I think 160. My old friend the Komodo dragon. You see, the Komodo dragon is not evil. He's not evil.
He's just being what he is. One bite from a Komodo dragon and your death is certain. It's only a
matter of time.
That's because of what he is. So the Komodo dragon is not evil. He takes a bite out of you and then
he follows you for a couple days because one bite from a Komodo dragon has so many incredible
bacteria in it that your death is certain. One bite from a Komodo dragon and you're done.
He waits. It takes four or five days for those bacteria. But then eventually the animal falls
over and now he has his meal.
Not because he's evil. That's just his nature. So to be able to discern truth from falsehood
is extremely sophisticated and extremely rare. Yes? How much time have you got? How much time
have I got left? What? Oh, thank you. One minute. That's all I want to know. Uno. Uno minuto.
I have invented the world I see. There is no, therefore, there is no point in trying to
save the world for the world you see does not even exist. What you think the world is,
the world is actually an opportune place for redemption and salvation. So what the world is
really calibrates very close to 600. What you see is only in the 300s. And if you calibrate lower,
what you will see is a world that's intrinsically evil. So there are two confusing things in the
Bible.
One is evil is in the eye of Jesus Christ. Evil is in the eye of the beholder. Condemn not. Don't
stone the woman because what you see is in the eye of the beholder. And the seeming contradiction
is in the Lord's fray. And you then say, and lead us not into evil. Should it be lead us not into
evil? Don't describe evil because evil is a projection of your own eye. To answer that riddle
will keep you busy next 24 hours.
20, 30 years. So we'll break for lunch and resume at what time? We'll, we'll come back at two o'clock
and avoid evil during lunch. Gloria in excelsis Deo. Praise be to thee, O Lord, most high. Amen.
I prayed for all of us. You don't have to pray now.
Yeah. Now we're going to resume where we left off.
All right.
Tell them about my drunken kitty. You want to hear about my drunken kitty?
Well, I was, I think in medical school and didn't have any money. I lived in public housing.
Anyway, it was $20, $15 a month rent, but you weren't allowed to have any pets. But I had a cat,
male cat. So I thought, Jesus, what am I going to do? So I smuggled the cat in. Well,
he started caterwauling around like a male cat will, you know.
Meow, meow.
Jesus.
You're going to hear it. So what'll I do? I'll sedate him. Ah.
So the cheapest was potassium bromide, you know, and bromo-seltzer. The sedative is potassium
bromide. So I got some potassium bromide and I salted his breakfast food a little bit with it.
When I got home from school that day and I walked into the apartment,
he came walking across like this. He went, meow, meow.
Purring up a storm. Meow, meow, purring. And then he fell over on his side. Plunk.
And he just lay there purring. Didn't even want to get up.
So that's my drunken kitty story. It's funny because it was true anyway.
But he was so happy and content to just be, he was just stoned, you know, just fell over.
Oh lordy. Let's see, where were we? 31. Yes, one's perception of the world,
it's pretty obvious to you now. One's perception of the world is consequent
to the observer's level of consciousness. And at a certain point you see the beauty
and the divinity of everything that exists. At lower levels, everything looks ugly.
and things are looked at utilitarian
and there's a certain level
everybody wants to know
how much is this worth?
You've seen people like that.
The only thing in their mind is money.
How much is this worth?
How much could I sell this for?
How much could I get for this?
How much is your soul?
Oh, okay, well.
All right.
One's perception of the world
is consequent
to your own level of consciousness.
So Nisargadatta Maharaj
when he said
there's no point in worrying
about the world you see
because the world you see
doesn't even exist.
But what he means by that
is you don't see the reality.
You only see what you project out there.
And if you look out there
and see that everyone has
all the resources they need
to survive at whatever
their level of consciousness is,
then at a certain level
of consciousness
it takes very little to survive.
It takes very little
to survive.
It takes very little to survive
because your needs
are very, very minimal.
Your needs are very minimal.
And the human world
is a spiritual hospital
and rehab unit.
That's a pretty easy one to accept,
isn't it?
You know.
The human world
is a spiritual hospital
and rehab unit, yes.
Everybody's here for rehab.
And karma is God's own
bailout plan and rescue package.
Calibrates, we said that
like for a joke,
but it does calibrate
around 350.
It is God's own bailout plan.
And divine intention
is that we have a chance
to undo the negative
and create positive karma.
Undo negative karma
Now we have permission
to ask what I'm holding in mind.
Uh, everyone has had a,
you know, let's say,
the majority of people here
have had a previous
human existence resist.
Most of the people here
have been here a number of times.
The average number is over four,
six, seven.
The average person has had
six previous human lifetimes
that you don't remember.
However, in an altered state
of consciousness,
you can remember them.
Past life, recall.
There are very specific
techniques of past life recall.
Uh, the Whatchamacallit Institute
in the east of Virginia.
Huh?
Monroe Institute teaches one.
And we've got people locally
that do past life regression.
And in altered states
of consciousness,
self-hypnosis is very simple.
Self-hypnosis,
you just picture yourself
going down the stairs.
You count yourself down.
And when you get to the bottom,
you say, the door will open
and I will,
emerge back into that
lifetime. And you open
the door and you walk in and that lifetime
just resumes. It's not
like the start of a film and the end of a
film. It just
resumes. It resumes.
So
to just be aware that
this is not your first and only time here
of course that's helpful because
if you screw it up you can come back again.
This time you just
don't bet on the horses.
I have a friend. First he got off
alcohol. Then he got on to
pills. Then he got
on to gambling. Then he
got on to women.
It was one
addiction after another.
And it's a good thing
he wasn't really into eating or he'd weigh about
400 pounds.
No matter what he did
he had to do it to an excess degree.
So
this is a spiritual
hospital and rehab unit. It has a
certain reality because it calibrates over
200.
265.
So the one
we said was a joke. God's own bailout
plan and rescue package
has a reality. It's 350.
And of course that's what the Buddha teaches.
So we've
calibrated
a basic Buddhic belief.
Christianity doesn't teach that.
Christianity comes from a different direction
and doesn't get into the whole
subject of karma.
It just has no opinion about it. It doesn't say
yes or no. It just
ignores it.
The world is getting hotter due to
human causes is 105.
So we
don't have to worry about
sheep gas,
moose gas,
elephant gas.
The world is not getting
hotter due to human causes.
And we wrote about that
and spoken about it.
The earth's temperature
ice ages
are due to
the sun's spot
activity on the surface of the sun.
The magnetic activity of the surface
of the sun. And of course
going down
through the ice
going down through the ice you can go to the sun.
You can go through 10,000, 20,000
down to 30,000 years.
And the
earth's temperature is related
to the sun's spot activity
of the surface of the sun.
Right now I think the sun's spot
activity has decreased.
Let me ask. The sun's spot
activity right now has decreased.
Resist. We are not
going into a hot period. Resist.
We are not going into a hot period.
So all that is hogwash
and
and other stuff.
The human world is a spiritual hospital rehab unit.
As you can see one thing is how to discern truth from falsehood.
So partly what we've discovered in our own research
is one of the reasons we came back here.
There is possible to discern truth from falsehood
and that you have within yourself the capacity.
The world won't end on 12, 21, 2012.
Oh that's good.
When I ask people, why are you worried about that?
They always say, because of the, what do you call the calendar?
Because of the Mayan calendar.
I say, well, if you're a Mayan, worry about it.
That only applies to Mayans.
And if you're not a Mayan, forget about it.
As I said before, if I'm wrong, I'll give you a million dollars.
What in the world? What is the world?
The last one.
With the removal of perception, in other words, when you stop projecting out,
and you see the world as it is,
the radiance of divinity shines forth as the exquisite beauty and perfection of the world.
I remember the first time I saw that,
because I had surrendered everything to God,
and was in a high and very,
very rarefied space.
Hardly anybody had ever been there.
I saw a few people had been there over the ages.
And then it dawned on me that I had surrendered everything to God,
but I had not surrendered life to God.
Uh-oh.
So I surrendered everything, all that I have, all that I have been,
all I believe, everything I could say about myself.
And then I said, this too,
I surrender to Thee, O Lord, and I laid down my life to God.
And, as I've described before,
there were a few moments of very intense agony,
extreme agony, as I felt myself dying.
And I was dying. That which I had been died.
And then, suddenly,
the door opened up, and the exquisite perfection and the radiance of divinity shone forth.
It was like blinding.
It's like the beauty is so stunning, it just knocks your back on your feet.
The radiance, the divinity, the perfection of all that exists.
In ordinary life, we blind ourself to it for,
because for one thing, you can't really function in that state.
And I didn't.
I didn't function for quite a while.
I didn't function for years, even.
And, uh,
but when you, when, by revelation, one sees
the true reality of, of life,
that is the exquisite perfection of all that exists,
is due to the fact that all that exists is divinity.
Everything that you see here is an expression of divinity.
Divinity as this table. Divinity as this paper Kleenex.
Divinity as this soda bottle. Divinity as this pointer.
Divinity as the coffee. Divinity as Susie.
You see divinity as me?
Yeah.
You better.
You see the perfection. You become aware of the perfection of all that exists.
This is because you let go of judgmentalism.
You don't process anything.
You see, one part of consciousness is the processor.
It doesn't just see a thing. It instantly processes it.
That processing happens in one ten-thousandth of a second.
And it's very hard to get ahead of it.
In a high meditative state, you can suddenly cross.
See things as they are before the processor gets to it.
The processor comes in one ten-thousandth of a second
and edits everything.
As it's perceived, it's edited as fast as you perceive it.
Therefore, in ordinary life, what you're constantly witnessing
is what your consciousness has processed.
You're not seeing what is.
You're seeing what has been processed in one ten-thousandth of a second.
It's been interpreted, labeled, given a name, made right or wrong, pro and con, anti.
In one instant, one can catch it, however.
And I've told before, the time I caught it, when a rabbit ran in front of the car,
and just as the rabbit ran in front of the car, my foot pushed down on the brake
and stopped the car, brought the car down.
And I caught that I did it before I thought of doing it.
And I caught the ego trying to take credit for saving the rabbit's life.
No, the foot went down and slowed and saved the rabbit's life.
And then the ego jumped in one ten-thousandth of a second and claimed credit.
So in the higher meditative states, what happens is you eventually cross over
the processor.
You see everything as it is, not as it has been processed.
Belief systems are so powerful, they're like a television set.
They interpret and process everything.
You see nothing as it is on television because everything, the angle has been selected,
the lighting has been selected, the sound has been selected,
the verbal description has been selected, the politicalization has been selected,
the grammar has been selected.
Thousands of selections have occurred before you even get a chance to view it on television.
So when you say you saw it, you didn't really see it.
What you saw was a processed interpretation of it with multiple slants.
You know, why they even picked this particular scene to take a picture of.
I mean, in the selection of it, they're saying this is important,
this contains a hidden message in the visual imaging, in the soundtrack, whatever.
So what we see is an edited world.
Within ourself is the processor, which is pretty much like a TV production studio.
It selects what to consider important, how to interpret it, how to feel about it, etc.
All right.
It comes to you once in a while in a meditative state, not necessarily formal meditation,
but a time very often when you're walking along in the woods.
And not thinking about anything in particular, and all of a sudden time seems to stop.
The whole woods become silent.
You can hear every leaf fall.
It's magical.
Everybody here had experiences like that?
Where suddenly the world is like mystically beautiful?
Everybody?
Thank God.
Thank you, Lord.
Time comes to a stop.
Judgementalism stops.
Mentalization stops.
And now let's say the old-fashioned tape recorder,
you recorded it and then you heard it come out the other end.
And that was already edited within one ten-thousandth of a second.
And when the processor stops, you hear it the way it's coming into the recording machine,
not how it comes out of the monitor.
All right.
So that is a divine state.
I think it occurs from 600 and up.
I think that state occurs from 600 and up, right?
So that state occurs, consciousness level 600 and up,
where the internal processor stops processing information
and just experiences it as it is,
with no intervention, with no editing, right?
With the removal of perception, then the radiance of divinity shines forth
as the exquisite beauty and perfection of the world.
That calibrates at 645.
So the experience that you had, we calibrated it, right?
It was 700, like that.
All right.
So when you have those experiences, you're seeing the world the way it is.
If you can remove yourself from the world,
and I had such opportunities in past decades to leave the world
for periods, prolonged periods of time,
I didn't have to function in the world,
and a divine state would take over.
And because you didn't have to go anywhere or do anything,
you had no responsibilities,
I didn't have a television set,
I never went out or read a book,
you could stay in this divine state for prolonged periods.
And such periods.
And I lived by myself in a relatively large house.
And as I said, I would forget there was a body
or had any connection with the body.
And when I passed a mirror, I saw somebody in the mirror,
and it scared me.
I didn't know who was in the house.
There's someone in the house.
And another time, as I've related before,
I tried walking through a wall,
and the physical body smacked right up against the wall.
It's because you no longer identified
yourself as the physical body.
So these are the expanded states of consciousness
that we strive for with meditation, fasting,
religious and spiritual techniques and rituals,
which we hope to increase
by the advancement of our own level of consciousness.
Now, is there another slide we'd have to do?
Uh-huh.
That's it. Oh, good. That's fine.
That's where I wanted to end up.
All right.
We were going to discuss something
because we have a little time before the question and answer starts.
And then we'll ask for questions from the audience later.
Yes?
Oh. Do you want this thing?
No. Okay. All right.
So, later we're going to have questions and answers from the audience.
And first, we'll just have some that we've been given.
And Susan has some that she wanted to bring forth.
In regards to our lecture. Thank you.
Yes.
So, you know, in the world, but not of it.
So, are you saying, you know, with all of us facing, you know,
mortgages being repossessed and the panicking of jobs being lost,
and what would you consider our approach to those everyday,
you know, grocery bills going up?
What would you consider the approach to that
as a spiritual person?
How should we approach those challenges that are in the everyday world?
I think by non-resistance, by acceptance.
You accept the fact that there's nothing but peanut butter and bread in the house to eat.
So, you got peanut butter and bread in the house to eat.
So, what is your complaint?
So, in a purified state, you let go wanting to change anything.
You let everything be as it is.
And then see the perfection and beauty of all that exists.
And know that God supplies all that is needed.
And if something further is needed,
it will be provided or you will be moved to go for it.
You know, something and you will say,
I think I'll look in the top shelf, there might have been a box of crackers
and by God, there is.
Okay.
Because, you know, so many of us are facing, you know,
challenges as far as it goes.
And it's not, it's not who we are.
It's the world outside of ourselves that are producing all these challenges to us.
So, it's a little difficult sometimes to have faith and let go.
Well, it's what we perceive as challenges.
It's a threat to the things that we're attached to.
So, if I'm worried about something, that means I've become attached to it.
So, what I do, anyway, what I do personally is I surrender my attachment to it
or my belief that I need it for happiness or for life itself. Okay?
And the things that people desire and crave for are really niceties.
You know, when it comes down to reality, to exist, you really need very little.
I existed for months with, I had a six-pack at that Pepsi
and a piece of cheese in the refrigerator.
That was it.
You might be malnutritioned, but...
Well, you see, that again would be judgmental and all.
So, you have malnutrition. So, big deal.
You get beriberi and your teeth get loose and so, let it go.
I'm talking about, you know, a devoted spiritual yoga, you know, where...
Don't forget, for years I had the opportunity to leave the world
and do nothing but pursue a spiritual goal and direction.
So, I was willing to let anything go and I did.
Let go of just about everything.
Even almost let go of the physical body permanently.
And then something said, well, you ought to reown it.
You ought to reown it.
So, I said, well, yeah, all right.
So, I went back in and reowned the body again.
But I was perfectly happy to leave it there.
So, could it be our attitudes?
Our attitudes are not the best in these harder times
that we're just not looking at it from the proper viewpoint then?
Well, we try to let go our attachment and our aversion.
Our attachments and our aversions.
And see that they're really frills.
Most of them are frills.
Saying, you know, I couldn't live without a soul.
So and so.
Well, you could.
Of course you could.
You don't need your mittens.
You can keep your hands in your pockets.
So, what do you need mittens for?
You know what I'm saying?
And so, after a while, you find out that what you actually need is very little.
What you actually need is very little.
And eventually, you cut down to whether you even need the body at all.
And that's a decision.
The times that I've had to make a decision about that.
Were mainly in a state of bliss.
And there was no necessity.
First of all, I'm not the body.
Secondly, I've experienced my own immortality.
That which I am has always been and always will be.
So, I didn't need the body for anything.
And then, the fact that others needed me at that moment made me resume the body.
Now, from a very advanced point of view.
Consciousness, spiritual position.
I should have released on that too.
So, when I was like free, you know, in a snow bank.
I was in a state of bliss.
And it was ten below zero, whatever it was out, blizzard.
And I hollowed out this space in the pile of snow by the side of the highway.
And I crawled in there to get out of the wind.
And after being in there a very short while.
This delicious sense of warmth and exquisite beauty.
And the radiance of light suffused.
And that which I am, I experienced as forever.
That which I am has always been and will always be.
And there was no need to resume the body.
The body was superfluous.
If you're eternal, what do you need a body for?
So, but then my father came and shook my ankle.
He'd followed my paper route and found me there.
And I had to make a decision.
If I was going to breathe and resume the body or not.
And I saw that if I didn't, my father would think that he was responsible for my dying.
So, I couldn't allow that to happen to him.
So, there the love was an attachment, you might say.
And from the highest, most advanced realm.
I should have left the body then and let him worry about his feeling of loss of self.
It's his problem, not mine.
But each time I resumed the body like that, it was always for the sake of something or someone else.
Yeah.
So, in the end, love can be an attachment.
In and of itself, it is not.
But one can also become attached about it.
Yes.
So, actually, what we need to do is go back to basics.
What are the basics?
What do, you know...
In essence, what do you really need to survive?
What do you really need to survive?
So, as far as it goes, it's hard times.
You know, people are losing their jobs and can't find work or whatever.
Yeah, the depressing news.
But like you, you were in the depression and you had three different jobs you were doing at one time.
I mean...
Well, that was during the last big depression, yes.
Well, I was sort of...
You know, born that way, sort of a driven self-sufficiency.
So, when other people can't find a job, I always have two.
I know.
I always had two jobs.
You know, I was a cab driver during the day and a bartender at night.
You know what I mean?
And on the way home, I'd put a newspaper.
I mean, I always had two or three things going because that was just the vitality that I had.
You know, I don't take any credit for it.
It's just the way I was put together in this lifetime with a certain drivenness and determination, go-go-ness.
Yeah.
And, well, the pressure, it seems like...
I don't know.
I look at people and I see that so many of them...
Their wants are so large.
Okay.
You can't hear me, huh?
Their wants are more a lot of times than what their earnings are and, you know...
I have to have that car and I have to...
And then I'll be happy.
And then I have to have this house and then I'll be happy.
And then I have to have, you know, this pool for the house and then I'll be happy.
But then when they get all that, it's always another thing that they're not happy with.
Yes.
That's...
The error of seeing happiness is something outside of yourself, something to be gained.
Happiness, the value of things is purely a projection, each and every thing of its own.
You know, if you were starving to death in the middle of the desert, the Hope Diamond wouldn't do you much good.
No.
So desirability then is, you know, is called glamour, the energy of glamour.
It's projected onto things.
We think the attractiveness is out there.
There's no attractiveness out there.
All attractiveness is in here.
It's because you desire that and want it and value it that it looks desirable and attractive to you.
Pickled beets look very good to you if you like pickled beets and if you don't, they don't attract you, you know what I mean?
So the projection of value onto the external world.
And that, of course, is the basis of materialism and the whole economy is based on wanting this and wanting that and wanting something else.
And to instill such wants.
If you don't want something, you'll get programmed to wanting it.
And better burial benefits.
Better burial benefits?
They're out to sell you something.
Prepaid funerals.
I mean, right down to the very last thing.
Better coffins, you know what I mean?
So there's no end to programming people to wanting this.
So wanting this is the backbone of our economy.
The backbone of our economy is wanting this.
And when people stop wanting things, it all comes to a halt.
But when you let go wanting the physical, then you want the emotional and you want the spiritual.
What you're looking for, the world cannot provide.
And you're looking for the return of love.
A glance of love is all that you really wanted that entire day.
One glance of love is enough for the entire day.
Enough for a week, if it's the right person.
Like somebody.
Just a glance.
A glance.
See how powerful love is.
Just a fleeting glance of love.
Instantly, your heart swells up, you feel fine, you're great.
But cutting off that glance of love, you look for the love and it's disappeared.
Now you're in the throes of the bottom of the pits.
So you see that of all the values that are out there, love is the one that you crave the most, actually.
You can live without money, you can go bankrupt.
But love is the one thing that we value above all else.
You had said in different lectures that you would go into a mall and you'd see two people
and they'd look at each other lovingly and you'd just burst into tears because you saw that love exchange.
So I understand that, but I don't know if everyone else here has that experience.
As you do just, you know, ordinary spiritual work, these phases come up.
There's the phase of the continuous miracles.
Miracles begin to happen.
Not only do they happen, but they start to become continuous, be continuous.
And then the infinite power of love begins to manifest.
And you see how infinitely loving everything is.
And all that matters is love itself.
And you get to a certain state where you cry easily with love
because a glance of love and it just knocks you out because it's so overwhelmingly blissful.
So you get into a state of bliss, loving bliss, loving bliss.
And some spiritual gurus get into the state of loving bliss and stay there.
Some stay for years.
Some withdraw from the world and just stay in that state of loving bliss.
Loving blissfulness.
Yes?
A lot of times we get questions from people that in the first book, Power vs. Force,
we wrote that, you know, that there were about 12 gurus at that time that were,
they were above 700.
And a lot of times people send us emails to that effect as to who they are.
That was at that time, yeah.
Right.
And so can you explain to them why we don't mention their names and why?
Well, you know, we don't like to get into it.
We can do it anonymously.
Anonymously.
Right.
Okay.
Right now, we have permission to ask this.
Right now, there's more than three people over 700.
Four people.
Six people.
Eight people.
What did I say, over 700?
Yeah.
Okay.
There's more than six people over 700 right now.
There's more than five people over 700 right now.
Six people.
Yeah, I think that we've got five or six.
And mostly they live all over the world, you know.
There was one in Indonesia that calibrated extremely high.
I never did find out who it was, but I knew he was there.
So, all that it does is counterbalance the extreme negativity.
Because, you see, even one person at 700 counterbalances, you know, practically millions
that are below 200 because the radiance from the energy field is so enormous.
And that radiance goes out through the vibration of the consciousness of the teacher, radiates
out.
And the student picks it up in their aura.
The student picks it up in their aura.
And it stays there and may not become manifest for several lifetimes.
But you can pick up the aura of a very advanced teacher.
And then it becomes, its full effect may not become manifest for a few more physical lifetimes.
And then suddenly the radiance comes forth.
Can you pick up the aura of the teacher in just reading or videos or?
Can you pick up the aura of the teacher in those?
I've never been happy with the answer I get for that.
It's actually picked up from the physical presence of the teacher.
Okay.
Yes.
All right.
So, what about meditating with the picture of the teacher?
Right.
Okay.
Meditating with the picture of the teacher is almost as good as the physical presence.
Almost as good.
Oh, that's surprising.
Oh, that's a very happy finding.
Yes.
We haven't asked that before.
No, we never asked it.
But that's traditional.
And you know, having incense and a picture or a statue, you're invoking the spirit of the teacher and identifying with the spirit of the teacher.
And the most powerful of all is that you pick up the vibration, the frequency vibration of the aura of the teacher and you pick it up in your own aura.
And there it stays for lifetimes.
Well, a lot of cultures, other cultures.
Yeah.
When you go into that high state, there's places you can go to be in that high state.
And here in the U.S., of course, we don't recognize a lot of the East Indian religions.
And so, there's a lot of no place for people to go like that, which is very difficult.
It's not a cultural tradition here like it is in, let's say, India.
Right.
So, is that why you say that we should carry that with us as a…
Yeah.
As a subconscious in our mind?
Because you say to carry it with us kind of as contemplation rather than…
Oh, rather than meditation?
Than meditation.
Well, I said in today's world, meditation is not to, you know, protracted meditation.
It really requires withdrawing from the world and going to unique places.
What can you do to the utmost and still remain in the world?
Right.
What you do is you practice all the spiritual disciplines that you can and you spend a
great deal of time in contemplation rather than meditation.
Because meditation, you have to withdraw from the world.
And I don't advise meditation when you're driving.
You know what I'm saying?
So, contemplation is more practical in today's world.
Okay.
Explain contemplation.
When you say contemplation, I want to know what you mean when you say that.
You say, but what is exactly do you mean when you say contemplation?
To me, that's kind of holding it in mind, but not in the present mind.
It's kind of in the back of my mind constantly.
But what do you…
What's your interpretation of contemplation?
Contemplation is more, you know, like a daily word where there is a statement of a spiritual
truth.
And now during the day, you sort of tend to hold that in mind and keep returning to
it and maybe even pray about it.
God, please reveal to me what is the true meaning of this and how does it apply to my
life, etc.
So, contemplation is something you can do almost all the time.
All the time, no matter where you are.
I mean, as I'm talking to you now, there is going on within the consciousness the letting
go of any desire to change anything.
The lighting is as it is.
Your voice is as it is.
The audience is as it is.
So, there's the letting go of any intention to make anything different than the way it
is and to be totally accepting that the light may not be as perfect as I want it to be.
Okay.
As perfect as I want it or the question may not be phrased the way I want it or the table
cloth is not the color I want it.
So, the mind is usually trying to be on top of things, change them, make them better,
make them smoother.
The Kleenex box should be this way.
No, it should be this way.
So, the mind is always trying to fix things up.
And as you reach a contemplative meditative state, the way things are is the way things
are.
And if somebody says, you know, that's the end of all that is, just say, well, goodbye
then.
So, it's a little bit like acceptance too.
It's profound acceptance, yes.
Yes, right.
That the world is the way it is and we can't change it.
The world is the way it is and you don't feel called upon to save the world, you see.
People don't feel there.
They're called upon to save the world.
I tell them, well, I was waiting for the second coming.
I'm glad you're here.
Well, it's kind of like that joke that you tell about the man that's being robbed.
It's one of my favorites.
You've got to tell that one.
I don't remember that one.
Where he says, give you my money.
What?
When he takes the gun out and he holds it to your head and says, it's your life or your
money.
Oh, Jack Benny.
This is a joke.
Jack Benny, yes.
Well.
The guy comes up to him and he says, your money or your life?
And Benny says, well, not so fast, no.
Like he had to think about it.
But also, you talk about one where someone, if a robber came up to you and held a gun
to your head and said, you know, your money or your life, and you said, I don't have any
money.
So he would take your life.
And you said, that's OK, too.
Because you're not really the one doing it.
In other words, you're handling the situation.
You know, I always look at the karmic consequence and, you know, and so you do what you can
because of who you are at that moment.
Hypothetically, you might have done otherwise, but you're not a hypothetical being.
You're who you are at the time.
But you said that all fears, if you took away, all fears lead to death.
So any fear that we have leads to death in the end.
I see what you're saying.
If you remove, peel off layer after layer after layer, you know, if I had no money,
I would.
Yeah, to get rid of fear altogether.
All right.
So when you clear a stack of fear, you start with whatever fear is foremost right now.
And you surrender to that.
You're going to get old.
OK.
You're going to get ugly.
Yeah.
You're going to lose your hearing.
What?
You won't be able to see anything anymore.
Right.
You can't climb a ladder.
No.
You can't drive the car because you can't see where the road is.
Right.
So you keep surrendering one thing after another until finally you end up with a so what.
So you don't go anywhere.
People have to drive you.
You can't put on your shirt.
So you won't wear a shirt.
You won't wear a shirt.
To hell with it.
Put a robe over yourself.
Yeah.
This, the surrendering comes up as a confrontation.
If your ideal is to be totally surrendered and released and free of all attachments or
aversions, then that intention will bring things directly to your attention that you
were not aware of before.
You'll become aware of them.
They arise because you're attached to it.
So if you're attached to comfort, then you have to let go of, you know, your attachment
to comfort.
Okay.
Last three or four nights I had to sleep with the steam kettle going in the steam pot,
perking away and gurgling away and hopping and buzzing.
And so I just had to let go of wanting to change it.
Time to get rid of it.
He's talking about a vaporizer.
Yeah.
He's had a cold for the last three weeks.
And this is about the first weekend that he hasn't been too congested.
I said, we have to get over it before Saturday.
That's all.
Yeah.
And you were.
But, yeah, he complained about it bubbling.
Bubbling and popping and talking to me.
Yeah.
When you start getting messages from the steam kettle, you know, you're getting
one.
Yeah.
That's true.
So all of us, when we're in the world but not of it, if we carry that in mind, that
will take us towards the goal which most of us have of becoming enlightened and realizing
that all this is happening outside of ourselves.
Well, Jesus said that, you know, wear the world like a light garment.
He didn't say ignore it.
Didn't say curse it.
Don't pretend that it's all illusion.
It's all illusion, but don't let it dominate your life.
Let your spiritual principles dominate your life.
And what the physical world is like is of only passing and minor significance.
The fact that you're rich today or poor today is, you know, of interest but not decisive.
You're not going to live or die according to that.
Rich men die and poor men die.
So not to be too attached.
Not to be too attached to anything in this world.
And to see that desire is a projection.
What makes a thing attractive is not what it looks like but what you project onto it.
Like Gabe and I don't like red cars.
Bright red cars.
We'll be driving along and I'll say, Gabe, do you see what I see?
Oh, he says, that's disgusting.
We play a game called bright red cars are vulgar and we hate them.
We like green cars.
We like blue cars.
We hate red cars.
Bright red cars are terrible.
So we pretend, you know, we play this game of having a terrible aversion.
And Gabe will say, I'll tell you what's ahead up above.
I said, no, no, I don't want to even hear about it.
There's a bright red pickup truck.
Oh, I said, no, no, no, don't tell me.
So you play the game of aversion, you see.
So in other words,
people that have worked so hard and they have this,
they finally bought this house that they thought they needed
and to find out that, you know, they lost their job,
they're not going to be able to make the mortgage and everything.
So it's an attachment to a style of life.
Yes, that's it.
It's the attachment.
And you can have them and lose them and life will go on just the same.
You see, and how long are you going to mourn it?
You have to mourn it until you let go of your attachment to it.
Okay.
So you think the mourning is due to the loss.
The mourning is due to the fact that you're attached,
not due to the loss, but attached to what you,
if it was your favorite fishing tackle and you dropped it in the water
and your favorite reel went to the bottom,
there's a feeling of loss that was your favorite fishing reel.
But it's not due to the fishing reel,
it's due to your attachment to the fishing reel.
And if somebody gives you a new one just like the one you lost,
you quickly recover.
So it's the feeling of loss of attachment.
And the attachment is really to the happiness involved with it.
When I had that reel, I was happy.
I could be a happy fisherman.
Now I've lost my reel.
I can never be a happy fisherman again, you know.
So you write this whole scenario and then you grieve the scenario.
If youth is the only thing that could make you happy, you know,
where would we be?
In high school.
I haven't been at 18.
I haven't been 18 for quite a while.
It's almost time for us to quit.
All right.
So all the things of the world.
So what Jesus is saying is he doesn't say ignore the world.
He doesn't say, like some people do, pretend it doesn't exist.
He doesn't say pretend it doesn't matter.
He says allow it to matter but only lightly.
You miss it a little bit.
You wish you had your old fishing reel back.
But life goes right on and you're just as happy by dinner time as you would be.
Once in a while you get a little pang about your good old fishing reel.
But your life really goes on.
So to be in this world, so it means respect the world.
Some people get into spirituality and they disdain the world,
which I think is incorrect.
I think it's incorrect to put the world down and make it evil or make it physical
and make the world wrong.
And then to pretend that it doesn't matter and that it doesn't exist is also wrong.
So the thing I liked about Christ's teachings is it seemed,
you know, in my living it through myself,
to be respectful of the world, appreciate, thankful of the world,
and to be in it but not of it.
In other words, not tied to the worldly world.
Because if you're tied to the worldly things,
then you're going to be run by television advertisements around the clock.
To respect the world, appreciate the world,
give thanks for its blessings,
and then have a higher purpose that takes you out of the world.
So whether the world is here or isn't here won't really affect you that much.
It's more convenience.
I like that teaching.
Wear the world like a light garment.
And I think that is, it allows you to contemplate and walk about your business
and at the same time not be tied into a knot.
You know, somebody didn't smile at you when you went to work this morning.
Oh, she didn't even smile at me.
I wonder what she means by that.
The whole day is poisoned now by paranoia.
I wonder what they meant by that.
I don't know.
It's their problem what they meant by it.
I don't care what they meant by it.
You know what I'm saying?
.
Smile at yourself in the mirror.
That's more important than having other people smile at you.
Give yourself a smile.
Everybody here, I pledge you to smile at yourself in the mirror next time you look there.
Everybody agrees?
Good for me.
God bless you, George, Herbert, and Serena, Pinky, Polly, whatever your name is.
Okay.
We're going to take a quick.
What?
Phoenix on it.
There's a white van with a phoenix on it, and the custodian has your keys.
Okay.
We're going to take a quick break, and then we'll resume with question and answers.
It'll be 15 minutes, and if you could please line up on this side for question and answers.
We will take question and answers and pictures at that time.
On the right-hand side of the auditorium, if you have any books that you need signed,
we will do that also.