What are we going to discuss today?
I don't know.
Okay, who's going to be number uno?
Numero uno.
Hippity hop, hi.
How are you?
Hello.
Hi.
I just wanted to say thank you.
Thank you for saying thank you.
That's it.
What do you want me to do?
Oh, sign that?
It's hard to see.
Hi there.
Hello.
I was wondering if you could speak briefly about what the significance is of Lucifer,
in particular as related from theosophy,
that there are some interpretations that the fall or descent was actually a beneficial thing.
I don't know.
That's a theory.
I doubt it myself.
How does he know it's beneficial?
I don't know.
That's why I'm asking.
Yeah, I've never come across that interpretation.
That it's the fall, we should thank Lucifer for our fall.
For his fall, for sacrificing his place in heaven, apparently.
For us?
Evidently.
Then he wouldn't be Lucifer, would he?
I guess not.
Okay, thank you.
If he sacrificed himself for us, he'd be Saint Lucifer.
Yes.
Hi, Dr.
Hi, Susan.
We have some little gifts for your animals and for you guys, some chocolates and some
doggie bones.
You mentioned in the beginning that you had a bird, a dog, and three cats.
That's correct.
Here we got bird treats, cat toys.
We don't know the size of the dog, so we just got these bones.
Broccoli for broccoli.
Since you have broccoli, we got you broccoli.
Oh, that's for broccoli.
Oh, how nice.
She loves it, too.
Yeah?
And we know you love chocolate.
We love chocolate.
But we didn't know what kind, so we got you from hazelnut to white to dark to coconut.
Oh, my gracious me.
Oh, my God.
And a pen to write more books.
Oh, yeah.
And a pen for each direct book.
A lioness for Susan and a little cute piggy for him.
Thank you.
To write those books.
But we don't have a question.
Yes.
I was just wondering if you could bless this for me and if I could just shake your hand.
Go ahead.
I'll do both at the same time.
God bless this lovely necklace.
Amen.
Thank you.
That's wonderful.
And could you bless my children?
I have four of them.
Lindsay, Brittany, Joshua, and Jessica.
How about your new car?
You want me to bless that?
Hold them in mind.
Okay.
Dear God, we ask for blessings on that.
The beloveds that are being held in our mind.
Amen.
Thank you.
And I just wanted to see you both again.
And I wanted to see.
Your eyes are like blue diamonds.
And I love you so much.
I love both of you so much.
Thank you.
And through the grace of God, through you.
If it wasn't for you, I'd still be sticking needles in my arms.
I'd still be living on the street and going to jail.
And because of you, I have a new life.
And I just, I love you so much.
Thank goodness.
Thank you and God bless you.
Thank you.
You see, the reason for addiction.
Alcohol or drugs, is that, you remember that scale of consciousness goes from the highest to the lowest.
Well, the drug or the alcohol suppresses all the lower levels of consciousness.
And therefore, it allows only, you experience only the higher ones because the lower ones have been suppressed.
You know, that's not coming from the drug.
It's just that that's the way you would be in a more advanced state of consciousness.
So what the drug does is suppress negative feelings.
And it allows you to feel elation and happiness and joy, which is what you should be experiencing all the time anyway.
So what you do is through spiritual endeavor, you reach those higher states of consciousness without the aid, without having to suppress or depress the lower feelings.
That's the purpose of the 12 steps.
Let go of resentments, live one day at a time, and stay with the group spiritual energy.
I want to say thanks, first of all, so much.
Thank you.
And my question is, I'm still having a really hard time.
You talked about it so much in previous lectures, but integrating spirituality with, like, work and stuff.
I still, I don't know, it probably just takes time, but, like, I really understand.
I mean, I don't know if I understand, but I appreciate the profundity of the lectures and everything.
But I still have, like, a desire for, like, lots of money and stuff like that that I can't seem to shake off.
Lots of money?
Well.
Not so much that, but just, like, I don't know.
Success.
Yeah, just, like, success, sort of, in material.
Oh, I was going to give you lots of money.
Oh.
I'll tell you, I used to live on Millionaire's Row, and those people shot themselves with the same frequency as people in the poverty section of the town.
Yep.
So happiness, then, has nothing to do with material possessions, because even if it was material possessions, what you're experiencing is the joy of accomplishment,
which is non-material.
It's non-physical, you know what I'm saying?
Mm-hmm.
Thank you.
I might get a picture, too.
Of course, if you've got a lot of money, you can't live in subsidized housing.
When I was a student, the county had subsidized housing.
I lived there for $15 a month.
Two bedrooms, $15 a month.
Can't beat that.
That was on the GI Bill.
Oh, you signed that one.
Yep.
Yes.
So, first, I just wanted to express my gratitude.
That you elect to stay here and be our teacher and guide and to your support staff who makes all this happen.
And I was wondering if I could hold someone in my mind, if you could tell me if they are an accurate muscle tester.
If they can accurately...
Do a muscle test to see if the person you're holding in town is a muscle tester.
I don't know how accurate it would be.
You don't think so?
I don't know.
We'll ask the arm.
Is what she's asking possible?
Resist.
All right.
So, you got the person in mind?
Mm-hmm.
All right.
We have permission to ask about the person she's holding in mind.
That person is an adequate muscle tester.
Resist.
No.
Thank you.
Maybe they get...
Go take a picture.
Sometimes when you first start out doing muscle testing, you sometimes get higher figures than what you should.
Do you think that my...
When you first start out...
When you first start out doing the muscle testing, you sometimes get a little bit higher calibration or figure than what you should.
And it's easy to do because you want the best for everybody.
So, it's a common thing.
So, you know, sometimes you're not right on.
But could I be the weak link in this test because I'm holding them in mind and I might not...
Yeah, you might be.
Okay.
We've never done that before, so...
Yeah, I didn't know if that was possible.
It's possible to test them out.
Yeah, it's possible.
Okay.
Thank you.
The testing technique itself, you know, we'd have to do a whole lecture on that again sometime.
It's very, very simple.
And yet people screw it up.
I don't know how they screw it up.
It's because it's so simple.
Okay.
Can we take a picture?
Oh, yes.
The problem is that purity...
People can't resist putting their intention on a thing.
And it's rare that people can just be objective.
And what they want, they want a certain answer.
So, they're trying to prove that that answer is true because they want it.
So, to be detached has to be scientific.
Yeah, I'm not sure I...
Scientific detachment means you don't care how many molecules there is in there.
You have the computer figure it out.
Whatever it is, whatever it is.
So, you've got to be detached like that.
I find most people are not that detached.
First of all, the reason they're asking the question to begin with is because they're not detached.
So...
Makes sense.
They say, this stock is going to go up.
The reason they want to know that is because they own a bunch of it.
All right.
Well, thank you.
Hello.
I just wanted to thank you.
My question is, I'm having a lot of trouble letting go of my judgment.
Judgmentalism and my spiritual ego.
Letting go of what?
Judgmentalism.
Oh, judgmentalism.
Judging of everything and it's constant commentary going on all the time and I don't know how to let it go.
Well, the thing to do is let go of it from your perspective.
In other words, what you don't think is correct or right or something maybe just right for the other person.
So, there's no way of knowing.
There's no way of knowing.
Well, let's see.
You see somebody angry and expressive and now you think they're wrong.
Well, that person spent three years in psychoanalysis learning how to be aggressive and assertive.
I remember the first time I told somebody to F off and gave them the arm.
I was jubilant.
I told them off.
I told them where to go.
I was happy as a...
I was happy as a lamb.
I was wondering if you could sign my course book.
Your cookbook?
My spiritual cookbook.
That's right.
That's a neat cover you have on.
I like that.
Thank you.
Yeah, I remember the first time I gave somebody the finger.
I was just jubilant that I was so assertive and aggressive.
Oh, dear.
Before that, I was always afraid of offending somebody.
You know what I mean?
I didn't want to breathe in and out for fear I would offend somebody.
My goodness, this is a book you must read.
Look at his tatters.
Okay.
Thank you.
This is my picture.
If you could sign that.
Sign that.
Oh, goodness.
There's a good...
Oh, he has a white sharpie here.
There's a good looking guy.
Who is that?
My question was about, are you familiar with the Self-Realization Fellowship?
And if so, what do you think?
What do you think about their lessons?
What's the Self-Realization Fellowship?
Obviously, you're not familiar with them.
No, it's a problem...
Yucca Nauticus.
You wrote the autobiography?
I'm not familiar with it as an organization.
You're asking me about an organization.
The Self-Realization Fellowship organization is what you're asking me about.
Yes, I think the last time I went near that, it's in the high 500s.
Self-Realization 500 is over 580, 575.
I don't know.
570.
Self-Realization Fellowship is over 565.
Yeah.
It's in the high 500s.
565.
What about Yogananda's teachings himself?
Who?
The founder.
Yogananda.
Yes.
Yogananda's teachings itself.
Yeah.
He's on the list up there.
He's like 570, 575, 580, 590, 585.
Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious.
Pretty high then.
Thank you for your time.
I appreciate it.
It was nice meeting you.
Oh, wait.
This is for you.
Oh.
Of course.
Yeah.
Autobiography of a yogi it's what he's asking me about.
Yes, I see.
Been so many years, I forgot it.
How long ago?
Yes.
Dr. Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
I just wanted to tell you that I love you very much and I'm really happy to be here.
Thank you, Susan, for sharing the experience.
I had something similar happened to me.
I was lying in bed and I was waking up.
This light came.
Okay.
Thank you.
So you know what happened?
it was like coming from within me and it came up and it just lit out the whole
room yes and it was like I felt like I couldn't breathe that's it and I didn't
know if that was the self like the big self you didn't know if it was what well
it wasn't the small one was it but just you sharing your experience yes that's
the experience of the presence of God itself with a capital S okay thank you
very much could I just touch your hand yes thank you well all day I was very
teary and just like I felt like I couldn't function I was just crying a
lot but I was happy yeah and nothing has come close since like absolutely
nothing about ten seconds that was it and just you sharing that just brought
it up within me today so fine yeah I'm getting an echo here it's hard to hear
the person speaking
okay
pick one yes yeah I have a question uh but uh the constitution you said was
700 and what is 700 the constitution so I may have to repeat okay yes
constitution of states of America yeah the second amendment all manner to
create arms is being you know uh people are for guns and against guns and uh I'm
a retired policeman and I've always carried a gun and I wondered you know it seems like from the
from my point of view, that the freedom of the country
is important for people to be able to bear arms.
Yes.
And I don't know, because there's so many people
seem to be against guns, which position is more true
or right?
Well, from what position?
The right to bear arms, let's see.
Let's just, we have permission to calibrate it.
It's over 450, 480, 500, 490, 495, it calibrates around 490.
In other words, that would be intellectually correct
and certainly would fit into the intention
of the Founding Fathers, that we should have
all the freedoms possible, except when to do so
would put others at grave risk or cause them
to lose their freedom, you know what I'm saying?
That would be my readout.
I'll put a link on it.
Thank you.
Been a lot of years since I packed that .45.
When the Navy would stand watch, you know,
we were in the South Pacific, you didn't have to wear
many clothes, it was so hot, so I'd be on night watch
totaled to four or something, and all you had on
was your shorts and your duty belt with a loaded .45
caliber and your holster.
A holster and your holster.
And your holster and your shorts.
Hello.
So, my question is regarding demonic energy.
And I just wanna know what the first step
in eliminating that kind of energy
and how it influences my actions and how to get rid of it.
Well, you lead a pure life.
And if you lead a pure life, the negative energies
will leave you because you become distasteful to them.
So, what you do is lead a pure life yourself.
Surround yourself with positive, pure energy.
Associate with people that are spiritually advanced.
Hang out with spiritual groups.
There's nothing demons hate worse than angels.
Hang out with angels and the demons will leave you.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Flies always hang around garbage, you know what I'm saying?
Yeah. Yeah.
So, you lead as pure a life as you can yourself.
Yeah.
Demons don't like spirituality and purity
and all those things.
Yes?
I wanted to ask if the person on that card
can accurately answer questions
through muscle testing with a pendulum?
I can't answer that.
Really?
Hm.
Yes.
I didn't work with the pendulums and all that.
They're all different energy of, you know?
Oh, well can muscle testing be done with a pendulum?
Like-
Why don't you just do muscle testing with muscle testing
and pendulums with pendulums?
So-
Why do you want to mix them up?
It's not the same thing exact,
it's not called muscle testing, or-
Pendulum is one thing, muscle testing is another.
If they're both accurate,
you should get the same answers both ways.
Оokay.
Yeah.
Okay. Okay.
answer both ways can I ask one more question how do you recognize demonic energy and like yourself
or your friends or whatever like if like if you're questioning whether you or your friends are
possessed you know by demons how could you recognize oh I wouldn't play with that game
you could use the same as you do with any other you know I'd say this person is possessed by evil
demons yes or no or if you use the pendulum also your intuition your spiritual intuition should
tell you although some are very sophisticated in the way they present themselves some come on
very holy in fact when people come on super holy I'm always suspicious of them if you're so holy
you don't have to do the whole like you're a movie movie holy person you know what I'm saying
you're just integrous because that's who you are so there's no need to
love you
lay it on people you know two-foot-high crucifixes a foot across and long robes and the sandals and
the Jesus haircut you know forget all that okay thank you can I ask if you know this person
yes you talk about giving people a shot of love what
I
found is that sometimes you'll give people a shot of love and out of the blue all of a sudden you
give them an overdose in which case they will either start crying and come up and give you a
hug or they go into a panic their eyes get big and they went to a panic and they will avoid you
is there any way that you can learn how to give them let's say five CC's instead of ten thousand
CC's don't give or receive love it's not a commodity just be a part of it and it's not a commodity just
be what you are period just be what you are walk around the beetle rather than squish them you don't
have to lean lean over and kiss them scare the beetle if you try to kiss it yeah now if you
respect the integrity of others and treat them integrously that that is loving to treat people
integrously to begin with yes you just tore my ear off
I love your laugh
Thank you very much for being here Dr. Hawkins
My question is I teach yoga in an adolescent psych ward and in the prison system for teens
You teach yoga where?
In the prison system for teenagers and in the children in psych wards at a children's hospital
and what would be my best approach with them because a lot of them are brilliant children
Are really what?
Are brilliant children
Yes
So what can I do to help get them to the next place of health mental health?
Well I can't answer it the way you're presenting it
You're talking about yoga that's one thing mental health is another
I know people who do yoga right and left for you know years in their careers they're in a loon
They weren't so crazy they wouldn't be doing yoga around the clock for years in and years out
Yoga is good if you're going to be a dance teacher
Is there some physical things that I can help them with with their bodies?
Because they're not in their bodies
Who's not using their bodies right?
They're not in their bodies you know the mentally handicapped are not in their bodies
So what can she do?
What are you supposed to be doing with them teaching them yoga?
I'm just doing I'm doing yoga with them but the thing that they absolutely love is relaxation
So in the relaxation it gets them to the next place
I don't get it are you hired as a therapist or yoga teacher or what?
Yoga teacher
A yoga teacher?
Yes
Alright so why don't you just teach them yoga?
Well she's saying in the relaxation and the cool down there's certain terms that you talk about to relax them after they've had this whole
Oh well whatever if that's the yoga then you do the yoga
You know you could maybe inspire them with wonderful thoughts is what I would say
And maybe that would take advantage of that
You could take beautiful thoughts rather than where their mind has been
Okay
That might help
Okay great
You know like a thought like that God loves you all the time no matter what?
Yes or anything like that
Yeah
You know that would help you know if you say that in a certain way you know without mentioning God
It can still be an uplifting experience in a cool down
Right
Yeah I just tell people you're lovable just as you are you don't have to be any different for God to love you
Awesome great I will thank you thank you very much
Alright
Thank you
Thank you so much
Keeping things simple answers most questions
Alright
You're supposed to teach them yoga then just teach them yoga
Nice to meet you
Thank you
Yes
Hello it's nice to meet you
I just want to ask you what is the soul in relation to the one self with a capital S
The soul is the self with a capital S
But there are many souls
That's right
And only one self with a capital S
What do you mean there's many souls?
Do you have multiple souls?
No
I hope not
No when he says self with a capital S
Self with a capital S that is the higher self
The higher self and then there's self with a small s that's the ego
Okay
Maybe it's because of A Course in Miracles when it said that there's only one son of God
And then it splits into many egos and there are many souls
And so I can't put it together
So I can't put it together
It's a breakdown in the language
The languaging oh yes
It's the languaging
Are you talking about the workbook or the textbook?
It's German so it's a breakdown in language
You're talking about the textbook or the workbook?
The textbook
Yes the textbook calibrates less than the workbook for this very reason
The workbook calibrates to 600 the textbook calibrates 550
Hmm
Because there is this hypothetical languaging
The experiential reality is not the way it's languaged in that book
Okay
Thank you very much
Yeah the workbook is much harder than that
There is only one self with a capital S which is divinity
So divinity cannot be multiple it's one
So the multiple is the expression of the one
Yeah
But you don't need to understand it intellectually anyway
So there is only one soul
Huh?
There is only one soul that we share together?
No
There is only one soul within you
Yeah
There is only one
Hmm
Ah
There is only one self with a capital S and that is the presence of God
See
The presence of God is each one is experiencing it as the self with a capital S
But there is only one divinity
Hmm
Each one experiences it as the presence of divinity within
There is only one sunshine shining
Each person experiences the radiance of the sun somewhat differently
That doesn't mean they are different suns
It just means each one is experiencing the sun from their own perceptual intellectual level
Yes
Hmm
Thank you very much
It clarifies it
Yes
Hmm
You go six inches this way for the camera
What do you want to do?
You go six inches this way
Six inches?
Yeah
Good God man
Next thing you want a foot
Ha
First they ask six inches then they want a foot
You know how it goes
So
Then your arm
Then your legs
Then your shoulder
Ha
If it ain't one thing it's the other
I
Yes
I'd like to ask you to bless this
And I'd just like to express gratitude
What?
It's a Buddha.
Yes.
What should I do with it?
He wants you to bless it.
Oh.
I know.
I have permission to bless this Buddha and resist.
All right.
It is blessed.
Amen.
Thank you.
And I just want to express gratitude.
Yeah, first of all, I want to say thank you very much.
And I have a question on guilt.
How do you transcend experience when you experientially feel like...
I'm not understanding.
Speak slow and near the microphone.
When there is experience that you have intentionally gone against the self,
how do you transcend the guilt from that?
The echoes are bearing.
When you intentionally go against the self, and you know you have,
how do you transcend that?
Because she feels guilt over that.
Or you have to...
You have to forgive yourself and decide to do better.
That's it.
Okay.
You decide that you're only human, and human does the best it can.
And it's not perfect in its expression.
So you're tolerant and benign.
You have a benign attitude towards your own self.
It's an honor to be here.
I just wanted to ask you if you could expound more on surrendering the
attachment to self-sabotage.
I'm not reading it.
Self-sabotage.
What about it?
The surrendering attachment to the...
Surrendering.
To where?
What do you mean by self-sabotage?
Just the ego's...
It seems like the ego's always trying to freeze it.
Lack of perfection?
Error?
Yes.
It's like nothing's ever...
Well, obviously nothing's ever good enough for it.
And then it's...
It's hard to surrender the programming behind that.
I don't hear what he's saying.
The programming behind what?
Perfection?
Like shame.
He's carrying shame.
Yes.
He wants to know how does he overcome shame.
Well, he should be ashamed of feeling shame all the time.
You accept the fact that you're only immortal.
And that you're prone to error.
And yes, forgiveness.
And you pray to do better.
Yeah?
Because it's almost impossible to live in this world
and not regret some action, be ashamed of some action.
So you forgive yourself that it's just part of being human.
And that's the reason we're here,
is to overcome these defects of character
and transcend them.
That's all.
So you have to be benign towards yourself as well as others.
See, so it's not only to stop being judgmental towards others,
but to stop being judgmental about yourself.
It's, you know, out of wisdom,
you decide you won't go in that direction anymore.
But you accord yourself the same forgiveness
that you would someone else.
If someone else did that,
would you be willing to forgive them?
Yes or no?
If you're willing to forgive them,
then you forgive yourself.
For being stupid and ugly.
Yeah.
You accord yourself the same forgiveness you would
to your brother, you know.
And say, look, he's an imperfect human.
And he's doing the best he can.
And so we forgive.
We give them in Christ's name.
And ask God to help us do better next time.
Uh-huh.
I first want to shake your hand and her hand.
Is that okay?
Wait a second.
Speak slowly, go ahead.
I first want to shake your hand and her hand.
Is that okay?
Who wants to shake your hand?
Or touch your hand.
Thank you.
We're having really bad audio feedback.
Here, this is a sign already.
My question is, what is the purpose of a mediator?
I have to concentrate on what I'm saying.
Yeah.
What is the purpose of a mediator in what regard?
In the sense of Jesus.
Jesus Christ or Buddha or Krishna?
Oh, yes.
The ordinary mortal would not have the temerity to address divinity directly.
And therefore, Jesus Christ, or an aspect of the Buddha,
acts in your behalf as your advocate.
Pleads your case.
So for Christians, Jesus Christ will say to God
that this is one of my flaws.
And I have taught him, and I will be looking,
and I'll be answerable for him.
So if you screw up, Jesus goes to God about you.
You know?
You're advocate.
Now, there is also a similar representation of Buddha.
In Lotusland Buddhism,
Vala Katsavara is that aspect of the Buddha
that will speak in your behalf before the ultimate.
Right?
Yes?
Mm-hmm.
So when you pray to Jesus Christ as Savior,
how does he save you?
He speaks for you before the Father.
Yes?
Okay.
Thank you very much.
Like a lawyer guarantees to the court
that you will come up with the fine next week.
Thank you.
Thank you both very much, Dr. Hawkins.
You've been inspirational.
I want to thank you.
Thank you.
And I love you both.
The following question is submitted by Rob Corr
from the consciousnessproject.org.
When we go through the process of enlightenment,
for example, leaving the world,
losing interest in worldly things, etc.,
will it be something we realize why it's happening?
And if it occurs to me,
oh, I'm losing interest in worldly involvement,
is that an ego trick?
No.
That is one indication.
You have less and less interest in the world
and the values of the world.
And spiritual values become predominant.
So the fact that you can make money at something
is interesting, but it's not sufficiently interesting
for you to change your lifestyle.
I could make more money practicing medicine right now
than sitting here talking to you, you know?
So what?
Agreed.
You know what I'm saying?
It's irrelevant.
Because, you know, you did that then and you do this now.
You know what I'm saying?
So what's suitable for one phase of life
may not be suitable for another.
There's a phase of life where you should be out there
working your butt off to, you know, pay for everything and all.
And then once you've accomplished that
and realize I can do that anytime,
then you may move on to the next level, see?
So what you're doing may be right for a certain time
of your life, but not at another time.
Thank you.
Yep.
Yeah.
Angel Lewis sends her love.
Yes.
Hi.
My question is, is there any place that God is not?
Is there any place that God is not?
No.
Thank you.
Thank you both for the work.
I know.
It's just remember they're all your friends.
I need your...
That was Greg Daniels.
Greg Daniels.
I need your help.
I'll take your hand.
Here, here.
I need your help.
Here.
Yes.
I didn't answer for her.
Thank you.
I didn't ask for her.
Yes.
Hello.
I just wanted to say thanks.
And I wondered if I could shake your hand.
Yes.
Thank you very much.
Thank you for coming up and saying hello.
Okay.
Straight to the question.
My question is about time.
About a year and a half ago at one of your presentations was almost an off-the-cuff when
you commented that...
at the moment of our birth, the moment of our death is already established. Do you
recall? The moment of your birth, the moment of your death is established. It's set. It's set. Yes. Could you elaborate on that? No. Oh. What more is there to say? Okay, can I put it into some context? No. Okay. You're asking
an abstract question. Is the moment of your death already preset? Okay. We have permission to ask this. Resist. The answer is yes. Resist. Well, may we conclude then from that? I accept that. You've already got the answer. Now, what is the question? Then health care just makes our life more pleasant. You're dealing with the hypothetical. You see, you're manufacturing a hypothetical rhetorical question with no reality. When you do, it'll leave. Bye.
It could be in a car wreck. Yeah. It could be all these other things. So health care is a waste of taxpayers' money because if you're going to croak, you're going to croak. Bye. That's the answer to my question. Hey, we finally got some sound. Thank you. Yeah, I say they're wasting money on these old guys. Their old crocs are going to go anyway. What the hell are you keeping them alive for? The longer they stay alive, the more it costs the taxpayer and Social Security.
I don't have a question. Yeah, we love your laughter so much. And I think you are the cutest and sweetest person in the world. Oh, my goodness. Can I have your hand? Yes. Yes. She's so right.
I just want to say just thank you for being what you are. And I love you. And I need all the help I can get and.
So I just I'm very appreciative. Thank you very much. Yes. Hi. I have a question about resistance. I find that to move from one level to the other, I encounter an awful lot of resistance to doing the things I need to do that I know I need to do. And yet quite often I don't do them. Oh, do it some other lifetime.
Pardon? Do it some other lifetime.
Okay. Thank you. Thank you very much. That's not good for me.
Is he a mean old crab or what? Sometimes. You want him to change, right? Well, I think he wants to. No, I'm asking you. You want him to change, don't you? I see it all over your face. Oh, all right.
Yeah, all right.
Now, to make her happy, would you be willing to do that?
Yes, I guess.
Oh, okay.
If he's working in that direction, at least you know he's trying, you know?
Okay.
My question is somewhat different.
I'm wondering if you'd share your thoughts about the atrocities in Rwanda around 1994.
Is that something you would comment on?
What was behind it?
What is the question?
The atrocities in Rwanda.
Rwanda.
Where they took out all those people, you know?
Oh, yeah.
What about it?
It was a genocide.
It was a genocide, yeah.
So, too much that your comments on that.
What is it that's going on?
Why do...
Genocide, well, in a general way, collective karma, there's collective karma.
A country, a community, an organization.
Jointly agrees to take certain behavior.
And if that's in a negative direction, now they're karmically in debt, are they not?
So, they come back, and this time they experience a volcano, and it blows 3,000 people, all the smithers.
So, there's...
Okay, we'll ask the arm.
There is such a thing as group karma.
What is this?
Group karma.
Well, we know that, but they were asking the question.
There's group karma, where everybody agrees.
Is in total.
In total agreement.
Then there's a certain spiritual cost to that.
So, to undo that, the person may then come back in this lifetime and undo the karma, karmic debt they owe.
If you were one of those who persecuted and killed the Jews during World War II, you may have a certain karmic debt.
And may come back and yourself, perhaps, be killed.
Because of your ethnic origin, or religion, or race, or something, see?
Because people are always saying, how do all those innocent people, blah, blah, blah.
And I always say, they aren't all innocent, or they wouldn't have been, you know, hot lava rained on them.
They weren't innocent.
That's why they were turned into ashes in 18 seconds.
Hot lava, you know, is at 3,000 degrees, will turn you into ashes in a matter of seconds.
Uh-huh.
So, it's not just accidental that there is a pattern, a karmic pattern, in death and disaster,
and why certain groups always happen to be right where the disasters are.
Why are they always right where a tsunami is happening?
Why aren't you on Jones Beach, you know what I mean?
Okay, thank you very much.
Yeah.
Thank you.
It's a group, group karma.
Yeah, group karma.
That which you align yourself.
Whether you take on, you take on some of the karmic consequences of that with which you align yourself.
Okay?
All right.
Okay.
My question is around physical conditions in the body, specifically diabetes.
Is it something that can be, I guess, cured, or can you actually complete the karma of it in this life, or in the body in this lifetime, and how?
Well, in and of itself, it has no specific karma.
There's no karmic pattern that, you know, comes forth just as diabetes.
You know, it's generally more genetic than anything else, you know?
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
And, of course, you do everything you can to transcend it using all the modalities that are available in today's world,
which were not available, you know, decades ago.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
Thanks.
Thank you very much for the work, both of you.
It's so, it touched me.
Yeah.
And my question has to do with my own purpose.
With your own what?
Purpose.
Right.
I've had a landscaping company for 10 years, and I've been called to begin doing spiritual, like, healing work.
And I've started that school, and my heart feels like it's just overflowing.
And I'll get spontaneous pains and so forth in my body, and then they'll disappear.
And.
And so I'm called to that work, and there's such a divinity with that.
And I feel like I still have responsibilities to these other things that I've created in my landscaping business and my home.
And, you know, there's just such a part of me I could just let it go, you know?
And, okay, bankruptcy, fine, whatever, you know, let it all go.
But I think there's some fear there around, you know, perhaps even the karmic consequences of that.
Karmic consequences of what?
Of not holding up to the obligations that I've created to date.
You're going to mow somebody's lawn for the next 30 years, and you feel guilty if you quit now?
That's a really good point.
You're seeing yourself as indispensable.
You're not indispensable.
You can do a trade-off.
Right.
When I closed up my private practice, I found other doctors that would take on the patients, you know?
I don't have to stay in practice forever.
I found other doctors that would take them over.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
Thank you.
You can help them find another landscaper.
Sell the job.
Thanks.
The camera's gone down.
The battery's loaded.
Yeah.
What?
Move the microphone.
Okay.
Yes.
Hello.
There's rocks in this box.
What?
Yeah.
yes
oh they're hearts
these are a gift from
the boulder flock
thank you
we have hearts
in rocks
thank you very much
that's kind of a symbol of
our enduring love for you
very good
thank you
can you put peanut butter on one side
and cream cheese on the other
peanut butter rocks
that's wonderful
thank you
hello
I just wanted to say I'm very grateful
to be here
thank you very very much
thank you for being here
and my question is
I have a dog
who I love very much
and it aroused me
well this question several times
I tell him
I love you so much
that I know that next life
you're going to be a human being
she loves what so much
she loves the dog so much
oh you're a dog
so my question is
is this possible that animals can attain
this level of
unconsciousness
or is only
for humans
or some beings
or
this is my question
can an animal obtain
a karmic
potential
to become a human
oh oh
I got it okay
we have permission to ask this question
an animal's spirit can evolve
into eventually
into a human spirit
it can evolve by getting reborn
in higher and higher realms
gets reborn in higher and higher realms
well thank you I'm very happy
for Domingo
and for all the animals
and for all of us
thank you
yes
didn't you ever say holy cats
holy cats
did you ever say holy cats
no
I don't have that expression
can I have a picture
now that you know
that which is elevated by love you know
the reason is love goes to love
love goes to love
so that which is loving goes to that which is loving
yes
I was wondering if um
dreaming is a product of the ego mind
and as you progress in consciousness
does dreaming stop
I've never done a study on it
do you have dreams
I've never done it
no
I uh
stopped dreaming uh
many years ago
once in a great while
there'll be a slight vignette
maybe a sentence
which I don't know whether it's a dream
or not a dream
yes
do they serve any purpose
like for spiritual growth
I don't know
do you think for spiritual growth
well dreams can be utilized in a variety of ways
psychoanalysis
you know I was in a Freudian psychoanalysis
or Jungian analysis
dreams become quite important
uh
because they're the royal road to the unconscious
and it brings up phenomena that you would not ordinarily consciously think of to bring up
you know what I'm saying
so dreams have their usefulness in psychoanalysis
uh
I've had prophetic dreams
I remember many of you
years ago, I had a dream, which then actually happened in daily life, literally practically
the same thing. As far as their incidents, they've disappeared. I don't know. I don't
dream. I haven't dreamt in years.
Another quick question. I go to college at a small liberal arts school, and a lot of
my friends are probably of questionable integrity, so I can't really do the muscle testing. I
was wondering if you could calibrate if I've had any previous lifetimes, and if so, how
many?
If I could calibrate what?
If you knew them in other lifetimes, and if so, how many?
If I've had any other lifetimes?
I don't know.
Okay. Thank you.
But this might be a test.
Yeah, sure.
You can look at it as a test of your integrity.
Yeah.
Good karma.
Thank you.
There's all kinds of love, and the love of our friends is—
I'm sorry. Your tape is not working.
The love of our friends is—
Yeah.
There you go.
It's one form of love.
Fraternal and maternal and familial love, all kinds.
I have a question about enlightenment, and sometimes I'll at least think that I've
had an out-of-body experience, if I climb to the top of a mountain or—I used to ride
horses, so a lot of those experiences are really vivid in my mind, and magical, even.
And my question is, is it possible to become enlightened?
enlightened and then in some way lose it and then come back to it or is it just you reach it and
you're there well no yeah you're talking about high states you know high states come and go
enlightenment is more in all of a calibratable although altogether level you know saying
so you can have very beautiful states but it's what you yourself calibrate at
because persistently or consistently that determines it you'll have glimpses of things
but that's not where you are permanently saying where you are is how you see and experience life
generally but they can be prophetic of higher states to come prophetic i would look at it as
prophetic first we'd just like to thank you both and everyone else for sharing this time together
today and um if you
find when communicating with others opinions just tend to be coming up in the discussion and it's
just really a matter of just describing how you feel what you think and sharing your point of view
you've said uh or in the material that it's wise just to do away with opinions and uh not have so
many but if you find that it really just eliminates talking with most people in general would you
still suggest just i don't get his question should you transcend opinions no just just when it's a
matter of
giving up opinions oh well you're in a conversation you look at the opinions as something that are
entertaining and they're disposable what opinion you got on monday you can completely turn around
and tuesday have a different one so they're entertaining they're entertaining entertain them
entertaining entertaining they're entertaining in other words my opinion on spirituality may be
different than your opinion on spirituality but we can really have a good conversation about it
because you're going to give me
your opinion i'm going to tell you about my opinion but it doesn't really change it really
doesn't matter it really doesn't matter it's just a conversation it's the content of consciousness
and not the level of consciousness itself yes the level is one thing and the content is another
yes i'm recovering from cancer colon cancer and i suffer some
uh anxiety at times and i'm just wondering if you could give me a few pointers do you take
tranquilizers no why not i don't know well how incapacitating is the anxiety oh it's not
incapaziting it's just it makes me uh it's mild yeah is it like fear it's fear of recurrence for
your consequences yeah that's normal yeah it brings on diarrhea which i had for six months before and i
it brings on diarrhea which i had for six months before and i don't want that again
don't want that again no but i would try to treat it first you know because its origin is number one
physical i would treat it physically of course it has its psychological applications as well
and the fear of death being the most primary and when you let go and surrender the fear of death
then you'll be left with less of it at the bottom of all fear is the fear of death itself
and even beyond that is the fear of non-existence which is not impossible once you are you are
and with your here or there in a body or out of the body becomes sort of irrelevant after a while
yeah if it's due to a medical condition i would look to see if maybe my medical tranquilizer
would be of help if its source is physical you know yeah but it could be anxiety just about
life and survival
and future pain and disfigurement
and all those things
and those are psychological
so you try to increase your faith
and in whatever
spiritual pathways you're following
and then trust in God
and whatever occurs is karmically
determined anyway
yes
hello thank you for your work
I was wondering if it would be relevant
if we could ask the question of course
and miracles would be beneficial
for me to do
ok
we have permission to ask this
the course of miracles would be beneficial
for this man to do
can I ask about the text
and the workbook
do the workbook
I just say do the workbook
alright thank you very much
thank you so much
there's also groups that meet on the course
discussion groups on the course
it's not so fun if you join a group
together
and the groups are fun you know
you get to share your experience and your understanding
try to figure out what it means
that's it
yep
thank you
he's not going to fall off something there is he
is that the edge of the stage there
no they just marked it so you could see
the edge goes out of the way
it was in the camera shot though right?
yes
thank you for remain to teach us
and thank you for help him to
keeps me in line yes
hello
we love you Dr.Hanekans
what?
we love you
oh
yes
thank you
I don't think it's possible to take you home physically
but please send loads of energy with us
where is your home?
Indianapolis, Indiana
Indiana?
yes
oh
Indianapolis
we're going to come over there Dr.Hanekans
if you can
bless you
you come over yes
we want you to touch your feet
I have to see if I can move now
okay
I get stuck in the chairs and all
oh
God bless you
Amen
God bless your reverence
I could feel you from down when you were sitting over here
ha ha ha
I could feel both of your energies
yeah
the energy of India is very distinctive
the sacred is
ultra sacred
yes
hello Dr.Hanekans
hello Susan
thank you very much
thank you Dr.Hanekans
I have one question in two parts
in the Long Beach
when you gave the
I'm sorry
you said in the last
seminar that I attended
that
Jesus came
to give us salvation
and Buddha came to give us enlightenment
and I want to know the difference
for a personal question
she wants to know what
the difference is
she doesn't understand the difference between
coming for
salvation and enlightenment
salvation is
that Jesus came for salvation
to give us salvation
and that Buddha came to give us enlightenment
you said
yeah well you asked the question
that's the answer
okay
no I wanted to know the difference
I just don't know what the difference is
between salvation and enlightenment
alright
salvation means that you're remaining
pretty much the same except that
like your sins have been forgiven
or undone
and
but it doesn't mean you're enlightened
enlightenment is a very advanced state of consciousness
so
forgiveness means that your sins are forgiven
your sins are forgiven
you understand that
yeah that would mean like in the Catholic Church
when they told us that
that
well I had a little misunderstanding then
because
if Jesus came to give us
forgiveness like you said
our sins were forgiven
but we still were suffering
but you still are what
suffering
she says there's still
I don't understand
there's a difference between suffering and
salvation
oh okay
maybe that's where I'm mixed up
yes it is
salvation is
you can't obtain enlightenment
without salvation
salvation is the forgiving of all sins
forgiveness of sins
all the past karma
the forgiveness of sins
Jesus Christ
not karma
sins
the forgiveness of sins
enlightenment means to transcend all of that
oh okay
because there is no personal self
to experience salvation or the lack thereof
there is no personal self according to the Buddha
you understand
yes
so what is there to save
if there is no personal self
who and what is going to be saved
I know I understand that
okay
now my question
so the Buddha is enlightenment
because he went beyond that
Buddha is enlightenment
Jesus Christ deals with people who are not enlightened
still think they see themselves as sinners
and prone to error etc
I understand that
and their need is more for
and their need is more forgiveness
and after forgiveness
they could then come back
and do a post-grad course in enlightenment
okay
I get it now
I understand now
now is my personal question
I was born and raised in a Catholic
and after
even I got married
my first marriage in Catholic Church
later on in my life
later later on in my life
I went away from the Catholic Church
because there were some questions
and things that I never got answered
in my inside
but Jesus Christ was always in my heart
I found a guru
later on this new path in my life
and that became
it became a lot of
enlightenment you would say
a lot of new information for me
and a new way of seeing the world
very wonderful new way
of seeing God within me
instead of going
God out there
and I am so guilty
yes
so that was a big difference in my life
oh yeah
but in a way
Jesus was always in my heart
yes
I want to know and ask you
if I should
if I hold in mind
this guru
and if you could tell me
if I should follow this guru
still
or if I should keep
my heart with Jesus
I am not in the Catholic Church anyway
if I were you
I would keep my heart with Jesus
because Jesus Christ calibrates at a thousand
and your guru
I doubt calibrates at a thousand
or more
you wouldn't be asking me
what you're asking me
it would have been resolved already
yeah
the spiritual truth of what one is
is obvious to one who
never mind
what should I ask further about it
the pathway she's on is sufficient
the pathway you're on is sufficient
resist
yeah don't be greedy
spiritually greedy
you got Jesus Christ
and Buddha
and now you got gurus
and you want to jam me in the box too
you are in the box
that's you
I have jammed you in that box too
am I too greedy
you think I'm
wait
can one be too greedy
in the spiritual path
see
your intention
and your alignment
is what counts
you see
my intention is to be
on the enlightenment path
and
if Christ is in your heart
that's already
in the enlightened state
who but an enlightened person
would ask for Jesus Christ
to be in their heart
and
you understand
so
enlightenment is really a progressive
realization of advanced
spiritual truth
spiritual truth eventually becomes
non-communicable
there's nothing that teach
because it's wordless
so words are useful
for a period of time
then you go beyond words
because you become what the words
are talking about
right
thank you
but you're in that box
so you don't
no
You don't have to give up, honey, because you have stopped killing animals already, you know what I'm saying?
Okay.
Yeah.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Thank you, Dr. Hawkins.
That was good.
Yeah.
Yes.
I have the first question is a friend of mine is wondering if there are any blocks or gates between level 540 and 570.
There aren't any major gates that I remember.
Are there some?
The love becomes more and more unconditional, that's all.
And the miraculous becomes more and more frequent.
All right.
Thanks.
And then the second question I'm asking for my mom.
I know I'm only supposed to ask one per person, but this is just for her.
So there's one each.
Both of us live with a grandma that's committed to negativity.
Yes.
And both of us are indecisive.
We're interested in spiritual evolutions.
We're wondering how to not allow that to hinder us.
Well, she can't hinder you.
But your response to her, what do you think it should be?
Compassion to her innocence, my response should be.
I guess she's innocent and ignorant, yes.
So that's pretty much it.
All right.
Thank you.
Well, you try to be as compassionate and patient as you can be.
A person like that who has no interest.
No interest in transcending their own level of consciousness.
It's just a matter of learning how to live with them.
I always think the only way I can think of is by example.
But generally, people like that are immune to example too.
They'll be kind to you and you can be kind to them and they'll be just as bitchy as usual.
I'll try my best, but thank you very much.
It's very difficult.
I wouldn't expect any change.
Yeah.
Can we get a picture?
Sure as well.
Thank you.
We love you.
Yes.
Get her to smoke marijuana.
That would help.
Take you anywhere.
I had an old lady, 70 years old, and she grew marijuana.
She smoked a little marijuana every night before bed for 40 years.
She grew it in the kitchen window.
I said, why do you do that?
She said, because I feel so relaxed and I just go to sleep.
I said, oh, okay.
She didn't take off her clothes and go dancing in the village square.
She just went to sleep.
Basically, the reason I and my husband and sister are here is because we needed your
aura patch, you might say, for our aura so that when we get to higher levels of consciousness,
maybe we can go through the high pass.
Oh.
My question is, when each level of consciousness has its own set of limitations that need to
be transcended, are there limitations?
Are there limitations?
That need to be transcended in the high 500s, 575, 585, are there limitations of perspective
that need to be transcended?
I don't know if that languaging is directly clinically correct.
In the high 500s, life becomes increasingly blissful and harmonious and eventually, eventually
constant joy.
And in the very highest 500s, you go into a state of ecstasy.
Also, it's very hard to function in the world.
I remember in the high 500s, if you even looked at love, you couldn't handle it.
You'd just get overwhelmed with how profound it was.
And you would find yourself weeping with happiness.
That's also noticed in certain...
In religious communities, what do you call them, communities?
Cloistered communities.
Cloistered, yes.
There's a period where you cry all the time, it may last a couple of years, and any time
you look at something, you can see the love and the beauty inherit.
So it sort of melts into the 600 level, and the enlightenment level?
I would say so, yes.
Yeah.
It just sort of melts and blends in.
It's a continuity, and of course, demarcating numbers is just an arbitrary, you know, what
temperature out is it when you can say it's cold, you know, 26 degrees, 25 degrees, 24
degrees.
It isn't that exact, but the higher states of the 500s are increasingly joyful, and as
I remember, actually ecstatic, and goes into a state of supreme ecstasy.
The presence of God.
Yeah.
The presence of God as profound joy and ecstasy, and you can't function in that state.
So you sit on the porch swing all day long.
Huh?
You sit on the porch swing all day long.
Yes, that's true.
Okay, don't you bliss.
Thank you.
Ramakrishna went into that state.
I remember exactly that state.
Yeah.
Well...
Yes.
Yeah.
And I have a question.
I have a question for my wife who was supposed to be here today but she couldn't make it,
so I'll read her question.
In May of 2007 my sister died of cancer.
The evening she died, I was swimming, lapsed in the pool, and for a split second I had
a feeling of extreme ecstasy.
And I thought my sister just got better, or she died.
Later, the next day, I found out that the feeling of ecstasy happened at the exact same
moment my sister died. Yes. Can you tell me the significance of that experience?
What was the relationship between the two people? They were siblings. Siblings, yes.
Very close. Yes, well because of the alignment of consciousness she
experienced the ecstasy as you enter heaven, yes. So was it her sister's soul
in a way, saying goodbye or saying everything is fine? Her sister was
merely experiencing what you experience in that transition from physicality to
heavenly. Because she was psychically attuned, she vicariously experienced it.
It wasn't like transmitted. It's like because of the
identification between the two. Okay, so my wife's feeling was the same as her
sister's feeling at that moment? Yes, yes, yes. She picks up the vibration of it.
Okay. Yeah. Thank you. Can I shake your hand?
Yes, because as you leave the body and enter that state there's a sense of
ecstasy. For one thing you've just left pain and suffering and you feel free and
you realize that you're reborn into a new realm. Yes. And it's the state is
ecstatic. Okay, thank you. I remember in my own lifetime when my
mother left the body the state was ecstatic joy. Yeah. Hello Dr. Hawkins?
I wanted to ask about surrender letting go of resisting the negative emotions
that come up for me right now a big one is just desire keeps coming up how do I
let go of resisting that what does that look like I mean what is the process
craving this and desire is like addiction and all you can do is
surrender to it and let go resisting it and let it run out of its own let it you
crave everything you want you don't crave it enough how much do you want
this table give me give me for this table how much how much give me how much
for this table huh your life I want your life for this table you can see this
tables worth your life yes you're willing to give up your life for every
craving your life won't last very long
you run out of gas I want that car I want that woman I want that house I want
this street I want them so wanting this you can let go resisting the feeling of
it all right so there's an energy behind the feeling let go resisting that energy
in that feeling let yourself crave you don't crave enough lay on the carpet and
cry and sob that you don't have if you don't have it you won't be able to live
etc so instead of
resisting it you're prolonging it it might be better to just surrender to the
feeling and let the feeling run itself out all feelings have a certain
limitation if you let that feeling run continuously it'll eventually run out
could take hours could take days it possibly weeks but unlikely very likely
if you don't resist craving this it'll run out and let's say seven to eight
days you get like sick and tired of
wanting and sick and tired of craving and and it'll run out it's like being
angry if you let yourself be angry and just don't resist it and you ride on the
floor with anger and scream with anger and bite your knuckles with anger and
kick your heels with anger and let go of resisting the anger you tell yourself
you're not angry enough okay thank you let's go running out of stack and you
run out the stack you run out the stack
you're not angry enough you know you let the other way as I said you know
whatever the feeling is it's limited I have found that when so when someone
wants materialistic things that they are not giving of themselves in other words
they're not giving themselves as volunteers or helping in some way
volunteering their time and once they do this they realize the material things
aren't as important to them anymore no so if you give to the community or give
back something other in you know not that kindness kindness you find that that wantingness isn't there
anymore it's it's it's moved into another field and you don't want those material objects anymore
yeah you've moved to a higher level you move to a higher level on that higher level you're not
craving anything you're not craving anything but if you have to give back so you have to give back
to the community or give back and whether it's volunteer or financially or whatever yeah you
have to give something back for what you have and i find that takes you to a different level
that's great that's great for you hello and first thank you both for what are you doing i don't know
where i would be without this work and um first of all i'm a spiritual student and i'm on a path
and my intention is to release anything and
anyone
out of my life that is not serving me i'm a pathway to god and uh in the last year of work
i came up upon a stack a stack of what stack you know a stack a whole stack of people you want to
get rid of and not just people emotions and people and just emotions and people yeah and nothing i do
seems to be able to shift it or no prayers i don't know this is how it seems to me and actually has
to do with a relationship in my life that i think is integrous
you
so my question is um what is the best way to release this
what is the question how to release what this person yeah this person this person and the stack
of you know everything that comes with it you know it's just with myself you want to dump somebody
right i guess dump them dump them yeah okay somebody's shirt up here oh here his shirt
somebody's shirt
i have a gift for you that's something that you had a great influence over so i just want to
to give my deepest thanks and gratitude to you for the influence that you've had on my life and my
work yes and my question really isn't for me it's a request that you would continue the influence on
that work and the people that it influences may i have your blessing for the people that
they choose to help in my work i don't get the
I'm a person with Western
life
yeah thank you for being my teacher um when the personal self disappears and the body is seen
separate from the self, and then the body moves around.
Does the self move?
No, the self doesn't move.
It's like that which is aware of what's going on is here,
and the body can be anywhere.
And then there is a shift where you can center in the body,
because you realize that's what the world thinks you are.
So for convenience, for convenience,
you can accommodate the world and humor it
so they think that you think you're the body, like they do.
So it's a matter of choice.
Yeah, yeah.
When it first happens, you don't have any choice.
Consciousness is here, and your body's there,
and everybody's talking to the body.
And you wonder, who in the world are they talking to?
Because you're here, see?
Thank you very much.
You're out of body, and they're talking
to the body, you see.
Who in the world are they talking to?
All right, we'll move it fast forward.
Hi.
I was wondering, what are your thoughts
on the presidency of Barack Obama so far?
Do you have any comments on that?
What is what?
What are your thoughts on Barack Obama as president so far?
So far?
Oh, god, that's an evolving condition.
Yes.
You know, I watched FDR.
I think the history of FDR is very interesting,
if you get that out and rerun it again.
And you'll see a lot of the same phenomena.
Right.
And because the role has multiple facets
and multiple responsibilities.
And you know, whether he's whatchamacallit
that leads them over the cliff.
What do you call that guy?
What's his name?
The Pied Piper.
Pied Piper, yes.
Whether he's the Pied Piper, or whether he's
the second coming, you know, you have
to make up your mind.
Is it Lima?
Huh?
What is it?
Lima's also.
Yeah.
Huh?
Lima.
Is it Lima that leads it?
Lemmings.
Lemmings into the sea.
That's it.
Lemmings.
No, no.
Yeah.
Okay.
Anyway, it's a very difficult role he has
to fulfill.
Yes.
There's no way you're going to fulfill that
without all kinds of criticism from somebody.
Right.
And a very difficult role that he has to fulfill.
I do have one question.
Yeah.
I'm back home running for mayor in my city.
It's about 12,000 people.
And my question is, would that be for the greater good of my community if I, a couple
of years from now, running for mayor back home?
Would what?
Who's for office?
Should he run for office?
Who, you?
Yes.
Oh, by all means.
Hey, thank you.
Yeah, the thing is to have integrity.
You can't be right all the time, and you can't be perfect.
But you can fulfill your role to the best of your ability, and that's all I hope any
president does is he fulfills the role to the best of his ability as he feels called
upon, and that's integrous.
And I always figure if you realize that you're answerable to God for everything you do and
say, that's the only safeguard that the whole country has.
If we have a president who feels he's answerable to divinity, then we're safeguarded by that,
by that sense of righteousness and accountability.
So as long as a leader, I see that he realizes that he's accountable, accountable for honesty
and integrity, then mistakes are inevitable.
Who cares about mistakes?
At least, you know, you realize that the person did the best they could at the time knowing
what they knew.
And if they knew what they knew now, they wouldn't, you know, have voted that way.
And they're all crooks anyway.
But there's honest crooks.
There's honest crooks and crooked crooks.
With the talk of these spiritual experiences earlier today, my question is about
an experience I had when I was 17, and I was at a camp, and they had, there was a minister
who said, if you want to accept Jesus as your Lord and Savior, I opened my eyes to the minister,
and it felt like one of those Monty Python movies where my head, like, split.
And this big, giant, gold beam of light poured out from wherever into my body and filled
every cell of my body with this golden white light.
And it wasn't the same as what you guys had, but it was, you know, what, like, what was
that?
You know?
I don't know if that's a foolish question or not, but it's, but I hadn't…
It's different for everybody.
You know, it's a divine energy.
He opened himself up.
It's a divine energy.
Was he a teacher of Jesus Christ?
Yes.
And that was the energy of Christ.
If you accept Christ as your Savior, you open the doorway for the radiance of that energy.
Isn't that so?
So then if we go about a normal, you know, then you kind of fall away and do your
own whatever normal…
Well, those epiphanies are not continuous.
That's why they call it an epiphany.
An epiphany is a high, high state like that, but you can't function in that state, so
that's a state of illumination.
It changes you forever and your calibration changes, but you can't function in that state,
so it fades out because you get used to it.
When you get used to the bright light, you're no longer blinded by it.
Okay.
And we just stay on the path and keep reading and keep learning and keep praying and keep
releasing and keep…
That's right.
Yeah, yeah.
Just walk straight ahead.
Walk straight ahead.
Thank you.
That condition is called an epiphany, a very high state of illumination.
Epiphany.
Hi.
I was on a spiritual path for a very long time, and I'm wondering if I hold this teacher
in mind, if you would calibrate him.
I don't know.
Okay.
I have permission to calibrate the teacher she's holding in mind.
Resist.
Okay.
This teacher is over 200.
This teacher is not over 200.
Oh.
And may I have your blessing.
It's okay to give her my blessing.
Give her my blessing.
Yes, indeed.
Thank you.
Sorry about that.
I'm glad we didn't mention any names.
Yeah.
Thank you.
I hope it wasn't even when we knew.
That's why I didn't want to know the name.
Yes.
Hello?
Hi.
Hello.
Thank you, Doctor.
Thank you.
I guess a little premise.
I got to write this down.
I tried to talk about it.
Formulating a relationship.
Yeah.
There you go.
I've done the best in two different things.
I've formulated a million different ways, but my life is divergent right now where I
need to make a choice between self-evolution or social responsibility.
So-
Why do you see a conflict?
How are they different?
They just seem to be mutually exclusive to-
How so?
Well, you say on the spiritual growth, the spiritual path, surround yourself with like-minded
people.
get on your way well that's an assist you don't need it you know you can get into lightning in a
cave all by yourself but fair enough that's that's a fair statement i guess my my ultimate
question was uh what in your words is uh your definition of integrity oh i can't really explain
integrity to you just kind of like love just that undefinable you either know what it is you don't
if you climb a flagpole you're going to pick one with integrity and that one that wavers as you
begin to climb on it right you're living your life and that puppy dog walks up to the door that sick
puppy dog that either can start taking care of that puppy or continue to live the rest of your
life what is that there's always that gray area there's no black and white there that's right
there's no black and white but each choice influences your karmic consequences yes
it's not either or
you
because each one is really also an expression of the other it's like saying so i serve myself or
shall i serve the society you know there isn't any real ambiguity there because if you serve
yourself by serving society a serving society you serve yourself so you know you can't create an
artificial dichotomy where there's none it's just a linguistic uh intellectual dichotomy in reality
there's no dichotomy
dichotomy that's to serve your fellow man serve god and serve yourself all the same really well said
thank you yeah was that the answer you wanted yeah i think it was your intention is that your
intention is but over power is everything else your intention is to save somebody and be a help
to them and if they drown inadvertently in the process
well that's something different
okay you meant to you meant to give him the order to hang on to and accidentally hit him over the head
and knocked him out with the order i mean and he and he drowned here's the order for the guys
yes
hi can i shake your hand yes can i shake your hand yes
thank you so um i don't um my energy has been really bad the last couple months
and i was wondering is it just that i need to change my antidepressant or
what's okay what do you mean by your energy being bad i mean i just feel very low and tired you mean
your emotions are feeling down yeah yeah okay yeah nothing wrong with your energy okay yeah yeah you're
in a down yeah well take antidepressants do you do that yeah i do that but i'm wondering if the one
i've been taking for over a year if i should switch may change you need to change the dose you may
become immune to it change the dose or just ask for another one well i would try increasing the
dose with the doctor's permission and what else do you do to avoid depression you'll eat sugar and
sweets yes when are you going to quit them when my craving is done when my craving is done when my
craving is done when my craving is done you quit sugar and sweets your craving will disappear and
so will your depression if i'm wrong i'll send you ten dollars if when you quit all sugar and sweets
you still go into these depressions then it requires a change in the medication dose
but the kind of symptoms you get i would first stop sugar and sweets
then see what remains and then raise the dose if it's necessary but what about low
blood sugar? I just got through answering your question. Okay. If you spend more time listening
and less time talking, you'd be better. Okay, thank you. Stop eating sugar and sweets. Okay.
All right. Thank you. And then see if you get better. Okay, thank you. If you don't get better,
you can go back to eating donuts and muffins. Okay. All right.
You know I pull your leg because I like you. She's coming a long way. Yeah. Yeah.
A little bit. The coffee toffee bars have caffeine, so if you need a jolt on the ride home.
Right. She has coffee toffee bars. Coffee toffee? Yeah, coffee toffee bars. Oh, oh, yes. Get the
hints. Get the hints. Yes, what else? May I have a blessing, please? Yes, indeed. Thank you.
And I do have one question. And what? One question. What? She has one question.
Yes. We're getting terrific feedback here. Yes. If you had permission to ask, could you
tell me if it's in my highest good to move to Sedona? In the highest good to what? For her to
move to Sedona. Is it in the highest good? Oh, oh, I don't know. Do we have permission to ask this?
It would be in her highest good to move to Sedona. No. That would save you a lot of rent.
Certainly.
Thank you.
It might be not at this time.
Yeah, it may be wrong timing.
It might be, you know, at another time it might be on there, but at this time you get it all.
Uh-huh.
That could change now.
Well, because there's other things other than just the living. Where she's living, there's
relationships and opportunities and obligations, you know what I'm saying?
Yeah.
Not just geographic.
Hi.
Yes.
Can I hold your hand, Susan?
Hello, Doc.
Hi, Susan.
Yes.
I work as an acupuncturist at a substance abuse program, and we show your tapes, and
I give them the map of consciousness, and I tell them that God is on the way up, and
recovery's on the way up, and addiction's on the way down, and they knew I was coming
here today, and I was wondering if we could say the serenity prayer.
If what?
If you could say the serenity prayer together, all of us.
All of us?
Yeah.
In the whole room?
Sure.
Let's do it.
That'd be great.
Ready?
Ready.
Okay.
God.
Grant me the serenity to accept the things I cannot change, the courage to change the
things I can, and the wisdom to know the difference.
Amen.
Thank you.
That was great.
Thank you both.
I've got to watch the time.
Honey.
I have to watch the time.
Do you know what time it is?
Yes.
We're past.
Huh?
We're past, but we can go on, because they said we could finish up real quick.
All right.
I was just wondering if you could give me your significance on an experience I had.
So, for like a split second, I convinced my mind that I was in a different body.
Yes.
And it was like for a split second, and that happened twice, actually.
I was just wondering what...
That's horrific.
Horrific?
Yeah.
Teach me how to do it.
How do you do that?
I don't know.
And then I tried doing it with my cat another time, but it didn't work.
By location.
That's just an interesting psychic.
It's a psychic phenomenon.
A psychic.
That's spiritual psychic.
So, okay.
It's fun anyway.
No significance behind it?
Just that, eh?
It's harmless, yeah.
All right.
Can I get a blessing from both of you?
Oh, yeah.
A double blessing?
God bless you.
Thank you.
Yeah.
And God bless the innocence of your experience.
Poor Dermot.
I want you to sign.
I can't see very well at all.
I'm going to sign things, you know.
Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
Yes.
I'm Jim, and this is Jerry.
We're from Denver.
Yes.
We came to relate a story to you.
Okay.
And Jerry's going to relate a story to you.
Yes.
Your books have been life-changing for us, as well as those around us.
We have a friend.
We met him at a coffee shop.
Jim's been reading your books.
He gave him the book.
Power Versus Force.
He didn't read it for a while.
He flew on a plane to Manila.
He goes there for three months out of the year.
He read it on the plane.
He met a gentleman in Manila who is one of the chief negotiators for the Philippine government
with Abu Sayyid.
He loved the book.
He ordered five more copies and is going with the team, negotiating team, with the terrorists
in the southern part of the Philippines with your books as guides.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
God bless you.
Great.
Hello.
Yes.
Quick question.
I've often heard you say that there's no identity in enlightenment where you're sitting.
There isn't an identity there.
And I'm curious as a student.
How?
What is an appropriate?
Or useful way to relate to the persona of Dr. Hawkins?
Don't get attached to it.
It's transitory.
It's pragmatic.
And it's also arbitrary.
I could also say the world needs another spiritual teacher like a hole in the head and quit it
and feel no loss.
I could take the opposite view and say God blessed me with certain realizations.
That are helpful to share with others and feel an obligation.
So the reason I became a teacher is I chose the latter.
That the gift was given to me and I didn't need to teach.
I was by myself in a state of bliss, infinite bliss, beyond time, place, and location.
And then I'd have to retrack again how that all came about.
The obligation of becoming a teacher.
I told you to write power versus force.
Oh.
Because remember, we were discussing it and I said you need to write this down so someone
would.
Oh, she told me to write it down.
Thank you.
That's right.
I just kept it to myself.
She said, gee, you really ought to share this and write it down.
I said, oh, okay.
Yes.
Great.
Thank you very much.
And then we went back into the world.
Thank you.
And then we spent every weekend traveling.
We spent all our life in.
Planes.
Charter, yeah, the Bill of Rights.
Yes.
I have permission to calibrate the bill.
What do you call it, Bill Charter of Rights?
Yes, the Charter of Rights and Freedoms.
I have permission to calibrate that.
It calibrates over 480, 490, 495.
It calibrates at 495, over 495.
It calibrates at 495.
That's very high, yes.
That's good.
I was reading it today, actually, and it doesn't mention God,
and that's probably one of the reasons why it doesn't calibrate high.
What, what did you say?
It doesn't mention God, did it?
No.
So that could be why it doesn't calibrate as high.
Over 500, yeah.
Thank you both.
It's just as well Canada stays away from God.
You see all the trouble it brings you.
You've got to have a place to escape.
At least Canada, you can escape God.
Good afternoon.
Yeah.
In my work in the world,
I'm an herbalist in the Oriental medical tradition.
Yes.
And through reading your books,
I've been inspired to, as I'm with a patient,
also just simply love them.
Oh, yes.
And I was wondering,
apart from simply generating that quality of love for who I'm with,
if you recommend a certain method like a visualization.
In the past, I've recited the Medicine Buddha Mantra
because that's part of my training.
Thank you.
If you had any advice for me
on how to benefit my patients more through the love principle.
Well, I think it's just your intention.
It's your intention.
You know, it came to the end of my practice, see?
And the insurance cost more than I wasn't making enough to pay the insurance.
But I couldn't stop practice because there were a couple of guys
that were hanging on really because of their relationship with me.
And I thought, geez, I can't desert these guys at this point.
You know, they've come all this way.
And they've only got a half a mile left to go anyway.
So I figured I'll hang out with them until they leave.
When they leave, then I'll close my practice.
So when they left the body, I closed my practice.
So it was just caring about them to realize what you mean to them
and to fulfill that meaning.
Now, if they were in psychoanalysis, it'd be different.
If they were in psychoanalysis, you would analyze out the positive transference.
Now, these people, the positive transference is what was keeping them going.
I can remember one old guy.
Geez, he was funny.
And he says, I want a picture of you, Doc.
I put it on the wall because when I look at it, I feel better.
I said, oh, okay.
But he and his wife would fight.
And she wouldn't allow him to drive the car because he was too senile.
So he would go into a screaming fit that she wouldn't let him drive.
So one day, he got the car.
He took the keys to the car, and he drove, and he got lost.
And he called me.
I said, tell your wife to come and get you.
Okay, God damn it.
He says, okay, Mildred, I get the point.
Thank you so much.
No, you care about them.
And it's the caringness is transmitted, you know.
The caringness, the energy of the caringness is carried over to the patient.
You don't say, I care about you.
That would scare them.
But your caringness.
Is your power with them.
So the healer is somebody who really cares about his patients.
He cares for their highest good, including preventing them from becoming
neurotically dependent on you.
So this old guy who felt better when he looked at my picture, because of his age,
I'm not going to analyze that positive transference because it's keeping him alive.
If he was younger, I'd say, you know, you're projecting magic onto me.
It's your will to get better and your will to live that's energizing,
you're functioning, not me, you know what I'm saying?
You know what I'm saying?
Yes.
So it depends on the patient, the relationship, the phase,
and what it is you're trying to accomplish.
Thank you so much.
Yeah.
Thank you also, Susan.
Thank you, doctor.
And it doesn't hurt to pray for a patient.
I used to pray for them.
And I said, God, if you don't mind it, I hope Mac gets better.
Bye.
I don't want to bother God with all kinds of stuff, you know what I'm saying?
Watch out.
Yes.
I really wanted to look into your eyes and experience you closer than back there in the back of the room.
But I have a question about something that happened to me quite a while ago.
Yes.
I was probably about 25 or so.
I started going to a meditation class, and they talked about love.
And I thought, well, I don't know what that feels like.
And so I meditated on love every day for about a year and a half.
Wow.
But what happened was, all of a sudden, I was leaving.
I mean, life was shit, but all of a sudden, I felt what love felt like, and I was leaving.
If this is what it feels like, I'm going to this.
Yeah, I know what you mean.
Well, my life just rolled in front of me, and I realized that wasn't a failure.
Yes.
Everything was a failure.
Everything I'd done was a total success, and that's the only way it could have ever been.
Yeah.
Recontextualize the whole thing, yeah.
So I decided to come back because I had more to do.
Yes.
So my question is, what did that mean?
How far did that go?
Is there something way past that in consciousness?
Way past what?
Love.
No, the ultimate love resolves all differentiation of a this from a that, or a me and a you.
And it merges into, what's the right word for it, of divinity.
It merges into divinity in which there is no me and you, or this and a that.
Unity.
Yes.
Well, thank you for all your writings, and your map is just amazing.
Thank you.
How much time we got left?
We better, I better watch it.
Yeah, we're all done.
We're over.
I think we're over the line.
Okay, now, doctor's going to shake everyone's hand in the audience.
Oh, my God.
So we need you to either come down, either the center aisles, because you cannot come down this outside aisle.
So if you could come down the center aisles and come across the front of the stage, he'll be over here, right?
Is that where he's going to be?
I have to have a soda.
He'll be over here in the corner.
And then you can file up this aisle to go out.
But he will try and shake everybody's hands here in the auditoriums, if that's all right.
Where's my coffee, honey?
Coffee?
Just a minute.
It's a handshake, I think.
Yeah, I'll just shake the hand of anybody who wants to shake my hand.
Is that all I get?
Yeah, because you've got to go right over there.
Okay.
That'll do me.
All right.
Put what's left back.
Oh, there's going to be a left point.
Let it go.
Come on.
I don't want to contaminate it.
Now, I'm not sure where to go.
Do you know where to go?
Yes, sir.
Oh.
Here's a place that you can lean.
Yeah, this is good for you.
Okay.
Where's all the people whose hands I'm going to shake?
I shakey shake.
God bless you all.
God bless you, sweetheart.
I can hardly see the people, though.
Hello.
Okay.
Well, what a joy to meet everybody.
What a great gift.
Yes.
God bless you.
God bless.
Unfortunately, yeah.
God bless you.
God bless.
There, I can see better now.
Yes.
Hey, it's good to see you.
I didn't notice.
Good to see you.
Hi.
Great to see you.
Hello.
Good to see you.
I'm like a bobble, though.
Hello.
Like a bobble.
some people get the game right away others don't get it oh god bless hello oh look at all these
sweets of sweet arts here look at all these sweet arts yeah look at all these sweet arts here god
bless oh god bless hello sweetheart yeah I love you sweet arts look at all these gorgeous people
everyone's a blessing everyone is a living blessing look at this guy here