Uh we're going to start. So if everyone
Uh we're going to start. So if everyone could sit down and take their seats.
could sit down and take their seats.
could sit down and take their seats. Thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you. >> We're doing our first question.
>> We're doing our first question.
>> We're doing our first question. >> Yeah. Sorry.
>> Yeah. Sorry.
>> Yeah. Sorry. Um actually I just have come to meet
Um actually I just have come to meet
Um actually I just have come to meet you. I don't really have a question for
you. I don't really have a question for
you. I don't really have a question for you.
you.
you. >> What?
>> What?
>> What? >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> She has to speak slowly and succinctly.
>> She has to speak slowly and succinctly.
>> She has to speak slowly and succinctly. >> India. And
>> India. And
>> India. And >> I've come from India.
>> I've come from India.
>> I've come from India. >> You're from India?
>> You're from India?
>> You're from India? >> Yes. And uh we just joined a small we
>> Yes. And uh we just joined a small we
>> Yes. And uh we just joined a small we formed a study group over there to study
formed a study group over there to study
formed a study group over there to study power versus force
power versus force
power versus force >> and I've come to take your blessings for
>> and I've come to take your blessings for
>> and I've come to take your blessings for our group and all our people back there.
our group and all our people back there.
our group and all our people back there. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much. >> And we really disappointed we can't hug
>> And we really disappointed we can't hug
>> And we really disappointed we can't hug you and touch your feet and shake your
you and touch your feet and shake your
you and touch your feet and shake your hands. My friends and people back home
hands. My friends and people back home
hands. My friends and people back home are going to be you know as soon as I
are going to be you know as soon as I
are going to be you know as soon as I land the first question is going to did
land the first question is going to did
land the first question is going to did you meet him? Did you hug him? Did you
you meet him? Did you hug him? Did you
you meet him? Did you hug him? Did you hold his hands?
She wants to She wants
She wants to She wants >> what?
>> what?
>> what? >> She wants to touch you
>> She wants to touch you
>> She wants to touch you >> in honor of their group. Okay.
>> in honor of their group. Okay.
>> in honor of their group. Okay. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Thank you so much.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Thank you so much. >> When in Rome do as the Romans do? Yes.
>> When in Rome do as the Romans do? Yes.
>> When in Rome do as the Romans do? Yes. >> What do you want now?
>> What do you want now?
>> What do you want now? >> Can I request a picture? Want
>> Can I request a picture? Want
>> Can I request a picture? Want >> me to sign this? Yeah.
>> me to sign this? Yeah.
>> me to sign this? Yeah. >> You You want a picture? Yes. Come around
>> You You want a picture? Yes. Come around
>> You You want a picture? Yes. Come around back here.
You're from India?
You're from India? >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Where is that? Outside of Ohio.
>> That's Indiana.
>> That's Indiana. >> Well, I was never in India. It's one of
>> Well, I was never in India. It's one of
>> Well, I was never in India. It's one of the places I missed in this lifetime.
the places I missed in this lifetime.
the places I missed in this lifetime. I'm in previous lifetimes. I died by the
I'm in previous lifetimes. I died by the
I'm in previous lifetimes. I died by the Ganges many a time
Ganges many a time
Ganges many a time >> and my body was burned on the gats.
We have both said that one reason that
We have both said that one reason that Dave said he might not ever be able to
Dave said he might not ever be able to
Dave said he might not ever be able to go to India is praying to never come
go to India is praying to never come
go to India is praying to never come back.
back.
back. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> But you know
>> But you know
>> But you know >> but what's interesting is the
>> but what's interesting is the
>> but what's interesting is the calibration of the Ganges River.
calibration of the Ganges River.
calibration of the Ganges River. >> You know the Holy River calibrates
>> You know the Holy River calibrates
>> You know the Holy River calibrates extremely high despite the fact that
extremely high despite the fact that
extremely high despite the fact that there's hundreds of dead bodies floating
there's hundreds of dead bodies floating
there's hundreds of dead bodies floating by garbage and refues. The Ganges River
by garbage and refues. The Ganges River
by garbage and refues. The Ganges River I forget was how it calibrates. I
I forget was how it calibrates. I
I forget was how it calibrates. I thought it was the 800s.
thought it was the 800s.
thought it was the 800s. >> 700. Let's see. The Ganges River
>> 700. Let's see. The Ganges River
>> 700. Let's see. The Ganges River calibrates over 700.
calibrates over 700.
calibrates over 700. >> The Ganges River calibrates over 700.
>> The Ganges River calibrates over 700.
>> The Ganges River calibrates over 700. >> The Ganges River, despite the fact that
>> The Ganges River, despite the fact that
>> The Ganges River, despite the fact that dead bodies are floating down, garbage,
dead bodies are floating down, garbage,
dead bodies are floating down, garbage, human feces, and god knows what all. The
human feces, and god knows what all. The
human feces, and god knows what all. The Ganges River calibrates at 700.
Ganges River calibrates at 700.
Ganges River calibrates at 700. Can anybody give a rational explanation
Can anybody give a rational explanation
Can anybody give a rational explanation for that?
You're right.
You're right. >> It's a sacred river. Yeah.
>> It's a sacred river. Yeah.
>> It's a sacred river. Yeah. >> That's amazing, isn't it?
>> That's amazing, isn't it?
>> That's amazing, isn't it? >> Touch.
>> Touch.
>> Touch. >> Yes. Yes. Honey, she wants to touch your
>> Yes. Yes. Honey, she wants to touch your
>> Yes. Yes. Honey, she wants to touch your feet. You have to turn around for all of
feet. You have to turn around for all of
feet. You have to turn around for all of us.
us.
us. >> Okay. God bless you. God bless you. Yes.
>> Okay. God bless you. God bless you. Yes.
>> Okay. God bless you. God bless you. Yes. You bet.
You bet.
You bet. >> The Ganges River calibrates at 700.
>> The Ganges River calibrates at 700.
>> The Ganges River calibrates at 700. despite all kinds of dead bodies,
despite all kinds of dead bodies,
despite all kinds of dead bodies, refues, garbage, feces,
refues, garbage, feces,
refues, garbage, feces, dog urine, god knows what. All
>> I'm waiting to go on here. I don't know
>> I'm waiting to go on here. I don't know what you're holding me up here for.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. >> All right.
>> All right.
>> All right. >> Question.
>> Question.
>> Question. I'd like to know what my calibration is.
I'd like to know what my calibration is.
I'd like to know what my calibration is. No,
No,
No, we don't do that.
we don't do that.
we don't do that. >> Oh,
>> Oh,
>> Oh, >> if it's low, you'll feel depressed. And
>> if it's low, you'll feel depressed. And
>> if it's low, you'll feel depressed. And if it's high, you'll get egotistical.
if it's high, you'll get egotistical.
if it's high, you'll get egotistical. So, it's no good.
>> No, maybe if you do not calibrate
>> No, maybe if you do not calibrate people.
people.
people. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> You know where you are.
>> You know where you are.
>> You know where you are. >> Don't you have
>> Don't you have
>> Don't you have >> I think I don't know.
>> I think I don't know.
>> I think I don't know. >> Yeah, but I have some idea where you're
>> Yeah, but I have some idea where you're
>> Yeah, but I have some idea where you're at. Now you're you're at a spiritual
at. Now you're you're at a spiritual
at. Now you're you're at a spiritual meeting for spiritual purposes.
meeting for spiritual purposes.
meeting for spiritual purposes. >> What I'm looking for is somebody that's
>> What I'm looking for is somebody that's
>> What I'm looking for is somebody that's into this kinesiology and I found some
into this kinesiology and I found some
into this kinesiology and I found some advers and stuff and to write or see if
advers and stuff and to write or see if
advers and stuff and to write or see if I can
I can
I can >> I can't hear what he
>> I can't hear what he
>> I can't hear what he >> run across people in this area.
>> run across people in this area.
>> run across people in this area. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Um well actually
>> Um well actually
>> Um well actually >> I'm not clear on what we're doing here.
>> I'm not clear on what we're doing here.
>> I'm not clear on what we're doing here. >> Um
>> Um
>> Um he is he's concerned about where he is
he is he's concerned about where he is
he is he's concerned about where he is at on the scale of consciousness.
at on the scale of consciousness.
at on the scale of consciousness. >> Yeah. And so he wants to have find
>> Yeah. And so he wants to have find
>> Yeah. And so he wants to have find someone that would calibrate him.
someone that would calibrate him.
someone that would calibrate him. >> Forget about calibrating yourself.
>> Forget about calibrating yourself.
>> Forget about calibrating yourself. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Choose to please God and be as
>> Choose to please God and be as
>> Choose to please God and be as spiritually uh
spiritually uh
spiritually uh correct as you can be and don't worry
correct as you can be and don't worry
correct as you can be and don't worry about the calibration. Let God worry
about the calibration. Let God worry
about the calibration. Let God worry about it.
>> God doesn't know how to do kinesiology.
>> God doesn't know how to do kinesiology. You had to teach him how. I said, "Dave,
You had to teach him how. I said, "Dave,
You had to teach him how. I said, "Dave, how do you do kinesiology?" I show him.
how do you do kinesiology?" I show him.
how do you do kinesiology?" I show him. Thanks a lot, Dave. So, that's what I
Thanks a lot, Dave. So, that's what I
Thanks a lot, Dave. So, that's what I sent you there for. Come back to heaven
sent you there for. Come back to heaven
sent you there for. Come back to heaven and teach me how to do kinesiology.
and teach me how to do kinesiology.
and teach me how to do kinesiology. >> Well, is that your only question? Was it
>> Well, is that your only question? Was it
>> Well, is that your only question? Was it >> that was the only question I had is I
>> that was the only question I had is I
>> that was the only question I had is I want to know how I calibrated.
want to know how I calibrated.
want to know how I calibrated. >> Yeah, we don't we don't try not to do
>> Yeah, we don't we don't try not to do
>> Yeah, we don't we don't try not to do that. Um,
that. Um,
that. Um, >> we don't do it. No, can't
>> we don't do it. No, can't
>> we don't do it. No, can't >> because it might not.
>> because it might not.
>> because it might not. >> You have some idea of where you're at.
>> You have some idea of where you're at.
>> You have some idea of where you're at. >> Are you loving and caring about your
>> Are you loving and caring about your
>> Are you loving and caring about your mankind?
I have a
I have a >> you what?
>> you what?
>> you what? >> I have a son that's 9 years old.
>> I have a son that's 9 years old.
>> I have a son that's 9 years old. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> And uh
>> And uh
>> And uh he's got a real bad cough.
I got to take him to a doctor, I guess.
I got to take him to a doctor, I guess. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> But I I'm really interested in seeing
>> But I I'm really interested in seeing
>> But I I'm really interested in seeing that he's on.
that he's on.
that he's on. >> Can't hear him.
>> Can't hear him.
>> Can't hear him. >> He has a son who's who's got a bad
>> He has a son who's who's got a bad
>> He has a son who's who's got a bad cough. I don't
cough. I don't
cough. I don't >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> know exactly what that
>> know exactly what that
>> know exactly what that >> What's that got to do with anything?
>> I didn't hear you.
>> I didn't hear you. >> He's having problems. We're having kind
>> He's having problems. We're having kind
>> He's having problems. We're having kind of a feedback. So, he's having problems
of a feedback. So, he's having problems
of a feedback. So, he's having problems hearing.
>> okay. Thank you for coming up.
>> okay. Thank you for coming up. >> Thank you, sir.
I I don't know how we could answer that.
I I don't know how we could answer that. Thank you.
>> I can't see what he's doing.
>> I can't see what he's doing. >> He's trying to take your picture. Hold
>> He's trying to take your picture. Hold
>> He's trying to take your picture. Hold on. He's
on. He's
on. He's >> That'll be a dollar.
>> What?
>> What? >> That'll be a dollar.
with tax.
with tax. >> No.
>> No.
>> No. >> Good golly, honey.
>> Good golly, honey.
>> Good golly, honey. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Okay. So, my question is um yogic and
>> Okay. So, my question is um yogic and
>> Okay. So, my question is um yogic and Buddha tech Buddhist texts mention that
Buddha tech Buddhist texts mention that
Buddha tech Buddhist texts mention that an enlightened person reaches a state of
an enlightened person reaches a state of
an enlightened person reaches a state of all knowingness
all knowingness
all knowingness um in which the person can know about
um in which the person can know about
um in which the person can know about whatever they put their attention on. At
whatever they put their attention on. At
whatever they put their attention on. At what level of consciousness, what
what level of consciousness, what
what level of consciousness, what calibration would this manifest?
calibration would this manifest?
calibration would this manifest? >> What's the question?
>> What's the question?
>> What's the question? >> The Buddhist text,
>> The Buddhist text,
>> The Buddhist text, >> you give a speech. Just tell me what is
>> you give a speech. Just tell me what is
>> you give a speech. Just tell me what is the question?
the question?
the question? >> Um, at what level of consciousness would
>> Um, at what level of consciousness would
>> Um, at what level of consciousness would the all- knowing state manifest?
the all- knowing state manifest?
the all- knowing state manifest? Well, the the divine states really
Well, the the divine states really
Well, the the divine states really calibrate 600 and up is the beginning of
calibrate 600 and up is the beginning of
calibrate 600 and up is the beginning of the divine state. 600 is satananda bliss
the divine state. 600 is satananda bliss
the divine state. 600 is satananda bliss states uh 700 is uh the level of the
states uh 700 is uh the level of the
states uh 700 is uh the level of the enlightened gurus.
It begins at 600.
It begins at 600. 600
600 one has transcended the world
600 is sat chittananda one is in a state
600 is sat chittananda one is in a state of infinite bliss nothing more is
of infinite bliss nothing more is
of infinite bliss nothing more is required there's no reason to s sustain
required there's no reason to s sustain
required there's no reason to s sustain physical life if physical life human
physical life if physical life human
physical life if physical life human life continues that's fine and if it
life continues that's fine and if it
life continues that's fine and if it doesn't that's fine
doesn't that's fine
doesn't that's fine and you're not able to function in that
and you're not able to function in that
and you're not able to function in that bubble and uh whether you come out of it
bubble and uh whether you come out of it
bubble and uh whether you come out of it or not is up to divine will
or not is up to divine will
or not is up to divine will and it's irrelevant.
and it's irrelevant.
and it's irrelevant. If the body continues on that's fine and
If the body continues on that's fine and
If the body continues on that's fine and if it doesn't that's fine. So 600 is
if it doesn't that's fine. So 600 is
if it doesn't that's fine. So 600 is sufficient for this world. You get the
sufficient for this world. You get the
sufficient for this world. You get the 600 you uh done what's possible in this
600 you uh done what's possible in this
600 you uh done what's possible in this world.
Okay. So at that level the potential for
Okay. So at that level the potential for the all knowingness would manifest.
the all knowingness would manifest.
the all knowingness would manifest. >> Not I'm not hearing
>> Not I'm not hearing
>> Not I'm not hearing >> at that level the potential for all
>> at that level the potential for all
>> at that level the potential for all knowingness would manifest at
knowingness would manifest at
knowingness would manifest at >> Oh yes it's 600. Yes.
>> Oh yes it's 600. Yes.
>> Oh yes it's 600. Yes. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> 600 is satananda. It's infinite bliss
>> 600 is satananda. It's infinite bliss
>> 600 is satananda. It's infinite bliss and peace and uh the world has served
and peace and uh the world has served
and peace and uh the world has served its purpose. There's no further point of
its purpose. There's no further point of
its purpose. There's no further point of be being in the world.
be being in the world.
be being in the world. >> Thank you.
Now, when he speaks to me, where is his
Now, when he speaks to me, where is his voice coming from? Because it's
voice coming from? Because it's
voice coming from? Because it's >> I don't know. We're having a little bit
>> I don't know. We're having a little bit
>> I don't know. We're having a little bit of feedback.
of feedback.
of feedback. >> All right.
>> All right.
>> All right. >> Good evening, ma'am. Uh, I don't really
>> Good evening, ma'am. Uh, I don't really
>> Good evening, ma'am. Uh, I don't really have a question. I I'm not sure.
have a question. I I'm not sure.
have a question. I I'm not sure. >> Speak into the microphone, please.
>> Speak into the microphone, please.
>> Speak into the microphone, please. >> I Good evening, sir.
>> I Good evening, sir.
>> I Good evening, sir. >> Good evening, ma'am. I don't really have
>> Good evening, ma'am. I don't really have
>> Good evening, ma'am. I don't really have a question, but uh I'd like to take a
a question, but uh I'd like to take a
a question, but uh I'd like to take a picture with you and uh I'd like you to
picture with you and uh I'd like you to
picture with you and uh I'd like you to autograph my ticket, please.
autograph my ticket, please.
autograph my ticket, please. >> And And you like him to what?
>> And And you like him to what?
>> And And you like him to what? >> The autograph the ticket.
>> The autograph the ticket.
>> The autograph the ticket. >> Oh, the ticket. She wants you to
>> Oh, the ticket. She wants you to
>> Oh, the ticket. She wants you to autograph the ticket.
autograph the ticket.
autograph the ticket. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> And she would like a picture taking with
>> And she would like a picture taking with
>> And she would like a picture taking with you.
you.
you. >> Are these her books?
>> Are these her books?
>> Are these her books? >> No, these are ones over here.
>> No, these are ones over here.
>> No, these are ones over here. >> Okay. I'm not sure what's
>> Okay. I'm not sure what's
>> Okay. I'm not sure what's >> coming at me from what direction here.
>> coming at me from what direction here.
>> coming at me from what direction here. Okay,
Okay,
Okay, >> we're almost done.
>> we're almost done.
>> we're almost done. >> All right, good. Good.
>> All right, good. Good.
>> All right, good. Good. >> Yes. Come right over here. Who's taking
>> Yes. Come right over here. Who's taking
>> Yes. Come right over here. Who's taking the picture?
the picture?
the picture? >> Oh.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Come up here and take it. Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> You're going to have a picture. You're
>> You're going to have a picture. You're
>> You're going to have a picture. You're going to show it to St. Peter at the
going to show it to St. Peter at the
going to show it to St. Peter at the gate.
gate.
gate. >> That's my gate to heaven. I picture it
>> That's my gate to heaven. I picture it
>> That's my gate to heaven. I picture it with
with
with >> St. Peter.
>> You heard about the long line of people
>> You heard about the long line of people on the way to heaven lined up there by
on the way to heaven lined up there by
on the way to heaven lined up there by St. Peter.
St. Peter.
St. Peter. There's this long line coming back from
There's this long line coming back from
There's this long line coming back from St. Peter. Guy guy lands in on the other
St. Peter. Guy guy lands in on the other
St. Peter. Guy guy lands in on the other side and he sees this long line long
side and he sees this long line long
side and he sees this long line long line of humans going way into the future
line of humans going way into the future
line of humans going way into the future waiting to see St. Peter.
waiting to see St. Peter.
waiting to see St. Peter. and and he hears a a a hum coming down
and and he hears a a a hum coming down
and and he hears a a a hum coming down the the line from way way miles away.
the the line from way way miles away.
the the line from way way miles away. Excited voice, you know, and finally it
Excited voice, you know, and finally it
Excited voice, you know, and finally it gets to him and he hears what they're
gets to him and he hears what they're
gets to him and he hears what they're saying. He says, "Sex doesn't count."
>> That's a funny old joke.
>> That's a funny old joke. >> Check.
>> Check.
>> Check. >> Check.
>> Check. >> Where are these books? The world is
>> Where are these books? The world is
>> Where are these books? The world is okay. Okay.
okay. Okay.
okay. Okay. >> I succeeded today because I thought that
>> I succeeded today because I thought that
>> I succeeded today because I thought that my success is really to be with you.
my success is really to be with you.
my success is really to be with you. >> Please bless my success.
>> Okay. In my case,
>> Okay. In my case, uh instead of asking a question,
uh instead of asking a question,
uh instead of asking a question, uh I just want to resonate with your
uh I just want to resonate with your
uh I just want to resonate with your vibration
vibration
vibration by uh through uh looking into your eyes
by uh through uh looking into your eyes
by uh through uh looking into your eyes for a moment.
for a moment.
for a moment. >> It's done. Yeah, it's done now and for
>> It's done. Yeah, it's done now and for
>> It's done. Yeah, it's done now and for eternity.
Oh, she said her success today is
Oh, she said her success today is because she thought that that she says
because she thought that that she says
because she thought that that she says her su su success today is to be with
her su su success today is to be with
her su su success today is to be with you.
you.
you. >> Oh
>> Oh
>> Oh >> yeah.
>> yeah.
>> yeah. >> Well, that's a compliment and I thank
>> Well, that's a compliment and I thank
>> Well, that's a compliment and I thank you very much.
My success my success is that you are
My success my success is that you are here.
here.
here. >> What do you want me to do?
>> What do you want me to do?
>> What do you want me to do? >> Uhhuh.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Uhhuh. >> Are you are you from Korea?
>> Are you are you from Korea?
>> Are you are you from Korea? >> Oh yes. Yes.
>> Oh yes. Yes.
>> Oh yes. Yes. >> You're part of the Korean uh people then
>> You're part of the Korean uh people then
>> You're part of the Korean uh people then or the delegation that came here. We
or the delegation that came here. We
or the delegation that came here. We have 30 people from Korea here today and
have 30 people from Korea here today and
have 30 people from Korea here today and we also have close to 30 from Mexico.
we also have close to 30 from Mexico.
we also have close to 30 from Mexico. So the work is
So the work is
So the work is the work is and these are part of the
the work is and these are part of the
the work is and these are part of the group that came all the way from Korea.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Thank you so much. >> Do you want to
>> Do you want to
>> Do you want to you want a photo? No. Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Oh god.
>> Oh god.
>> Oh god. >> Hi.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. At first I'd like to thank you for being
At first I'd like to thank you for being
At first I'd like to thank you for being my teacher
my teacher
my teacher and I have a question. Um you recommend
and I have a question. Um you recommend
and I have a question. Um you recommend to ask ourself how am I aware?
to ask ourself how am I aware?
to ask ourself how am I aware? Uh in the book I reality subjectivity
Uh in the book I reality subjectivity
Uh in the book I reality subjectivity um you wrote the best question to work
um you wrote the best question to work
um you wrote the best question to work with is how am I aware? That question
with is how am I aware? That question
with is how am I aware? That question leads directly and non-verbbally to the
leads directly and non-verbbally to the
leads directly and non-verbbally to the ever present reality.
ever present reality.
ever present reality. This is actually the only practice that
This is actually the only practice that
This is actually the only practice that leads directly through the doorway. My
leads directly through the doorway. My
leads directly through the doorway. My question is how would you actually have
question is how would you actually have
question is how would you actually have me to work with this question in my
me to work with this question in my
me to work with this question in my everyday life?
everyday life?
everyday life? >> What is the question?
>> What is the question?
>> What is the question? >> They give me recitations. What is the
>> They give me recitations. What is the
>> They give me recitations. What is the question?
question?
question? >> What is this one? Um
>> the question is what leads directly
>> the question is what leads directly to the doorway basically and how it you
to the doorway basically and how it you
to the doorway basically and how it you say um it's actually only the present
say um it's actually only the present
say um it's actually only the present that leads presence that leads directly
that leads presence that leads directly
that leads presence that leads directly through the doorway. He's he's asking
through the doorway. He's he's asking
through the doorway. He's he's asking you to interpretate interpretate
you to interpretate interpretate
you to interpretate interpretate interpretate that.
interpretate that.
interpretate that. >> Interpret it.
>> Interpret it.
>> Interpret it. >> Anticipating it
>> Anticipating it
>> Anticipating it >> in what?
>> in what?
>> in what? >> Interpreting it or anticipating it.
>> Interpreting it or anticipating it.
>> Interpreting it or anticipating it. >> He wants you to turn. You wrote that in
>> He wants you to turn. You wrote that in
>> He wants you to turn. You wrote that in Eye of the Eye. And so he would like to
Eye of the Eye. And so he would like to
Eye of the Eye. And so he would like to know how is he to work with that quote.
know how is he to work with that quote.
know how is he to work with that quote. >> What is the quote?
it says the
it says the the question leads directly to
the question leads directly to
the question leads directly to the nonverbal
the nonverbal
the nonverbal >> the
>> the
>> the >> which is the which is the quote here
>> which is the which is the quote here
>> which is the which is the quote here >> this
>> this
>> this is the quote
is the quote
is the quote the question to work with is what am I
the question to work with is what am I
the question to work with is what am I aware?
aware?
aware? >> Okay. The be the quote is the best
>> Okay. The be the quote is the best
>> Okay. The be the quote is the best question to work with is how am I aware?
question to work with is how am I aware?
question to work with is how am I aware? >> Why am I how am I aware?
>> Why am I how am I aware?
>> Why am I how am I aware? >> Yes. And this came out of I
>> Yes. And this came out of I
>> Yes. And this came out of I >> Yeah. What is the source of awareness?
>> Yeah. What is the source of awareness?
>> Yeah. What is the source of awareness? Because the source of awareness leads
Because the source of awareness leads
Because the source of awareness leads you directly to the infinite field of
you directly to the infinite field of
you directly to the infinite field of consciousness itself. It's not a
consciousness itself. It's not a
consciousness itself. It's not a personal self that's aware. It's
personal self that's aware. It's
personal self that's aware. It's awareness that's aware. Awareness is an
awareness that's aware. Awareness is an
awareness that's aware. Awareness is an impersonal phenomena.
impersonal phenomena.
impersonal phenomena. It's a quality of life. And uh it's
It's a quality of life. And uh it's
It's a quality of life. And uh it's it's awareness that's aware. There's no
it's awareness that's aware. There's no
it's awareness that's aware. There's no personal eye that's aware. So if you
personal eye that's aware. So if you
personal eye that's aware. So if you reflect on it, you realize that there
reflect on it, you realize that there
reflect on it, you realize that there isn't any personal eye that's aware.
isn't any personal eye that's aware.
isn't any personal eye that's aware. There is no personal eye. Consciousness
There is no personal eye. Consciousness
There is no personal eye. Consciousness is aware.
is aware.
is aware. But consciousness is independent of a
But consciousness is independent of a
But consciousness is independent of a personal eye.
personal eye.
personal eye. So the uh it it's a phenomena that
So the uh it it's a phenomena that
So the uh it it's a phenomena that occurs as a consequence of its own
occurs as a consequence of its own
occurs as a consequence of its own reality,
reality,
reality, not because of a personal you. It
not because of a personal you. It
not because of a personal you. It doesn't require a personal pronoun.
doesn't require a personal pronoun.
doesn't require a personal pronoun. So reality does not require a personal
So reality does not require a personal
So reality does not require a personal pronoun. There is no person that becomes
pronoun. There is no person that becomes
pronoun. There is no person that becomes enlightened.
enlightened.
enlightened. There is no person that becomes
There is no person that becomes
There is no person that becomes enlightened.
Okay. Thank you.
Okay. Thank you. >> Does that answer your question?
>> Does that answer your question?
>> Does that answer your question? >> Yes. Yes.
>> It's a little hard to hear with the
>> It's a little hard to hear with the >> Yeah, we're here.
>> Yeah, we're here.
>> Yeah, we're here. >> When he speaks, when he speaks in there,
>> When he speaks, when he speaks in there,
>> When he speaks, when he speaks in there, where does the sound come out of?
where does the sound come out of?
where does the sound come out of? >> The speaker.
>> The speaker.
>> The speaker. >> When he speaks into there, where does
>> When he speaks into there, where does
>> When he speaks into there, where does the sound come out of?
the sound come out of?
the sound come out of? >> Speaker.
>> Speaker.
>> Speaker. >> Speaker where? In the ceiling. Oh, I'm
>> Speaker where? In the ceiling. Oh, I'm
>> Speaker where? In the ceiling. Oh, I'm just asking where is the sound coming
just asking where is the sound coming
just asking where is the sound coming from?
from?
from? Huh?
Huh?
Huh? >> It's coming from speakers on the sides.
>> It's coming from speakers on the sides.
>> It's coming from speakers on the sides. That's why I can't locate it in one
That's why I can't locate it in one
That's why I can't locate it in one place cuz it's coming from two places.
place cuz it's coming from two places.
place cuz it's coming from two places. Okay, that makes sense now. Okay.
>> All right. Yes. Thank you. Yeah.
>> All right. Yes. Thank you. Yeah. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Now it makes sense now. I couldn't
>> Now it makes sense now. I couldn't
>> Now it makes sense now. I couldn't understand the acoustics.
understand the acoustics.
understand the acoustics. >> Good.
>> Good.
>> Good. >> I couldn't understand the acoustics. Now
>> I couldn't understand the acoustics. Now
>> I couldn't understand the acoustics. Now I understand the acoustics. what you
I understand the acoustics. what you
I understand the acoustics. what you were asking me. Go right anywhere.
were asking me. Go right anywhere.
were asking me. Go right anywhere. >> Yeah, I was asking where is the sound
>> Yeah, I was asking where is the sound
>> Yeah, I was asking where is the sound coming from, you know.
coming from, you know.
coming from, you know. >> Thank you. Thank you, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Thank you. Thank you, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Thank you. Thank you, Dr. Hawkins. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Um, we would like to ask for the silent
>> Um, we would like to ask for the silent
>> Um, we would like to ask for the silent transmission of knowingness from the
transmission of knowingness from the
transmission of knowingness from the enlightened teacher for me and my wife.
enlightened teacher for me and my wife.
enlightened teacher for me and my wife. >> I can't hear what he's saying.
>> I can't hear what he's saying.
>> I can't hear what he's saying. >> He wants you to send in the silent
>> He wants you to send in the silent
>> He wants you to send in the silent transmission.
transmission.
transmission. >> It's already done.
>> It's already done.
>> It's already done. >> Okay. Well, okay.
>> Okay. Well, okay.
>> Okay. Well, okay. >> Oh, great. Thanks,
>> Hi.
>> Hi. The energy field of the teacher's aura
The energy field of the teacher's aura
The energy field of the teacher's aura radiates into the energy field of the
radiates into the energy field of the
radiates into the energy field of the aura of the student and it's silent and
aura of the student and it's silent and
aura of the student and it's silent and it's automatic and it happens you know
it's automatic and it happens you know
it's automatic and it happens you know for eternity 1,000 years from now the
for eternity 1,000 years from now the
for eternity 1,000 years from now the same energy will be there. Yeah.
same energy will be there. Yeah.
same energy will be there. Yeah. >> Okay. We have
>> Okay. We have
>> Okay. We have >> Yeah. Yes.
>> Yeah. Yes.
>> Yeah. Yes. >> Thank you Dr. Hawkins for being here for
>> Thank you Dr. Hawkins for being here for
>> Thank you Dr. Hawkins for being here for us.
us.
us. >> Thank you. Thank you so much.
>> Thank you. Thank you so much.
>> Thank you. Thank you so much. >> Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Thank you very much. >> Thank you.
H
H or is that man?
or is that man?
or is that man? >> Hi. Hi, sweetheart.
>> Hi. Hi, sweetheart.
>> Hi. Hi, sweetheart. >> He's speaking under the scourge of the
>> He's speaking under the scourge of the
>> He's speaking under the scourge of the table.
>> Okay, go ahead. Prayer beads.
>> Okay, go ahead. Prayer beads. >> Thank you, Doc, for everything that
>> Thank you, Doc, for everything that
>> Thank you, Doc, for everything that you've done for us. Um, we two sisters
you've done for us. Um, we two sisters
you've done for us. Um, we two sisters are here to ask you for your blessings
are here to ask you for your blessings
are here to ask you for your blessings um on our prayer beads, please.
um on our prayer beads, please.
um on our prayer beads, please. >> They want blessings on their prayer.
>> They want blessings on their prayer.
>> They want blessings on their prayer. >> God bless. God bless. Amen.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> They're blessed.
>> They're blessed.
>> They're blessed. >> Your intention is already blessed
>> Your intention is already blessed
>> Your intention is already blessed because of your intention.
because of your intention.
because of your intention. >> Thank you both.
>> Thank you both.
>> Thank you both. >> Thank you.
>> We're We are having a few time hard
>> We're We are having a few time hard times hearing. Oh.
Hi.
Hi. >> Hello. Hello. thanks for this uh
>> Hello. Hello. thanks for this uh
>> Hello. Hello. thanks for this uh opportunity.
opportunity.
opportunity. And uh earlier this morning you
And uh earlier this morning you
And uh earlier this morning you mentioned about the karmic bank account
mentioned about the karmic bank account
mentioned about the karmic bank account and uh we had an incident in our family
and uh we had an incident in our family
and uh we had an incident in our family where
where
where my daughter was involved in a serious
my daughter was involved in a serious
my daughter was involved in a serious accident
accident
accident and she's such a delightful person. I
and she's such a delightful person. I
and she's such a delightful person. I wonder if you can help me understand
wonder if you can help me understand
wonder if you can help me understand how bad things
how bad things
how bad things happen to good people.
happen to good people.
happen to good people. >> That's a tough one.
>> That's a tough one.
>> That's a tough one. >> What is he asking? How does bad things
>> What is he asking? How does bad things
>> What is he asking? How does bad things happen to good people?
happen to good people?
happen to good people? >> Good people.
>> Good people.
>> Good people. >> What do you mean by a bad thing?
>> What do you mean by a bad thing?
>> What do you mean by a bad thing? >> Well, his daughter was in a bad car
>> Well, his daughter was in a bad car
>> Well, his daughter was in a bad car accident.
accident.
accident. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> And so he wants you to have
>> And so he wants you to have
>> And so he wants you to have >> It's his view of badness, right?
>> It's his view of badness, right?
>> It's his view of badness, right? >> Oh, that's your view of bad badness.
>> Oh, that's your view of bad badness.
>> Oh, that's your view of bad badness. Yeah. That's just life. Yeah.
Life is full of bumps, ups and downs.
Life is full of bumps, ups and downs. You can call this bad or you can call it
You can call this bad or you can call it
You can call this bad or you can call it good, but that's arbitrary
good, but that's arbitrary
good, but that's arbitrary because it serves some karmic purpose.
because it serves some karmic purpose.
because it serves some karmic purpose. So some
So some
So some un unresolved karmic debt is being paid
un unresolved karmic debt is being paid
un unresolved karmic debt is being paid off would be my guess. Some unresolved
off would be my guess. Some unresolved
off would be my guess. Some unresolved karmic debt is being paid off. Resist.
karmic debt is being paid off. Resist.
karmic debt is being paid off. Resist. So it's not going to waste.
So it's not going to waste.
So it's not going to waste. Nor is it undeserved.
>> It's paid.
>> It's paid. >> It's a karmic balance is perfect.
>> Thank you. Yeah.
>> Thank you. Yeah. >> So all suffering ser serves some
>> So all suffering ser serves some
>> So all suffering ser serves some purpose. It undoes negative karma.
purpose. It undoes negative karma.
purpose. It undoes negative karma. And it also brings about a certain
And it also brings about a certain
And it also brings about a certain strengthening of the spirit that you
strengthening of the spirit that you
strengthening of the spirit that you overlook the physical. You realize the
overlook the physical. You realize the
overlook the physical. You realize the physical is not your reality.
>> Suffering very often brings us to a
>> Suffering very often brings us to a point of surrender and that point of
point of surrender and that point of
point of surrender and that point of surrender is a major leap forward.
surrender is a major leap forward.
surrender is a major leap forward. Certainly aa is probably one of the best
Certainly aa is probably one of the best
Certainly aa is probably one of the best examples of that. Through endless pain,
examples of that. Through endless pain,
examples of that. Through endless pain, suffering, indignation, humiliation,
suffering, indignation, humiliation,
suffering, indignation, humiliation, sickness and suffering, the person is
sickness and suffering, the person is
sickness and suffering, the person is finally led to give up and turn to God.
finally led to give up and turn to God.
finally led to give up and turn to God. So every everything serves its purpose.
So every everything serves its purpose.
So every everything serves its purpose. Nothing uh happens without it fitting
Nothing uh happens without it fitting
Nothing uh happens without it fitting into the overall field of spiritual
into the overall field of spiritual
into the overall field of spiritual purpose.
purpose.
purpose. The divine will divine will there's
The divine will divine will there's
The divine will divine will there's nothing beyond divine will.
nothing beyond divine will.
nothing beyond divine will. So whatever happened you can say
So whatever happened you can say
So whatever happened you can say yourself for reasons which I am not
yourself for reasons which I am not
yourself for reasons which I am not understanding. Uh this is in somehow in
understanding. Uh this is in somehow in
understanding. Uh this is in somehow in accord with divine will.
>> Can I get a picture?
>> Can I get a picture? >> Thank you.
There we go.
There we go. >> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much. >> You bet.
>> They're moving everything to the back.
>> They're moving everything to the back. >> Oh, look at this. These are all our
>> Oh, look at this. These are all our
>> Oh, look at this. These are all our books in Korean that are coming up here.
books in Korean that are coming up here.
books in Korean that are coming up here. It's just wonderful to see them.
>> Hello, David. Hello, Susan.
>> Hello, David. Hello, Susan. >> Hi.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. >> We came from Canada just to receive the
>> We came from Canada just to receive the
>> We came from Canada just to receive the transmission, which I guess we found out
transmission, which I guess we found out
transmission, which I guess we found out we already got.
we already got.
we already got. >> I can't hear what he's saying.
>> I can't hear what he's saying.
>> I can't hear what he's saying. >> He went in the transmission, but he
>> He went in the transmission, but he
>> He went in the transmission, but he says, "I guess we already got it."
says, "I guess we already got it."
says, "I guess we already got it." >> Yep.
>> Yep.
>> Yep. >> So, I guess we'll uh we'll settle with a
>> So, I guess we'll uh we'll settle with a
>> So, I guess we'll uh we'll settle with a picture today if we could get one.
picture today if we could get one.
picture today if we could get one. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Thank you. You bet.
>> It's kind of directing the
>> It's kind of directing the Okay, we're all right. We're set.
The transmission is
The transmission is it does so of its own accord.
it does so of its own accord.
it does so of its own accord. Does so of its own accord. Okay.
Does so of its own accord. Okay.
Does so of its own accord. Okay. >> Hi.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Hi.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. >> Um, what's the best way to get over a
>> Um, what's the best way to get over a
>> Um, what's the best way to get over a passive aggressive tendency?
passive aggressive tendency?
passive aggressive tendency? >> What's the best way? What
>> What's the best way? What
>> What's the best way? What >> she has a passive aggressive tendency?
>> she has a passive aggressive tendency?
>> she has a passive aggressive tendency? Yes.
Yes.
Yes. >> What is the best way to get over it? to
>> What is the best way to get over it? to
>> What is the best way to get over it? to be middle of the road instead of too
be middle of the road instead of too
be middle of the road instead of too much one way and too much the other way.
much one way and too much the other way.
much one way and too much the other way. To to image the way that you wish to be
To to image the way that you wish to be
To to image the way that you wish to be and then practice it.
Image the way you wish to be and then
Image the way you wish to be and then practice it.
practice it.
practice it. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> You understand that?
>> You understand that?
>> You understand that? >> I hope so.
>> I hope so.
>> I hope so. >> Can you say yes?
>> Can you say yes?
>> Can you say yes? >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Yes. This is no time to be stupidly
>> Yes. This is no time to be stupidly
>> Yes. This is no time to be stupidly passive.
When I say yes, you say yes. Hello. Yes.
When I say yes, you say yes. Hello. Yes. Hello. Good morning. Good evening. You
Hello. Good morning. Good evening. You
Hello. Good morning. Good evening. You practice with me. Good morning, doctor.
practice with me. Good morning, doctor.
practice with me. Good morning, doctor. >> Morning, doctor.
>> Morning, doctor.
>> Morning, doctor. >> Good afternoon, doctor.
>> Good afternoon, doctor.
>> Good afternoon, doctor. >> Good afternoon, doctor.
>> Good afternoon, doctor. >> I enjoyed being with you today, doctor.
>> I enjoyed being with you today, doctor.
>> I enjoyed being with you today, doctor. >> I enjoyed being
>> I enjoyed being
>> I enjoyed being >> Oh, I Well, I enjoyed your commentaries.
>> Oh, I Well, I enjoyed your commentaries.
>> Oh, I Well, I enjoyed your commentaries. Thank you for coming up and sharing
Thank you for coming up and sharing
Thank you for coming up and sharing yourself in a straightforward honest way
yourself in a straightforward honest way
yourself in a straightforward honest way without embellishment
without embellishment
without embellishment without being passive mousy dopey
without being passive mousy dopey
without being passive mousy dopey without being aggressively.
without being aggressively.
without being aggressively. >> Is that good enough?
>> Is that good enough?
>> Is that good enough? >> That's great.
>> That's great.
>> That's great. >> You got to practice that in front of the
>> You got to practice that in front of the
>> You got to practice that in front of the mirror.
>> You practice that in front of the
>> You practice that in front of the mirror. Put a thing that says Good
mirror. Put a thing that says Good
mirror. Put a thing that says Good morning, whatever your name is. And just
morning, whatever your name is. And just
morning, whatever your name is. And just be a normal person. Try being normal.
be a normal person. Try being normal.
be a normal person. Try being normal. >> You got to practice being normal.
>> Hello.
>> Hello. >> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. Hello, Susan. Just
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. Hello, Susan. Just
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. Hello, Susan. Just want to say thank you very much. Ask if
want to say thank you very much. Ask if
want to say thank you very much. Ask if you would sign my book. And uh could I
you would sign my book. And uh could I
you would sign my book. And uh could I get a photograph, please?
get a photograph, please?
get a photograph, please? >> And what? Can he get a photograph?
>> And what? Can he get a photograph?
>> And what? Can he get a photograph? >> Can you get a photograph?
>> Can you get a photograph?
>> Can you get a photograph? >> What?
>> What?
>> What? >> A photograph.
>> A photograph.
>> A photograph. >> Yeah, there you are. Thank you.
>> Yeah, there you are. Thank you.
>> Yeah, there you are. Thank you. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much. >> I'm sorry. It's been one of these days,
>> I'm sorry. It's been one of these days,
>> I'm sorry. It's been one of these days, you know,
you know,
you know, >> there you go.
>> there you go.
>> there you go. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Yep.
>> Oh, sorry.
>> Oh, sorry. >> That way, Dave. We got it. Don't worry.
>> That way, Dave. We got it. Don't worry.
>> That way, Dave. We got it. Don't worry. Okay. Thank you very much.
Okay. Thank you very much.
Okay. Thank you very much. >> Oh, wonderful.
>> Oh, wonderful.
>> Oh, wonderful. Hi.
>> Hi. It's good to be here.
>> Hi. It's good to be here. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Um, I just wanted to give a big major
>> Um, I just wanted to give a big major
>> Um, I just wanted to give a big major thanks for everything. Um, it's been a
thanks for everything. Um, it's been a
thanks for everything. Um, it's been a huge blessing to my life and my kids'
huge blessing to my life and my kids'
huge blessing to my life and my kids' life and everybody that I love. So,
life and everybody that I love. So,
life and everybody that I love. So, thank you for that. And
thank you for that. And
thank you for that. And >> it radiates out to everyone.
>> it radiates out to everyone.
>> it radiates out to everyone. >> Yeah. So, and I don't have to do
>> Yeah. So, and I don't have to do
>> Yeah. So, and I don't have to do anything for it. So, that's the best
anything for it. So, that's the best
anything for it. So, that's the best part.
>> Yes. to be loving of all of life,
>> Yes. to be loving of all of life, courteous towards all of life, to
courteous towards all of life, to
courteous towards all of life, to respect all of life in all of its forms,
respect all of life in all of its forms,
respect all of life in all of its forms, whether you like it or don't like it.
whether you like it or don't like it.
whether you like it or don't like it. You can't tell a dragon you don't like
You can't tell a dragon you don't like
You can't tell a dragon you don't like as being a dragon because the purpose of
as being a dragon because the purpose of
as being a dragon because the purpose of a dragon is to be a dragon. You know
a dragon is to be a dragon. You know
a dragon is to be a dragon. You know what I'm saying?
The purpose of a saint is to be a saint.
The purpose of a saint is to be a saint. So each thing already is the expression
So each thing already is the expression
So each thing already is the expression of that which it is.
of that which it is.
of that which it is. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Perfect.
>> Perfect.
>> Perfect. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Yeah. Thanks a lot.
>> Yeah. Thanks a lot.
>> Yeah. Thanks a lot. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> Can I get a picture?
Doc,
Doc, >> you need you need picture ID to get into
>> you need you need picture ID to get into
>> you need you need picture ID to get into heaven though.
heaven though.
heaven though. >> You have to have picture ID. Yeah.
>> You have to have picture ID. Yeah.
>> You have to have picture ID. Yeah. >> Oh, yeah.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Oh, yeah. >> That's where they get their picture
>> That's where they get their picture
>> That's where they get their picture taken with me.
taken with me.
taken with me. >> All right.
>> All right.
>> All right. >> Yeah.
St. Peter wants to see your
St. Peter wants to see your >> bad karma to argue with the dog. You
>> bad karma to argue with the dog. You
>> bad karma to argue with the dog. You know,
know,
know, >> St. Peter wants to see your ID.
>> St. Peter wants to see your ID.
>> St. Peter wants to see your ID. >> My ID.
>> There we go.
>> There we go. Yeah. He claims he's from planet Earth.
Yeah. He claims he's from planet Earth.
Yeah. He claims he's from planet Earth. Well, let's see your ID.
>> Can I touch your hand?
>> Can I touch your hand? >> Is that okay?
>> Is that okay?
>> Is that okay? >> What?
>> What?
>> What? >> Touch his hand.
>> Touch his hand.
>> Touch his hand. >> No, I don't want to touch people's hands
>> No, I don't want to touch people's hands
>> No, I don't want to touch people's hands today.
today.
today. >> Oh, yeah.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Oh, yeah. >> There's too many viruses around, you
>> There's too many viruses around, you
>> There's too many viruses around, you know.
know.
know. >> Then you got to wash your hands with
>> Then you got to wash your hands with
>> Then you got to wash your hands with that uh
that uh
that uh >> sterilizer stuff. Yeah,
>> sterilizer stuff. Yeah,
>> sterilizer stuff. Yeah, >> no problem.
>> no problem.
>> no problem. >> I in one or whatever that is.
>> We're trying to be careful.
>> We're trying to be careful. >> Oh, you're still asking.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Can you sign this?
>> Can you sign this?
>> Can you sign this? >> Yes, we are.
>> Yes, we are.
>> Yes, we are. >> Okay. What's your question?
>> Okay. What's your question?
>> Okay. What's your question? My question is you mentioned
My question is you mentioned
My question is you mentioned surrendering and how the last thing to
surrendering and how the last thing to
surrendering and how the last thing to surrender. Can you please this?
surrender. Can you please this?
surrender. Can you please this? >> Oh
>> Oh
>> Oh >> yeah.
>> yeah.
>> yeah. >> Do you want to sign this?
>> Do you want to sign this?
>> Do you want to sign this? >> Yeah. It's a picture.
>> Yeah. It's a picture.
>> Yeah. It's a picture. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> From a friend.
>> From a friend.
>> From a friend. >> You want to sign that?
>> You want to sign that?
>> You want to sign that? >> Yeah. The last thing to surrender is
>> Yeah. The last thing to surrender is
>> Yeah. The last thing to surrender is life itself. Because the last illusion
life itself. Because the last illusion
life itself. Because the last illusion from the ego is that it is the source of
from the ego is that it is the source of
from the ego is that it is the source of its own life.
its own life.
its own life. >> I can't hear what he's saying.
>> I can't hear what he's saying.
>> I can't hear what he's saying. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. make it as clear as possible. Okay. All
make it as clear as possible. Okay. All
make it as clear as possible. Okay. All right.
right.
right. >> You can repeat to me what he's saying.
>> You can repeat to me what he's saying.
>> You can repeat to me what he's saying. >> He's not clear.
>> He's not clear.
>> He's not clear. >> We're having feedback. He's having
>> We're having feedback. He's having
>> We're having feedback. He's having feedback. It's going out to the
feedback. It's going out to the
feedback. It's going out to the audience. And so over here, he can't
audience. And so over here, he can't
audience. And so over here, he can't hear as well. So just just
hear as well. So just just
hear as well. So just just >> what is the question?
>> what is the question?
>> what is the question? >> Well, the last thing to be surrendered,
>> Well, the last thing to be surrendered,
>> Well, the last thing to be surrendered, the last illusion you mentioned through
the last illusion you mentioned through
the last illusion you mentioned through your work is that the ego is the source
your work is that the ego is the source
your work is that the ego is the source of of of its own life
of of of its own life
of of of its own life >> of life. Yes.
>> of life. Yes.
>> of life. Yes. >> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. >> And you mentioned that when you
>> And you mentioned that when you
>> And you mentioned that when you surrender that you go you experience
surrender that you go you experience
surrender that you go you experience that.
that.
that. >> I run through that. I didn't say you do.
>> I run through that. I didn't say you do.
>> I run through that. I didn't say you do. I said that's what I experienced.
I said that's what I experienced.
I said that's what I experienced. >> Oh, that's your experience.
>> Oh, that's your experience.
>> Oh, that's your experience. >> I just shared what I experienced.
>> I just shared what I experienced.
>> I just shared what I experienced. >> Oh, I see.
>> Oh, I see.
>> Oh, I see. >> I didn't say everybody's going to do
>> I didn't say everybody's going to do
>> I didn't say everybody's going to do that.
that.
that. >> Oh, I see. Cuz I was under the
>> Oh, I see. Cuz I was under the
>> Oh, I see. Cuz I was under the impression I like I wanted to The
impression I like I wanted to The
impression I like I wanted to The question is on what LLC on what level
question is on what LLC on what level
question is on what LLC on what level does the ego death happen?
does the ego death happen?
does the ego death happen? >> What level does the ego death or the ego
>> What level does the ego death or the ego
>> What level does the ego death or the ego dies? What level does the eagle die? Ego
dies? What level does the eagle die? Ego
dies? What level does the eagle die? Ego die completely.
die completely.
die completely. You
You
You >> asked this before.
>> asked this before.
>> asked this before. I can't answer that
I can't answer that
I can't answer that >> because it's different in each person.
>> because it's different in each person.
>> because it's different in each person. >> Some people the ego is very tenacious
>> Some people the ego is very tenacious
>> Some people the ego is very tenacious and uh
and uh
and uh other people uh you know because of many
other people uh you know because of many
other people uh you know because of many years of spiritual work the ego is uh
years of spiritual work the ego is uh
years of spiritual work the ego is uh lessened its hold and uh also it's more
lessened its hold and uh also it's more
lessened its hold and uh also it's more identifiable.
identifiable.
identifiable. A lot of people uh don't know what
A lot of people uh don't know what
A lot of people uh don't know what within their own psyche and
within their own psyche and
within their own psyche and consciousness is ego and which is
consciousness is ego and which is
consciousness is ego and which is spirit. They don't know what what is
spirit. They don't know what what is
spirit. They don't know what what is their ego speaking or not. Very often
their ego speaking or not. Very often
their ego speaking or not. Very often it's just the ego that's seeking
it's just the ego that's seeking
it's just the ego that's seeking enlightenment.
>> So there is no question no answer to
>> So there is no question no answer to that.
that.
that. >> I see.
>> I see.
>> I see. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> So how do I know that? I I thought that
>> So how do I know that? I I thought that
>> So how do I know that? I I thought that 599
599 you surrendered life itself.
you surrendered life itself.
you surrendered life itself. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> How do you know that you were lying?
>> How do you know that you were lying?
>> How do you know that you were lying? And what
And what
And what >> how do you know that you become
>> how do you know that you become
>> how do you know that you become enlightened at 599?
enlightened at 599?
enlightened at 599? >> All that becomes irrelevant.
>> You do what you do for God and uh worry.
>> You do what you do for God and uh worry. Don't worry about enlightenment. Hi,
Don't worry about enlightenment. Hi,
Don't worry about enlightenment. Hi, >> he can sign this for me.
>> he can sign this for me.
>> he can sign this for me. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> I just wanted to tell you that you
>> I just wanted to tell you that you
>> I just wanted to tell you that you passed divine grace to my brother and he
passed divine grace to my brother and he
passed divine grace to my brother and he passed it to me and I wanted to thank
passed it to me and I wanted to thank
passed it to me and I wanted to thank you on behalf of both of us for being
you on behalf of both of us for being
you on behalf of both of us for being you.
you.
you. >> I don't hear what she's saying.
>> I don't hear what she's saying.
>> I don't hear what she's saying. >> Thank you for being you.
>> Thank you for being you.
>> Thank you for being you. >> She's just she's thanking you because
>> She's just she's thanking you because
>> She's just she's thanking you because she said you gave divine grace to her
she said you gave divine grace to her
she said you gave divine grace to her brother.
brother.
brother. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> And he passed it to her. Oh, okay.
>> And he passed it to her. Oh, okay.
>> And he passed it to her. Oh, okay. >> And so that's why she's
>> And so that's why she's
>> And so that's why she's >> I thought she was said he'd passed on.
>> I thought she was said he'd passed on.
>> I thought she was said he'd passed on. >> No, he's he's here. He's sitting in the
>> No, he's he's here. He's sitting in the
>> No, he's he's here. He's sitting in the audience.
audience.
audience. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> He's here.
>> He's here.
>> He's here. >> But thank you for meeting you.
>> But thank you for meeting you.
>> But thank you for meeting you. >> Thank you. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thank you. >> Thank you so much.
>> She said he he passed on.
>> She said he he passed on. >> She did. She said he he passed it on.
>> She did. She said he he passed it on.
>> She did. She said he he passed it on. >> Oh, he passed it on. I thought you said
>> Oh, he passed it on. I thought you said
>> Oh, he passed it on. I thought you said he he passed on.
he he passed on.
he he passed on. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Hi,
Hi,
Hi, >> I'm representing a contingent of us that
>> I'm representing a contingent of us that
>> I'm representing a contingent of us that are here from South Africa this
are here from South Africa this
are here from South Africa this afternoon and
afternoon and
afternoon and >> we have South Africa
>> we have South Africa
>> we have South Africa >> and there's um I just wanted to ask for
>> and there's um I just wanted to ask for
>> and there's um I just wanted to ask for a blessing from you for all of us and
a blessing from you for all of us and
a blessing from you for all of us and for the continent and for South Africa
for the continent and for South Africa
for the continent and for South Africa >> blessings on South Africa
>> blessings on South Africa
>> blessings on South Africa >> for the group and for the group that's
>> for the group and for the group that's
>> for the group and for the group that's >> Oh the South Africa group yes I know the
>> Oh the South Africa group yes I know the
>> Oh the South Africa group yes I know the group you mean yes God bless that South
group you mean yes God bless that South
group you mean yes God bless that South Africa group amen Yeah,
>> we have groups all over the world.
>> we have groups all over the world. Australia and South Africa and India and
Australia and South Africa and India and
Australia and South Africa and India and Dubai and God knows where.
Dubai and God knows where.
Dubai and God knows where. >> Uhhuh.
>> Hello David. Hello Susan.
>> Hello David. Hello Susan. >> Hi.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. >> I came today strictly to say thank you
>> I came today strictly to say thank you
>> I came today strictly to say thank you for all of the work that you have done
for all of the work that you have done
for all of the work that you have done for all of us.
for all of us.
for all of us. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Yes.
>> Yes. And may I get a picture?
And may I get a picture?
And may I get a picture? >> What?
>> What?
>> What? >> She wants a picture,
>> She wants a picture,
>> She wants a picture, >> huh?
>> huh?
>> huh? >> She wants a picture.
>> She wants a picture.
>> She wants a picture. >> Oh, yeah.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Oh, yeah. >> It's guarantees are getting into heaven.
>> It's guarantees are getting into heaven.
>> It's guarantees are getting into heaven. >> Oh, okay. Okay.
>> Oh, okay. Okay.
>> Oh, okay. Okay. >> Want ID for St. St. Peter.
>> Want ID for St. St. Peter.
>> Want ID for St. St. Peter. >> St. Peter checks your ID at the gate.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Thank you so much. >> Yeah.
Good afternoon.
Good afternoon. >> Good afternoon.
>> Good afternoon.
>> Good afternoon. >> Um, we've come from Jersey in the
>> Um, we've come from Jersey in the
>> Um, we've come from Jersey in the Channel Islands. It's a blessing to be
Channel Islands. It's a blessing to be
Channel Islands. It's a blessing to be here.
here.
here. >> You come from where?
>> You come from where?
>> You come from where? >> Jersey in the Channel Islands off of
>> Jersey in the Channel Islands off of
>> Jersey in the Channel Islands off of it's a UK island.
it's a UK island.
it's a UK island. Um my question today is could you please
Um my question today is could you please
Um my question today is could you please clarify as students receiving the aura
clarify as students receiving the aura
clarify as students receiving the aura imprint?
imprint?
imprint? Um
Um
Um does it require us to touch others or
does it require us to touch others or
does it require us to touch others or just by being in the presence we can
just by being in the presence we can
just by being in the presence we can pass it on to others where we live?
pass it on to others where we live?
pass it on to others where we live? >> What's the question?
>> What's the question?
>> What's the question? >> The aura. Yes.
>> The aura. Yes.
>> The aura. Yes. >> He wants to know if they if just by
>> He wants to know if they if just by
>> He wants to know if they if just by being in the presence. That's all.
being in the presence. That's all.
being in the presence. That's all. >> That's all that's required. requires the
>> That's all that's required. requires the
>> That's all that's required. requires the physical presence,
physical presence,
physical presence, >> right? But not necessarily the physical
>> right? But not necessarily the physical
>> right? But not necessarily the physical touching.
touching.
touching. >> No.
>> No.
>> No. >> Is that on on the basis of the students
>> Is that on on the basis of the students
>> Is that on on the basis of the students as well?
as well?
as well? >> Is that on the basis of the students as
>> Is that on the basis of the students as
>> Is that on the basis of the students as well?
well?
well? >> Can the students pass it on?
>> Can the students pass it on?
>> Can the students pass it on? >> Can the students pass on that aura?
>> Can the students pass on that aura?
>> Can the students pass on that aura? >> Oh. Oh, I don't know.
>> Oh. Oh, I don't know.
>> Oh. Oh, I don't know. >> Outside of this room,
>> Outside of this room,
>> Outside of this room, >> uh the the students,
>> uh the the students,
>> uh the the students, >> you better ask me if we can do this
>> you better ask me if we can do this
>> you better ask me if we can do this permission, please.
permission, please.
permission, please. >> We have permission to ask about the
>> We have permission to ask about the
>> We have permission to ask about the student.
student.
student. >> Thank you. The student picks up the
>> Thank you. The student picks up the
>> Thank you. The student picks up the teacher's aura. The student now has the
teacher's aura. The student now has the
teacher's aura. The student now has the teacher's aura and can and can pass it
teacher's aura and can and can pass it
teacher's aura and can and can pass it on to others. Resist.
on to others. Resist.
on to others. Resist. >> Thank you.
>> Please let me have um a photograph. Um
>> Please let me have um a photograph. Um but I think Carl's forgotten the dollar.
but I think Carl's forgotten the dollar.
but I think Carl's forgotten the dollar. >> They want a photograph but they forgot
>> They want a photograph but they forgot
>> They want a photograph but they forgot their dollar.
their dollar.
their dollar. >> Christianity does spread that way. You
>> Christianity does spread that way. You
>> Christianity does spread that way. You know just not only the word of mouth but
know just not only the word of mouth but
know just not only the word of mouth but the energy field itself.
the energy field itself.
the energy field itself. Yeah. So all religions have spread via
Yeah. So all religions have spread via
Yeah. So all religions have spread via the energ the transmission of the energy
the energ the transmission of the energy
the energ the transmission of the energy field resist
field resist
field resist from Krishna resist from Buddha from
from Krishna resist from Buddha from
from Krishna resist from Buddha from Christ. Yeah. Okay.
Christ. Yeah. Okay.
Christ. Yeah. Okay. >> Thank you. Um the photograph.
>> Thank you. Um the photograph.
>> Thank you. Um the photograph. >> Yes. Go ahead.
>> Yes. Go ahead.
>> Yes. Go ahead. >> Thank you. Um that that made sense to me
>> Thank you. Um that that made sense to me
>> Thank you. Um that that made sense to me because remember when we were talking at
because remember when we were talking at
because remember when we were talking at noon and you had said you know that that
noon and you had said you know that that
noon and you had said you know that that the energy in the field there was enough
the energy in the field there was enough
the energy in the field there was enough to go around. Remember when you said
to go around. Remember when you said
to go around. Remember when you said that and I said that was really
that and I said that was really
that and I said that was really relieving to me to know that
relieving to me to know that
relieving to me to know that >> and it was because this is just what we
>> and it was because this is just what we
>> and it was because this is just what we were talking about that the energy that
were talking about that the energy that
were talking about that the energy that you hold within you is enough to go
you hold within you is enough to go
you hold within you is enough to go around.
around.
around. >> So that energy comes forth when it's
>> So that energy comes forth when it's
>> So that energy comes forth when it's drawn upon doesn't it?
Yep.
Yep. >> Yep.
>> Yep.
>> Yep. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Yep.
>> Yep.
>> Yep. >> Perfect.
>> Perfect.
>> Perfect. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> God bless.
>> God bless.
>> God bless. >> God bless.
>> God bless. >> Yeah, that makes sense that cuz I said
>> Yeah, that makes sense that cuz I said
>> Yeah, that makes sense that cuz I said that was really a relief to know that
that was really a relief to know that
that was really a relief to know that that your own spirituality there's
that your own spirituality there's
that your own spirituality there's enough to give out. You know, some
enough to give out. You know, some
enough to give out. You know, some people feel like, you know, it's my
people feel like, you know, it's my
people feel like, you know, it's my spirituality and I don't have to give it
spirituality and I don't have to give it
spirituality and I don't have to give it out. And then when you said there was
out. And then when you said there was
out. And then when you said there was enough energy that could be given out.
enough energy that could be given out.
enough energy that could be given out. >> Well, you radiate out that which you
>> Well, you radiate out that which you
>> Well, you radiate out that which you are. Yeah.
are. Yeah.
are. Yeah. >> Yeah. Not what you are.
>> Yeah. Not what you are.
>> Yeah. Not what you are. >> It's not what you do. It's what you have
>> It's not what you do. It's what you have
>> It's not what you do. It's what you have become.
become.
become. >> So the light shines forth because of the
>> So the light shines forth because of the
>> So the light shines forth because of the radiance of the light, not because the
radiance of the light, not because the
radiance of the light, not because the light wills itself to radiate forth.
light wills itself to radiate forth.
light wills itself to radiate forth. >> Okay. It's very very beautiful. I uh I
>> Okay. It's very very beautiful. I uh I
>> Okay. It's very very beautiful. I uh I love you. And I I got these amazing
love you. And I I got these amazing
love you. And I I got these amazing books. Um, oh, first I want to say that
books. Um, oh, first I want to say that
books. Um, oh, first I want to say that a very wise a
very wise man taught me about all this
very wise man taught me about all this information that I've learned. And uh,
information that I've learned. And uh,
information that I've learned. And uh, Anastasia, it calibrates at 850 and has
Anastasia, it calibrates at 850 and has
Anastasia, it calibrates at 850 and has uh, the fastest thought and has the
uh, the fastest thought and has the
uh, the fastest thought and has the highest level of vitality. Um, this is a
highest level of vitality. Um, this is a
highest level of vitality. Um, this is a book of Yeshua Christ.
book of Yeshua Christ.
book of Yeshua Christ. >> I can't tell what he's talking about.
>> I can't tell what he's talking about.
>> I can't tell what he's talking about. >> He's talking about someone else's work.
>> He's talking about someone else's work.
>> He's talking about someone else's work. I don't know anybody else. Is it okay if
I don't know anybody else. Is it okay if
I don't know anybody else. Is it okay if I just go through it and then just what
I just go through it and then just what
I just go through it and then just what about you?
about you?
about you? >> Just ignore it. Um well then there's a
>> Just ignore it. Um well then there's a
>> Just ignore it. Um well then there's a Okay. And well, I wanted to uh I really
Okay. And well, I wanted to uh I really
Okay. And well, I wanted to uh I really want to make all of this stuff a reality
want to make all of this stuff a reality
want to make all of this stuff a reality and I want to make it happen in my life.
and I want to make it happen in my life.
and I want to make it happen in my life. Like going to like the best school
Like going to like the best school
Like going to like the best school that's
that's
that's uh full of like the most happy students
uh full of like the most happy students
uh full of like the most happy students and
and
and uh also um max out my stats according to
uh also um max out my stats according to
uh also um max out my stats according to uh
uh
uh uh just um a subnal energy analysis that
uh just um a subnal energy analysis that
uh just um a subnal energy analysis that I went through. I don't get what he's
I went through. I don't get what he's
I went through. I don't get what he's saying.
saying.
saying. >> You don't have to understand. We're not
>> You don't have to understand. We're not
>> You don't have to understand. We're not I'm sorry. We're not familiar with this
I'm sorry. We're not familiar with this
I'm sorry. We're not familiar with this work at all.
work at all.
work at all. >> What are you asking?
>> What are you asking?
>> What are you asking? >> Um I'm actually asking if I can give
>> Um I'm actually asking if I can give
>> Um I'm actually asking if I can give this to you as a gift if you want to
this to you as a gift if you want to
this to you as a gift if you want to review and you can just do whatever
review and you can just do whatever
review and you can just do whatever you'd like. If you would accept it.
you'd like. If you would accept it.
you'd like. If you would accept it. >> What is he asking?
>> What is he asking?
>> What is he asking? >> He I don't know. Wait.
>> He I don't know. Wait.
>> He I don't know. Wait. >> Is it possible to give this to you as a
>> Is it possible to give this to you as a
>> Is it possible to give this to you as a gift?
gift?
gift? >> Um if you would
>> Um if you would
>> Um if you would >> take this as a gift. Do you want to take
>> take this as a gift. Do you want to take
>> take this as a gift. Do you want to take this?
this?
this? >> No.
>> No.
>> No. >> You don't want to take it as a gift?
>> You don't want to take it as a gift?
>> You don't want to take it as a gift? >> No. What I want to do with it?
>> No. What I want to do with it?
>> No. What I want to do with it? >> I don't read it or look at it or
>> I don't read it or look at it or
>> I don't read it or look at it or >> No thanks.
>> No thanks.
>> No thanks. >> Okay.
You're bringing Kohl's to Newcastle.
You're bringing Kohl's to Newcastle. Well, thank you.
Well, thank you.
Well, thank you. >> Um, I wanted to I want to make a
>> Um, I wanted to I want to make a
>> Um, I wanted to I want to make a business and I really want it to happen
business and I really want it to happen
business and I really want it to happen in my life for me in as soon as
in my life for me in as soon as
in my life for me in as soon as possible. And that's basically
possible. And that's basically
possible. And that's basically um I mean and I keep falling into all
um I mean and I keep falling into all
um I mean and I keep falling into all these um into the world and not
these um into the world and not
these um into the world and not following my heart. And uh I'm I try to
following my heart. And uh I'm I try to
following my heart. And uh I'm I try to follow my heart as much as I can. And I
follow my heart as much as I can. And I
follow my heart as much as I can. And I I keep getting uh mistaken. And uh how
I keep getting uh mistaken. And uh how
I keep getting uh mistaken. And uh how do you follow your heart, your soul, and
do you follow your heart, your soul, and
do you follow your heart, your soul, and your
your
your >> You're mixing up, but you're asking
>> You're mixing up, but you're asking
>> You're mixing up, but you're asking about six different questions.
about six different questions.
about six different questions. >> I'm only asking one. How do you follow
>> I'm only asking one. How do you follow
>> I'm only asking one. How do you follow your heart? H
your heart? H
your heart? H >> how do you uh get success in the world?
>> how do you uh get success in the world?
>> how do you uh get success in the world? That was one question.
That was one question.
That was one question. >> Okay. Sure.
>> Okay. Sure.
>> Okay. Sure. >> You articulated that. Are you aware that
>> You articulated that. Are you aware that
>> You articulated that. Are you aware that you said that
you said that
you said that >> that you're interested in success in the
>> that you're interested in success in the
>> that you're interested in success in the world?
world?
world? >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Were you paying attention to the lecture
>> Were you paying attention to the lecture
>> Were you paying attention to the lecture this morning?
this morning?
this morning? >> Yeah. You gave 101 answers. Why are you
>> Yeah. You gave 101 answers. Why are you
>> Yeah. You gave 101 answers. Why are you asking now? Were you sleeping during the
asking now? Were you sleeping during the
asking now? Were you sleeping during the lecture?
lecture?
lecture? >> I actually uh all a whole bunch of my
>> I actually uh all a whole bunch of my
>> I actually uh all a whole bunch of my past came up and I went through a whole
past came up and I went through a whole
past came up and I went through a whole bunch of my all my pain and I just felt
bunch of my all my pain and I just felt
bunch of my all my pain and I just felt all my pain and all my suffering and I
all my pain and all my suffering and I
all my pain and all my suffering and I kind of got to release it because I got
kind of got to release it because I got
kind of got to release it because I got to experience it.
to experience it.
to experience it. >> So, you weren't at the the lecture this
>> So, you weren't at the the lecture this
>> So, you weren't at the the lecture this morning. You were off into your own
morning. You were off into your own
morning. You were off into your own space.
space.
space. >> I was off in my own space.
>> I was off in my own space.
>> I was off in my own space. >> Oh, okay. Well, you can always get it on
>> Oh, okay. Well, you can always get it on
>> Oh, okay. Well, you can always get it on video and watch it later.
video and watch it later.
video and watch it later. >> When you listen to a lecture, listen to
>> When you listen to a lecture, listen to
>> When you listen to a lecture, listen to a lecture. When you go into inner
a lecture. When you go into inner
a lecture. When you go into inner meditation, you go into meditation.
meditation, you go into meditation.
meditation, you go into meditation. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> You're trying to mix the two up.
>> Okay. Well, thank you.
>> Okay. Well, thank you. >> You bet.
>> You bet.
>> You bet. >> Thank you so much.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Thank you so much. >> Information is one thing. Meditation is
>> Information is one thing. Meditation is
>> Information is one thing. Meditation is another. Yeah.
>> Oh, it's not tax.
>> Oh, it's not tax. Okay. Hold on, guys.
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. Hello, Susan.
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. Hello, Susan. >> I I need another band-aid.
>> I I need another band-aid.
>> I I need another band-aid. >> You need another band-aid? another
>> You need another band-aid? another
>> You need another band-aid? another band-aid.
band-aid.
band-aid. >> Yeah. Oh, go ahead.
>> Yeah. Oh, go ahead.
>> Yeah. Oh, go ahead. >> What's the question?
>> What's the question?
>> What's the question? >> Um the question is about um letting go
>> Um the question is about um letting go
>> Um the question is about um letting go of aversions and attractions
of aversions and attractions
of aversions and attractions and um other than setting the intention
and um other than setting the intention
and um other than setting the intention of the aversions and and letting go of
of the aversions and and letting go of
of the aversions and and letting go of them
them
them and praying about it. Are there any baby
and praying about it. Are there any baby
and praying about it. Are there any baby steps that we can take to basically tell
steps that we can take to basically tell
steps that we can take to basically tell the mind to shut up or bury it in a
the mind to shut up or bury it in a
the mind to shut up or bury it in a backyard?
Are there simple
Are there simple steps to quiet the ego mind of letting
steps to quiet the ego mind of letting
steps to quiet the ego mind of letting go of the aversions and the attractions?
>> She's asking a question. I don't know
>> She's asking a question. I don't know what it is. something about aversion and
what it is. something about aversion and
what it is. something about aversion and attraction.
attraction.
attraction. >> Okay, you'll have to start over. I'm
>> Okay, you'll have to start over. I'm
>> Okay, you'll have to start over. I'm sorry.
sorry.
sorry. >> What is the question about aversion and
>> What is the question about aversion and
>> What is the question about aversion and attraction?
attraction?
attraction? >> Do it in a couple sentences, not not
>> Do it in a couple sentences, not not
>> Do it in a couple sentences, not not three paragraphs.
three paragraphs.
three paragraphs. >> What is the your question is about
>> What is the your question is about
>> What is the your question is about aversion and attraction,
aversion and attraction,
aversion and attraction, >> right? The in the lectures he said, let
>> right? The in the lectures he said, let
>> right? The in the lectures he said, let go of the juice. I just want to learn
go of the juice. I just want to learn
go of the juice. I just want to learn how to let go of the attraction and the
how to let go of the attraction and the
how to let go of the attraction and the aversions, especially to disempowering
aversions, especially to disempowering
aversions, especially to disempowering emotions. Are there any simple steps
emotions. Are there any simple steps
emotions. Are there any simple steps other than setting the intention
other than setting the intention
other than setting the intention to do that or praying? Are there any
to do that or praying? Are there any
to do that or praying? Are there any other things we can do?
other things we can do?
other things we can do? >> What she's asking about is letting go of
>> What she's asking about is letting go of
>> What she's asking about is letting go of the emotion.
the emotion.
the emotion. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Of a situation or
>> Of a situation or
>> Of a situation or >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> And how do you go about doing that? You
>> And how do you go about doing that? You
>> And how do you go about doing that? You know, you talk about letting go.
know, you talk about letting go.
know, you talk about letting go. >> You're letting go. You let go wanting to
>> You're letting go. You let go wanting to
>> You're letting go. You let go wanting to change it.
change it.
change it. >> Ah, okay. So you let go of wanting to
>> Ah, okay. So you let go of wanting to
>> Ah, okay. So you let go of wanting to change
change
change >> or control it
>> or control it
>> or control it >> or control it.
>> or control it.
>> or control it. >> So let go of wanting to change it,
>> So let go of wanting to change it,
>> So let go of wanting to change it, wanting to control it.
wanting to control it.
wanting to control it. >> Right?
>> Right?
>> Right? >> So
>> So
>> So >> because that's just willfulness. So you
>> because that's just willfulness. So you
>> because that's just willfulness. So you surrender your will and you surrender it
surrender your will and you surrender it
surrender your will and you surrender it to God.
to God.
to God. Somebody says, "Well, my daughter
Somebody says, "Well, my daughter
Somebody says, "Well, my daughter shouldn't be sick in the hospital with
shouldn't be sick in the hospital with
shouldn't be sick in the hospital with so- and so." Who said so? Did God say
so- and so." Who said so? Did God say
so- and so." Who said so? Did God say that? No. God said she should be in the
that? No. God said she should be in the
that? No. God said she should be in the hospital sick. That's why she's there.
So who's the to thwart God's will?
So who's the to thwart God's will? >> So basically acceptance of what is.
>> So basically acceptance of what is.
>> So basically acceptance of what is. >> You have to accept it for what it is and
>> You have to accept it for what it is and
>> You have to accept it for what it is and make the best of it.
make the best of it.
make the best of it. >> Why would you want to change it?
>> Why would you want to change it?
>> Why would you want to change it? Why do you want to change it?
Why do you want to change it?
Why do you want to change it? >> Why do I want to change it? I don't like
>> Why do I want to change it? I don't like
>> Why do I want to change it? I don't like to be stuck in disempowering emotions.
to be stuck in disempowering emotions.
to be stuck in disempowering emotions. That's why
That's why
That's why >> she doesn't want to be stuck in what?
>> she doesn't want to be stuck in what?
>> she doesn't want to be stuck in what? >> In in in emotion in
>> In in in emotion in
>> In in in emotion in >> disempowering emotions. And
>> disempowering emotions. And
>> disempowering emotions. And >> she doesn't want to be stuck in
>> she doesn't want to be stuck in
>> she doesn't want to be stuck in disempowering emotions.
disempowering emotions.
disempowering emotions. >> Who said it was disempowering?
>> Who said it was disempowering?
>> Who said it was disempowering? >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Who said that an emotion is
>> Who said that an emotion is
>> Who said that an emotion is disempowering?
disempowering?
disempowering? >> Sadness appears disempowering. Shame
>> Sadness appears disempowering. Shame
>> Sadness appears disempowering. Shame appears disempowering.
appears disempowering.
appears disempowering. >> Yes. But anger also is motivating. It'll
>> Yes. But anger also is motivating. It'll
>> Yes. But anger also is motivating. It'll get you through something.
get you through something.
get you through something. >> Without anger, we wouldn't have won
>> Without anger, we wouldn't have won
>> Without anger, we wouldn't have won World War II.
World War II.
World War II. >> So there's good and bad of each serves
>> So there's good and bad of each serves
>> So there's good and bad of each serves another purpose, you see.
another purpose, you see.
another purpose, you see. >> Okay. Yeah. My my question was about
>> Okay. Yeah. My my question was about
>> Okay. Yeah. My my question was about attraction and aversion. And basically
attraction and aversion. And basically
attraction and aversion. And basically what I heard you say was let go of
what I heard you say was let go of
what I heard you say was let go of wanting it to be of ch of wanting to
wanting it to be of ch of wanting to
wanting it to be of ch of wanting to change it.
change it.
change it. >> Going to change it. Surrender it to
>> Going to change it. Surrender it to
>> Going to change it. Surrender it to God's will. It's not up to you. Why do
God's will. It's not up to you. Why do
God's will. It's not up to you. Why do you care if a million people drowned in
you care if a million people drowned in
you care if a million people drowned in a typhoon? Is it your problem? Is it
a typhoon? Is it your problem? Is it
a typhoon? Is it your problem? Is it your business? Tell God you shouldn't
your business? Tell God you shouldn't
your business? Tell God you shouldn't wipe those people out with the typhoon.
wipe those people out with the typhoon.
wipe those people out with the typhoon. Is it up to you?
Is it up to you?
Is it up to you? Are you a typhoon eater? I mean, are you
Are you a typhoon eater? I mean, are you
Are you a typhoon eater? I mean, are you a typhoon maker?
a typhoon maker?
a typhoon maker? >> So,
>> So,
>> So, >> yeah. What do you want to change in the
>> yeah. What do you want to change in the
>> yeah. What do you want to change in the world is what I want to know.
world is what I want to know.
world is what I want to know. >> Just my response to life.
>> Just my response to life.
>> Just my response to life. >> What?
>> What?
>> What? >> Her response to life is what she
>> Her response to life is what she
>> Her response to life is what she >> She wants to change your response to
>> She wants to change your response to
>> She wants to change your response to life. Well, then just do so.
life. Well, then just do so.
life. Well, then just do so. >> Simple enough.
>> Simple enough.
>> Simple enough. >> If you wanted to do it, you do it.
>> If you wanted to do it, you do it.
>> If you wanted to do it, you do it. The reason you haven't done it is you
The reason you haven't done it is you
The reason you haven't done it is you don't want to do that. You want to
don't want to do that. You want to
don't want to do that. You want to change things out there.
change things out there.
change things out there. >> Surrender everything to God as it as it
>> Surrender everything to God as it as it
>> Surrender everything to God as it as it occurs.
occurs.
occurs. practice on things that are less
practice on things that are less
practice on things that are less emotionally significant. Do you want to
emotionally significant. Do you want to
emotionally significant. Do you want to change the lights in this room?
change the lights in this room?
change the lights in this room? >> Yes or no?
>> Yes or no?
>> Yes or no? >> No.
>> No.
>> No. >> No. You want to change her the way she
>> No. You want to change her the way she
>> No. You want to change her the way she is?
is?
is? >> No.
>> No.
>> No. >> You want to change me the way I am?
>> You want to change me the way I am?
>> You want to change me the way I am? >> Absolutely not.
>> Absolutely not.
>> Absolutely not. >> You want to change my soda?
>> You want to change my soda?
>> You want to change my soda? >> No, sir.
>> No, sir.
>> No, sir. >> Just keep it going.
>> Thank you for being
>> Thank you for being >> That was good.
>> That was good.
>> That was good. that head home. That was good.
that head home. That was good.
that head home. That was good. >> All right.
>> Hello. I'm grateful to be here. Thank
>> Hello. I'm grateful to be here. Thank you so much for sharing. I wanted to ask
you so much for sharing. I wanted to ask
you so much for sharing. I wanted to ask for blessings for my family and my
for blessings for my family and my
for blessings for my family and my friends.
friends.
friends. >> God bless you and your family and your
>> God bless you and your family and your
>> God bless you and your family and your friends. Amen.
friends. Amen.
friends. Amen. >> Thank you.
Oh,
Oh, okay. I'm try and keep track.
okay. I'm try and keep track.
okay. I'm try and keep track. >> Hello. Thank you. I have just one
>> Hello. Thank you. I have just one
>> Hello. Thank you. I have just one obstacle I want to overcome. Uh I love
obstacle I want to overcome. Uh I love
obstacle I want to overcome. Uh I love my wife. She's a US citizen. I'm a
my wife. She's a US citizen. I'm a
my wife. She's a US citizen. I'm a Canadian citizen. Immigration won't let
Canadian citizen. Immigration won't let
Canadian citizen. Immigration won't let us be together. And I'm wondering um how
us be together. And I'm wondering um how
us be together. And I'm wondering um how I can overcome that obstacle
I can overcome that obstacle
I can overcome that obstacle because I don't want to lose my family.
Are you American or Canadian?
Are you American or Canadian? >> I'm Canadian.
>> I'm Canadian.
>> I'm Canadian. >> Why did Why did you marry an American?
>> Why did Why did you marry an American?
>> Why did Why did you marry an American? >> Cuz I love her. I don't know why, but I
>> Cuz I love her. I don't know why, but I
>> Cuz I love her. I don't know why, but I love her.
love her.
love her. >> And now what do you want the world to do
>> And now what do you want the world to do
>> And now what do you want the world to do about this?
about this?
about this? >> I just want to be together and live.
>> I just want to be together and live.
>> I just want to be together and live. >> Well, both of you moved to Europe.
>> Well, both of you moved to Europe.
>> Well, both of you moved to Europe. >> Okay. Okay.
>> Okay. Okay.
>> Okay. Okay. >> I moved to Paris myself or London.
>> I moved to Paris myself or London.
>> I moved to Paris myself or London. >> Okay. She has a son that she can't move.
>> Okay. She has a son that she can't move.
>> Okay. She has a son that she can't move. But
But
But >> Huh? She has a step I have a stepson.
>> Huh? She has a step I have a stepson.
>> Huh? She has a step I have a stepson. >> She has a son that she can't move.
>> She has a son that she can't move.
>> She has a son that she can't move. >> She has what?
>> She has what?
>> She has what? >> She has a son. There's children involved
>> She has a son. There's children involved
>> She has a son. There's children involved in
in
in >> Oh, you're in a pickle.
>> Oh, you're in a pickle.
>> Oh, you're in a pickle. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Yes, I see.
>> Well,
>> Well, that's one of those things uh that
that's one of those things uh that
that's one of those things uh that you'll feel sad about later on. It was a
you'll feel sad about later on. It was a
you'll feel sad about later on. It was a mistake. Yeah.
mistake. Yeah.
mistake. Yeah. >> No, no. I love her. I love her.
>> No, no. I love her. I love her.
>> No, no. I love her. I love her. >> Oh, so what is this question? How do I
>> Oh, so what is this question? How do I
>> Oh, so what is this question? How do I beat these immigration turkeys trying to
beat these immigration turkeys trying to
beat these immigration turkeys trying to break up my family? How do I overcome
break up my family? How do I overcome
break up my family? How do I overcome these guys?
these guys?
these guys? >> Why do you want to overcome them? It's
>> Why do you want to overcome them? It's
>> Why do you want to overcome them? It's the law of the land. You disrespect.
the law of the land. You disrespect.
the law of the land. You disrespect. >> I didn't break the law. I didn't break
>> I didn't break the law. I didn't break
>> I didn't break the law. I didn't break the law.
the law.
the law. >> Well, then what are you complaining
>> Well, then what are you complaining
>> Well, then what are you complaining about? I don't get it.
about? I don't get it.
about? I don't get it. >> But they won't let us be together.
>> But they won't let us be together.
>> But they won't let us be together. Saying I have to go back and I didn't
Saying I have to go back and I didn't
Saying I have to go back and I didn't break the law. I'm a good person. I
break the law. I'm a good person. I
break the law. I'm a good person. I think I earned to be with my family.
think I earned to be with my family.
think I earned to be with my family. I should uh In other words, if I want to
I should uh In other words, if I want to
I should uh In other words, if I want to go 55, they should change the the law of
go 55, they should change the the law of
go 55, they should change the the law of the speed limit on the highway.
the speed limit on the highway.
the speed limit on the highway. >> No, sir. But I love her. I don't think
>> No, sir. But I love her. I don't think
>> No, sir. But I love her. I don't think that's wrong. I I a good person. I never
that's wrong. I I a good person. I never
that's wrong. I I a good person. I never broke the law.
broke the law.
broke the law. >> They'll go keep on loving. There's
>> They'll go keep on loving. There's
>> They'll go keep on loving. There's nothing wrong with it.
nothing wrong with it.
nothing wrong with it. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Yeah. There's nothing wrong with loving
>> Yeah. There's nothing wrong with loving
>> Yeah. There's nothing wrong with loving her.
her.
her. >> Of course.
>> Of course.
>> Of course. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So, what is the question?
So, what is the question?
So, what is the question? >> All right. I don't care what the
>> All right. I don't care what the
>> All right. I don't care what the question is.
question is.
question is. >> I need some ideas like how to how to
>> I need some ideas like how to how to
>> I need some ideas like how to how to beat these guys so we can be together,
beat these guys so we can be together,
beat these guys so we can be together, be happy together in America. I love
be happy together in America. I love
be happy together in America. I love this country. I love her.
this country. I love her.
this country. I love her. >> What can I do? Uh
>> What can I do? Uh
>> What can I do? Uh >> nothing probably
>> nothing probably
>> nothing probably >> become American citizen if you're
>> become American citizen if you're
>> become American citizen if you're married and everything. Why?
married and everything. Why?
married and everything. Why? >> See, they're saying no. They're saying
>> See, they're saying no. They're saying
>> See, they're saying no. They're saying >> they they've looked at all the legal uh
>> they they've looked at all the legal uh
>> they they've looked at all the legal uh alternatives.
alternatives.
alternatives. >> They approved it, but they they won't
>> They approved it, but they they won't
>> They approved it, but they they won't let me stay.
let me stay.
let me stay. >> So then you'll end up being frustrated.
>> So then you'll end up being frustrated.
>> So then you'll end up being frustrated. >> So So how long do you have to leave for?
>> So So how long do you have to leave for?
>> So So how long do you have to leave for? >> He wants to be
>> He wants to be
>> He wants to be >> I don't know exactly. They won't tell
>> I don't know exactly. They won't tell
>> I don't know exactly. They won't tell us.
>> So what is the question? I don't get
>> So what is the question? I don't get what
what
what >> Well, we don't have the answers because
>> Well, we don't have the answers because
>> Well, we don't have the answers because we're not immigration.
we're not immigration.
we're not immigration. >> But anyways, I thank you uh for your
>> But anyways, I thank you uh for your
>> But anyways, I thank you uh for your >> He wants to know how to overcome.
>> He wants to know how to overcome.
>> He wants to know how to overcome. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Federal law in Canada and America.
Federal law in Canada and America.
Federal law in Canada and America. >> Yes.
>> No, I just
>> No, I just >> You need a psychiatrist to know you. No,
>> You need a psychiatrist to know you. No,
>> You need a psychiatrist to know you. No, >> no, there's uh there's no answer to this
>> no, there's uh there's no answer to this
>> no, there's uh there's no answer to this because you know it involves government.
because you know it involves government.
because you know it involves government. >> Oh, there is a way. It hasn't dawned on
>> Oh, there is a way. It hasn't dawned on
>> Oh, there is a way. It hasn't dawned on them. You have to move the new move new
them. You have to move the new move new
them. You have to move the new move new to a third neutral country.
to a third neutral country.
to a third neutral country. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> And don't give me excuses. She's got a
>> And don't give me excuses. She's got a
>> And don't give me excuses. She's got a daughter. That's got nothing to do with
daughter. That's got nothing to do with
daughter. That's got nothing to do with it.
it.
it. >> All right. You got
>> All right. You got
>> All right. You got >> I don't care. She's got a daughter. You
>> I don't care. She's got a daughter. You
>> I don't care. She's got a daughter. You want to be with this lady, then you got
want to be with this lady, then you got
want to be with this lady, then you got to move to Paris,
to move to Paris,
to move to Paris, >> London.
>> London.
>> London. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Argentina. Bonazeras.
>> Argentina. Bonazeras.
>> Argentina. Bonazeras. >> Yeah. We'll both go.
>> Yeah. We'll both go.
>> Yeah. We'll both go. >> Okay. That's the only way to do it.
>> Okay. That's the only way to do it.
>> Okay. That's the only way to do it. >> Thank you very much. Appreciate it.
>> Thank you very much. Appreciate it.
>> Thank you very much. Appreciate it. >> Move to a neutral third country.
>> Move to a neutral third country.
>> Move to a neutral third country. >> Thank you. Thank you.
>> That's the only answer, you know.
>> That's the only answer, you know. >> Yeah.
It's all that people want to have it
It's all that people want to have it both ways, you know.
both ways, you know.
both ways, you know. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> It's difficult.
>> It's difficult.
>> It's difficult. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Thank you both. I'm so very very pleased
>> Thank you both. I'm so very very pleased
>> Thank you both. I'm so very very pleased to be here and I thank you Dr. Hawkins
to be here and I thank you Dr. Hawkins
to be here and I thank you Dr. Hawkins very much. Um I my question is about
very much. Um I my question is about
very much. Um I my question is about self-doubt
self-doubt
self-doubt and
and
and >> questions what
>> questions what
>> questions what >> selfdoubt
>> selfdoubt
>> selfdoubt >> self-doubt yes
>> self-doubt yes
>> self-doubt yes >> and still having um trouble um with per
>> and still having um trouble um with per
>> and still having um trouble um with per you know perception be being
you know perception be being
you know perception be being understanding when uh you believe you
understanding when uh you believe you
understanding when uh you believe you you are perceiving something intuitively
you are perceiving something intuitively
you are perceiving something intuitively and then you start to doubt that and and
and then you start to doubt that and and
and then you start to doubt that and and I'm just having difficulty with that.
I'm just having difficulty with that.
I'm just having difficulty with that. And what advice
And what advice
And what advice >> um she intuit in other words she's
>> um she intuit in other words she's
>> um she intuit in other words she's >> sometime
>> sometime
>> sometime >> well it's a difficult question I'm
>> well it's a difficult question I'm
>> well it's a difficult question I'm trying to put it into words.
trying to put it into words.
trying to put it into words. >> Yeah
>> Yeah
>> Yeah >> she feels that she perceives things or
>> she feels that she perceives things or
>> she feels that she perceives things or or she thinks that this it's one way and
or she thinks that this it's one way and
or she thinks that this it's one way and then when it actually happens it's
then when it actually happens it's
then when it actually happens it's another way.
another way.
another way. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> And so she feels doubt.
>> And so she feels doubt.
>> And so she feels doubt. >> Yes. in
>> Yes. in
>> Yes. in >> reality testing is not very uh
>> reality testing is not very uh
>> reality testing is not very uh dependable.
dependable.
dependable. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> So, it's the way you're reading
>> So, it's the way you're reading
>> So, it's the way you're reading situations. Are you reading them
situations. Are you reading them
situations. Are you reading them emotionally or how are you reading a
emotionally or how are you reading a
emotionally or how are you reading a situation? How can you be so wrong all
situation? How can you be so wrong all
situation? How can you be so wrong all the time?
the time?
the time? >> No, I'm not saying I I am wrong. I'm
>> No, I'm not saying I I am wrong. I'm
>> No, I'm not saying I I am wrong. I'm just saying I feel I doubt it. I doubt
just saying I feel I doubt it. I doubt
just saying I feel I doubt it. I doubt what comes up uh initially.
what comes up uh initially.
what comes up uh initially. >> A doubt comes up about what
>> A doubt comes up about what
>> A doubt comes up about what >> she she doubts um initially. Initially.
>> she she doubts um initially. Initially.
>> she she doubts um initially. Initially. No, I don't doubt initially. I feel like
No, I don't doubt initially. I feel like
No, I don't doubt initially. I feel like I have I feel like I understand
I have I feel like I understand
I have I feel like I understand something and and have intuited
something and and have intuited
something and and have intuited something accurately,
something accurately,
something accurately, but then self-doubt comes.
but then self-doubt comes.
but then self-doubt comes. >> Then don't intuitit it.
>> Then don't intuitit it.
>> Then don't intuitit it. >> I don't understand. It it sounds to me
>> I don't understand. It it sounds to me
>> I don't understand. It it sounds to me like all right some uh people that
like all right some uh people that
like all right some uh people that intuitit things they are able for a
intuitit things they are able for a
intuitit things they are able for a while to do that and do it with very
while to do that and do it with very
while to do that and do it with very accuracy and then all of a sudden they
accuracy and then all of a sudden they
accuracy and then all of a sudden they go through a period where they can't
go through a period where they can't
go through a period where they can't they can't inter.
Well, intuition and the average person
Well, intuition and the average person is correct some of the time, but not all
is correct some of the time, but not all
is correct some of the time, but not all the time.
the time.
the time. >> Right. But then you you and I have both
>> Right. But then you you and I have both
>> Right. But then you you and I have both talked about this. There's certain times
talked about this. There's certain times
talked about this. There's certain times in where you can intuit it everything
in where you can intuit it everything
in where you can intuit it everything and everything is is perfect.
and everything is is perfect.
and everything is is perfect. >> It's perfect. But then there's times in
>> It's perfect. But then there's times in
>> It's perfect. But then there's times in your life when you can't intuitit
your life when you can't intuitit
your life when you can't intuitit anything and it's just off,
anything and it's just off,
anything and it's just off, >> right? Well, psychics are the same way,
>> right? Well, psychics are the same way,
>> right? Well, psychics are the same way, >> right?
>> right?
>> right? >> They'll have periods when they're
>> They'll have periods when they're
>> They'll have periods when they're extremely psychic and extremely
extremely psychic and extremely
extremely psychic and extremely accurate. And then there's other times
accurate. And then there's other times
accurate. And then there's other times when they just uh have lost their muse,
when they just uh have lost their muse,
when they just uh have lost their muse, you might say.
you might say.
you might say. >> So, you know, it may come back, it may
>> So, you know, it may come back, it may
>> So, you know, it may come back, it may not come back, but don't rely on that at
not come back, but don't rely on that at
not come back, but don't rely on that at this time because
this time because
this time because >> it's something you should check out your
>> it's something you should check out your
>> it's something you should check out your intuition. Check it out, but you can't
intuition. Check it out, but you can't
intuition. Check it out, but you can't uh necessarily depend on its accuracy
uh necessarily depend on its accuracy
uh necessarily depend on its accuracy all the time.
all the time.
all the time. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Many, you know, intuition saved my life
>> Many, you know, intuition saved my life
>> Many, you know, intuition saved my life a number of times, you know.
So it can be it can save your life
So it can be it can save your life many times and I came close to that and
many times and I came close to that and
many times and I came close to that and my intuition told me
my intuition told me
my intuition told me and I just missed it like that.
>> So I I respect intuition but you can't
>> So I I respect intuition but you can't depend on it for everyday life about
depend on it for everyday life about
depend on it for everyday life about average matters day in and day out.
>> Thank you. Thank you. Remember the time
>> Thank you. Thank you. Remember the time I a guy was going to mug me and I jumped
I a guy was going to mug me and I jumped
I a guy was going to mug me and I jumped up in the air.
up in the air.
up in the air. >> Yeah, it's on New York City.
>> Yeah, it's on New York City.
>> Yeah, it's on New York City. >> I heard these footsteps coming down. I
>> I heard these footsteps coming down. I
>> I heard these footsteps coming down. I was in the west side of New York City in
was in the west side of New York City in
was in the west side of New York City in late at night. The footsteps got louder
late at night. The footsteps got louder
late at night. The footsteps got louder and louder and I know this guy is about
and louder and I know this guy is about
and louder and I know this guy is about to mug me. So,
to mug me. So,
to mug me. So, >> sorry this is
>> sorry this is
>> sorry this is >> Yeah, I'm sorry. So, at the last minute,
>> Yeah, I'm sorry. So, at the last minute,
>> Yeah, I'm sorry. So, at the last minute, my intuition said, "Do it." I suddenly
my intuition said, "Do it." I suddenly
my intuition said, "Do it." I suddenly spun around 180 degrees and I jumped in
spun around 180 degrees and I jumped in
spun around 180 degrees and I jumped in the air and I screamed at him. A and the
the air and I screamed at him. A and the
the air and I screamed at him. A and the guy just went.
guy just went.
guy just went. So I hit him on the shoulder. I said,
So I hit him on the shoulder. I said,
So I hit him on the shoulder. I said, "Better luck next time."
>> um
>> um >> I was the wrong guy to try to mug right
>> I was the wrong guy to try to mug right
>> I was the wrong guy to try to mug right at that moment. So you know, intuition
at that moment. So you know, intuition
at that moment. So you know, intuition is very good in warning about muggers.
is very good in warning about muggers.
is very good in warning about muggers. >> That's for him. Oh,
>> That's for him. Oh,
>> That's for him. Oh, >> okay. This is for you.
>> okay. This is for you.
>> okay. This is for you. >> Intuition is very
>> Intuition is very
>> Intuition is very I'm speaking. Intuition is very good to
I'm speaking. Intuition is very good to
I'm speaking. Intuition is very good to warn you about muggers. I find intuition
warn you about muggers. I find intuition
warn you about muggers. I find intuition is very good. If you're walking down the
is very good. If you're walking down the
is very good. If you're walking down the street and something warns you there's a
street and something warns you there's a
street and something warns you there's a mugger up ahead, it's very likely. So
mugger up ahead, it's very likely. So
mugger up ahead, it's very likely. So why? Because they give out a certain
why? Because they give out a certain
why? Because they give out a certain energy and if you've lived in big cities
energy and if you've lived in big cities
energy and if you've lived in big cities long enough, you can spot a mugger, you
long enough, you can spot a mugger, you
long enough, you can spot a mugger, you know, half a block away. And if you walk
know, half a block away. And if you walk
know, half a block away. And if you walk past the storefront, you see somebody
past the storefront, you see somebody
past the storefront, you see somebody lurking in in the storefront and your
lurking in in the storefront and your
lurking in in the storefront and your the hair on the back of your head goes
the hair on the back of your head goes
the hair on the back of your head goes up. That is a mugger.
always truck trust your hair going up in
always truck trust your hair going up in the back of your head
the back of your head
the back of your head mugger.
mugger.
mugger. >> Hi.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. >> Hi.
>> Hi. >> Just wanted to thank you for everything
>> Just wanted to thank you for everything
>> Just wanted to thank you for everything you do and I brought you a gift that I
you do and I brought you a gift that I
you do and I brought you a gift that I thought you would enjoy reading that
thought you would enjoy reading that
thought you would enjoy reading that helped me through many tough times.
helped me through many tough times.
helped me through many tough times. >> Oh, thank you so much. Really
>> Oh, thank you so much. Really
>> Oh, thank you so much. Really appreciate.
appreciate.
appreciate. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Here, you want to hand that to me? I'll
>> Here, you want to hand that to me? I'll
>> Here, you want to hand that to me? I'll put it over here.
put it over here.
put it over here. That's a thin book. Thank God.
That's a thin book. Thank God.
That's a thin book. Thank God. When they give you a book this thick,
When they give you a book this thick,
When they give you a book this thick, there goes your life for a year.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much. >> Yes.
What?
What? >> Hello.
>> Hello.
>> Hello. Oh, I didn't see him standing there.
Oh, I didn't see him standing there.
Oh, I didn't see him standing there. A human being with a camera.
A human being with a camera.
A human being with a camera. I've seen them before around someplace.
I've seen them before around someplace.
I've seen them before around someplace. Human beings with cameras. H.
Human beings with cameras. H.
Human beings with cameras. H. Planet Earth must be where I saw them.
Planet Earth must be where I saw them.
Planet Earth must be where I saw them. Yes. Go ahead. I'm just making fun.
Yes. Go ahead. I'm just making fun.
Yes. Go ahead. I'm just making fun. >> I
>> I
>> I suppose preet lady.
suppose preet lady.
suppose preet lady. Is our death
Is our death
Is our death preset already?
preset already?
preset already? >> Is our death preset already?
>> Is our death preset already?
>> Is our death preset already? >> The answer I get yes.
>> The answer I get yes.
>> The answer I get yes. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Okay, let's ask it one more time. We
>> Okay, let's ask it one more time. We
>> Okay, let's ask it one more time. We have permission to ask this question
have permission to ask this question
have permission to ask this question now.
now.
now. >> We have permission to ask this question
>> We have permission to ask this question
>> We have permission to ask this question now.
now.
now. >> You the time of your leaving this planet
>> You the time of your leaving this planet
>> You the time of your leaving this planet is preset for the moment of your birth.
is preset for the moment of your birth.
is preset for the moment of your birth. Resist. We've gotten the same answer for
Resist. We've gotten the same answer for
Resist. We've gotten the same answer for years and years and years. So now that's
years and years and years. So now that's
years and years and years. So now that's answered. And if it's answered, stop
answered. And if it's answered, stop
answered. And if it's answered, stop asking the question all the time.
Why are you worried about it? You're
Why are you worried about it? You're going to apply for an extension.
>> Dear God, I want to die 10 days later
>> Dear God, I want to die 10 days later than what you decided.
than what you decided.
than what you decided. >> I My future husband I wonder
>> I My future husband I wonder
>> I My future husband I wonder >> your what? Oh, my my picture husband.
>> your what? Oh, my my picture husband.
>> your what? Oh, my my picture husband. I wonder
I wonder
I wonder >> future husband.
>> future husband.
>> future husband. >> Oh, her what? Future husband.
>> Oh, her what? Future husband.
>> Oh, her what? Future husband. >> Oh. Uh, she wonders if she'll have a
>> Oh. Uh, she wonders if she'll have a
>> Oh. Uh, she wonders if she'll have a future husband.
future husband.
future husband. >> She wants to know if she'll have a
>> She wants to know if she'll have a
>> She wants to know if she'll have a future husband.
future husband.
future husband. >> Yeah, you we're supposed to do that.
>> Yeah, you we're supposed to do that.
>> Yeah, you we're supposed to do that. >> I could not tell you that.
>> I could not tell you that.
>> I could not tell you that. >> No, there's no way of knowing that.
>> No, there's no way of knowing that.
>> No, there's no way of knowing that. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> There's no way of knowing it. Right?
>> There's no way of knowing it. Right?
>> There's no way of knowing it. Right? >> With consciousness technique, you can
>> With consciousness technique, you can
>> With consciousness technique, you can calibrate anything that is has been
calibrate anything that is has been
calibrate anything that is has been anything that's possible, but you cannot
anything that's possible, but you cannot
anything that's possible, but you cannot calibrate the future because the future
calibrate the future because the future
calibrate the future because the future has no reality. If there's no reality,
has no reality. If there's no reality,
has no reality. If there's no reality, you're asking what is the reality and
you're asking what is the reality and
you're asking what is the reality and the non-reality. So, it's a nonsensical
the non-reality. So, it's a nonsensical
the non-reality. So, it's a nonsensical question and cannot be answered.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> It has no reality.
>> It has no reality.
>> It has no reality. It's It's it's the same as the
It's It's it's the same as the
It's It's it's the same as the hypothetical question. There is no
hypothetical question. There is no
hypothetical question. There is no answer to a hypothetical question
answer to a hypothetical question
answer to a hypothetical question because a hypothetical question has no
because a hypothetical question has no
because a hypothetical question has no reality.
reality.
reality. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> What if an elephant had fur? Would it be
>> What if an elephant had fur? Would it be
>> What if an elephant had fur? Would it be hot in the summer? You know, it's a
hot in the summer? You know, it's a
hot in the summer? You know, it's a stupid question.
>> I would like to sign this is from a
>> I would like to sign this is from a friend.
friend.
friend. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> And he wants you to sign this for a
>> And he wants you to sign this for a
>> And he wants you to sign this for a friend.
friend.
friend. >> Yeah. Right. And this is uh what I want
>> Yeah. Right. And this is uh what I want
>> Yeah. Right. And this is uh what I want to have signed by you. This is from
to have signed by you. This is from
to have signed by you. This is from Heagel and I was very impressed of your
Heagel and I was very impressed of your
Heagel and I was very impressed of your forward for the German speaking public.
forward for the German speaking public.
forward for the German speaking public. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> And I'm very grateful for you. Yes.
>> And I'm very grateful for you. Yes.
>> And I'm very grateful for you. Yes. Right.
Right.
Right. And I was a former Marxist and communist
And I was a former Marxist and communist
And I was a former Marxist and communist and Stalinist and Mauist and everything.
and Stalinist and Mauist and everything.
and Stalinist and Mauist and everything. What can you imagine? And
What can you imagine? And
What can you imagine? And >> what is the question?
>> what is the question?
>> what is the question? >> Oh my question. All right. What is he?
>> Oh my question. All right. What is he?
>> Oh my question. All right. What is he? He's a former what?
He's a former what?
He's a former what? >> Marxist.
>> Marxist.
>> Marxist. >> He's a former Marxist. Yes.
>> He's a former Marxist. Yes.
>> He's a former Marxist. Yes. >> Yeah. And and he says so he says, "Can
>> Yeah. And and he says so he says, "Can
>> Yeah. And and he says so he says, "Can you imagine?" Because he's ch All that's
you imagine?" Because he's ch All that's
you imagine?" Because he's ch All that's changed
changed
changed >> because what?
>> because what?
>> because what? >> He all that has changed.
>> He all that has changed.
>> He all that has changed. >> What's changed?
>> What's changed?
>> What's changed? >> He's no longer a Marxist.
>> He's no longer a Marxist.
>> He's no longer a Marxist. >> Oh, good. God bless you. Yes. Very good.
>> Oh, good. God bless you. Yes. Very good.
>> Oh, good. God bless you. Yes. Very good. >> Mark's car caliber is at 130.
>> Mark's car caliber is at 130.
>> Mark's car caliber is at 130. >> So following Markx doesn't put you in
>> So following Markx doesn't put you in
>> So following Markx doesn't put you in too high a place of consciousness.
130 is less than that of a dog. You
130 is less than that of a dog. You understand? Dog dog family dog
understand? Dog dog family dog
understand? Dog dog family dog calibrates at 250.
calibrates at 250.
calibrates at 250. >> Carol Marks calibrates at 130.
>> Carol Marks calibrates at 130.
>> Carol Marks calibrates at 130. Better to believe and worship your
Better to believe and worship your
Better to believe and worship your family dog.
>> Yeah. Go ahead.
>> Yeah. Go ahead. So
saying that how can one overcome his
saying that how can one overcome his spiritual hide and seek somehow I I had
spiritual hide and seek somehow I I had
spiritual hide and seek somehow I I had a I had a vision of you that you were
a I had a vision of you that you were
a I had a vision of you that you were looking at me with a with a very burning
looking at me with a with a very burning
looking at me with a with a very burning and very intense look. So and I thought
and very intense look. So and I thought
and very intense look. So and I thought this was a time where I had to get real
this was a time where I had to get real
this was a time where I had to get real somehow and I would just ask if you
somehow and I would just ask if you
somehow and I would just ask if you confirm this is this is right. So my
confirm this is this is right. So my
confirm this is this is right. So my idea
idea
idea >> he he had a vision of you looking at
>> he he had a vision of you looking at
>> he he had a vision of you looking at him.
him.
him. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Very intensely telling him it's time to
>> Very intensely telling him it's time to
>> Very intensely telling him it's time to get real.
get real.
get real. >> Get real. Okay.
>> Get real. Okay.
>> Get real. Okay. >> And so he wants to wants us to confirm
>> And so he wants to wants us to confirm
>> And so he wants to wants us to confirm that that was an actuality that you did
that that was an actuality that you did
that that was an actuality that you did come to him and in some dream or
come to him and in some dream or
come to him and in some dream or >> vision and that was an actuality.
>> vision and that was an actuality.
>> vision and that was an actuality. >> I don't know.
>> I don't recall because it's not in a
>> I don't recall because it's not in a linear recallable dimension.
linear recallable dimension.
linear recallable dimension. But it's a good thing that you did get
But it's a good thing that you did get
But it's a good thing that you did get real,
real,
real, >> right? Yeah. So, I was a little bit
>> right? Yeah. So, I was a little bit
>> right? Yeah. So, I was a little bit scared at first, but then I thought
scared at first, but then I thought
scared at first, but then I thought maybe maybe that's
maybe maybe that's
maybe maybe that's >> coming to get you
>> But she has her arm. Maybe she can do
>> But she has her arm. Maybe she can do that to that.
that to that.
that to that. >> Anyway, the the reality of that field of
>> Anyway, the the reality of that field of
>> Anyway, the the reality of that field of consciousness is what you got into.
consciousness is what you got into.
consciousness is what you got into. That's all. Yeah.
That's all. Yeah.
That's all. Yeah. >> Yeah. It's a very good thing that you
>> Yeah. It's a very good thing that you
>> Yeah. It's a very good thing that you gave up
gave up
gave up uh hanging out with wickedness. Yes.
uh hanging out with wickedness. Yes.
uh hanging out with wickedness. Yes. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> And maybe that's what the vision was to
>> And maybe that's what the vision was to
>> And maybe that's what the vision was to do is to make you do that to push you to
do is to make you do that to push you to
do is to make you do that to push you to that point that you would do that.
that point that you would do that.
that point that you would do that. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Yeah.
>> Right. So
>> Right. So >> and and today is the 20th year of the
>> and and today is the 20th year of the
>> and and today is the 20th year of the fall of the Berlin wall. So we have a
fall of the Berlin wall. So we have a
fall of the Berlin wall. So we have a peace today.
peace today.
peace today. from the day of Germany.
from the day of Germany.
from the day of Germany. >> Yeah. Very good. Yes.
>> Yeah. Very good. Yes.
>> Yeah. Very good. Yes. >> That's right. October 5th.
>> That's right. October 5th.
>> That's right. October 5th. >> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Reoot.
Reoot.
Reoot. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Thank you so much.
>> Yeah. He speaks a little German.
>> Yeah. He speaks a little German. >> I'm Bishkin.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Thank you. Don't
>> Thank you. Don't
>> Thank you. Don't >> sweeetheart.
>> It's okay.
>> It's okay. >> I just want to look into your eyes for a
>> I just want to look into your eyes for a
>> I just want to look into your eyes for a moment.
moment.
moment. >> What?
>> What?
>> What? >> She just wanted to look into your eyes
>> She just wanted to look into your eyes
>> She just wanted to look into your eyes for a minute. Oh, God bless you.
Yes.
Yes. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> Thank you.
>> Oh, I don't have my glasses. Here we go.
>> Oh, I don't have my glasses. Here we go. >> Go ahead.
>> Go ahead.
>> Go ahead. >> Uh, I can't come here, Gabe. I can't
>> Uh, I can't come here, Gabe. I can't
>> Uh, I can't come here, Gabe. I can't read this. I don't have my glasses.
read this. I don't have my glasses.
read this. I don't have my glasses. >> Why do you have to read it?
>> Why do you have to read it?
>> Why do you have to read it? >> I don't have any question. Just wanted
>> I don't have any question. Just wanted
>> I don't have any question. Just wanted to see his eyes for a moment.
to see his eyes for a moment.
to see his eyes for a moment. >> Okay. It says, "I don't have any
>> Okay. It says, "I don't have any
>> Okay. It says, "I don't have any questions. I just want to see his eyes
questions. I just want to see his eyes
questions. I just want to see his eyes for a minute." Moment.
for a minute." Moment.
for a minute." Moment. >> Oh, yes. Okay.
>> Oh, yes. Okay.
>> Oh, yes. Okay. >> God bless you, love. God bless you.
>> God bless you, love. God bless you.
>> God bless you, love. God bless you. You're blessed by your own reverence for
You're blessed by your own reverence for
You're blessed by your own reverence for God.
>> Beautiful job, huh?
>> Beautiful job, huh? >> He's perfect.
>> He's perfect.
>> He's perfect. perfect beauty she is.
>> All right.
>> All right. >> Um I'm a medical doctor. I came from
>> Um I'm a medical doctor. I came from
>> Um I'm a medical doctor. I came from Korea. I have a stomach problem. I have
Korea. I have a stomach problem. I have
Korea. I have a stomach problem. I have not been able to treat effectively.
not been able to treat effectively.
not been able to treat effectively. Is it partly karma? And if yes, what is
Is it partly karma? And if yes, what is
Is it partly karma? And if yes, what is the lesson?
the lesson?
the lesson? >> Oh my god.
>> Oh my god.
>> Oh my god. >> That I should do or what should I do?
>> That's a whole diagnostic hour.
>> That's a whole diagnostic hour. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Uh you might say by definition all
>> Uh you might say by definition all
>> Uh you might say by definition all things are karmic because all things are
things are karmic because all things are
things are karmic because all things are controlled by the reality of divinity
controlled by the reality of divinity
controlled by the reality of divinity and its expression and therefore all
and its expression and therefore all
and its expression and therefore all things you might say are karmic. The
things you might say are karmic. The
things you might say are karmic. The karma of being a human for one thing.
karma of being a human for one thing.
karma of being a human for one thing. Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. So
So
So what is the nature of the stomach
what is the nature of the stomach
what is the nature of the stomach problem?
problem?
problem? What is the nature of the stomach
What is the nature of the stomach
What is the nature of the stomach problem?
problem?
problem? >> Um uh what is the nature of the stomach
>> Um uh what is the nature of the stomach
>> Um uh what is the nature of the stomach problem?
problem?
problem? >> Is it what's the nature of the stomach
>> Is it what's the nature of the stomach
>> Is it what's the nature of the stomach problem?
problem?
problem? >> I I don't know. Um, is there someone
>> I I don't know. Um, is there someone
>> I I don't know. Um, is there someone could
could
could um he's asking
um he's asking
um he's asking uh for specifics on the stomach problem
uh for specifics on the stomach problem
uh for specifics on the stomach problem that he has.
that he has.
that he has. Here we go. We got a translator.
He's ulcer.
He's ulcer. >> He what?
>> He what?
>> He what? >> He has a stronger
>> He has a stronger
>> He has a stronger >> Oh, he has an ulcer.
>> Oh, he has an ulcer.
>> Oh, he has an ulcer. >> He has an ulcer. Yes. What about it?
>> He has an ulcer. Yes. What about it?
>> He has an ulcer. Yes. What about it? >> 10 years. Maybe.
>> 10 years. Maybe.
>> 10 years. Maybe. >> For 10 years, maybe he's had an ulcer.
>> For 10 years, maybe he's had an ulcer.
>> For 10 years, maybe he's had an ulcer. >> Huh?
>> Huh?
>> Huh? >> He's had an ulcer. Yeah. For maybe 10
>> He's had an ulcer. Yeah. For maybe 10
>> He's had an ulcer. Yeah. For maybe 10 years.
years.
years. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> And so that's causing him the problem.
>> And so that's causing him the problem.
>> And so that's causing him the problem. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Okay. And he's asking what could he do?
>> Okay. And he's asking what could he do?
>> Okay. And he's asking what could he do? >> Well, there's many treatments for an
>> Well, there's many treatments for an
>> Well, there's many treatments for an ulcer. Psychoanalysis for one thing,
ulcer. Psychoanalysis for one thing,
ulcer. Psychoanalysis for one thing, repressed feelings,
repressed feelings,
repressed feelings, um anti- uh spasmotics,
um anti- uh spasmotics,
um anti- uh spasmotics, ant acids,
ant acids,
ant acids, uh
uh
uh spiritual evolution to take be you
spiritual evolution to take be you
spiritual evolution to take be you beyond the level at which you're having
beyond the level at which you're having
beyond the level at which you're having some ambivalence.
some ambivalence.
some ambivalence. >> Acupuncture.
>> Acupuncture.
>> Acupuncture. >> Acupuncture.
>> Acupuncture. Acupuncture is very good.
Acupuncture is very good.
Acupuncture is very good. >> I I practice acupuncture doctor.
>> I I practice acupuncture doctor.
>> I I practice acupuncture doctor. >> He's a hob doctor.
>> He's a hob doctor.
>> He's a hob doctor. >> A what? He's a hob doctor. Korean
>> A what? He's a hob doctor. Korean
>> A what? He's a hob doctor. Korean traditional doctor, he can use
traditional doctor, he can use
traditional doctor, he can use acupuncture.
acupuncture.
acupuncture. >> Oh, okay.
>> Oh, okay.
>> Oh, okay. >> Yes. Even though he is a doctor,
>> Yes. Even though he is a doctor,
>> Yes. Even though he is a doctor, >> he he's he's an herb or herb doctor and
>> he he's he's an herb or herb doctor and
>> he he's he's an herb or herb doctor and and he can use acupuncture. So, the
and he can use acupuncture. So, the
and he can use acupuncture. So, the acupuncture doesn't work. So, we were
acupuncture doesn't work. So, we were
acupuncture doesn't work. So, we were giving him
giving him
giving him >> Well, acupuncture works, but he's not
>> Well, acupuncture works, but he's not
>> Well, acupuncture works, but he's not going to the right doctor. Then
>> you need a better doctor.
>> you need a better doctor. >> He is a doctor.
>> He is a doctor.
>> He is a doctor. >> Well, you do. You need a if the earth
>> Well, you do. You need a if the earth
>> Well, you do. You need a if the earth will cure you, you'd be cured. If he was
will cure you, you'd be cured. If he was
will cure you, you'd be cured. If he was a good acupuncturist, he would have
a good acupuncturist, he would have
a good acupuncturist, he would have cured you. I got cured from a ulcer of
cured you. I got cured from a ulcer of
cured you. I got cured from a ulcer of many decades in three treatments.
Three treatments right there is the
Three treatments right there is the place
place
place >> for the ulcer of the stomach.
>> for the ulcer of the stomach.
>> for the ulcer of the stomach. >> For the ulcer, it's right there. You
>> For the ulcer, it's right there. You
>> For the ulcer, it's right there. You know the spot. You know the name of this
know the spot. You know the name of this
know the spot. You know the name of this spot?
spot?
spot? >> Neguan.
This spot right here.
This spot right here. Come over here, idiot. Come here. Come
Come over here, idiot. Come here. Come
Come over here, idiot. Come here. Come over here.
over here.
over here. Come here. Come here. Come here. Come
Come here. Come here. Come here. Come
Come here. Come here. Come here. Come here.
here.
here. You want answers to things without
You want answers to things without
You want answers to things without cooperating with the questioning?
cooperating with the questioning?
cooperating with the questioning? Is this the place he should get a a
Is this the place he should get a a
Is this the place he should get a a needle put?
needle put?
needle put? Let's see.
Let's see.
Let's see. >> Oh,
>> Oh,
>> Oh, >> okay.
>> okay.
>> okay. Jeepers, creepers. This is where he
Jeepers, creepers. This is where he
Jeepers, creepers. This is where he should have a needle put. Resist. If you
should have a needle put. Resist. If you
should have a needle put. Resist. If you put a needle there, get away.
>> Have you put the needle there? There.
>> Have you put the needle there? There. >> Yeah. Have you put it there?
>> Yeah. Have you put it there?
>> Yeah. Have you put it there? >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> And it doesn't do And it doesn't do any
>> And it doesn't do And it doesn't do any
>> And it doesn't do And it doesn't do any good.
good.
good. Yeah. Well, keep doing it.
>> You put the needle there and if you have
>> You put the needle there and if you have to do enough treatments, you'd be you'd
to do enough treatments, you'd be you'd
to do enough treatments, you'd be you'd be cured. Yeah. Therapy. I think some
be cured. Yeah. Therapy. I think some
be cured. Yeah. Therapy. I think some psychotherapy would help too. He's got
psychotherapy would help too. He's got
psychotherapy would help too. He's got some kind of conflicts,
some kind of conflicts,
some kind of conflicts, emotional conflict back up, you know,
>> more writing. All
>> more writing. All right.
right.
right. >> Okie do.
>> Okie do.
>> Okie do. >> Yeah. You see an answer to a man like
>> Yeah. You see an answer to a man like
>> Yeah. You see an answer to a man like that, you know, it takes a half hour of
that, you know, it takes a half hour of
that, you know, it takes a half hour of interview and discussion and karmic
interview and discussion and karmic
interview and discussion and karmic propensity
propensity
propensity and uh physical diagnosis
and uh physical diagnosis
and uh physical diagnosis and psychological set and the use of
and psychological set and the use of
and psychological set and the use of tranquilizers and medical history.
tranquilizers and medical history.
tranquilizers and medical history. Uh so you can't just answer it in about
Uh so you can't just answer it in about
Uh so you can't just answer it in about a three minute a quick uh oversight, you
a three minute a quick uh oversight, you
a three minute a quick uh oversight, you know.
know.
know. Um he also is a medical doctor and he
Um he also is a medical doctor and he
Um he also is a medical doctor and he says how can he help patients to recover
says how can he help patients to recover
says how can he help patients to recover from not only physical but mental and
from not only physical but mental and
from not only physical but mental and spiritual troubles
spiritual troubles
spiritual troubles mental and
mental and
mental and >> mental and spiritual
>> I think it's spiritual
>> I think it's spiritual >> you become a psychiatrist
>> yeah
>> yeah you become a psychiatrist No, he I mean
you become a psychiatrist No, he I mean
you become a psychiatrist No, he I mean he he wants to you know how you said
he he wants to you know how you said
he he wants to you know how you said that it's up to the medical doctor to
that it's up to the medical doctor to
that it's up to the medical doctor to become
become
become >> um
>> um
>> um you know you have a way with your
you know you have a way with your
you know you have a way with your patients that they become better doctors
patients that they become better doctors
patients that they become better doctors because you know they're successful with
because you know they're successful with
because you know they're successful with their business because uh patients come
their business because uh patients come
their business because uh patients come to
to
to >> what's I don't get what is the question
>> what's I don't get what is the question
>> what's I don't get what is the question you have to become compassionate and
you have to become compassionate and
you have to become compassionate and committed to the patient's recovery with
committed to the patient's recovery with
committed to the patient's recovery with an unconditional lovingness towards them
an unconditional lovingness towards them
an unconditional lovingness towards them uh doctors who are compassionate have uh
uh doctors who are compassionate have uh
uh doctors who are compassionate have uh two to three times the recovery rate
two to three times the recovery rate
two to three times the recovery rate from other doctors.
from other doctors.
from other doctors. >> Right?
>> Right?
>> Right? >> So you have to be more than scientific.
>> So you have to be more than scientific.
>> So you have to be more than scientific. On the one hand you have to be
On the one hand you have to be
On the one hand you have to be scientific. On the other hand you have
scientific. On the other hand you have
scientific. On the other hand you have to have a caringness and care whether
to have a caringness and care whether
to have a caringness and care whether the patient gets better or not.
the patient gets better or not.
the patient gets better or not. And uh do you have that caringness
And uh do you have that caringness
And uh do you have that caringness caring caring? Does he know what caring
caring caring? Does he know what caring
caring caring? Does he know what caring means?
means?
means? >> Um does he have that caringness towards
>> Um does he have that caringness towards
>> Um does he have that caringness towards all his patients and that he prays for
all his patients and that he prays for
all his patients and that he prays for them to get better? Does he do that?
them to get better? Does he do that?
them to get better? Does he do that? >> Okay. Yes. Yes.
>> Okay. Yes. Yes.
>> Okay. Yes. Yes. >> Yes. Well,
>> Yes. Well,
>> Yes. Well, >> all right. So, then they will get
>> all right. So, then they will get
>> all right. So, then they will get better. What's your complaint?
better. What's your complaint?
better. What's your complaint? >> Then then you're doing all you can for
>> Then then you're doing all you can for
>> Then then you're doing all you can for that.
that.
that. >> You want them to get better quicker,
>> You want them to get better quicker,
>> You want them to get better quicker, maybe.
maybe.
maybe. >> Yeah. That's about all you can do for
>> Yeah. That's about all you can do for
>> Yeah. That's about all you can do for the patient.
the patient.
the patient. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Okay. We're we're running real close on
>> Okay. We're we're running real close on
>> Okay. We're we're running real close on time, so I need to hurry through. We'll
time, so I need to hurry through. We'll
time, so I need to hurry through. We'll take one more or two. We're um
take one more or two. We're um
take one more or two. We're um >> Yeah.
You do the best you can scientifically.
You do the best you can scientifically. At the same time,
Okay, here we go. Questions again. All
Okay, here we go. Questions again. All right. Um,
this is a question for my PL. This is a
this is a question for my PL. This is a question for my friend.
question for my friend.
question for my friend. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Explain more about being awakened and
>> Explain more about being awakened and
>> Explain more about being awakened and the knowing mind.
>> Explain enlightenment and throw in its
>> Explain enlightenment and throw in its flat.
I can't answer it the way that's is
I can't answer it the way that's is phrased.
phrased.
phrased. >> You want to say right here?
>> You want to say right here?
>> You want to say right here? >> I cannot answer the question in the way
>> I cannot answer the question in the way
>> I cannot answer the question in the way in which is it's being asked.
>> Um
>> Um >> the desire for enlightenment. The desire
>> the desire for enlightenment. The desire
>> the desire for enlightenment. The desire from enlightenment.
from enlightenment.
from enlightenment. Yeah. I always advise spiritual reading
Yeah. I always advise spiritual reading
Yeah. I always advise spiritual reading and spiritual study. We gave a whole
and spiritual study. We gave a whole
and spiritual study. We gave a whole list of spiritual teachers that
list of spiritual teachers that
list of spiritual teachers that calibrate high. I said if you will start
calibrate high. I said if you will start
calibrate high. I said if you will start reading the great spiritual literature
reading the great spiritual literature
reading the great spiritual literature of the world and uh bring yourself up
of the world and uh bring yourself up
of the world and uh bring yourself up into the a higher level of intellectual
into the a higher level of intellectual
into the a higher level of intellectual understanding of what it is you're
understanding of what it is you're
understanding of what it is you're asking yourself to do. You know
asking yourself to do. You know
asking yourself to do. You know after you've read all the books on that
after you've read all the books on that
after you've read all the books on that list give me a call.
You'll either be enlightened or dead by
You'll either be enlightened or dead by then. So
then. So
then. So >> okay. And then then she says um these
>> okay. And then then she says um these
>> okay. And then then she says um these are the same just on the cover.
are the same just on the cover.
are the same just on the cover. These are the same
These are the same
These are the same meaning each these are the same meaning
meaning each these are the same meaning
meaning each these are the same meaning to each other and these are the same
to each other and these are the same
to each other and these are the same meaning as being enlightened.
meaning as being enlightened.
meaning as being enlightened. >> What is the question?
>> What is the question?
>> What is the question? >> Um I'm not really sure I understand
>> Um I'm not really sure I understand
>> Um I'm not really sure I understand this. Okay. It says these are the same
this. Okay. It says these are the same
this. Okay. It says these are the same meaning.
meaning.
meaning. >> Okay. It says explain awakening.
>> Okay. It says explain awakening.
>> Okay. It says explain awakening. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> And the knowing mind. And then it says
>> And the knowing mind. And then it says
>> And the knowing mind. And then it says these are the same meanings each other.
these are the same meanings each other.
these are the same meanings each other. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> And are these the same meanings as being
>> And are these the same meanings as being
>> And are these the same meanings as being enlightened. But we're kind of confused
enlightened. But we're kind of confused
enlightened. But we're kind of confused on the question.
on the question.
on the question. >> So she's asking that being awakened,
>> So she's asking that being awakened,
>> So she's asking that being awakened, knowing mind, being enlightened. Same.
knowing mind, being enlightened. Same.
knowing mind, being enlightened. Same. They all same. All right. Um,
They all same. All right. Um,
They all same. All right. Um, >> question is what
>> question is what
>> question is what >> is being awakened, knowing the mind,
>> is being awakened, knowing the mind,
>> is being awakened, knowing the mind, uh, being enlightened, are they all the
uh, being enlightened, are they all the
uh, being enlightened, are they all the same?
same?
same? >> They're all references to the same
>> They're all references to the same
>> They're all references to the same thing. Yes.
thing. Yes.
thing. Yes. >> Yes. They're all references.
>> Yes. They're all references.
>> Yes. They're all references. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> So, in other words, they all are about
>> So, in other words, they all are about
>> So, in other words, they all are about the same.
the same.
the same. >> Yeah. Because they're they're
>> Yeah. Because they're they're
>> Yeah. Because they're they're approaching consciousness itself as a as
approaching consciousness itself as a as
approaching consciousness itself as a as a matter for study. And
a matter for study. And
a matter for study. And >> so would one appear before the other
>> so would one appear before the other
>> so would one appear before the other depending on on the person?
depending on on the person?
depending on on the person? >> They're not as sequential. They're just
>> They're not as sequential. They're just
>> They're not as sequential. They're just ways of phrasing the same thing.
ways of phrasing the same thing.
ways of phrasing the same thing. >> All right.
>> All right.
>> All right. So they're all the same meaning.
So they're all the same meaning.
So they're all the same meaning. >> They're all the same referring to the
>> They're all the same referring to the
>> They're all the same referring to the same phenomena.
same phenomena.
same phenomena. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> All right. So
>> All right. So
>> All right. So >> they don't happen sequentially.
>> they don't happen sequentially.
>> they don't happen sequentially. >> Okay. Thank you.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Oh, here we go again. Okay. Um,
>> Oh, here we go again. Okay. Um,
>> Oh, here we go again. Okay. Um, I have no question. I just want to see
I have no question. I just want to see
I have no question. I just want to see into your eyes possibly. Can I touch
into your eyes possibly. Can I touch
into your eyes possibly. Can I touch your hands?
Oops.
Oops. >> Boy, she puts out a lot of bulbage.
>> Boy, she puts out a lot of bulbage.
>> Boy, she puts out a lot of bulbage. >> She wants you to look into your eyes.
>> She wants you to look into your eyes.
>> She wants you to look into your eyes. >> Yeah. Okay. I see you.
>> Yeah. Okay. I see you.
>> Yeah. Okay. I see you. >> Okay, let me sign this real quick.
>> Okay, let me sign this real quick.
>> Okay, let me sign this real quick. >> God bless you. Ain't she a beautiful
>> God bless you. Ain't she a beautiful
>> God bless you. Ain't she a beautiful creature?
creature?
creature? All God's creatures are beautiful.
Some people are beautifully ugly.
Some people are beautifully ugly. >> Okay, this is where they want you to
>> Okay, this is where they want you to
>> Okay, this is where they want you to stand up and say some things at the end.
>> Ah.
>> Ah. Oh, is this the end of the discussion
Oh, is this the end of the discussion
Oh, is this the end of the discussion question and answer period?
question and answer period?
question and answer period? >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Oh, good gosh. Golly whiz.
>> Oh, good gosh. Golly whiz.
>> Oh, good gosh. Golly whiz. Little did I realize
Little did I realize
Little did I realize that there we have come. Oh,
that there we have come. Oh,
that there we have come. Oh, I don't know what happened to the day. I
I don't know what happened to the day. I
I don't know what happened to the day. I just got here.
just got here.
just got here. I just got here and the day is gone
I just got here and the day is gone
I just got here and the day is gone already.
already.
already. Do we have some kind of music that we
Do we have some kind of music that we
Do we have some kind of music that we close with? Yes. Well,
close with? Yes. Well,
close with? Yes. Well, that would certainly be great if we had
that would certainly be great if we had
that would certainly be great if we had it.
The Lord is present
The Lord is present as all of us.
that it was going to be other than the
that it was going to be other than the reality of that which you are?
reality of that which you are?
reality of that which you are? What? like a donkey or a camel or a
What? like a donkey or a camel or a
What? like a donkey or a camel or a statue.
Divinity is the essence
Divinity is the essence of that which we are.
of that which we are.
of that which we are. There's no point of looking
There's no point of looking
There's no point of looking out there for it
out there for it
out there for it when you are the manifestation of that
when you are the manifestation of that
when you are the manifestation of that which it is.
Thus, we are all children of God
Thus, we are all children of God by virtue of our identity.
All of us have the same last name,
All of us have the same last name, God.
So hidden by the ego
So hidden by the ego is the awareness of the reality
is the awareness of the reality
is the awareness of the reality of that which we are.
of that which we are.
of that which we are. And as we give up the ego,
And as we give up the ego,
And as we give up the ego, the reality of that which we are stands
the reality of that which we are stands
the reality of that which we are stands forth
forth
forth overwhelmingly prominent,
overwhelmingly prominent,
overwhelmingly prominent, all prevailing,
all prevailing,
all prevailing, all present,
all present,
all present, all eternal,
all eternal,
all eternal, all powerful,
all powerful,
all powerful, all gracious,
all gracious,
all gracious, all loving,
all loving,
all loving, all forgiving.
The source of joy
The source of joy is within you.
There's a point of going after God out
There's a point of going after God out there.
It's God within that you seek.
It's God within that you seek. the realization of the divinity
the realization of the divinity
the realization of the divinity of your own existence.
of your own existence.
of your own existence. Nothing exists without the will of God.
Nothing exists without the will of God.
Nothing exists without the will of God. Your existence is the manifestation of
Your existence is the manifestation of
Your existence is the manifestation of the will of God.
the will of God.
the will of God. You are the expression of God as it is
You are the expression of God as it is
You are the expression of God as it is in this world at this moment.
And that's why we start our meetings
And that's why we start our meetings with
with
with Gloria and Excelsius Dio.
Gloria and Excelsius Dio.
Gloria and Excelsius Dio. All thanks be to thee, O Lord most high.
All thanks be to thee, O Lord most high.
All thanks be to thee, O Lord most high. Those
who surrender themselves to me said the
who surrender themselves to me said the Lord
Those who turn to me said Krishna
Those who turn to me said Krishna are mine.
Those of us who turn to me to Jesus, I
Those of us who turn to me to Jesus, I will be your advocate before the Lord.
Whether we turn to Jesus, Krishna, the
Whether we turn to Jesus, Krishna, the Buddha,
we are asking for the awareness of a
we are asking for the awareness of a reality that already exists.
How can salvation be in the future when
How can salvation be in the future when time is just an illusion? Salvation is
time is just an illusion? Salvation is
time is just an illusion? Salvation is here and now. All of us that turn to God
here and now. All of us that turn to God
here and now. All of us that turn to God have are already saved.
Divinity is eternal. Your spiritual,
Divinity is eternal. Your spiritual, your soul is the eternal. In that which
your soul is the eternal. In that which
your soul is the eternal. In that which is eternal. There is no then, now or the
is eternal. There is no then, now or the
is eternal. There is no then, now or the future.
future.
future. All exists as an absolute reality beyond
All exists as an absolute reality beyond
All exists as an absolute reality beyond and transcending all time.
and transcending all time.
and transcending all time. The fact that you are here now.
The fact that you are here now.
The fact that you are here now. Devoting your life to the knowledge and
Devoting your life to the knowledge and
Devoting your life to the knowledge and love of God is sufficient to just to
love of God is sufficient to just to
love of God is sufficient to just to justify your own salvation.
Merely to be here is to already justify
Merely to be here is to already justify one's salvation. Resist.
I thank you so much for being here.
I thank you so much for being here. You are my joy.
All of you here today
All of you here today are God's gift to me.
Oh
Oh the Lord's going to knock me out today.
the Lord's going to knock me out today.
the Lord's going to knock me out today. Okay. I've taken all I can take.
That's all the love I can handle today.
That's all the love I can handle today. You know that
You know that
You know that you reach a saturation point where we
you reach a saturation point where we
you reach a saturation point where we just sort of melt into falling over.
If you get close enough to God, you just
If you get close enough to God, you just fall over.
So
So we are very blessed to have each other.
we are very blessed to have each other.
we are very blessed to have each other. We are blessed to have each other in a
We are blessed to have each other in a
We are blessed to have each other in a group such as this. A group so
group such as this. A group so
group such as this. A group so powerfully committed to God. This group
powerfully committed to God. This group
powerfully committed to God. This group counterbalances do you realize many
counterbalances do you realize many
counterbalances do you realize many millions of people in the world. This
millions of people in the world. This
millions of people in the world. This group here alone counterbalances the
group here alone counterbalances the
group here alone counterbalances the negativity of multi-millions of people.
negativity of multi-millions of people.
negativity of multi-millions of people. Let's just ask out of curiosity.
Let's just ask out of curiosity.
Let's just ask out of curiosity. This group here counterbalances
This group here counterbalances
This group here counterbalances the negativity of over 50 million, 100
the negativity of over 50 million, 100
the negativity of over 50 million, 100 million,
million,
million, 75 million, 70 million.
75 million, 70 million.
75 million, 70 million. This group here counterbalances the
This group here counterbalances the
This group here counterbalances the negativity and evil put out by 70
negativity and evil put out by 70
negativity and evil put out by 70 million people. 70 million.
million people. 70 million.
million people. 70 million. Well, that's a day well spent, huh?
I guess that gave evil a bopper in the
I guess that gave evil a bopper in the nose. Take that one, baby.
nose. Take that one, baby.
nose. Take that one, baby. Oh, thank you so much for being here.
Oh, thank you so much for being here.
Oh, thank you so much for being here. Thank you for your love. You made it
Thank you for your love. You made it
Thank you for your love. You made it such a marvelous, marvelous day. I thank
such a marvelous, marvelous day. I thank
such a marvelous, marvelous day. I thank you so much. Amen. And I name you I I
you so much. Amen. And I name you I I
you so much. Amen. And I name you I I bless you in the name of the Buddha and
bless you in the name of the Buddha and
bless you in the name of the Buddha and Krishna and our Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.
Krishna and our Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.
Krishna and our Lord Jesus Christ. Amen. Thank you again. Love.
Thank you again. Love.
Thank you again. Love. Yeah.