Well, what happens next?
>> First questions.
>> Questions.
Is anybody still talking to me?
>> Hey, David.
>> Hello.
>> How are you?
>> Uhhuh.
Fine indeed.
Put this right here. Eddie.
>> Oh, what's up?
>> Okay. First of all, thank you for not
leaving the body and staying with us to
pass on the teaching to me. I want to
genuinely thank you for that.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And
yeah.
>> Okay. My question is
how do you how if I had to ask you how
do you want someone like me to continue
what you have already started in terms
of evolution of consciousness?
>> I'm not here.
>> Um how do you want how do you want
someone to continue your work?
>> How would you what would you ask your
students to do once you do pass on?
>> Well, they they read the books. that
become familiar with the material
because there's many concepts there that
are not available elsewhere
and then there's uh DVDs of lectures
where it's been explained and uh so
between reading the books and the DVDs
a person would get the gist of it all.
Yes.
>> And then the rest of it is one's own
practice.
>> David, how can we continue evolving what
you have already started?
You're not going to evolve it because
when you get to the mind of God, that's
the end.
What's beyond the mind of God? Nothing.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. And I just can I have your
blessings so I can go all the way.
>> Your personal blessings.
>> You want your blessing?
>> That'll be a dollar.
>> A dollar. Dollar.
>> Oh, that's no problem.
Now you have your you have my blessing
by being up here on the table with me
and speaking with me. Amen.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you for coming up.
>> I'm going to have to move those over
there.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. And could I have your signature as a
souvenir for my husband?
>> Look at this.
It's a dollar.
>> That's funny.
>> That is
>> Oh.
Oh, no. Sign the dollar, please.
>> Sign the dollar.
>> Okay.
>> And I know how much that's worth.
Now for my question.
Uh examination of something
changes that which is examined
calibrates as a true statement.
>> Yes.
>> So my question is when you're
calibrating something why does that not
change what's being calibrated?
>> I don't get the question.
>> Okay. When you
>> if I calibrate the energy of a company,
that doesn't change the energy field of
the company. No,
>> but if you calibrate it the second time,
it sometimes does.
>> No, not usually.
>> Well, it sometimes it'll vary.
>> Harvard calibrated at 200, it still
calibrates at 200.
Doesn't change.
>> Can prior prejudice affect the
calibration?
It depends on how expert you are at
calibrating things.
A a very uh
well-defined person
can calibrate a thing without without
intention.
See, why would I want
uh General Electric to calibrate higher
or lower than it does? So the integrity
of the question,
the integrity or the inte integrity of
the question.
If you want to know what a thing
calibrates, that's one question. If you
want to change it, that's that's
something completely different. Yeah.
>> So if I have stock in General Electric,
that won't change the calibration.
>> No.
>> Okay. Thank you. General Electric would
be through the sky if that was
Everybody wants GE to go up because they
bought the stock.
>> Hi. Uh Dr. Hawkins, do I have permission
uh to shake your hand?
>> Okay. Later. Okay. Um, this is a
question um from my son who's in a
mental hospital and uh he's taking meds.
>> This is a question what?
>> From my son who's
>> from your son?
>> He's in a mental hospital.
>> He's too close to the sit back.
>> I'm sorry. Can you hear me better?
>> Yes.
>> Okay. This is from my son uh who's in a
mental hospital and he's taking
medication. Ailify and clonoprin. This
is what he says. He's a student of
yours. I've been using affirmations
almost nonstop. such as I love myself.
Jesus heal me. Jesus take these negative
thoughts away. Now it is almost nine
months later and I am in a mental
hospital with uncontrollable shaking and
anxiety. I am too afraid to continue the
use of affirmations because of what
happened to me being in the hospital.
Enlightenment seems out of the question
and I would simply like to have a nice
stable happy life. How can I do this now
that I'm so out of it with the meds? I
>> How can I do this? Is an awful long
message.
>> Okay.
>> How can I do what?
>> How can he reach enlightenment when he
feels like he
>> forget about it for now?
>> First get your act together.
>> That's the answer. Okay. All right.
Besides the road to enlightenment can
take a number of lifetimes.
>> Okay.
>> This may be just one step in a long way,
you know, for him.
>> Yeah. Try try to get your life back
together just on a normal level.
>> Okay.
>> Worry about enlightenment some other
time.
>> Okay.
>> You got to be kidding.
>> Yeah. It's very Okay, that's a good
answer.
>> He needs to concentrate on himself and
get better.
She wants to shake her hand.
>> Yes.
>> Um,
>> first of all, thank you so much for your
teachings. They've affected me greatly.
>> I can't hear him.
>> Yeah.
>> I'd like to I have a question. I'd like
to ask for your your blessing as a
teacher. Um, first
>> he wants you to bless bless him. You're
doing a blessing.
>> Yes. God bless you. Amen.
>> My my question is, do you do you have
any tips for staying on the razor's
edge?
>> Well, intention plus endeavor will
automatically handle it.
>> Mhm.
>> Intention.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Plus endeavor for staying on that.
>> Yeah. Right.
>> Okay. Okay.
>> Staying on the edge of the wave.
>> Okay.
Thank you. May I shake your hand?
Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> God bless.
>> Good golly, look at all this. Hey,
>> I know.
>> Um, we didn't sign any of the Korean
books and that's what this is all about.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
I have a question for you about a a
spiritual experience that I had.
>> Wait a minute. I can't hear him now.
>> I have a question.
>> He has a question about a a spiritual
experience that he had.
>> Oh,
>> you actually explain it pretty well on
page 220 of Eye of the Eye. You say, "As
the state of enlightenment presents
itself, there's a glad moment as though
experiencing a re-entry into the
profoundly familiar. There's a fleeting
transitory thought that one had
forgotten who they were. This was
forgetting was a consequence of the
operation perception itself.
It happened one night. I was doing the
watching the dots meditation.
>> I can't understand.
>> Yeah, we're having problems with the
>> You need to speak directly to the mic.
>> I was doing the watching the dots
meditation.
>> Um
>> All right. Go ahead.
>> I did it for about an hour and a half
before I went to bed that night. And
>> he took what? An hour and a half before
bed?
>> No. watching the Fosgenist meditation
where you close your eyes and you look
at where you close your eyes and you
look at the dots
>> where you close your eyes and look at
dots, you know,
>> and look what
>> you close your eyes and you see little
dots. He
>> Oh, yes. Yes.
>> Hour before you went
>> Oh, yeah. Uhhuh.
>> I woke I woke up and I was in a dream. I
was sleeping and it was all of a sudden
everything melted. It seemed like
everything was melted down. It was like
perception perceptual filter just
dropped. There was no there was no
perception and it was just like you say
in the book. It was like re-entry into
the familiar.
>> That's too long a story. I can't
>> um I was I'd like to ask what I mean was
this the void because I experienced like
a it was like a fear of non-existence
there. There's like a it came up
>> a fear. He had a fear of non-existence.
>> There's like exactly how
>> Yes, that's correct. Yes. It's exactly
how you explain it too. It's like how I
I might not have come into existence.
>> That's the ego's afraid. You forget.
>> And where where do I go with it from
here? I mean, there's this this happened
over a year ago where does what does he
do now? He
>> was it was it the void?
>> It's gone now. It was a year ago.
>> Okay. What was it? The void or will I
face this again?
>> I can't hear anything he say.
>> He wants to know if it was the void.
Was that the void he experienced? Did he
get a glimpse of the void?
>> The void is nothingness. So, how if it's
nothing, how could you get a glimpse of
it?
>> There was there was a fear of
non-existence though. It was like
>> fear of non-existence.
>> Oh, a fear of non-existence. Yes. That's
normal.
When you get to a certain level, you're
afraid you're going to disappear and you
will no longer exist. Yes.
>> Okay. Can I have your blessing and shake
your hand?
get my book signed.
>> There you go.
>> Yes. God bless you.
>> God bless you. God bless your endeavor.
Holy smokes.
>> I know.
jumping Jehoshaphat.
>> It's enough to give you the wagglies.
>> Okay, go ahead.
>> I often find it hard to uh differentiate
when I'm coming from love or when it is
sympathy. How can I remain pure for
whether I'm from love or from sympathy?
you have difficulty.
>> Yeah. To to understand but when am I
handling from sympathy? So
>> he um he has difficulty in knowing when
he uh is coming from the sign of love or
is it the sign of sympathy for that
person?
>> He doesn't know the difference between
love and sympathy. Huh?
>> Well, you know,
>> I don't know how to tell him.
Compassion would answer it.
Compassion is better than sympathy.
Sympathy is okay, but compassion is of a
higher level of love.
>> So yeah, so compassion would be higher
than sympathy.
So from compassion to help someone
rather than
>> rather than resonate at the same level.
>> Yes.
>> Can I give him a hand?
>> He wants to shake your hand.
I'm trying to sign this book. Just a
second.
Forgetting this poor name.
>> They give me six books to sign. They
want me to bless them and ask me a
question.
>> Hello.
>> And recite the
>> Lord's Prayer backwards
>> while standing on my head.
>> Okay.
>> Yes.
>> I'm going off to college next year.
>> You got to speak slower and more.
Definitely.
>> To the mic. You might not be right at
your
>> I'm going to college. College next year.
>> You're going to college?
>> Yeah. I was wondering about the
collaboration
of the level of consciousness um of the
universities in Sweden.
>> Oh, the University of Sweden.
>> Yeah. In the general in Sweden and in
Stockholm.
>> In Stockholm.
>> Yeah.
>> If you could calibrate.
>> He wants to know what the uh University
of Sweden calibrates at.
because that's where he's going to be
attending school.
>> University of Sweden and Stockholm. We
have permission to ask this. It's over
400, 450, 470,
460,
465. We're on 460. That's excellent.
>> And Stockholm,
>> you want me to calibrate Stockholm?
>> He wants the cal. He wants the
calibration of Stockholm.
>> Stockholm. I thought you asked me the
university.
>> He did.
>> Yeah.
>> Well, I gave it to you.
>> Yeah, but the Stockholm is different.
>> What do you care what Stockholm is? It's
just a big city.
>> Going to be living.
>> Oh,
Stockholm Cali. 300 350
340.
Okay, we're on 340.
>> So that's
>> May I shake your hand?
>> Yeah.
>> Look up Gabe while you're there. Gabe is
living in a small town in Scot in
Sweden.
>> Yeah.
>> D wherever you used to work for us.
>> Yeah. Yep.
>> Good luck.
>> He's playing soccer.
>> Yeah, he'll be okay.
>> Good luck. Good luck.
>> It's a long way to go for Swedish
meatballs, you know what I mean?
But they're good.
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. Hello, Susan. Uh,
it's very nice to be here today. Um, my
question was, uh, if you could explain
some of the traps or pitfalls of the 400
level.
>> What are the traps?
>> It's the intellect.
>> Intellectualism would be the obvious
downside.
intellectualism for its own sake.
I heard some guy on TV the other night.
He's sort of a well-known personality,
but I forget his name. He was so smuggly
superior about how stupid it is to be a
a believer and how only an atheist is
intelligent.
And he was so smug about it all. How
stupid you are. Could you believe in God
when there's no proof of that? So,
here's a guy whose ego is all into his
intellect and he's dumber than hell. You
know what I mean?
So stupid. He's pathetic.
>> Thank you.
>> Trying to prove the existence of God
with your intellect is, you know, for
fools.
>> How to define the undefinable. Huh?
Yeah, that's a project.
But he was so smuggly superior about it.
I just thought, "Oh my god, this guy's
too much."
>> Thank you. Uh, may I shake your hand?
>> Yeah.
>> Yes. Good wishes. Yes.
He's good looking man.
>> You cannot realize the truth of God nor
a denial of the truth of God through the
intellect.
That's sending a spade to do the job of
a bulldozer. It's not possible.
>> I was a professional atheist for years
so I know.
>> Hi Dr. Alkins.
>> Hi. Uh my question is um the fire in the
belly for towards spiritual evolution
seems to come in waves and I wonder if
it's like stabilizes or does it happen
like this? He he says he's having, you
know, he has bits and glimpses and it
comes like in waves.
>> He gets what?
>> There's waves of spiritual
>> Yes, that's true.
>> kind of comes over him and he says,
"Does it stabilize or does it always
kind of come up like this?"
>> It depends on the individual. For some,
it stabilizes for others it continues to
come and go for years.
Then it reaches a profound level then it
stops fluctuating.
>> Okay. Mhm.
>> So, how how would he if he wants it to
come in waves more, how would he just
continue?
>> He just stop wanting it, wanting to
control it.
>> If you're going to surrender to God,
then do so. Don't be telling God what to
do.
>> I guess you shouldn't ask that.
>> That was good.
>> All right, shake your hand, sir.
>> God doesn't get offended by it. I think
it's comicalable.
>> Can he shake your hand?
>> Either. What do you want? The the book
signed or you want to shake my hand?
>> I want to shake your ass
>> with my feet. I could play you a tune on
it.
D shake your hand and sign the books.
What else?
I can whistle too.
Don't pay any attention to the doc, you
know.
>> Yeah.
>> Sorry.
>> Hi. First of all, I want to say that I'm
very thankful to be here. My question is
about a member of my family. I brought
>> just
>> Okay, not that far.
>> Here.
>> There.
>> I brought a picture of her.
Her name is Maria Claudia Roas. She was
kidnapped
about three years ago in Colombia, South
America. I would like to know if it's
possible to know that if is she is still
alive or not. She was abducted in South
America and she wants to know whether
she's still alive.
>> Kidnapped. She was kidnapped.
>> She was What does she want to know?
>> She was abducted or kidnapped in South.
>> She was
>> No.
>> No. This person.
>> Oh, that person. Yes.
>> She wants to know if she's still alive.
>> Oh. Why did you want to know? Is she a
relative or what?
>> Yes.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Uhhuh.
Was she on television? That picture?
>> This picture was on a newspaper. was in
the newspaper.
>> In the newspaper? Oh. Uhhuh.
>> We have permission to ask if this
>> if I
have permission to ask is this person
still alive.
No,
we do not have permission to ask if this
person is still alive or this. We
sometimes get that with life and death
and strangers or family members. We
don't know why.
>> Yes, I know. It's um
>> maybe it isn't decided yet.
>> Maybe it's in this in the sign of hope
that you would give up hope if you knew
she wasn't alive and that your prayers,
you know, you stop the prayering praying
for her. So maybe that's why. I don't
know.
>> Okay. So, you know, if you can put her
on her name on pray prayer groups, uh I
would do everything possible as far as
it goes as um
put her on every single prayer list you
can.
>> Yes, we have been doing that since she
got kidnapped.
>> Yes, that would be your answer. And you
know, it also you're dealing with karma.
You don't know what her karma is.
>> Yes.
>> So, you you're dealing with both of
those situations. So, you just do what
you can. Yes.
>> And it's horrible not knowing.
>> Yes.
>> Not a very good position to be in.
>> So, but you know, email us and we'll put
her on our prayer list.
>> Okay. Thank you so much.
>> Appreciate it.
>> Yes.
Yes,
>> Dr. Hawkins, we are from the Cape Town
Study Group and we would like to ask
>> They're from where?
>> The Cape Town study group in South
Africa.
>> Oh, yes. Uhhuh.
>> Yes. We're familiar with you guys.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you for
>> Thank you.
>> Yes. Thank you. Thank you, Susan. And we
would last like to ask individually for
your blessing and for your blessing on
the study group in Cape Town.
>> They went to us to bless the study group
in Cape Town, South Africa. And they
have we have been sending them things
for what five years now?
>> Since 2000,
>> seven years you say.
>> Yeah. Seven years. And so this got study
group has been in the I mean there for a
long long time.
>> Seven years.
>> Yeah.
>> Uhuh.
>> Here. Sorry.
>> Oh, honey. You're funny.
>> I have to
tweak your nose sometimes.
All righty.
>> Illegible scrawl.
>> That's all right. It's done.
Okay. So, they want a blessing for South
for their uh Cape for the Cape Count.
>> I think we already have blessed them.
Uh did they what bless this or
>> oh I don't think we can do that.
>> Okay. So
>> okay we do send our blessing to that
group in South Africa and I think we
have done so before as well
and we wish it well.
>> Thank you.
>> We're getting all our books in foreign
languages. A lot of people are here from
foreign countries. This is wonderful.
>> Oh, this is an interesting language.
It's called gobbledegook.
>> Here, look up.
>> It's in gobbledegook.
>> Yep.
>> Can I touch his hand?
>> Yes.
>> They want to touch your hand
over there.
>> Oh.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you.
Are they from South Africa?
>> Yes.
>> Are you all from South Africa?
>> Okay.
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Yes.
>> I first want to start by just saying
thank you, Susan, for your devotion
>> all these years.
>> Sometimes it's better than others.
I've got no questions. I just want to
say thank you, doctor, for your
excellent sense of humor. You just make
it pleasure to watch your work and get
through it with with a smile on her
face. There's my dollar for a blessing.
>> She wants a blessing. Gave you a dollar
for a blessing.
>> No, no, keep the dollar. God bless you.
I don't charge a dollar anymore.
The IRS wanted their cut of it.
I said it was God's money.
They said even God has to pay him tax.
No excuse.
>> Boy, oh boy. What do I
>> question you had? No,
>> there's another question from the side.
>> Okay.
My question is
as being a musician I study the works of
Mozer Bau and all these big musical
giants but we all know that when they
were alive in their time they was
weren't appreciated by the society
opposite the society thought Mozart is a
loser his music was never appreciated
when he was alive
>> my question is nowadays how we can
determine
is a good person, is a truthful person
by just seeing his behavior
like Mozart or Beethoven. If you want to
find Beethoven, you can find under the
bridge drunk and always cross of people.
How a good people
>> get short. Holy cats. What is this
history of mankind or what?
What is the question? She says, "How do
you determine if a person, you know,
like these uh artists were drunks and
under bridges?"
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> So, how do you determine if someone is a
good person?
>> That's judgmental. What do you mean by a
>> I think uh
>> like a drunken French artist is a fine
person to begin with.
>> Very kind. Well, so for instance, like
you know these artists, a lot of them
had other problems like alcoholism and
that
>> Oh, yeah. So how do you determine that
you know any
>> I wouldn't ask the question what do you
mean by a good person according to what
definition and what is a good person
>> like the music of Mozart calibrates
above 500
>> what
>> Mozart calorie is about about 500 so how
did you you determine
>> I asked the arm Mozart's level of
consciousness is and then I find out
what it is yeah he also had an extremely
high IQ.
>> Through kinesiology or muscle testing,
you could find out what whether this
person what their intentions were and
and whether or not they would be a good
person or as you put it,
>> not necessarily looking at the actions.
>> There's one thing being a great artist,
another being a good person.
>> You can be a great artist and be an sob,
you know.
>> So there's two different
>> You can be a saint but a lousy artist.
The world's full of them.
Okay, thank you very much. We are also
from South Africa. It was and our little
present with cards. And we want these
cards to be signed this day.
>> I was so poor when I was young. I
couldn't afford to be an artist. I
couldn't afford the paints. I couldn't
afford the canvas.
So, I gave up being an artist.
The pigments were expensive.
>> Well, you were a member of what group?
>> Oh, the art institute. Yeah,
>> he's good to the back.
>> I used to pose for him. They give me $10
an hour.
>> That's the truth.
couldn't afford it, but I could make 10
bucks.
>> Thank you.
>> They allowed me to drape my pants over
certain areas of my life
for 10 bucks.
Otherwise, I wanted 20.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
>> David, you're not supposed to be telling
me.
>> 10 bucks will do. Yeah,
>> you're not supposed to be telling me. I
was I was wandering I was in the Navy
wandering through the the San Francisco
Art Institute
and this lady came over to me and asked
me did I want to pose you know they
needed a young male model I was in the
Navy 10 bucks an hour sound like good
money to me
that's the story my uh that's the story
made quick 10 bucks
>> okay hi Dr. Hawkins. Um, I don't have a
question. I just wanted to say thank you
and tell you that you mean so much to me
and I was hoping to get a picture with
you.
>> Well, I don't know what she said.
>> Um, she said that she appreciates your
work and she wanted to have a picture.
>> Oh, okay.
Right
there.
Got it.
>> Oh,
>> you're very cooperative today.
>> Hi.
Um, my question is, uh,
I was just wondering if by reading your
books and
listening to your CDs and watching your
DVDs if that puts me in the exact same
consciousness as we're all in right now.
>> I get it. Then I think she's saying
>> Repeat it one more time. I'm sorry.
If reading
>> slowly
>> if reading your books, CDs, DVDs, if
does that put me in the same
consciousness as being with you here
right now?
>> No. But it exposes you. It exposes you
to his consciousness.
In other words, the things that he are
saying, you know, you're absorbing into
your subconscious and eventually that
will raise your consciousness level
>> if you if that's what your intentions
are. So,
right,
>> what is your question? I still don't get
what is her question.
>> The she said watching your DVDs and CDs.
Yes. That put her in the same
consciousness as you level as you
>> as I am right now.
>> No. or as you are right now. Okay.
She wants to know I don't know is her
>> can she get enlightened via DVD? No. No.
>> Okay. So So
are you asking if if you watch him on a
DVD will that help you to uh
>> I'm in a certain consciousness level
right now. Right.
>> She wants to advance her consciousness.
Would watching the DVDs and doing what
the doctor there says to do advance your
consciousness? Sure.
>> Of course.
>> Great.
>> Would practicing baseball make you a
better baseball player? Yes.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Perfect.
>> No, you're She's okay.
>> Okay. My family's gonna come up. Okay.
Hi.
>> Hi.
Um, I'm with my son
>> and I don't think either of us have a
question. We just kind of wanted to be
in your presence and tell you how
grateful we are to be here with you.
>> Yeah.
>> Did you hear that?
>> Yes. The last since I heard it. Yeah.
And we were wondering if uh we could get
a picture with you.
>> Now, what did she say?
>> She wants they want a photo with you.
>> Oh, photo. Yeah. Okay,
>> we're good. Thank you.
>> He gets a feedback on here and it's very
difficult to hear.
>> Yeah, this
>> the sound in here is terrible.
I don't know what this is. Oh, here it
is.
>> The cap's on.
>> There we go.
>> Thank you. Thank you very
>> good afternoon, Dr. Hawkins. Hello.
>> I'm honored to meet you and I have a
question for you. Um, what would you
suggest to facilitate all of the world
religions to get along to truly work
together and unite to increase God's
power here on earth?
>> What's the question?
>> What would you suggest to unite?
>> I wouldn't suggest it.
>> That's just a neat a neat human idea.
>> Okay. We'll combine all the world's
religion in one super religion.
>> No, doesn't work that way.
>> Keep it as it is.
>> Works the way it is.
>> Okay.
>> Unfortunately.
>> Yes. Okay.
>> Well, thank you very much.
>> Thank you so much.
>> All right.
>> They struggle through
>> Thank you.
>> what religion really is not and then
discover what religion really is.
Can he repeat? Yeah.
>> Um he said discover what religion is
not.
>> They discover what religion is not with
all their wars and god knows what all
>> and eventually they discover then what
religion is.
>> Yes.
>> But they don't discover till they're
ready.
>> Okay.
>> You know the way you spread God's word
is not by killing everybody who doesn't
agree with you.
>> Correct. I mean, that's the height of
narcissism. Have I ever heard it,
>> right?
>> We're going to behead everybody who
doesn't agree with us. Help us.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Well, spreading consciousness
would be a great way to do that.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> Yes.
>> Beautiful voice.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Thank you.
>> Oh. Oh.
>> Dr. Hawkins. I've studied your work.
I've listened to your CDs.
I belong to a study group, so I
understand it. I practice it every day.
In my heart, I understand it. In my
head, I understand it. But my body seems
to still be fight or flight. I still get
u a gut reaction from negative
experiences. I get my fingers get cold
and I get insomnia. Even though I have a
great wonderful life and I have a lot of
gratitude, my body hasn't got that
uh message.
What can I do?
>> What's your question?
>> Um she still has um her body's telling
her that she's having second thoughts.
Her body's telling her body doesn't
>> I have a stress response.
>> What?
>> She gets a stress response.
>> Oh
>> yeah.
>> From what?
>> I'm a very happy person. It's just my
body seems to be upset.
>> In my mind, I'm happy. In my heart, I'm
happy. But I get physical symptoms from
as if as if I'm being attacked.
like uh
>> I don't know what you're saying
>> the like fight.
>> What does she mean she gets physically
attacked? I don't know.
>> Physical symptoms like
>> she gets physical symptoms that she
>> Yeah. Like throwing up, fainting,
passing out, getting angry, getting
goosebumps. No, like insomnia
and um my fingers turn white and
pounding of the heart.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Okay.
>> But I have nothing to be upset about. I
have a great life. So I can't figure out
why my body doesn't know that yet.
>> I don't know. It's a psychiatric
problem.
>> Oh, okay.
Okay. Thank you very much. Yeah.
>> Can I have a picture with you?
>> Yes.
>> Yeah, sure.
>> We're sorry. We're trying to do three
things that the cover of the CD.
>> Yes.
>> Did it work?
Namaste.
>> Namaste. Um, first of all, I want to
thank you and I appreciate your presence
here. And I only want to ask for your
blessings
so that I um can have more success with
my healing. Um, it's a holistic healing
practice
and help more people.
>> She wants what?
>> Blessings.
>> Spend her blessing on her her holistic
healing practice so that she can help
more people.
>> Yeah,
sure. I bless your holistic healing.
Amen.
>> Okay.
>> Yep.
>> Can I shake your hand?
>> Yes.
>> Sure.
>> Yeah. God bless you.
Hello.
>> Yes,
>> we came together. We are friends and we
would like to just receive a tri silent
transmission.
>> They want to just sit.
>> What?
>> They just want to feel your silence
transmission
transmission.
>> So, put it out there.
It's done.
>> Good.
>> God bless you both. Yeah.
>> God bless you both. God bless you.
>> Yes. Is that it?
>> Oh, good. Thank you, honey.
Yep.
>> Are you okay?
>> Mhm.
>> All right.
>> Hello.
>> We're done.
>> My question is, how can I heal inner
judgmentalism?
>> What?
>> Sorry. What? How can I heal inner judge
judgmentalism?
>> How can you heal interjudgmentalism?
>> Being self-critical.
>> Stop doing it.
>> How can you stop picking your nose?
Don't pick it.
>> Okay. Just that.
>> Well, do you know when you're doing it?
>> Yeah. Yeah, I know when I'm doing it.
>> Okay. Well, then
>> stop it
>> then. So, you know, if you know when
you're doing it, then stop.
>> Turn on the radio, watch television,
read the newspaper,
>> go meditate.
>> Do you think you're qualified to to
judge people that way or judge things
that way?
>> No.
>> Okay, then. No,
>> you you can you can pray instead. Pray.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. Ask God to remove these defects of
character. Period.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. Thank you. May I shake your hand?
>> What?
>> Shake your hand.
>> No, you don't want to shake my hand.
>> Don't do it. Don't ask.
>> Ask God to remove your defects of
character. Live one day at a time.
>> Keep it simple.
>> Okay.
>> Easy does it.
First things first,
get with the program.
Okay. I would like to ask you if I could
sit next to you for a couple of
questions for the silent transmission.
>> What?
>> He wants to sit next to you for a couple
of questions for silent transmission.
>> Yeah. You don't have to sit next to me.
Just ask me what you want to ask me.
>> Okay. I I'm working with shame at the
moment and uh I would like to ask you if
you have any pointers
how to heal it.
>> He's working with shame at the
>> shame. Yes. Yes.
>> So can you give him some pointers as to
how to overcome that
>> shame?
Uh look at it this way. Shame is
egocentricity.
Oh me, how bad I was. Oh me. Oh me. Oh
me. Oh me. Oh me. How did I do that? Oh
me. Give up being egocentric.
Try to judge yourself is egocentric.
Am I good? Am I bad? Or was I terrible?
You know, give up egoentricity. Stop
looking in the mirror at yourself.
worry about other people who need your
help instead of yourself.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank you very much. May I shake
your hand?
>> You get over shame through forgiveness.
And what is the shame?
That you have a weak human ego.
That you're born human. You're born
human. You have an ego.
And the ego is only concerned with me
me.
Give up worrying about me.
>> Hello Susan. Hello David.
>> Mhm.
>> Jacob here come from Coventry England to
say hello.
>> From where?
>> Coventry England. England.
>> Coventry.
>> Coventry England.
>> Thank you. And uh haven't got a question
really. just like shake your hand. Me
and Jake,
>> you come right on over.
>> They're from England. They came way to
see you.
>> Oh, okay.
>> Okay.
>> This is the son.
>> Oh, God bless you.
>> All right.
>> It's been a long time since we've been
in London.
>> England. Yeah. uh 2003 I think.
>> Okay. Yes.
>> I I just
I just want to tell you I thank God
every day that I found your teachings
and I thank God now that I found finally
had a chance to see you in person. Can I
hold your hand?
>> I can't understand a word. She's
mumbling.
>> I thank you so much.
>> Yeah.
>> And I work.
>> Okay.
>> Stop mumbling and crying.
>> Well, she's really crying. It's kind of
>> know
>> Okay. Oh my god. That'll be an extra
dollar.
>> Come over, baby. Give me the nice keys
right there. Give me the nice keys right
there.
All the women want your body.
>> All the women are fighting after my
little body.
Oh, narcissism.
>> Yeah.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins and uh Susan. First of
all, I want to thank you both for doing
all the work that you do for all of us.
I really appreciate that. Okay. Um, and
I have one question and I have a
blessing for you. Um,
some people I respect think that
promoting divine and unconditional love
to everything in the universe is the
proper path. Right.
>> Others what he said. He's reading it.
>> I'm trying. Mhm.
>> I'm I had to write this down because
it's a heavy question, but
>> tell me what is the question.
>> Not yet.
>> Oh, okay.
>> I'm going to get right to the question.
Can we have it both ways and have a
wonderful loving relationship
while devoting our lives to service unto
others?
Can we do both?
>> Can we be in love with one person?
>> Yeah.
>> And still have enough to give to the
rest.
>> Why not?
>> Look at us.
>> Something to look forward to.
>> Absolutely.
I was expecting you to answer like that.
So, finally, my blessing is this. Can I
please ask that you, Dr. Hawkins, and
the audience give a blessing to my soon
to be asked fiance, Tiffany, and me?
>> All right.
>> You want the whole audience?
What is that? Spiritual gluttony.
>> Yes.
I just sent you best wishes.
Can you say that a little bit louder?
Let those who can hear hear. Let those
who can see see.
Now we certainly send you the best
wishes.
>> We send you the best wishes. Yes.
>> Thank you so much.
>> The best wishes.
Little ones, but lots and lots of them.
Or a big one. Just one.
>> Hello.
>> How are you?
>> Hi.
>> Um, I do have a question.
Do you think
when I go home on my drive back to
Toronto, we should drive four hours out
of our way to see the Grand Canyon?
>> Yes.
>> No calibration necessary.
>> I wouldn't I would go and see uh Niagara
Falls
>> on the way back, too. Okay.
Thank you so much.
>> Niagara Falls.
>> Oh, yes. It's just down the road.
>> Well, then you better see the Grand
Canyon because it might be gone by the
time you get around there.
>> Thank you.
>> It is worthwhile.
>> All right. Thanks, guys.
>> You'll thank me.
>> Even the president went to see it.
>> Didn't the president president go and
see it?
>> Yeah, the president was
>> Yeah. Yeah.
Hello.
I have no question. I just wanted to sit
here and look into your eyes. Thank you
for your work and your autograph.
And uh I started reading your stuff in
April and it's been wonderful for me and
I'm sure many other people here and I
just feel it. And uh the bag piper at
the beginning,
I was crying through the whole thing.
And I've never done that before with bag
pipes.
>> What is he saying?
>> He said he he said he cried through the
whole uh bag pipe.
>> I said it's the first time I've ever
cried at bag pipes. Usually I cry
because they go on too long.
>> Yes.
Anyway,
he doesn't really have a question. He's
just saying that you really appreciate
seeing you at this event.
>> Oh, I see. I've got a set of bag pipes
at home. It's on the They're hanging on
the wall.
>> Yep.
>> Thank you very much. And I would also
like to shake your hand.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Yeah. Yes.
Yeah. The pipes are on the wall.
>> Hello.
>> Hi.
>> Thank you. Um, two questions. One is
what does the big book of Alcoholics
Anonymous calibrate at?
>> Oh, the book. I don't know the book.
>> I don't remember.
>> No, I don't.
>> We've done it before, but I don't
remember what I did.
>> I've done it a dozen times. Uh, the book
is over 900.
book is over 700, 750,
725,
730, 720 is good enough.
>> And then my other question is um you
know I'm coming up on on 20 years in the
program and in the last year.
>> All right.
>> You've been in the program 20 years
>> in two weeks.
>> Time to stop drinking, don't you think?
got you there.
>> It got me there. Um my question is in
the last year when I find myself
meditating or or feeling that gratitude
for God's grace, I find myself just
starting to just weep uncontrollably and
I I I don't understand what it is. It
feels good, but it's I just don't
understand it. You know, it's
>> What do you mean understand it? You want
to mentalize about it?
>> No. No. I
>> just is what it is. It is what it is.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. Thank you.
>> Tell them how many years you have.
>> Oh, God. Close to 50.
>> All right.
>> 47.
>> You knew Bill Wilson? No.
>> Yes. All right. Well, I got to shake
your hand.
>> We used to speak together.
>> We used to speak together at uh
there was a retreat out a retreat house
for alcoholic priests in uh in Michigan.
And uh Bill and I used to speak there.
>> Hello.
>> How are you, Dr. Hawk?
>> Yes.
>> Uh we're from the Edmonton Group
>> up in Canada.
>> Oh. Uhhuh.
>> And we got a gift for you.
We went down to a park two blocks away
from my friend Pat's place.
>> It says Hawkins Park.
And it's got Edmonton on it.
>> Wonderful.
>> That's hysterical.
>> There's a guy by the name of Ken holding
a cat and I got a coffee. So,
>> oh, that's just need cigarettes in there
and I think it'll be all good.
>> Thank you.
>> And uh I also recently started an
electrical company and I named it power
or integrity power. I was inspired by
you
>> and it seems to be going very well. So,
all the doors are opening wide. Oh,
that's wonderful.
>> What kind of a company?
>> Electrical. Like uh doing electrical
work.
>> Electrical.
>> Oh, yes. Running wire.
>> Oh, yes.
>> Yes. I like electrical work.
>> It's shocking, isn't it?
>> Yes. Lots of
>> As long as you're well grounded, you're
right.
>> Would it be okay if we took a picture
with you?
>> Okay. Take it home.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Oh, thank you for that. This is lovely.
>> Can I have that
>> so I don't blend it? Oh, thank
>> sorry we didn't have
>> That's all right.
>> Do we have his name?
>> Thank you so much.
>> Mhm.
>> Okie do.
>> God bless you.
Thank you for coming all this way.
>> Everything is fine.
>> Wonderful.
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Hello. Hello, Mrs. Hawkins.
>> Hi.
>> It's good to be here again. My question
is if a person or a guru calibrates
really high on the map and then falls
down below 200 and then in the next
lifetime is reincarnated still below
200.
Is it possible that even though they're
non-integrous
that their spiritual will will still
have them choose God and plow back up
through the levels of consciousness
because they've been there before and
they know how to do it?
>> Where is he asking?
>> I'm sorry. I was reading this.
>> Okay.
>> Is it possible that if somebody
calibrates really high and then in the
same lifetime falls down below 200
>> Yeah. and then is reincarnated in the
next lifetime below 200.
>> Yeah.
>> Even though they're below 200, can they
still will the spiritual will still have
them choose God? And
>> I don't know. That's a hypothetical
proposition you're putting forth.
>> It's a hypothetical question.
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> So, we have trouble answering
hypothetical questions like that. Has to
do with karma. It has to do with past
lives. So,
>> you know, it's kind of a hypothetical.
>> Okay. creating a whole story that hasn't
even taken place.
>> Right. I understand.
>> Yeah. If you have a question that we can
answer.
>> No, that was all I all I had.
>> Well, is there anything you'd like to
ask? Doctor,
>> if you could if you crash, if you have
enough good karma, you can earn the
right to come back and undo it. Yes.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay.
>> May I shake your hand?
>> Yes.
>> Thank you.
Yeah, you can earn earned right.
>> I have to announce there is no smoking
on this campus.
So, um they won't let us come back if if
you smoke on campus. Uh so, there's no
smoking on the school campus.
>> Hi, Susan.
>> Hi.
>> Hi, doctor.
>> Yes.
I have uh one question. I'm wondering uh
you've said that uh kitten's purr cal
calibrates at 500.
>> Uh when a kitten jumps up onto your knee
and uses her paws.
>> For the patt
on your knee, what does that calibrate?
>> I'm wondering what it calibrates at.
>> What?
>> The the way they massage your lap.
>> Yeah. cake.
>> P of cake.
>> Yeah. In in in English England, it's the
massage.
>> Do you do you know what that
calibration?
>> No.
>> Do you want to calibrate it?
>> May I
>> just be happy with the pur?
>> I like the pur. It's nice.
>> What is this question? I don't get it.
He wanted to know what when a cat patty
cakes on you, you know.
>> When a cat goes like so. Yes.
>> On you. What does that
>> He's contented and happy.
>> All right.
>> He's contented and happy. You watch the
nursing kitten. The nursing kitten is
going like this.
>> So it goes back to that primordial state
of bliss of happiness and contentment
with the mother. Yeah.
>> Thank you. And thank you for all your
work.
>> Yes.
God bless all the kitties.
>> Could I shake the hand, please?
>> Yeah, sure.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah. God bless all the cute little
kitties. Yeah.
>> Thank you,
>> Kitties. Purr purr purr purr purr purr
purr.
>> Hi.
>> Hello.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. My question is
when I meditate
uh not all the time but
every now and then I will see flashes of
light.
Would you happen to know what that means
or is
>> he sees flashes of light when he
meditates? Let's know what that's all
about.
>> What is it when you see flashes of
light?
>> Normal.
Do you see little like little tiny
sparkles of light or is it like flashes?
>> I focus on that and then I see flashes.
>> Okay.
>> Huh?
>> He sees like whole flashes of light.
>> Yeah, that's common. Yeah. Mhm.
Those are the rockets going off in your
head.
Means you're a child of God. Yes.
>> No, those are those visual things are
very interesting.
>> Mhm.
>> And they tend to occur at certain depths
of meditation.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> Certain depths of meditation. Yes.
>> Also, how would one transcend the belief
that smoking is bad?
>> Also, what
>> what
>> how would you transcend the belief that
smoking is bad? How do you transcend the
belief that smoking is bad?
>> I don't know where you'd have it.
Basically, you become you've been
programmed by it.
>> Yeah. You could have been programmed.
>> Yeah.
>> It's a heavy duty program in today's
world.
>> Mhm.
>> They demonize it. Demonize it. You know,
the generation I grew up, everybody
smoked all the time everywhere. Mhm.
>> on the front cover of Life magazine or
the movies.
TV commentators smoked while and then
the guests smoked.
And if you're invited to speak someplace
on the speaking stand there was an
ashtray. Everybody smoked all the time
everywhere. It was a Victorian society.
In a Victorian society, everybody smoked
except the bad guys.
Adolf Hitler did not smoke.
Emperor Hiro did not smoke.
But FDR smoked. Winston Churchill
smoked. Eisenhower smoked. All the good
guys smoked.
>> Thank you.
>> Only the bad guys did not smoke.
If you want to be like Mussolini or
Adolf Hitler, they did not smoke.
I will continue to enjoy my cigarettes.
>> In today's world, they would be hit,
you know. Adolf Hitler, well, he can't
be too bad. He doesn't smoke, you know.
Yeah. Society tends to promote and
glamorize certain things at one time and
at another, you know.
>> That thing is in, smoking pot is in or
smoking pot is out. You know, drinking
is in, drinking is out.
It's, you know, it's a passing fashion.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. Thank you. I will continue to
enjoy my cigarettes.
>> May I shake your hand?
>> You must shake your hand.
>> Yeah, sure.
>> Yeah.
What was it where camels were good for
your T-zone?
showed the doctor with a pack of camels
says camels are good for your T-zone,
your throat.
Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> Hi.
Okay. My question is um
what do we need to do to make sure that
we reach the level of 500 on this
lifetime you know
or to be able to jump a little bit
>> on this lifetime
>> she really in this lifetime she would
like to reach the level of 500. Can you
give her some tips that would let her,
you know, that she
>> Well, hang out with loving people. Join
loving groups. Find out what love really
means. Steady love. Yes.
Pray for love.
Do you love animals?
>> Yeah.
>> Start there.
Do you love your kitty more than people?
Your doggy?
Huh? More than people.
>> More than people.
>> Yes.
>> I mean, what
>> you want to know? Do Do you love a cat
or a dog more than you do people?
>> It's easier to love a dog or a cat.
People are hard to love.
>> Anyway, it gives you what
>> it gives you what love is a concern for
the happiness of the other. Concern for
the welfare and happiness of others is
what love is. Yes. And you can transfer
that from animals to people.
>> All right. Okay. Thank you.
>> Can I take a picture?
>> Yes. I was trying to figure out where
you were taking that because
>> I didn't know what you really meant by
that.
>> It's a trick question.
Chocolate ice cream. Start with that.
>> My weakness.
>> That's your way to love, isn't it?
Chocolate ice cream.
>> Yes.
>> Couple licks of that and boy oh boy,
you're on your way to heaven.
>> We're talking about love.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Chocolate ice cream.
>> Pathway of the stomach. Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
Hi, Susan.
>> Hi.
>> I was wondering uh what the best way to
deal with non-integrous family members
is. I I find it a lot harder to let go
of that than like non- integrous music.
>> I don't hear. What do you say?
>> Uh non-integorous family members.
>> What about them?
>> You can pick your friends. You can pick
your friends. You can't pick your
relatives. So, take it from there.
Realize that you can pick your friends,
but you can't pick your relatives.
tell if they're bad relatives, stay away
from them.
>> Yep.
>> Just, you know, isolate your time with
them
>> so that because it's not it doesn't make
anybody happy.
>> Yeah.
>> So, just, you know, minimize your time
with them. Be cordial with their family,
but
>> we're all we all have our we all have to
have our own uh tolerances.
>> Yeah. you know, so
>> I'm trying to find the best way without
causing them suffering.
>> Just be who you are, but just don't
spend too much time with it.
>> If you know, if they're hurtful, some
families are hurtful. Oh, yes. So,
>> okay.
>> If a dog bites you, stay away from it.
>> You don't have to go to college for
that.
Okay. Um,
I want to know why I'm afraid of being
great.
>> She wants to know why.
>> She's af She's afraid of being great.
Great at what?
>> Like being great, like like being like
high on the map. I'm afraid to like move
forward. I'm afraid to be what I am,
which is great.
Why am I afraid of my own greatness, my
own capability, my own what I could do?
>> She wants to go forward on the map, but
there's something holding her back.
She's kind of afraid of of going.
>> Yeah.
>> Of on the map.
>> Going from what to what? What do you
mean by higher?
>> Going from the level that I'm on now to
500 to love.
>> What? Well, what level are you at now?
>> I don't know.
>> Huh? I don't know.
>> That's a nonsensical question.
>> Why?
>> You're going to start from nowhere and
go nowhere. What are you What do you
say?
>> Should probably Well, um, let me see.
>> Good good will. Goodwill towards all of
life. That is a good starting place.
Solid good will towards all of life in
all of its expressions. Yes.
And lovingness as an attitude towards
your fellow human beings. Yes.
You can't go much higher than that.
Yeah.
Lovingness towards all that exists in
all your fellow human beings even though
you may disagree with them.
Is loving this
is it always
is it is it more rough like tough love
sometimes you know like
creating a boundary between yourself and
someone like you said don't spend too
much time with your family members who
are rude to you.
That's part of it.
It's not necessarily hugging everybody
and saying, "Oh, you're so lovely and I
like your shirt." And
>> what is she asking? What is she asking?
I don't want the recitation.
>> I don't I'm not really sure.
>> All right.
Sorry. No, that's all right. I was busy
doing something, so I wasn't paying
attention. Um Okay. Um,
she wants to know how basically that you
would show do how do you go about
showing that love for someone? How do
you go about
>> I can't explain it to you.
>> It's automatic. When you love somebody,
it's automatic.
>> There isn't kind any kind of a thing you
can memorize what to do.
>> So,
>> if you love a puppy, you love the puppy.
If it cries, you you feed it. You love
it. I don't explain what she means. Were
you never on planet Earth as a human?
>> What is your question?
>> Well, she wants to know how do you show
love? I mean, how do you
>> Don't you go to the movies?
>> Don't you have relatives? Don't you have
friends? You go to school?
>> I don't go to school.
>> Huh?
>> I have friends. I have family.
>> She has friends and family. Yes.
>> Yes. So, you know what it's like? Yes.
Uhhuh.
>> And that's all things.
So what is the question please?
>> I should have thought about this more.
Um
>> there we go.
>> So So anyway, she what it is is
basically do does she uh as far as it
goes is showing someone they that you
care about them?
>> Yes.
>> Through actions. Is it actions? Actions?
>> Yeah. All of that.
>> All of that. Right.
>> And that's every even the people who
scare you,
>> right? And
>> yeah,
>> you can if the people scare you, you can
say a prayer for them.
>> Yeah.
>> That does not hurt anything.
>> That would be a way of showing respect
for that person.
>> Even if you walk away from them
>> because they scare you and you don't
want to be around them, you walk away
from them,
>> right? You can still pray for them that
they still pray or that you know they do
not hurt you again.
>> So it's not necessarily hugging them and
kissing them
>> and being their best friend.
>> Not physical.
>> No,
>> it's say a prayer. Hold them in mind.
Goodwill.
>> Goodwill.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> I I like I worry that I'm too harsh with
people. like I can be very like get away
from me and I'm like that is that is
that very loving but if you say a prayer
>> yeah you can say a prayer saying
>> life is not just black and white it's
various shades of gray
>> life is various shades of gray very
seldom is it just black or just white
okay it subtly moves from one little
thing to another like the breeze through
the leaves and the woods
>> we shake your
Yes,
>> it's cheesy now.
>> Yes, indeed.
>> Next time I'll have a better question.
>> Thank you.
>> It was a good question.
>> Hello.
>> Hello. I don't have a question. I just
wanted to thank you for your work and
your teachings. It's been very helpful
to me in my life.
And I just wanted to know if I could
receive your blessing and shake your
hand.
>> Yes. God bless you.
>> Thank you.
>> I'm glad it's useful to you.
>> Essentially, I'm a pragmatist.
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. I just wanted to
thank you for your teachings and
everything you've done for my life and
ask if I could shake your hand and have
your blessing.
Thank you.
>> She wants to know if I can walk and chew
going at the same time. Is that what you
said?
>> That's it.
I can walk and chew gum at the same
time. Yes.
By divine dispensation.
>> Yeah, she's cute.
>> Yeah.
Hi, this is my son and we wanted to come
and say thank you to you and I made you
a present. Thank
>> you.
Did she get your name and everything?
>> Um,
>> Andrea. Andrea. Andrea. Did you get
this?
>> I need to I'm trying to keep track of
who gets us what and so that we can say
thank you.
>> Well, we just wanted to say thank you
and how much we enjoy studying your work
>> and
>> I can't hear what they're saying.
>> She just want to say thank you.
>> Oh, yes.
>> You've changed so many people's lives
and everybody is so grateful to you.
>> Oh, hopefully. Good. Good. Thank you.
>> And we wanted to have a picture taken
with you. That's okay.
>> They want a picture.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you.
Oh, thank you. Thank you so much. Thank
you for the
>> Here. He wants to shake your hand.
>> Yes.
>> Oh, thank you.
>> Yep.
How much did you pay to go to the
pyramid? I will pay to tell us.
>> Oh, how much did you How much did you
pay to go to see the pyramids?
>> You said $10 you
>> No, there's no fee
>> to tell us to tell us.
>> Nobody's allowed to go in there. They
have guards.
>> Oh, he wants to know about the
experience that you when you were
meditating in the
>> Yes.
>> What was the experience that
>> I cannot describe it.
It was transcendental.
It was transcendental
beyond description.
To be alone all night in one of the
great pyramids cannot be described.
Has to be experienced. Yeah.
>> Thank you very much.
I had the whole pyramid to myself. Isn't
that something?
>> So, so did you go into a high state when
you're in the pyramid?
>> Oh, God. Yes.
>> Was it like, you know, some of the
states that I have seen you in or is it
just
>> I can say it was transcendental that you
you you've lost all reference points.
It's pitch dark. There is no sound.
There is no direction
between you and the sky. There's a 400
ft of of stone.
It's silent beyond all capacity for
silence.
And there were other entities that came
to visit.
You can imagine the pyramid attracts
tremendous amount of spiritual interest
from huge numbers of people for many
decades. Yes.
Yeah.
So it would be like a spirit
whose job it is to come to people who
meditate
to come to you for like reassurance that
Your
intention
is known by your trip from around the
world to just be here
alone with God all night long in the
complete total silence.
It's a
very different kind of experience than
you can really
explain.
Sometimes being in one of the great
cathedrals that we've been in, the whole
cathedral is completely deserted.
There's not a single person. They got a
whole cathedral all to oursel. Remember
that's happened to us several times.
It's hard to describe.
A giant silent cathedral and you're the
only ones there.
There's just you and the cathedral and
the stained glass window cannot be
described. It's experiential and
transcendent. Transcendent is about the
only term I can think of.
Yeah.
>> Like when you walk the uh what the m you
walk the labyrinth, you know. Uhhuh.
You walk the labyrinth. It's an inner
experience. It cannot be described.
>> That's great. Thank you so much.
Um, my question is, would it be helpful
to cancel the belief system that it's
more difficult for a female body to
reach to survive the higher levels of
consciousness than a male body?
>> Hey, we survived birth.
>> Take it from there.
>> What is the question? Is it? She wants
to She said, "Would it be good to cancel
the belief system that it's easier for a
male body to reach enlightenment than a
female?"
>> Who who holds that belief system?
>> I've heard you say that the reason that
there's less women at the higher levels
of consciousness on your charts is
because the female body can't.
>> It could it could be. Yeah. The the
female physiology.
Yeah.
It's easier for the male body to handle
the stress of a high level consciousness
resist.
>> Oh okay.
>> Yeah fact.
>> Is there any limitation involved in the
belief of that?
>> What
>> is there any limitation involved in
>> it's just a fact you know just a fact.
If you plan to get enlightened this
lifetime.
>> Yeah.
>> I plan to realize my fullest potential.
>> Yeah. Good. That's all you want to do?
>> Good question.
That's all you want to do.
>> May I shake your hand, please?
>> Come complete your highest complete
>> and then you reach certain stage and you
drop dead and then you get reborn.
Who knows what it's all about. I don't
know.
>> Um Dave says it's like electrical,
you know, like you're being electrified,
you know, within your skin when you hit
certain levels. And so it's, you know,
it's not pleasant.
>> Yeah.
>> All right.
It would take separate study about that.
You know, it's something I ran across
over the years, but I never set out a
study plan about it. Hi. We're going to
do a little bit something different. Um,
I want all of our staff members, if they
would come up on stage, we want to give
them a hand uh for this year of helping
us with all the lectures. And um if all
of you could come upstairs, we have
about 20 people that help put on these
lectures, including people that handle
the parking and all of them. And so I'm
going to go down the line here and ask
for them to give us their names. And um
if you could uh and maybe you all could
tell what you do for Veritas.
>> This is Gabriel.
>> Gabriel, I do production.
>> My god, who are all these people?
My name is Ethel. I do that some
strangely familiar.
>> I'm Andrea. I work in the office.
>> Laura, I work in the office. Donna, I
work in the bookstore and production.
Darlene greeter.
>> Jeremy in the bookstore.
>> Julie production. Vicki bookstore and
production.
>> Anna bookstore. Lynn bookstore
>> Jack bookstore.
Gizel office and registration.
>> Don Bookto
>> and he's our healer by the way. He um
does work on everybody.
>> Don guard at the door.
>> I'm transporter.
>> I'm Janice. I run the PowerPoint.
>> I'm Wally. I work in the bookstore.
>> I'm Lonnie and I stand at the door.
I'm Damut and I do what needs to be
done. I'm George. I work up here.
>> I'm Cynthia. I work back there.
>> I'm Jonathan. I help with the parking.
>> I'm Mike. I get stuck with the parking,
too.
>> I'm Gwen. I do parking.
>> And I'm Steve. Wherever needed.
>> And there's others that are in the
bookstore that aren't even here. So, Oh,
wait.
>> I'm I'm Scott. I work in production and
parking.
>> That's right. And parking.
>> And parking.
>> Allison mostly bookstore.
>> Kathy bookstore and walk-ins.
>> Josh production.
>> And then there's a couple more that are
in bookstore that aren't out here.
>> Lisa,
there's Lisa and John that um are their
trail head. They do all of our
production
up here. Lisa, where's John? Back there
somewhere.
Fran
photographer Fran.
Now, some of these people have full-time
jobs and then come out and help us out
in so many ways. I can't tell you. So,
we're so appreciative that we have a
staff that takes such good care of us.
And if all of you could give them a big
hand, we would appreciate it.
My god, aren't they? It's hard to
believe. Yeah.
Wow.
That's fantastic.
Good golly. There's many that many
people. Oh,
>> okay. You want to come
>> Who you got now? Are you going to come
up here and say goodbye? And
>> we're going to let the staff st stay up
here if you would because you need to
feel this energy that comes off this
this uh
>> audience here.
>> Here I am all by myself out in the
middle of the stage.
>> All right.
>> What do you want me to do?
Say hello. Smile. Well, we could do we
could do the music.
>> You know, you could say a few words and
we'll do some music.
>> It's the end, honey.
>> Oh. Oh. Oh.
>> Where's the music?
>> I don't There it is.
>> Oh,
>> thank you.
God wrote that song.
It represent an aspect of God
that cannot be verbalized
beyond intellectual.
coming off the coast, the Pacific coast
in California one time. I looked up
above and here were these giant these
huge birds
and the wind was coming off the ocean
and the way the birds maintained themsel
there. They did not flap their wings.
These giant birds were just angled
himself against the wind like so and
like so and like so like so. The bird
just made the most minute movements
and instead it took advantage of the
power of the wind.
So with practically no expenditure of
energy, the birds stayed up there for
like half an hour, an hour at a time.
All they did was move their little
bodies a slight half an inch this way
and this wing would go up half an inch
this way.
So that's the way it is
>> to be
>> with God,
>> your angle
>> yourself
so that the energy of divinity
flows through you
and by the angle of your heart.
It uplifts you and sustains you
>> through a whole lifetime.
The winds of God sustain us.
We thank thee oh Lord
for this life
for the beauty
of this life.
We're the real power of beauty
is nonverbal.
The minute you hear this particular
music, you're instantly in a different
dimension.
What it expresses is grace.
The grace of God
>> part of God's grace
>> is the awareness of beauty.
Those who do not walk in God's grace
are oblivious to beauty,
oblivious to kindness.
So it's love at the highest level.
It has a name. Love
agape. Is that so?
Transcends personal love. I guess
see you cannot reach God
by bypassing love.
The bird cannot get all the way up to a
higher elevation without going through
these various layers.
So we position ourself in a loving way.
We say thank you God
for all the blessings of this life
for the chance to experience each other
at a meeting like this.
Millions and millions of people live and
die and never have a single experience
like the people in this room are having
right now.
Millions live and die, bereft of any
spiritual
experience or awareness or opportunity
because it takes many lifetimes to earn
it.
Yeah, let's ask.
Takes many lifetimes to earn
to be here. Is this Wow.
So
we thank our own past selves.
Well, you get fragments of it.
You see that there were moments of great
contrition for having made mistakes
and then bring to God in a very intense
earnestness.
Out of which God responded by allowing
us to come into this lifetime
to fulfill that desire.
So we thank you oh Lord for the gift of
all these people present
all aligned with reaching God and
divinity
relying upon the love of God.
The bag pipes have a certain energy
that's specific.
And this particular music
has an energy that is specific to this
style of beauty.
One's not better than the other.
They're just different aspects.
So we thank you Lord
for the blessing of this group of people
here assembled
and we pray for those who are missing
today
because of illness.
Amen.
>> And his joy indeed.
>> That's all I can handle. My nose.
Okay, thank you.
>> Here. Here.
Thank you.
Deathlle.
Hallelu
Hallelujah.
Halleluah.
Hallelu.
Hallel.
Hallelu
Hallelujah.