Hello. Um, I had the wrong announcements
on the table this morning.
So, the rest of the announcements are
um we must leave promptly at five
o'clock. So, um there's another event
here at 7 tonight. Little Women, they're
putting on the play Little Women. Um and
so, uh we will have to leave promptly by
5:00. Uh make sure that you clean up
around your seats if you can because
there is another event and if we can
help them by cleaning up that would help
tremendously. Um, there are pre-orders
for today's lecture in the bookstore.
So, if you'd like to fill one out, we
will definitely mail you one as soon as
they come out. And, um, the schedule for
2010 is also at the bookstore. So, if
you want to pick those up. And, um, let
me see. I think that's it.
>> Good.
>> Okay.
Okay. In the um b birth process, I
forgot to mention
uh I I was born addicted to nicotine.
That's a fact.
I was born addicted to nicotine
because
when I was a
wouldbe infant
uh women everybody smoked and uh
president smoked every everybody smoked.
It was uh uh the result of a certain uh
era in
American development
and everybody smoked in that age and so
my mother smoked too. She was a flapper
and she was modern and she smoked. So
the women didn't think anything of that
because smoke only goes down to here and
the baby's down here. So what's the
problem?
So when I was born, the first thing I
wanted was anybody got a smoke.
Okay,
that's a fact. Resist. That's a fact.
You can be born addicted to nicotine
before you have your first smoke. So as
soon I was born, there was all these
loud noises and bright lights and I
needed a smoke.
So these make up the vicissitudes of
life. You see in in those days everybody
smoked and my my family were all
Victorians.
My grandparents were all Victorians. In
the Victorian era, everybody smoked all
the time, everywhere, except my two
grandmothers. Old grandmothers could get
away with not smoking.
But I had one grandmother who was more
modern, and she said, "I'll have a
cigarette with you to be sociable."
And they all lived to be 95 or so, so I
guess cigarettes weren't all that bad in
those days.
All right. So, where were we now?
Uh what's slide? Okay.
Uh all right. So all of these things
could make a lecture. Any one of these
things that we talk about
uh obviously your vocation and your
courtship.
Uh the quality of marriage, the quality
of marriage. If you see yourself as
partners, if you see yourself as
mutually beneficial,
you're committed to the partnership. And
uh if you're lucky, you find a good wife
and uh a good husband. And if you're not
so lucky, your life is hell,
murder, and suicide. Other than that,
we looked at all the factors that
influence success.
Um,
belief in yourself, to believe in
yourself.
Uh, it's important to believe in
yourself. No matter where you are in
life,
want you to have a positive attitude
towards that.
Let's say you've done everything wrong
and you're in jail and you're being sued
by everybody and everybody's left you.
You're a great success
cuz you have now learned what does not
work in this world.
However, there are some people
congenally unable to learn what does not
work in this world.
We have a friend of ours who who
examines people that are chronically in
and out of prison in the in the in the
prognosis and uh there are people that
just never get it congenatively
just don't have the capacity or the
interest or
uh unable to learn from experience.
So we're happy that if we have a bad
experience, at least the average person
learns that we don't want to go that
way.
We're the average person learns. That
way does not work. But there are some
people that are inherently incapable of
learning from experience.
What did we say? They were 6% of the
population at one time. Let's see if
that's still correct. There are people
unable to learn from experience and it
comprise about 6% of the population 7%
6%
6% of the population is unable
congenitally
uh
unable to learn from experience.
And you see the receivist criminal does
this. He lands in jail. He goes out and
the first thing he does is what put him
just in jail before.
We used to have sexual offenders
uh that went after children and the
minute they let them out, what's the
first thing they did? They went to the
park and began to sexually molest
children. In less than five minutes
letting them out, they're already in the
park soliciting some child. And you say,
"Didn't they learn anything from
experience?" And the answer was no.
They apparently lack the capacity.
So instead of condemning them, we should
be compassionate but also take proper
protection. This person is nice as they
can be and they can be quite amiable and
pleasant. Uh is unable to learn from
experience. So all we can do is use bars
or whatever to prevent them uh from
molesting children in the park.
the adverse events and success, family,
world conditions,
uh, world conditions, uh, affect us more
than we think. We say, well, that's on
the other side of the world. But don't
forget the human consciousness is
collective. There's a collective human
consciousness. So when you see something
on the other side of the world without
your being aware of it, it's affecting
you. Okay? Uh, that's a fact. Resist.
That's a fact. The things that you think
have nothing to do with you, that's on
the other side of the world. Different
country, different culture. That's got
no effect on me. It affects the
collective consciousness of mankind to
which you are connected. Okay? Everyone
is connected to the collective
consciousness of mankind. Therefore,
everyone is influenced by world events
whether they know it or not. resist.
That's a good thing to know. You say,
"Well, that's got nothing to do with
me." That's those nut jobs on the other
side of the world.
It does affect you. It affects your
sense of inner security, uh your trust
to your fellow human beings and your
overall worldview. Uh whether it's of
the pessimistic or optimistic,
uh mankind evolves slowly and often by
leaps and jumps. Nothing will happen for
a couple hundred years and suddenly you
see an enormous jump.
All right. World conditions then our
health affects our uh our mental
condition and our mental condition
affects our health. The poorer our
mental condition the more likelihood is
that we'll have health problems. Uh on
the other hand, a lot of illnesses seem
to be uh genetic and uh we recently did
a published a book called um health and
healing. Was that it? Health and
healing. Is that the name of it?
>> Healing and recovery.
>> Huh?
>> What's the name of it?
>> Our book.
>> The one on health and healing. Is that
what's the name of the book?
>> Healing and recovery.
who recently published a book which is a
very good one
called healing and recovery.
Uh I in I include a lot of personal
experiences in there myself
and uh learned a lot of things about the
health system in general specific health
problems in particular and certain
doctors etc.
I would always use the arm on any doctor
you're seeing. You see, and uh doctors
seem to have lost a certain sense of
caringness that was endemic in the
profession. When I went through medical
school and of course I went to a Jesuit
university and um caringness about the
patient uh was extremely important. And
when I had a very big clinic, we found
that
uh the doctors, we had a lot of doctors
on the staff and certain doctors had
very high recovery rates and other
doctors had very low recovery rates. And
we discovered that the doctors who had
high recovery rates uh cared about their
patients. They cared about them. Doesn't
mean they have a positive counter
transference. It just means that as
human beings they care. They care
whether you get well. They care whether
you are happy. They care whether you've
stopped suffering. So to have a caring
doctor is extremely important. So you
could use your arm, use the arm and
check out your doctor.
He's a caring doctor and therefore a
good doctor to see.
Some people some people had huge uh uh
practices and did extraordinarily well.
And other people had a little small
practices and did orally. And it was the
whole difference was caring.
Caring. when you care. So, the same
thing applies to uh all of your life. To
care about your neighbors, to care about
your pets, to care about how your lawn
looks, to care about yourself, that you
look halfway decent when you go out,
that you're not too ugly and don't scare
people.
There's a point at which you should get
a face job. You know, I mean, just
kindness for your fellow human beings.
to care about life because the essence
of life uh the essence of all life is
divinity.
All of life is the expression of
All of life is an expression of
divinity. Resist all of life is God.
Resist.
All of life is God. So you're caring
this about your garden. You're caring
this about your kidneys. You're carrying
this about the dogs. Right now the
hummingbirds are back. I hope you have
hummingbird food up. I hear them out
there. They go
little hummingbirds. They're so cute.
Don't shoot the hummingbirds. No.
I'm sure there's hummingbird killers out
there someplace.
Anything that lives, you'll find
somebody that wants to stalk them and
shoot them.
Yeah.
I've never been a I've never been much
on hunting.
And uh my father wasn't big on hunting
either. He got taken to go hunting
because all men in Wisconsin in the fall
went hunting.
So to be a good guy, he went along with
the hunting and he finally got a deer in
the sights and he got and he started to
shake. He looked at the deer and it's
life energy
almost knocked them out and he realized
that he could not pull the trigger. So
he never went deer hunting again.
A
deer fever. You look down the telescopic
sites and you see this incredible,
incredible creature.
And we have a little place where we go
in the summertime. And these incredible
creatures with their little funny ears
sit out there and the idea of killing
Bambi is just not even conceivable.
How can you kill Bambi? Right.
How can you kill Bambi?
All right. That's how your world
conditions affect us. Our wealth, our
health, our financial comfort zone.
Comfort zone is simple. Just to spend
less than what you make. That's simple.
Simple concept.
Nobody lives by it. That's how we have
charge cards, right? So today, what you
figure is how much you can afford to pay
a month on your charge card. And that
decides on your level of living. Aging
of course you're going to go through all
different phenomena. Aging has a
profound effect. Uh the 80s certainly
are not the 60s and certainly not the
40s and certainly not the 30s. So we
take into account and many things I say
to myself. Well, it's because of how
long I've lived that I see it that way.
Okay, it's not really political. It's
not really intellectual. It's just that
I belong to a different age group.
My age group lived through certain
things that people in different age
groups did not live through
because I didn't live through it. Their
understanding of it is different than
mine.
Uh our philosophical position
uh some people are intellectuals and
calibrate in the 400s and they eat up
philosophy and they love to read books.
I used to read 500 books a year, 500
books a year for decades. And I made
notes on each book and kept them all on
file. Uh 500 books a year. So how many
books a year do you read? Depends on how
much time you've got and how much
intellectual curiosity.
But I found philosophic works of the
great books of the western world for
instance. I I forgot the name of the
university. It's out west of California
that the whole curriculum is the what's
the name of it?
Thomas
>> St. John
>> Thomas Aquinas
>> John
>> St. John that's right St. John, uh, the
whole curriculum is the great books of
the Western world. That's really quite
profound, isn't it? Quite profound that
they make a whole curriculum of it. That
would be a great place to go or send
somebody. And uh, I'd like to go again.
I don't have enough time.
I'm sure if I went back to the
university now, I'd just be fascinated.
All the stuff I missed the first time
through, the stuff I've forgotten, I
say, "Oh my god, I forgot that Deart
said that." Whatever.
All right.
Introvert versus extrovert. Did we find
our comfort zone to be within ourself or
only when we're other with other people?
Uh be to be an ambbervert would be
perfect. It's okay if you're alone all
by yourself and it's okay if you're
surrounded by people. Your physical
appearance of course has an effect on
people both consciously and
unconsciously.
If you're just badl looking, you got to
learn to live with it.
If you're irresistible, you got to fight
off the women. They're all after your
little body.
I think that's hysterically funny. Okay,
the next one.
Oh, what's the next slide?
Is there anything uh we need to go back
to? Well, we'll have a question and
answer later, but if anybody has a
really pressing question that they want
to ask, uh, it's okay with me if you
hold up your hand and holler.
It's okay with me if you ask a question.
Uhhuh.
So, the each level of consciousness, as
you can see from what we said this
morning, has its own level of reality.
Reality is therefore a subjective mental
presumption
and it's both linear and nonlinear
and reality is one thing. Truth is what
you say about it.
Therefore you finally after many years
of meditation and study you come up with
the question
is is what I consider to be myself or me
or I real?
It's experiential, but is it a reality
or is it the product of mentalization?
Is there a a real eye? And if what is
the eye?
Because we change your education, you're
still me. You take off one leg, you're
still me.
Everybody leaves, you're all by
yourself, you're still me. No matter
what happens, you seem to be stuck with
something that you call I.
What is this that you call I?
Is it an independent entity? How does it
arise?
So in the end when looking for
enlightenment,
you begin to examine what is it that I
consider to be myself, my reality.
What hap what is I? Is reality a
subjective mental presumption?
Uh is it real or not real?
Is reality a truth? Is it the me that's
real? Who or what is the I?
You could say, well, I is the
experiencer.
Therefore, I think the most common one
is I am the experiencer.
At different levels, people will say,
well, I am the that which makes
decisions. I am that which remembers. I
am that which imagines things. I am that
which is happy or not happy.
So the sense of eye then becomes vague
and diffuse and can cover almost
anything
with u meditation. One of the greatest
benefits of meditation is that which you
choose to call I becomes progressively
more clear and then finally dissolves
altogether
and there the only reality that that
remains is the existence of divinity.
So I as the experiencer, I'm the
experiencer of my experiencer.
I you can define as the one who makes
decisions. That's what we put in jail is
the eye that made a bad decision.
Uh we say I is the source of our
willpower.
We say that I is a certain social
personhood. What the world calls I is
what they perceive. Another person would
say well what is I depends on how I feel
feel and uh my thoughts.
So you can see your sense of I who you
are your sense of reality your
identification is constantly changing
and shifting. You're so used to it
changing and shifting you don't even
notice it. One instant eye is what
you're feeling. The next instant eye is
what you're thinking. The next instant
eye is what it's imagining about the
future. The next instant eye is hanging
out redoing the past. So why did I do
that? Uh
so the sense of I is constantly shifting
is diffuse and not really dependable.
When you say I, what are you talking
about? Uh what are you talking about? I
as a social personhood, I as a taxpayer.
I as an American.
Okay. I as is feelings or thoughts.
Then finally you you get more
sophisticated and you say well I is
either all of them or none of them.
Therefore the self is a blank screen
upon which all the above can be
reflected.
You know whatever is on the TV set today
that's what you are as your feelings and
your thoughts today.
So the self becomes then the screen not
the program on the TV set but the TV set
itself capable of any program.
So the self is therefore
not just the content of what's going on
with you but it's the whole context the
whole phenomena within which the
subjective
uh appears and and returns.
rest internal versus rest external.
Decart said there's this inner self, the
inner reality as you see it and then
there's the external reality the way it
is.
That's internal is your personal view of
the world. I see the world thusly. I
believe thusly.
And then there's the world the way it is
which has nothing to do with you.
Nothing to do with you.
So when we use the arm to find out a
fact about something, we're trying to
transcend
rest internally
and discover what is ex rest external.
What is the reality of the world itself?
I know what I think about a certain
politician. I know how I feel about that
politician. How much of that is real? So
then we ask the arm. We say so and so
calibrates over 200 or not over 200 and
we get then an objective read. So the
purpose of calibrating things is it
gives you a way of checking on your own
sense of reality and whether you're
being deceived or not deceived.
What happened to the wolf in sheep's
clothing? What was that one?
What was it? What was that slide?
So the self knows
and the mind thinks
that which is the self
is an automatic knowingness
about which you don't think. The mind is
separate from the from that. The mind
thinks about things and the self just
knows them. I know there's a more to
this
to put my feet on
without thinking about it.
I just know it's there because the self
remembers all the things having to do
with your security and in the back of
your mind warns you when you're getting
too close to the edge of the stage. Yes.
Okay.
We have to know the difference between
essence and appearance.
Uh essence and appearance.
What happened to our um what happened to
our wolf and sheep clothing? What what
numbers what number slide is that?
>> There we are.
All right. So, the difference to know
the difference between
essence
here's the essence here
and the sheep's clothing is the
appearance.
That's very helpful in understanding the
political world. If you don't understand
that, you can't understand why the the
phenomena that are happening are
happening because inside of that sheep
was actually the wolf paying them off.
If you want to get your way with them,
figure out how do you pay them off
apparently. Okay. I I got a kick out of
the the news the last couple days. These
guys are supposed to be watching Bernie.
What's his name? And they're all
watching pornography on their computers.
I think it was hysterically funny.
The taxpayers are paying these guys to
watch the investment and they're busy
watching pornography on their computers.
That's hysterically funny. Isn't that
funny?
Okay, we'll move on then.
I think it's hysterically funny.
Collapse of the banking system and the
investment firms, etc. because they're
all busy watching pornography. It's
hysterical.
It's like they don't get enough. You
know what?
Okay.
Alice in Wonderland. We talk about
opinion,
the virtual reality of the media,
watching the media. So, we're sub
subject to something that people weren't
really subject to that intensely when I
grew up.
I mean, there was the daily newspaper
and there was the radio, but you weren't
bombarded with visual images. What
happens with visual images is that you
get programmed without realizing you've
already been programmed. You think it's
just a picture, but that picture has
said the whole thing, come to a
conclusion, and already laid claim to
your vote. This picture is going to get
you to vote for him. every in today's
world everybody there's protesters
everywhere. If you're not a protester
apparently you're nobody. You got to
find something to protest about and then
you can get out with the field and where
you can get arrested and punched.
You got to get out there and protest.
Uh otherwise you can't get punched in
the face and abused by the police and
etc.
Uh, so you get to be a hero by going out
there and express yourself. The old
American way is to express yourself. I
have no idea why everybody wants to
express themsel.
Frankly, I'm not interested in any of
their opinions.
There are 10,000 people out there
demonstrating and protesting,
and I have the slightest interest in
what any of them think.
Why should I care what they think?
What they think is going to be gone
tomorrow. They'll be thinking about
something else. Because they love
protest demonstrations.
People love protest demonstrations. We
think they're all heroes out there. We
think all these protesters are out
there. So, you know, such great
Americans, American values, freedom,
fighting for American values.
Most protesters are out there for the
egocentric fun of protesting. Resist.
Most pro protesters are out there for
the egocentric fun of protesting.
Resist.
Aha.
So the next time you're going to allow
your opinion to be swayed by the crowd
showing up at the something or other
convention,
they're all out there because they get
off on it.
If you change what the what the protest
is about, same people go.
If you photograph protesters,
you find the same group shows up all
over the place. They're protesting this
here. They protest that there. The same
protesters show up because they're
hooked on protesting.
The excitement of the crowd. I mean,
what fun to get out there and holler and
hold up a sign. Down with then you put
anything in there. Down with whatever
you'll see today. Down with Republicans.
Down with Democrats, down with virgins,
down with old people, down with social
security, down with the government,
down with the president, down with the
Congress, down with the
Everybody just gets off. They love
protesting.
So they love to protest.
That's good to know it. So you're not
naive and think that this is really a
demonstration of human opinion. modern
opinion is not. It's just a protest
demonstration.
And the rules of protest demonstrations
were set years ago by the communists.
And you can start a protest
demonstration anywhere for 50 bucks
within 20 minutes. Give me 50 bucks in
20 minutes and I'll have a protest
demonstration for you. By 20 after the
hour, you head for the nearest bar. You
say, "Folo,
everybody wants a drink. They're all on
me."
There's a son of a down the same
where you need to go out and and express
oursel about. And then you tell them all
what the person you wanted to protest
against, whether wicked they are, etc.
Next thing you know, they're all
tripping out. When you get back to the
bar, we'll buy you a double. Back from
the bar, they got a double. 50 bucks you
can get a protest going in just about
anywhere in the world.
So that removes our naivity about it.
You just go to the nearest bar, you can
hire a whole bunch of B for 50 bucks.
They'll protest anything. When you get
back, we'll give you a double shot in a
mirror.
I used to work for an auto factory and
at a certain hour was a rest period, I
think. Yeah. certain the bell rang and
the factory was right across from a big
bar. It was a really really long bar and
he would have like a hundred shots and
beers set up. The whole bar was two
shots and a beer, two shots and a beer.
Two shots and beer. You had 20 minutes.
Everybody rush across the street, throw
a buck on the bar,
back to work
on the assembly line, which is very
tedious. Without two shots in a beer,
you'd die. Die from boredom. This this
piece auto part hangs from this rack and
this rack goes
you got to wait 30 seconds for that part
to come over to you and then you go and
then you're done for 30 seconds. The
boredom would drive you insane.
If you didn't drink, you wouldn't be
able to handle it. So
people have a congenital, you know,
predisposition to alcoholism.
The farther north your your your people
come from, the greater the likelihood of
alcohol addiction.
So if you have alcohol addiction
yourself or in the family, you look
where your family comes from. If your
family comes from close to the
Mediterranean,
south of southern Italy, Spain around
there, it's a very low level. But if it
comes from north, Finland, Sweden,
the Eskimos, Native Americans, the
farther you are near the Earth Pole, the
greater the likelihood of alcoholism. So
alcoholism is genetic
and it's environmental.
And uh if it ran in your family, the
likelihood is very high that you will
also become addicted. So these are
factors in childhood. Nowadays, people
are more sophisticated. You tell the
child, I don't want you drinking because
it runs in the family. Our family has a
genetic predisposition.
We have a deficiency of an enzyme called
alcohol dehydrogenase.
There's a deficiency of alcohol
dehydrogenase
in the in the Eskimo, the North American
Indian in Scandinavians,
people of Northern European extraction.
And that proclivity disappears as your
people come from closer and closer to
the equator. So instead of viewing it as
a moral question, you begin to realize
it's not just social, it's not just
moral, it's genetic predisposition.
Uhhuh.
reality as essence versus appearance. We
saw the the wolf in sheep's clothing,
the Alice in Wonderland. Then life is
what your opinion is. If it's so, it's
because I say it's so. If I say it's so,
it's so. And if I don't say it's so,
it's not so. That's a nice world to live
in. I'd like to live in Alice in
Wonderland.
the virtual reality of the media we've
covered. The world is a projection, an
illusion.
Uhhuh.
So what we edit then mind is without a
compass. Alternative realities above or
below level 200.
The 55% error in the United States. We
see that only 45% of the people
calibrated 200 or over
only 45% of the people in the United
States are even capable
of discerning reality.
do this
only 45% of a population in America
which is a very sophisticated country
are capable of comprehending reality
from unreality.
Huh?
So that diminishes our expectations of
the world. So we're all not always being
disillusioned. Our hopes are being
dashed.
45% of the population does not have the
capacity, doesn't have the gray matter,
uh
genetic uh
the mind is without a compass. Then
alternative realities above or below
level 200
55% error in the United States.
Therefore, the politicalization of
beliefs, you can see what a trap that
is.
On top of the politicalization and the
indoctrination that goes on, you have an
underlying narcissism.
Now, we could look at any feeling as
narcissistic. We were talking the other
day about about guilt
and um you know people feel that it's
worthy you should go to church and
confess your sins and feel guilty.
Then we asked what about guilt and we
found that guilt is really egoentricity.
You should give up a thing because it's
a bad idea not because you get guilty
about it. You learn to avoid it because
you feel guilty about it.
And you sort of tweak a little piece of
virtue out of that. Feeling virtuous. At
least I felt guilty about it.
Guilt is all about me.
I did wrong. I should have known better.
I'm going to do better. I'm going to do
better next time. The reason I did that
was because of me of this. And I I so
guilt instead of feeling inflating your
ego about it, you realize that it's
narcissistic.
Nobody cares why you feel guilty.
It's your choice. You want to feel
guilty about it, go ahead.
Uh
so it does not it's not exactly a
virtue.
You grow up in a Christian
Judeo Christian society, you get the the
illusion that guilt is somehow a
noteworthy. Well, I'm glad he feels
guilty about it. He's in jail now and I
hope he feels guilty.
We think that guilt is then
self-punishment for bad behavior. So,
it's your inner parent. Your inner
parent now is going to punish you. I
went and did this and that. say your
inner inner mom dad is going to make you
feel guilty and punish you. Uh
so there we see that that is essentially
egoentricity which is really narcissism
indoctrination
trumps reality that we've already spoken
about. All information is presumptive.
Everything that you think may be so is
only presumptively so.
And send your kids to Yavapai College.
Yavapai College came out quite well.
440.
That's a good place to go. You can't
hardly find a college anymore that
calibrates over 200, much less 440.
Some of our friends have been to Yavapai
College and they reported that it was
indeed what's the name of that other
college that teaches the great books of
the western world? St. John's of
somebody mentioned it before.
Anyway, for people that live around
here, it's just nice to know that
Yavapai College calibrates 440 and many
of the colleges with big fancy names,
Eastern colleges calibrate about 180.
The book indoctrination spells out that
indoctrination. Indoctrination
that nowadays kids are being
indoctrinated. You send your kid off to
college and he comes back talking a
certain kind of weird language in belief
systems and you wonder how do you get
that? Uh and it's explained in the book
indoctrination.
Protagoras is dictim. Reality is
subjective presumption.
Protagoras is dictim.
Reality is subjective presumption.
So we all presume that the way we
experience reality is the way it is.
The way I experience everybody in this
room right now, my mind can only presume
that it's correct.
You get more sophisticated. and you
begin to doubt the capacity of your mind
in certain circumstances.
When you turn on the TV news, then your
more sophisticated mind comes up and you
begin to realize that you're hearing
programs. You're being programmed from
one side of the one side to the other.
The far left, the far right, either one
of them has a set of programs they're
trying to sell you or a different set of
values.
a different set of values.
Okay, next we go up to the next slide.
Now we go to the next slide.
Then we want to talk about practical
everyday spirituality without becoming
enlightened, without joining a
monastery.
Uh what's practical in today's world?
How can you be spiritually oriented
person and be successful in today's
world and make make both of them go
together? Do you have to join complete
total secularism
or do you have to rejoin a nunnery or
join a
a a community of uh spiritually oriented
religious people.
So these are the basic rules to stay
with holy company. Stay with holy
company.
Why? Because the energy field the aura
radiated by
and people influences you. Uh so right
now this audience this audience uh would
calibrate as holy company resist.
Oh thank god
people interested in enlightened people
interested in pursuing spiritual truth.
people that really prefer go to heaven
when they die rather than elsewhere.
Uh
all right so there's what I call the
energy field effect. The energy field
effect then we're all profoundly in
influenced by the the energy field of
the crowd.
The spiritual teacher, the energy field
of the spiritual teacher is what the
seeker of truth who visits a spiritual
teach teacher
is not there to understand what the
spiritual teachers teachings are.
Although that can that can be a side
effect and nice to have too. But what
they want is the energy field radiated
by the spirit of the spiritual teacher.
It's not the teaching.
uh it's not the teaching specifically
although it the teaching itself is
important but the fact that that energy
field is transmitted via the aura
that's what it means that the Buddha
when he um
transmitted the truth to whatever his
name was with a flower what was his name
I forget
>> well when the Buddha transmitted the
truth to his first
>> advanced student. His name I tend to
forget. Anyway, he passed a flower,
>> right?
>> And people think it was it was the
flower. No, it was the energy field of
the Buddha which his student picked up.
I forget the name of the student.
Oh, well,
>> God will forgive me.
>> Mahaka.
>> Yeah.
I knew there'd be a good student in the
room
who remembers those things.
The thing that's important is when you
hang out with holy people, you pick up
the aura. You become that. So people
study that, people read about it, people
try,
but it's it's actually the energy field
that you pick up.
the caringness for life. So we said
doctors who care about life
have a much higher recovery rate in
their patients. Where did they get that
caringness from?
Presumably they grew up and evolved in a
family in which caringness prevailed as
a dominant environmental
factor.
Some doctors have high recovery rates
and others have low. The caringness, the
caringness accounts for success in every
level of life. To be a caring carpenter,
to be a caring plumber, whatever you do,
to be a caring guard, a caring usher,
caring cab driver,
to be caring, to go out of your way. And
I remember people when I was driving cab
would want me to take them someplace and
it was really in a different zone. I
wasn't really allowed to go in the zone.
So I said, "Well, I'm going to turn out
my headlights and we're going to go in
and then you got to get the hell out of
here."
I turned out my headlights and go in
this way. They go out the other way like
close turn lights back on and there I
was back in my zone again.
But I didn't want him to walk home alone
in the dark. So I I took them to it so
they would be right by their own front
door. Uh so caring this that's one of
the great values of having pets and
animals is you learn to care for others.
So every child I think benefits by
having a pet even if it's a pet canary
or pet worm and pet bugs. I had all pet
everything when I was a kid. I had pet
spiders and pet
and little pee peep. You know, pee pee
would be in my hands like this and the
little the little duckling when it was
born thought I was its mother.
So I would go out in the backyard and
pee peep would come running across the
lawn like this to try to get to me. So I
would pick it up like this. And as far
as the duckling was concerned, I was its
mother. And I love that little baby
duck. So I'd take him hunting. We'd go
out in the garage and hunt spiders.
He'd ride in my hands like this and we'd
go to the the garage windows usually
have a spiderweb and there'd be a nice
fat spider and pee pee would go
and he'd have most of the spider except
the couple legs would still be sticking
out from his bill.
So she's trying to go swallow the spider
and a couple of spider legs are still
wobbling really.
So the little duckling imprinted. So we
imprint. Now I would the the caretakers
when I was young uh when I was still an
infant were both uh were both black and
white exist. I had the good fortune that
some caretakers when I was infant or
black and some were white. I've never
had any trouble feeling great affection
for black people. And if I haven't seen
any for a while, I feel deprived. And
when I see them all again, there's a
feeling of gladness that I get when I'm
only with black people. And and so that
imprinting, you see, the caretakers were
either black or white and therefore
equally lovable, equally valuable. And
so the kind of experiences that we have
when we're infants, their imprint and
tend to stay with us, whether a baby
duckling or a human being. That's
interesting to know, is it not?
>> Yes.
So that's one reason you can stop
feeling guilty about a lot of things.
You were not surrounded by factors when
you were an infant which you imprinted.
And you have to work at liking white
people or work at liking black people.
And uh you have to learn how to love
them. And then when you see how lovable
they are, uh you then you're over the
brink. And so I'll be your companion. If
you have trouble, put mentally in your
mind. If you have trouble liking black
people, you just love them like I love
them and say, "Well, my god, they are
lovable." Yes. Or if you have trouble
loving white people, say they probably
are lovable if you get to know them.
So you learn how to imprint. You learn
how to artificially imprint yourself.
And um the groups that you choose to
associate with. I remember when I was
young, there was no place to dance
nearby my house except a dance hall that
was a short distance away. And I like
the the music music and I love dancing
and I was a good dancer all my life. So
anyway, where could you go dancing with
this great music? There was only one
nightclub within five or 10 miles. And
it was all black. I mean, 100%.
A big crowd of people. 100% black. And I
just went in and the music was so
fantastic. I started, you want to dance?
Yeah. I danced the whole night. Didn't
see one white person the whole night.
Not a single per black person made any
no notion that they'd even noticed.
Nobody reflected any why are you here or
are you in the right neighborhood or
nobody said anything. All the ladies
danced with me and all the guys were
respectful and we had a fantastic time.
100% black people. I suppose a lot of
people gotten scared if they'd walked in
to find 100% black people. And then when
I lived in New York I I'd go up to
Harlem and that was the best music the
best reason to go there was that was
where the best money most best music I
mean was. And so you transcend then
racial identifications
uh racial identifications and sex and um
heredity and social position and all the
titles
uh that you you get given
stay with holy company
because you get an energy field effect
you picking up the aura
and we found out you know it was found
out in aa people would go
Aa gets sober and leave and if they left
they had a high relapse rate that they
needed the energy field of a a itself
which calibrates extremely high. I
forget what it is right now but I've
referred to it before. So the energy
field of a so they'd say
even if you don't believe a thing we say
just go to the meetings because if you
go to the meetings uh you'll pick up the
energy. Sure enough, didn't believe a
thing they said. Kept on drinking. Would
go to an AA meeting and just lay in the
back of the room. Lay on the floor in
the back of the room. Figure, you know,
you're picking it up by osmosis. Sure
enough, in the end, you get sober.
There's that band of brothers bonding,
cultural paradigms of reality. We're all
influenced by what everybody considers
important and real. Then of course we
have things that are a little more
sophisticated to track down karmic
influences
and also the importance of discerning
spiritual versus religious. It can be
very religious
and not spiritual. It can be very
religious and not spiritual.
And uh many of things that have gone
wrong with some of the world's major
religions are very good demonstrations
of that. They were technically correct
but uh operationally wrong.
Spiritual versus
versus religious karmic influences.
Uh that's one place where using the arm
that certain things can be uh
enlightening.
uh and you'll find out things about
yourself and you say, you know, in some
lifetime it must have something other
like that and you use the arm and you
find out yes that is so
you're too cheap to uh let too cheap to
take him back to port. So you had them
all walk the plank
because nobody could be that mendacious.
Nobody could be that greedy. Oh yeah,
it's cheaper to just drown them than it
is to feed them all the way back to
port.
Spiritual versus religious. So religions
come and go, but spiritual as an overall
attitude.
So the spiritual person then values all
of life and all of its expressions. The
spiritual person automatically steps
over the spider rather than crushing it.
The spiritual person automatically steps
around the bug rather than killing the
bug. Yes. You see a bug on the sidewalk
and you walk around it and another
person goes over and goes.
So you have to decide in life, am I
going to go or am I going to walk around
the bug? Well, I like little bugs. I say
I used to collect bugs. I had a great
bug collection.
It was given to the state teachers at
university. a great collection of bugs.
So either bugs are something beautiful
and you love them, collect them because
you realize that they they express life.
All right? So then by constantly living
this way, there comes a dawning upon you
sometime
out of nowhere out of nowhere
that all that exists is God. Period.
Nothing exists except divinity.
God is the essence of all of creation
and all of its expressions.
So this is God's expression as a stage.
God's expression is a right knee. God's
expression as four fingers.
Let's say there's only one substance out
of which all material things can be
made. And that substance is called
godness. Godess there's only one thing
possible
and therefore the entire universe is
nothing but the physical expression of
divinity.
So everything is God.
God bless you all. God bless you.
God bless you.
Where do I go, honey?
>> Where do I go?
>> Gabe's going to go get your bag now,
doc.
>> Where where do I go?
>> You're going to be teaching.
>> Where? Where do you want me to go?
>> Over to the chair.
>> Oh, there. Okay.
Oh, good enough.
What happens next, honey?
Did you say we had a slide to do?
>> Yes, there's one right there.
>> Oh, well, I didn't notice it was up
there.
>> Turn your back for a second. Next thing
you know,
I thought we did practical spirituality.
Stay with holy company.
>> Yeah, this is the last
>> energy field.
>> Last one.
>> Uh, the last one.
No,
>> okay. What what what do we uh
our uh alignment with primary teacher?
Oh, these are general rules. practical
spirituality.
First of all, you you locate a primary
teacher that you calibrate that you know
is bonafideed and you can look the list
of teachers. Uh they're all calibrated
there.
You put principles above personalities.
Somebody may have a great personality
but their principles are not too good or
vice versa.
Uh oh, we we saw the chart of
authenticated teachers.
Avoid uh newagism and that which is
novel and exotic.
Talking to entities on the other side is
very problematic.
It's very chancy.
Uh and you should always calibrate the
entity on the other side. And if they
were very high, they wouldn't be
channeling on the other side. So
avoid channelneled entities. Why?
Because most of them really want
control. Most of them just get their
egos get off on controlling people.
And uh
self-styled self-styled masters.
Yeah. People can declare themselves a
master. I am master bumbleaboo.
Master bumbleaboo.
And who appointed a master? He did.
Selfappointed.
So stick with what you can verify,
calibrate,
and if you don't know about it, you ask
people who who have some degree of
sophistication in the matter.
>> Two more slides.
>> Huh?
>> Oh. Oh,
>> she was wrong. You thought it was one,
but it's two.
>> Oh, I see. Okay.
>> Now, wait.
Now you're going to tell me the truth,
are you?
You see, threats work.
Okay. Study and contemplation and
meditation on the teachings of any
spiritual teacher. And of course,
usually people read more than one and
you find crossverification.
You cross find crossverification.
Then you want to use reason. But also
balance it with faith.
You want to become
that which you've studied instead of
just know about. To know about it is
different than becoming it. Avoid all
hatred doctrines.
I hate all hatred doctrines.
be watchful of the spiritual ego.
uh that's the idea that I know
I know and uh people will work to get
rid of the ego and instead they develop
a spiritual ego
and then uh utilize inspiration
music cathedrals beauty the beauty of
nature the beauty of music
be watchful of religionism
number of the current
as well as not too far along ago.
Religions are carried away with
themselves.
Uh they become imbued what I call
religionism.
The value of intention and religious
practices.
We've calibrated most of the religious
practices commonly used in all of them.
Practice of the virtues
and the practice of the great
commandments.
Avoidance of the seven deadly sins.
Glamlamorize
that which is has undue attraction.
Avoidance of the seven deadly sins.
Didn't even list them there, did they?
Goodwill towards all of life.
There's all kinds of secret ancient
mysteries and prophecies.
It's always for a price. Yeah. For $500
or $5,000, we'll will share with you the
secrets of the ancient mysteries.
Uh and prophecies, all the prophecies
have been wrong and there's continuing
to be the the current prophecies are all
wrong as well, 2012 and all that. Avoid
high price gurus with specialness.
Yeah, they get they get they get into
the news and uh people spend thousands
of dollars to spend a a couple hours
with some guru and who tells you what I
could have told you for nothing over the
phone.
Uh avoid evil.
Avoid the seduction by glamour.
So glamour means, you know, the
glamorization of a spiritual teacher
with big crucifixes and robes and long
flowing white hair and sandals and and
the whole Jesus trip, you know,
a course of miracles.
A course in miracles, inner direction
arose via inner direction. It was not
channeled.
And I met the lady who who did it and it
was an inner voice that came to her by
virtue of a previous agreement on her
part. It came from the White Brotherhood
and p per a personal agreement on her
part. And I got to meet her. Her name
was Helen, I think it was.
And uh got to know her. So I got to
certify how she got it. It was via an
inner voice.
Uhhuh.
That's nice to know.
All right. Where do we go from here?
Um, we're going what we're going to do
is we're going to change the stage
because we have to be out of here at 5.
The question and answer. A lot of people
want to do that. So, if you'll start
lining up for question and answer.
People who have already asked a
question, please do not line up.
>> Thank you for Thank you for loving us
and caring for us.
Uh I should start my question by saying
that I do believe in uh
God being formless.
>> You believe in what?
>> God being formless.
>> Yes.
>> But uh and that um
everything is one.
But I was reading the Bhagavad Gita and
there was uh a part that confused me. I
wasn't sure how to interpret it. And
it's where Arjun
um asks to see Krishna's
uh form.
>> Yes. What?
>> Asks to see Krishna's form. His form.
>> Oh yes. Yes.
>> And I I've been following a bakti yoga
which considers Krishna as God.
And um
Krishna then changes his
>> Krishna
isn't God. Krishna is
>> what? What is Krishna?
>> Jesus Christ. Krishna,
>> the Buddha.
>> What are they all
>> the Buddha? God.
>> Well, I guess everything's God is.
That's what you said before.
>> Okay. Okay, you got me there.
>> But uh
>> that was because God answered you.
>> Well, who was it that spoke?
>> Well, the part that confused me was uh
Krishna changed his form to forearmmed
opulent form.
Krishna came into form for what?
>> He changed his form to four arms and had
like a a mace and disc and things
>> and
>> and he said to Arjun, behold my
my supreme universal form. And he says
uh no one has ever seen this this
supreme form of mine. Even the
demagogues desire to see this form which
is so dear and
I I believe that God is a formless and
that
>> we are all
>> You believe God is what?
>> Formless.
>> Formless. Yes. Okay.
>> And that we are all God. But this
passage confused me and I wasn't sure
how to interpret it. And so I guess my
question would be about what exactly is
this form and are is it or are we part
of this form?
Is it is it just that
>> what what's sitting in the chair?
>> A form.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay.
So, uh
>> to enter this domain
to enter this domain and participate in
this domain
of the of that which is form requires
that you temporarily adopt form. The
thing is not to get into the delusion
that you are that which you have chosen
for an experience to be. Because you put
on a costume for a party, it doesn't
mean you become an elf, you know.
>> But it's convenient, you know. It's
convenient to have a body when everybody
else seems to have one. You know what
I'm saying?
>> Right.
>> You don't be the only one around without
a body. You know what I mean?
So I guess it's dualistic thinking to
think of maybe that I was worried about
that causing a dualism
but uh if I could uh I'd like to ask for
a picture
>> I'd like to ask
>> a picture a po a photo but uh
>> that'll be a dollar
>> I
I I have been following uh Indian
tradition and studying saying Indian
religion and uh I would like to ask if
before I have a picture if I could touch
your feet.
>> Could he have a picture?
>> He wants to he wants to touch your feet
because he's been following the Indian.
>> Oh, I see. You're coming from the Indian
>> spiritual traditions as it's done in
India. Yes, indeed. Yes.
>> Because he's studying those.
>> Yes. You're saying that style of
>> There we go.
Uh-huh.
>> Yes.
God bless you. God bless you.
Amen.
I'll bet you in a minute.
>> Oh, here.
>> Thank you.
There we are.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Hello.
>> Oh my goodness. This one's well read.
>> So is this one.
>> Yes.
>> I just wanted to first off express my
deep gratitude for your teachings and
your presence.
And my request was simply to um hold
your hand and receive your blessing. And
if you had anything that you felt you
needed to tell me,
>> bless you.
>> You are in the right place doing the
right thing.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Look at this.
>> The other kids are all playing
stickball.
Well, it's wonderful to play with you.
Thank you very much.
>> Very hard to see here.
>> That's right.
>> The way the lights are, the shadow of my
hand falls right where I'm trying to
write. There's nothing I can do about
it. So,
>> stop complaining. Oh, but I want to
complain.
You're not allowed to complain until you
get home. Okay.
>> Hello, Susan. Dr. Hawkins. Uh, first if
I ask if I could hold your hand and ask
for a blessing.
>> Well, let's do that later. Ask a
question.
>> Okay. Um,
>> yeah. My question has to do with um
motivation and intrinsic like the drive
to achieve.
>> I'm still not hearing right. motivation
in the uh in the
>> drive to achieve like that to excel.
>> Motivation and achieving you've talked
earlier.
>> You you've talked earlier about uh
people trying to be the absolute best
they could be for like the
to
basically live the best life they can.
And
uh I found that I could intellectually
get that but there's not that internal
drive, that reason to do it. There's
just the reason to exist. So I was
wondering how would one get that true
reason, that true motivation to excel
and be all they it can be type of thing.
>> You want to do something but not enough
to do it.
I I don't
>> Is that what you're saying?
>> You want to become a de devote, but
you're too lazy.
>> Um
>> all that praying and kneeling and
meditating.
>> Not even that. It's it's
>> what's the truth?
>> It's more in like in everything.
>> It's like there's just the reason to
exist, but there's not the reason to do
anything more than exist.
>> Oh, well, for you, existence is good
enough.
>> Okay.
So it's not a big deal then.
>> All right. Okay.
>> What gives you satisfaction?
>> Um
I don't I don't quite know yet. It's
>> well you're become a spiritual de
devote. So that's obviously bringing you
spiritual satisfaction, right?
>> It's a quest to find
>> but you don't see as the obvious. You
try to make it into something obscure
and intellectual
>> maybe.
>> What is this thing here?
>> It's a table and a cloth.
>> It's a table. Yeah. What's this thing
here?
>> It's a cloth.
>> Oh, you see how simple life is? What's
that?
>> It's a can of
>> What's the purpose of this?
>> Depends on what you do with it. Suppose
you drink it.
>> Very good. What's the purpose of this
>> tissue paper?
He's going to graduate in about 3
minutes.
>> You're complicated.
>> Maybe.
>> Yeah. You're looking for my people think
that things that are spiritual and
mystical are obscure.
No, the truly mystical is obvious.
>> So, I'm missing something obvious.
I I I guess so.
>> Yeah.
>> So, can touch your hand.
>> People look for the mystical. They want
something that's obscure
and fancy sounding
like magical colored fog that drifts
across their vision.
And they realize that mystical fog is
really God. Oh,
how come that's God and this ain't?
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Yes.
>> Um, I don't have a question, but I just
wanted to express my gratitude for uh
teaching me the straight and narrow
path. Thank you very much.
>> Thank you.
Thank you.
Yeah, people look for the they rather
obscure and enchanting when they talk
about Mr.
>> Dr. Hawkins and everybody here today has
been a total gift and a dream come true.
Love you guys and I love you. You um
>> what is that?
>> What was that that just happened?
>> Well, he just said he loved everything.
>> It's just it's just great to be here.
That's all I'm saying.
>> Oh, okay.
>> In your in your lecture today, you said
that part of our task is to stay with
holy company and to be aware of the
energy field effect.
>> I teach school
>> and I teach low socioeconomic
title one. I teach
>> social e economic children.
>> In other words, children who
>> um have not read your book.
>> Children who are what? children that
haven't read your books.
>> Oh,
>> obviously.
>> Oh, okay. So
my humble question to you
um
is what is a what what is one to do if
if by their occupation they are told to
go over and over and over into a
compromised energy field?
>> I don't understand the question.
>> What do you mean a compromised energy
field? I I don't understand either.
They're told over and over again.
>> No, no, no, no. Those my question is by
my employment, I am told I I'm required
to be in low energy.
>> Yeah. Your your employment is to be
what?
>> In low energy fields.
>> My question is not valid. No. No. Um
basically
>> you're talking about teaching
disadvantaged children.
>> Yes. Yes, sir.
>> Why don't you just say that?
>> Oh.
Thank you. Okay.
>> Okay. Now, what's your question? So my
question is if
it's my perception, which is probably my
fault, that I'm stepping into lower
energy
on a daily basis.
What is what am I to do in order to
>> how does that affect?
>> For example, people who are here want to
be here and so they listen to every word
and we're just we're, you know, with
total gratitude. But
>> the lower energy field of the people
you're dealing with is not going to pull
you down.
>> Okay.
>> On the contrary,
your interest and concern for them.
That's why I emphasized caringness
earlier. Your caringness they get. No
matter what you say, you either care and
they get that or you don't care and they
get that too. So, a lot of kids who go
to special schools don't really do much
better because the people who are
looking after them really don't care.
They're getting paid for that job or I'm
teaching special children. LA,
but they don't really give a rap about
the kid. If you really care about the
kid, then that shows up. And a kid knows
if you care about him or not. You're not
going to fool them. My dog knows it. So
my kitties and my dog if they know that
you can be sure that a child's
mind will also get whether you are there
to participate with them in an exciting
experience or not.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Yeah.
If you think of the children as dumb
little offs,
that's indicative that you don't have
the right attitude.
Uh
>> instead of question, I I want blessing.
>> He you want a blessing?
>> Yes.
Um as
Is that what you want is a blessing?
Okay.
>> I bless you in the name of the Lord.
Amen.
So be it.
>> That's it.
Who did Buddha give the flower to?
Ananda was it?
>> Um, he says he wants to compose music
over 500, but I lost my way. Please
teach me.
>> Teach me what?
>> How? How to do that?
>> I can't teach you how to
write good music.
>> I can't teach you how to write good
music. Your inspiration
pervades whatever creative products you
put out, whether it's sculpture or
painting or music or dancing
or teaching
or writing. Yeah.
your your energy comes out through
whatever uh expression you choose.
You can write, teach, dance, paint,
do them all at once.
Carpentry. I loved carpentry, too.
I mean, when I made a door, it was a
door.
Yes.
>> Do everything you can do to the best of
your ability.
>> Hi Doc.
>> Hi.
>> Hi Dr. H.
>> Yes.
>> Um I was wondering what's the best way
to encourage spiritual growth in my
children?
>> I can't hear.
>> Uh what is the best way to encourage
spiritual growth in his children?
Well, by example,
most children in our society get taken
to church.
Uh they go to Sunday school.
They visit holy places, cathedrals, and
churches, and
they observe reverence on the part of
their parents.
There's a new big Catholic church we
pass on that we come down. And I just
can't wait till I get a chance to go in
there and check it out and see what it
looks like and all.
>> Yep.
>> May I have my picture taken with you?
>> Huh?
>> May he have Yes.
>> May I have my picture taken with you?
>> He wants to know if he can have his
picture taken with you.
>> Oh, sure. I can't understand. There's
something wrong with his feedback.
>> It's not It's not coming from that mic
in here.
>> One of those things I hear where he is.
It's not working this way.
>> I don't hear what he's saying.
Yes.
>> Hello.
>> Um, I came primarily just to receive the
energy of the uh of the aura.
>> You you what? I just came primarily just
to receive the energy.
>> Oh, the energy
>> of the oil.
>> Oh yes.
>> Uh my question was about the final run.
>> Final run
>> for the final.
>> Oh yeah.
>> Is it is it premature to anticipate that
or should you rely on it arising?
>> You don't have to know anything about it
till the time approaches and as it
approaches you'll know it.
>> Yeah.
>> So beforehand should be just
concentrating.
>> It's like you're facing certain death.
So up until that point should be focused
on on generally on forgiveness.
>> Yes. You should f focus on the teachings
really that you know not all of us are
going to face that final.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> So there's no need to focus on it.
>> No. But he wanted you to know what to
expect when you do face it. That's why
he told us about it. So not all of us
are even going to
>> not this lifetime necessarily. In this
life,
>> we're setting the groundwork so that we
can
>> Mhm.
>> Because the energy of that teaching
stays within your aura even if you get
reborn.
>> Yeah.
>> Mhm.
>> So, how am I doing?
>> Does she have her name in there or
anything?
>> I don't know. This microphone is not
working very good for me. want your name
put in there.
>> I couldn't understand what he said. I'm
sorry.
>> What' you say? I'm sorry.
>> Um, how am I doing?
>> How is he doing?
>> How is he doing
>> towards that run?
>> Towards that run.
I wouldn't be attracted by the
mystification of it.
If the time approaches, you don't need
to be reminded
>> because the fear grabs you from stem to
toe.
>> Yeah.
>> And you realize you are about to cease
existence.
It's terrifying.
So you won't need somebody to tap you
and say, "Hey, it's time to get scared."
I would say it was close to being like
terror.
>> Yes.
It was like terror.
>> Thank you.
>> I never should have written about it. I
did. So
>> yes.
>> Hi Dr. Hawkins. Hi.
>> So
uh I am a dentist from Korea.
>> Dentist.
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
>> So first of all uh thank you for being
my spiritual teacher.
>> Uhhuh. And um uh I have been uh not so
happy through the years. Uh but I am
getting and getting happier.
Uh when I u u know
u what the ego is, you teach me.
So uh I I just I would like to hold your
hands and uh look in your eyes for
silent transmission.
It already happened.
Well, it's the intention of the seeker
that that precipitates the it's the
intention of the seeker that
precipitates the
transmission.
>> My wife question, so could you raise
this for me?
>> I don't have my glasses.
>> This is all dark colored here. I'm going
to put it in here. Okay. He says, "I
recently realized that I have been
experiencing samate
from his teenage years and I am in
>> samati. In the state of samadei, all the
sudden all of a sudden everything
becomes silent."
>> Yes.
>> And I hear nothing.
>> I I feel that I go down into a deep
place within within me.
>> Yes.
>> And space around me becomes infinite.
>> Yes. And my mind becomes crystal clear.
>> Yes.
>> And no judgment, no comp comparison of
any sort, but just quite different from
overflowing joy that I feel within.
>> Yes.
>> When I pray to God.
>> Uhhuh.
>> My question is why does the status of
mommy I have been experiencing
lack the joy I experience when I pray?
Why does samati what
>> lacking the joy that he experiences?
>> They're two different states. Joy is one
state, samati is another. Samati is is
higher and more more uh
is a higher state of consciousness.
Sami is a higher state of consciousness
than joy. Remember on a calibrated scale
of consciousness, joy is around uh I
forget what number it is but anyway it's
uh it's not as high as infinite peace.
When you reach the stage of infinite
peace
uh you could leave the body. You could
just uh disappear if you wanted and it's
just sort of karmic whether you stay
here or you leave.
The joy is a completely different state.
Yeah.
>> Okay.
Uh the second question is if the state
of samadei becomes more frequent would I
be able to function in the world?
Sometimes I become fearful as of
>> No, you wouldn't be able to.
>> No. Eventually you'll have to make a
choice between the world and the state.
>> Uhhuh.
Dr.
is nothingness or allness
>> or
>> is samani nothingness or allness.
>> It's both.
>> Thank you.
See the opposites disappear.
>> The opposites disappear in somebody.
>> Yeah. Allness and nothingness are all
the same state.
It's all and by being all it is no
thing. So it is no thingness.
It is also void
because it's void. It's all inclusive.
You will confuse the void with
nothingness.
>> Hello.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. Um, I had a question. Um, I
experience a lot of inner peace and joy
and but I still also sometimes feel a
heavier energy as well.
>> Sure.
>> And I know that if I'm, you know, in
that moment when I realize that if I'm
fully present,
then that heaviness kind of fades away.
>> Yes. But I I find that that kind of
comes and goes and I just have a
question.
>> What's the question?
>> Essentially of transcending that.
>> Yes. That's just a phase.
That's just a phase where you
vacasillate from one level to another.
Eventually you identify with the higher
level and the lower level disappears.
It's like again to return to the
familiar. Mhm.
If you go out of body, body has a
certain attraction to you because it's
very familiar. Then you learn how to be
comfortable out of body and it no longer
attracts you
to function in this world. It's better
to
identify, you know, at least the the one
who was occupying the body.
I always figure I got eternity on the
other side. You know what's the big
worry?
We don't have to finish it by August.
You know,
your last chance. Your last chance is
April 15th, right?
No, that's income tax day. Oh, okay.
>> Thank you.
You get a chance to fulfill your karmic
destiny. Yeah. Mhm.
>> Thank you for being here.
I'm trying to take step three to a
deeper level of surrender, but my ego
doesn't seem to want to let go of hopes
and dreams. What can I do to
>> think? He's got to slow down. What? My
ego doesn't want to seem to let go of
hopes and dreams.
>> Let go of what?
>> Hopes and dreams.
>> Hopes and dreams. Oh, yes.
>> You know, positive things,
>> but there's still obsessions and
desires.
>> So, I'm wondering what I can do to get
gain greater surrender to God in the
process while I'm dealing with
>> you. Just continue in the direction
you're going.
You just keep surrendering everything to
God and u eventually it happens of its
own
and then eventually you realize there
isn't any eye that's that's uh making a
decision to do that that it's happening
of its own by virtue of your own
intention.
The phenomena occur autonomously
there isn't any me that does that.
On the contrary,
thatness is happening of its own
spontaneously of its own.
I got a good feel. Thank you.
Yes.
>> Hello.
Um, with the regards to to the thoughts
or the voices in the head, is there any
specific way I could distinguish
which is the the ego or which is the
self or which are the guardian angels?
>> Do you want to know the origination of
the thought?
>> Yes.
Uh,
how do the ordinary the everyday
thoughts seem to you?
>> Compulsive.
>> They seem okay.
>> What?
You want a drink of water? You don't
want to think drink of water. What do
you want? How are you going to get a
drink of water?
>> He don't perceive that as
>> as a thought.
>> He doesn't perceive that as a thought.
>> The drinking a drink of water.
>> Yeah. Oh. Oh. Oh. Uhhuh. So if you think
drink of water then that's different. Is
that right?
>> Yeah. I mean that's
>> okay. So in the best possible world as
far as you're concerned everything is
happening autonomously without thought.
>> Would that be fine?
>> Not necessarily. It's just that some
some
>> Well, thinking is happening without your
intending to think is what you're
saying, right?
>> Yes.
>> Okay. Despite your best efforts thinking
this is happening.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. But my question is how do I know
when a thought comes from the ego or
when it comes from the self for
instance?
>> Uh if how does he know whether when the
thought comes in?
>> Oh yeah. Is it his his ego or is it
being taught?
>> Yeah.
>> Well, there's a sense of ownership that
it's your own thought. Uh there's a
there's a feeling of like otherness when
it's not of your thought. You say the
thought
arose
that it's time to get a cheeseburger.
That's different than I think I want a
cheeseburger.
So the thoughts arise autonomously.
So the way to surrender all this is to
allow the phenomena
to be phenomena.
Allow them to just be what they are and
not seek authorship.
Neither accept or reject them. The
phenomena occur of their own. You don't
say, "I just took a breath
and now I'm going to take another breath
and now I'm gonna take a breath and now
I'm gonna exhale." I mean, all that
phenomena is happening without all that
jabber walking. So, you got to let the
mind go as far as amusing you with
jabber with jabbering. It jabers.
It's fighting for its existence.
So you just allow it to ignore it to be
dumb and stand in the corner with a
dunce cap.
>> So actually the origination of the
thought is irrelevant.
>> What did they say?
>> So what' you say again?
>> The the the origin of the thought is is
irrelevant. Where does it come from?
>> Origin of the thought is irrelevant.
>> Yeah. Who cares?
You don't have to pay taxes on it.
Well, the neurons are firing away
because they've been trained for
billions of years of evolution.
So, there's the autonomous
physiologic functioning.
And to transcend all that takes some
years of spiritual discipline generally.
And of course, the way to eliminate big
hunks of it is to eliminate the
underlying emotion or ambition.
When you no longer want to be rich, the
thoughts of money don't come to your
mind anymore.
Your personal life is happy. You don't
be not always thinking about finding
some partner out there in the world, you
know. So the satisfaction so satisfying.
So as the teacher says, you can either
surrender them and let them go or
satisfy them.
I forget who said that Roman or
somebody.
>> I have a question relating our mission
in life. There is a scientific uh
spiritual school in Romania where we are
coming from and uh this school also is
based on kinesiology. They are using
muscle testing in order to get answers
about spiritual reality and uh they have
calibrated that uh besides the fact that
we come here to evolve we also come here
with maybe specific missions like in
order to I don't know maybe build a
school write a book or I don't know do
something specifically and I was
wondering is is that so I mean it some
somehow seems
>> you know what the question is
>> yeah
what it This is she says you know some
people come here you know to evolve and
some people come here as a mission you
know they have a duty they have to
perform.
>> You mean coming to earth
>> coming coming back. Yeah.
>> Oh. Oh yes.
>> Yeah. So some people and is that true
that some people come here to evolve and
some people are here to specific
>> with a specific mission?
>> Yeah sure you bet. Because it's karmic
propensity. Mhm.
>> So it is like a mission in doing
something or just being somehow. I mean
it's in action or in just being.
>> Okay. Both.
>> Both.
>> Yeah. Okay. Thank you. And also uh I
would like uh your blessing. Uh we are
expecting a child and uh it's five
months inside. So but we decided to call
him David because you inspired us so
much.
>> So talk so much. She has a she's
expecting a child and they're going to
call it David.
>> Yeah. And we would like your blessing
for us as a family and for the child.
>> Is it a Is it a boy?
>> Yeah,
>> it's a boy.
>> How do you know? It's not even here yet.
>> Well, we measured it. We could we muscle
tested?
>> They tested it to see what sex it was.
>> Oh, that's clever.
You know, you say he's got a little
wingle wangle. You figure it's a boy.
>> Yeah.
>> So, she was a blessing.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. If you can even touch him.
>> Yeah.
>> Let's feel the baby, huh?
>> Oh, that's that's very nice, honey. God
bless you. God bless the baby.
>> God bless you. God bless the baby.
>> Okay. Thank you.