I'd like to introduce Dr. Hawkins.
Thank you.
Thank you all.
Where's the audience?
Oh, out there.
Gloria in excelsis Deo.
All praise be to thee, O Lord, most high.
Amen.
And with that, we set the context of reality for the day.
As you can see, we'll be calibrating all kinds of levels of consciousness.
And what these levels mean, it means relative to divinity.
So God will be here to help us out.
We have nothing to worry about today.
And what are we talking about again today?
You told me, and I went and forgot.
Oh, the secret of life.
Oh, yes.
The secret of life.
The secret of life was.
Well, the secret of life, we'll get to later.
I forgot what it is now.
But you already know it.
So today we'll just remind you that you're only going to be learning what you already know.
That makes it nice, doesn't it?
Also, today is, I've declared it to be National Humility Day.
Where's our humility?
Where is it?
Okay.
I want the person who's the most humble.
I want the most humble person in the.
I want the most humble person to raise their hand.
Okay.
Here's the humility award for today.
As you can see, today is going to be a very serious day.
Humor is, humor is what's serious.
Tragedy is crap.
It's everybody's, everybody's full of tragedy.
It's a dime a dozen.
Okay, so, uh, what were we talking about again today?
Huh?
Spiritual challenges.
Oh, that sounds scary.
Well, as long as we're here and there's a whole audience, we might as well give a lecture today.
How's that?
We might as well do that.
Uh, anybody want me to discuss spiritual challenges?
Yeah.
Two left jabs and a right cross.
There you go.
That knocks the devil right on his tail.
Right.
So, we have slides that we're going to be talking about.
So, uh, there is a method to our madness today.
And there is a certain coherent sanity behind it all.
Which we won't reveal, however.
All right.
So, we've got slides.
We're going to start with the slides.
Is that correct?
Yes.
All right.
Because we're going to do like a review of basics.
How many people are here for the first time?
Oh, boy.
Okay.
All right.
For the sake of review for all of us, so we're all on the same page, and, uh, especially
for the new people, we're going to go through some basic slides, which covers material we've
presented over the years, sort of basic knowledge, and, uh, so that slide will go on right now.
Is this where it is?
Oh, my goodness sakes alive.
Oh, my gracious me.
Oh, what is that?
It says a map of consciousness.
Oh-ho.
Well, that certainly is an interesting looking slide.
And if I could see it, it would help a lot.
A map of consciousness.
Well, that's how all this work started.
We started to count.
We discovered how to tell truth from falsehood.
Uh-oh.
In this world, to know that there has been truth from falsehood, it's a wonder I'm still
living.
Any time somebody gets on from Washington or some country and pontificates, Susan and
I do the arm.
And if they all knew what we're up to, we wouldn't be breathing in and out.
So we're going to review all so quickly how to tell truth from falsehood.
Does anybody like to know how to tell truth from falsehood?
Oh, boy, oh, boy.
Okay.
We'll see if they're telling the truth.
We have permission to ask this question.
Those people do want us to show them how to tell truth from falsehood.
Here's this.
Aha.
We're probably the only people in the universe that can tell truth from falsehood in an instant.
People who have been to these lectures.
Isn't that an amazing thing?
Isn't it?
simple observation was simply that truth for biologic reasons makes your body go
strong and falsehood makes it go weak. By knowing that simple technique you can
tell the truth of anything. Not only can you tell the truth of anything but you
can calibrate the level of truth of anything. So we have the scale and as you
can see the scale goes and covers all the possible attitudes we can have.
Where is the numbers? Here they are. The numbers go up to a thousand. So the
higher the number the greater the level of truth and we find out that many
things in this world that the whole world bets on and the government pays
billions of dollars for. For instance what were the
SEC's
people doing about these investments that they were supposed to be guarding?
Well we know how they were spending their time on their computer. So the
guardians of truth they were working for the SEC. We have
permission to calibrate their level of functioning resistance. It was over a
hundred resistance.
The guardians of our national security were busy with other entertainment that
calibrates at level 100. So it's possible then to tell the truth about anything.
First however we ask we have permission to ask the truth. We have permission to
ask a certain question and first we get an answer to that. Then if we get a
yes we proceed with the question once in a great while you'll get a no and it's
not always clear why you get a no it may be the circumstances and maybe we might
get a no in front of an audience but a yes at home so it could be due to a
number of factors both known and unknown but generally you get a yes if your
question is for the highest good so when we ask a question they're all in the
name of the highest good presuming that the truth is the higher good than
falsehood yes that may be naive of us but that's been our presumption all
right now we want to review then first we anybody got one anymore about the
technique of how to tell truth from falsehood is it is there anything you
want me to ask her that you might be embarrassed to ask your wife
so you have to do it with somebody you trust there has to be mutual trust and
when she holds out her arm she's holding it out at a certain level of strength it
doesn't mean that I couldn't push her down if I used all my strength but it's
a relative strength so truth makes you relatively strong and weakness and
falsehood makes you relatively weak and if there's nobody around to do it
there's a simple code
called the o-ring technique you hold the thing in mind and see how hard it is to
pull these two fingers apart the truth you'll find you can't pull it apart with
falsehood your finger easily slips through there's another simple way you
take a stack of encyclopedias and you look at a picture of Jesus and try to
lift it then you take a look at a picture of Adolf Hitler and try and lift
it and you'll see there's a remarkable difference in your strength so truth
makes us strong falsehood makes us weak and that is a very useful very
pragmatically useful technique huh all right so this scale goes up to a
thousand and I had a pointer someplace so who stole my pointer find that pointer
thief have we got a pointer there well we'll do without a pointer today
we have an invisible pointer are you all familiar with this map of
consciousness yeah all right so it's become relatively well known around the
world yes and as you can see our view of our level of enlightenment which is
the all of us are moving towards enlightenment so we move out of these
lower levels of hate and hopelessness
and tragedy and things that are frightening we move out of being
vindictive callous punitive and vengeful indifferent we move out of pride so from
the bottom we have shame at the very bottom guilt somebody is asking me how
can you get rid of guilt one way of looking at other than self-forgiveness
during the course of miracles let's say
you can realize that guilt is really guilt is really well guilt is really
egocentricity oh me look what I've done wrong oh me God must hate me oh me so
you'll see people go around feeling guilty feeling that they're doing some
kind of spiritual good by feeling guilty and all they're doing is a
obsessing about themselves so therefore instead of feeling guilty if you give
yourself for the error and commit you recommit yourself to God and say dear
God please show me what is therefore the correct attitude to have about that
error so Christianity teaches also that guilt that sin is really error so
instead of wallowing in guilt if you give yourself for the error and ask God
for clarity
of understanding yes all right so the view of God you see is here you're such
an a worm that God really despises you here's a vindictive God a great deal of
some major religions that picture God is vindictive he like gets even with you
for sin and then he condemns you and therefore God is really uncaring and
he's punitive and God's really vengeful
and a lot of traditional great religions make God sound as though he's
worse than the devil you know God's gonna get even with you and vengeful
it's like you've somehow injured God by being stupid here we have a you're so
you're so worthless that here God is indifferent to whether you survive you
don't survive yeah so the deal the pictures of God as you can see come out
of this world views as we move up we see the divinity becomes inspiring
merciful infinite wisdom infinite love finally oneness with our reality so love
is there for an aspect of divinity it's a reflection of divinity we have
permission to ask this question here
love.
Love is a reflection, the radiance of divinity, resist.
Love is the radiance of divinity, wow.
Love is the radiance of divinity.
Okay, I'm holding in mind a different idea about love.
This love is correct, resist.
Love is an attachment, we just asked that question.
Is love an aspect of divinity?
Agape is the highest form of love?
Or is it an attachment?
All right, because that has only come up recently
in our culture, I thought we should stomp it out
while it's still in its adolescent naivety.
The fact that we can become attached to something we love
is not an aspect of love, it's an aspect of attachment.
We get attached to the things to which we're attracted
to become attached.
But that is not love.
So you cannot say love is an attachment.
They are too independent.
Just like you can't say the atmosphere is rain
or the atmosphere is the sun.
The atmosphere is all inclusive of all possibilities, yes?
I did have a pointer sticker thing, didn't I?
No?
Well, now we're really in trouble.
How can you give a lecture without a pointer?
You know that.
All right.
So we wanted to go, has anybody got any questions
about the scale of consciousness?
It's relatively self-explanatory.
It's extremely useful, extremely useful.
And we listen to the news, we keep one eye on the news
to see what's happening with the world.
And then periodically we check a thing out with the arm.
And so we'll hear something absurd or ridiculous
or unbelievable.
And then we'll say, let's check that out.
All the people there couldn't be watching pornography
instead of watching the investments, but they were.
All these people were actually, well,
we have permission to ask this, we have permission to ask.
All these people actually were watching pornography.
So that's how Bernie Madoff got to be
where Bernie Madoff got.
Because the SEC, they were supposed to be watching Bernie Madoff
with all these billions of dollars of investor's money,
were actually watching porn.
You'd think people would get bored with porn
after watching it for a couple of hours or a couple of days,
a couple of weeks, a couple of months, a couple of years.
It must be a porn heaven.
You can spend all your life looking at porn.
And heaven is one giant pornographic scene.
Everybody's doing you-know-what everywhere.
Oh, I think this is very cool.
Look what you got there.
Yeah, you just hit that.
Oh, thank you.
Hit that front one.
It'll give you the dot.
Oh, that's a, okay, thank you very much.
There's a little dot.
Nobody can see it anyway, so I'll be good.
Now, what were we gonna talk about today?
I forgot already.
Did anybody remember what we were gonna talk about today?
What?
It says right here,
aftermath of consciousness comes what?
What comes next, Mrs.?
What comes here?
What's that circle there?
This is a graph of consciousness.
Okay, let's have the next slide.
Okay.
If you don't know something, just ask questions.
I think there's too much of a spot on this,
and it's drowning out the projector.
Is there any way we can turn off the spots on this slide?
That helps.
Does that help?
Can you see anything?
Here's the scale of consciousness again.
We still aren't getting a spot on here.
Is there any way to get these spots off the screen?
Seems to me we've had that trouble before.
I forget how we solved it.
Hmm?
That's as good as it gets.
All right, well, this is just the scale of consciousness,
showing that 85% of the world's population
lives below the level of 200.
Now, on the scale of consciousness,
truth calibrates from 200 on up to infinity.
Truth starts at level 200.
85% of the world's population calibrates below 200.
The implication of that is overwhelming.
overwhelming let us see if that is a fact 85% of the world lives below
conscious level 200 resist Wow so let's see we have permission to ask the level
of the world's consciousness right now is this Wow the world the world of
humans calibrates over 100 resist 150 180 190 199 200 205 the majority of
mankind lives at about 200 201 203 204 205 the world right now is it the world
right now Kurt is at 205 okay let's do America right now we have permission to
do
right now. He's over 410, 420, 415, 412. America's at 412. And the world is at 204, 205.
The world is at 204, and America is at 415, 412. Somebody can remember that out there.
America's at 412, and the world is at 204?
204, because we're down at 204.
Okay. That gives us an idea of where we are with the world.
The world's at 204. That's terrific, the fact that it's over 200.
You see, because the consciousness level of mankind was below 200 until actually relatively recently,
it was below 200. So the history of mankind is one of savagery and mutual raiding each other
and cannibalism and God knows what.
So what we call civilization is a really relatively recent in the last thousand years or so.
Okay. All right. So 85% of the world's population lives below this level right here,
which explains the phenomena.
85% of the world. So instead of being puzzled or overwhelmed or feeling badly about it,
it's just where mankind has evolved to by now. Okay.
85% of the world's population lives below the level of integrity. Integrity.
Lives below the level of integrity.
Next time somebody wants to borrow a thousand dollars, keep that in mind.
If somebody wants to borrow a thousand dollars from us, it's easy.
We just ask, this is a good idea.
So it's a very pragmatic system.
And the biologic reason for it, I've given in previous lectures,
that for life to survive, it must know that which is pro-life and it must know that which is anti-life.
If it didn't, it wouldn't live long enough to succeed.
So built into our living organism is the capacity to discern that which is useful and that which is poisonous.
If a bug doesn't know poison from food, then no more bug.
So because of the necessity of life then, because of life,
there is innately the capacity to discern that which is pro-life, that which is true,
and that which is anti-life, which is poisonous. Okay?
That seems like a simple enough explanation.
And it's actually all there is to it.
All right. So 85% of the world's population.
Now if we put this in a different form, you'll see.
The distribution of the levels of consciousness of mankind.
We see.
This whole pyramid is mankind.
We see that 85% of mankind is below level 200.
We see that only 15% is above.
So therefore, the survival of the world depends on this 15%.
And I'm presuming everybody here calibrates over, well, calibrates high enough.
Above 200.
Yes.
If you didn't calibrate 200 or over, you wouldn't be here.
Yeah, you wouldn't be here.
So everybody here calibrates extremely high, actually, in the 400s.
All right.
So here we see mankind.
And this helps you with being compassionate.
If you realize that 85% of mankind calibrates below 200.
85, the great masses of mankind, therefore, don't know truth from falsehood.
And will believe anything that you can convince them of.
Because they have no guidance towards truth and integrity.
There are people, there are cultures where if you don't cheat the customer, you get beaten.
If you don't cheat the customer, you get beaten when you get home.
No cultures are built that way.
All right.
What's the next slide, huh?
Here's the evolution of consciousness over time.
And you can see that the level and percentage of elapsed time, that it's only very recently,
it's only very, very recently that mankind suddenly evolved in a very forward, upward direction.
So mankind throughout most of history then,
was extremely primitive.
There are large parts of the world where man is still primitive.
Large parts of the world where people are still extremely primitive.
The idea that you serve God by killing your fellow human beings is a current dumb idea.
The way you please God is by killing people who don't think the way you think.
Okay.
And where that prevails dominates very important pieces of culture in the world today.
These earth epics, we have your earth epics and the amount of time that's going by.
And as you can see, the earth epics then have, you might say, speeded up.
Let's go to the next one.
We don't care about earth epics at all.
Sounds too scholastic, doesn't it?
We want to stay simple so that we can all comprehend what we're talking about.
So to keep it simple, I love animals because animals keep it simple.
And the animals exhibit these various qualities.
Various wonderful qualities.
Now we left the dog at home.
Let's see, where is Kelsey calibrated?
We have permission to calibrate Kelsey.
She's over 200.
Over 300.
She's over 250.
245.
Kelsey's over 240.
The doggy at home, my dog calibrates at 240.
The dog calibrates at 240.
And where do we say mankind rated?
You're safer with our doggy than most of mankind.
Why?
The dog loves.
The dog appreciates kindness.
Is a charitable person.
Is attracted to goodness, truth, and beauty.
You might say.
Yeah.
So therefore, that's very interesting, isn't it?
That animals calibrate higher than a large percentage of the human population.
You don't have to get depressed about it.
Just don't go there where they live.
Don't get on a plane with them.
Come here, buddy.
Why do you have to take your shoes off?
You got to take your shoes off to get on an airplane because somebody who calibrates less
than my dog is not bored.
I used to just worry about their shoes.
I have to try and keep a straight face.
Now I have to worry about what they got in their shorts.
Okay, buddy.
What a great job.
Thank you.
That must be a shorts inspector.
Oh, a shorts inspector.
Good God, man.
I'm glad our guards checked everybody's shorts on the way into this auditorium tonight.
The shorts inspector have checked you all out.
All right.
So in the animal kingdom then, where is the doggy?
Oh, yep.
Here's the dog's wagging tail.
500.
So Kelsey's tail on his wagon is 500.
And a kitty's purr is 500.
So animals are capable of exhibiting and feeling and returning love.
So we won't put down the animal kingdom anymore.
Seeing as dogs and cats calibrate higher than a large percentage of the population.
That is a shock.
That is a shock, is it not?
Well, we have at home a parrot.
What's her name?
Broccoli.
Broccoli speaks English.
Tell her what your parrot is saying recently.
Call my lawyer.
All the things that the bird knows Susan's taught her.
The bird, I mean, Susan has such a sense of humor.
She teaches the bird all these funny things.
So I'm sitting there watching the news and the bird is saying, call my lawyer.
That's her latest, call my lawyer.
She always says, mama's not happy, nobody's happy.
If mama's not happy, nobody's happy.
So you're better off with a pig that calibrates at 205 than many of the people in the world
who would like to praise you.
Praise God by blowing you up.
When I was like that, it'll say, busload of children, busload of 30 children blown up.
Then it'll name some group, claims credit.
Such a group, claims credit for blowing up the busload of children.
Claims credit, hysterical.
All right.
So Oscar the cat.
Oscar the famous cat.
Oscar is that cat that can tell when somebody is due to die within 24 hours.
You all know about Oscar the cat?
Ew, okay.
All right.
So I just want to, I think it's so interesting that the animal kingdom, the animal kingdom,
it shows the evolution of consciousness from the beginning right up to the highest levels of mankind.
So man actually calibrates lower than a lot of the animals on the planet.
You can't trust an alligator.
People are always fighting alligators.
Alligator fighters, alligators only calibrate at 45.
So people put their head in the mouth of an alligator.
Need a psychiatrist.
They think it's a well-trained alligator.
The alligator doesn't.
The alligator's strategy is we'll do this for about 20 times and then we're going to have dinner.
The alligator has you planned for dinner.
When an alligator invites you for dinner, he means he's going to have you for dinner.
All right.
So that is very interesting.
Just to give us an overall context.
An overall context of reality and how it has evolved up through the Komodo dragon, alligators, dinosaurs, whales, dolphins.
And dolphins are at 95.
That's very interesting.
Okay.
Any questions about the animals or is that enough?
That's enough about animals.
Okay.
We'll go on to more interesting things.
The great books of the Western world.
The great books of the Western world came out of the University of Chicago and are extremely well known around the world.
Great books of the Western world then recalibrate the intellectual foundation of Western society and the evolution of Western society.
And just for reference, some of these things are just good to know.
Aristotle calibrates at 500, 498, 498.
Aristotle.
Chaucer at 480.
Copernicus at 455.
Darwin, the evolution of the species, calibrates at 450.
Darwinism.
Descartes at 490.
Dostoevsky, 465.
Engels, 200.
Hmm.
Who was Engels' co-worker?
What was his name?
Who did Engels work with?
Oh, Karl Marx, 130.
Karl Marx calibrates at 130.
Therefore, we understand why the far left calibrates low.
Because the closer you get to Marxism, the lower the calibrated level of consciousness.
Marxism has been tried in several major countries, and it resulted in the starvation of 100 million people in one country and 10 million in another.
So I don't have much sympathy for Marxist concepts.
It's very good to know this is the background of Western culture as we know it today.
Immanuel Kant, Kepler, Herman Melville.
Isn't that an interesting list of people?
Plato at 485.
Well, when I grew up, we adolescents were sort of intellectuals, I guess, according to local standards.
Because we used to study Plato and discuss Plato and Socrates while other kids, I guess, were playing stickball or something.
I don't know what they were doing out there, but anyway.
Adam Smith, Sophocles, Tolstoy, Virgil.
Any question about the great books of the Western world?
It's a great thing to know of.
As I say, it came out of the University of Chicago.
I forget what year it was.
The great books of the Western world.
So there are whole universities.
There are universities whose name I forget.
Where the curriculum consists solely of...
It consists solely of studying the great books of the Western world.
I forget the name of the university.
The great books of the Western world is the curriculum.
Having studied them, you are more educated than people who go to ordinary universities,
which teach a great deal of things that are not particularly intellectual of great value.
The average university today...
We have permission to ask.
The average public university today...
Calibrates over 200, resist.
The average public university, supported by your taxes,
calibrates over 200, resist.
The average university, supported by your taxes,
where you send your children to be educated,
calibrates over 200, resist.
The average university in the United States does not even calibrate over 200.
All your hard-earned books to send them off to school.
So when you send them off to school, they calibrate high and they're bright.
And then when they come home again, you realize they have gone down,
have become some kind of strange phenomena,
because they've been brainwashed.
There's a book called Indoctrination.
Indoctrination U.
Explains the phenomena in our current world.
The world can go to hell in a handbasket if it wants to.
I have no objection.
It's okay to send your kids off to become educated idiots.
I have no objection to that.
I believe in freedom.
However, you should be aware of what it is you are doing
and what the consequences are.
And I think I did write about this phenomena in some recent book.
Yes.
Okay, so Marxism at 130 then explains the phenomena
and the low calibration below the low.
The level of reality explains why when it's tried in a country,
the country goes into starvation and the economy collapses.
Okay, next.
Now, this is the functions of the brain, left brain and right brain.
We see that below 200, you have the animal brain.
Below 200, you have left brain dominance.
Stress results in fight or flight.
The release of adrenaline.
Alarm reaction.
It releases killer cells into the body.
And there's a thymic test.
Ha, ha, ha.
So if you want to straighten out your energy field,
which has gotten reversed by bad energy,
by bad circumstances, bad environment, whatever,
you say to yourself, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
That's called the thymic film.
If you think of something, someone you love, it's even better.
So I think about Susie and I think, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
Okay.
I now calibrate up over 500.
600.
I calibrate over 600, 700.
I'm not going to do this.
You should tell everyone what you're calibrating at on this.
What?
I'm not going to do this.
Okay, okay.
Never mind.
Anyway.
The thymic thump is how you recover from your energy being blown out
by something very negative happening.
So below 200, then, the left brain dominates.
Stress releases adrenaline.
The fight or flight phenomena disrupts the acupuncture meridians
and results in disease.
So negative thinking and negative environments, then,
eventually lead to activation of the disease process.
Disease process.
People want to know, how can I get well?
Well, you do the opposite of what leads you over there.
Above 200, the emotion of being loving towards everyone.
Peace and lovingness release endorphins.
It releases the killer cells that kill off diseases.
Increases immunity.
Increases healing.
Balances the acupuncture system.
And you get a positive muscle test response,
the test that we do with each other.
And therefore, you try to stay in a positive environment
with a positive attitude and let go of negativity
because it has a deleterious effect physiologically
as well as psychological and emotional.
Okay.
Next.
The cause of social problems.
There's all kinds of theories of what causes social problems.
But when we correlate the levels of consciousness and social problems,
we see that what accounts for unemployment,
poverty, happiness, and criminality,
all these things are explained, not by sociologic phenomena.
Cleaning up the neighborhood, let's say, should get rid of criminality.
But it doesn't.
Why?
Because of the level of consciousness.
So the level of consciousness is 600 and over.
Unemployment is zero.
Poverty is zero.
Happiness is 100%.
Criminality is zero.
As the level of consciousness goes down,
for the 400s to the 500s,
the rate of unemployment is 2%.
Rate of poverty is 0.5%.
Happiness is 70%.
And criminality is, again, very small, 2%.
So the higher the level of consciousness,
you see the more these phenomena become positive.
The level of consciousness, then,
is the main determinant of what we consider to be social problems.
Poverty is not due to poverty-ism.
It's people with a low level of consciousness
are prone to poverty.
People with a higher level of consciousness
will become successful no matter where you put them.
And if you put me in a poverty neighborhood,
I'm going to find out what poverty people buy
and start selling it.
That's what the criminal does.
They like heroin, so we'll sell heroin, right?
All right, so we'll go on to the next slide.
And correlational levels of consciousness
and rate of happiness.
100% of enlightened people are happy.
100 people who came...
100% of people calibrated over 600, the 500s.
Over 590% of the people are happy.
The rest are kooks of some kind.
People dominated by a reason, 80% are happy.
People dominated by neutrality, 60% are happy.
People dominated by courage, 55% are happy.
So the higher levels of consciousness, then,
are correlated with greater satisfaction,
pleasure, and happiness in life,
and a much lower arrest rate.
They're not likely to end up on welfare.
All right, dominated, then,
by the lesser levels of consciousness,
you can see that the number of people who are happy
becomes lower and lower.
Prideful people are...
Pride goes before a fall.
Angry people, we all avoid angry people.
People who are addicted to cravingness and desiringness.
People that are dominated by fear, grief.
Down here, apathy and hatred.
And finally, guilt.
And we said the way to get off guilt
is stop being egocentric.
Nobody cares about your guilt except you,
so get rid of it.
Next time you feel guilty, just say,
that's just egocentricity and I don't need it.
Instead of guilt, just learn to do better.
Instead of being condemning towards people,
become forgiving.
You don't have to feel guilty about condemning them.
Okay, there we go, the next level.
Next one.
These are the spiritual teachers.
People very often write us about spiritual teachers,
and we get a lot of emails and mail about it.
Spiritual teachers.
And so we listed it.
This isn't the complete list, but it's quite a few.
It covers 90% of the great spiritual teachers in the world.
More than 90%.
Great teachers of all time.
And we list what their level,
the level of consciousness that they represent.
Uh-huh.
Aurobindo Black Elk.
Jacob Bohm.
Swami Bhutananda.
Eric Butterworth.
Kelvin Confucius.
Dalai Lama.
All these people represent truth of various levels.
It's useful primarily for orientation, you know,
for orientation,
so that you can tell where you are
in your own belief systems.
Uh-huh.
Nisargadatta Maharaj.
I always liked Nisargadatta.
I like that name.
I had to have another name.
You can call me Nisargadatta if you want.
Calibrate to 720.
That'll be fine.
That'll last this lifetime.
Okay, let's go to the next one.
Spiritual teachers continued.
Oh, there's a lot of them, aren't there?
So we have listed in some of our books,
and we just re-present it here for the reminder
that we have calibrated all the great teachers
throughout all of time.
It's useful.
It's a practical, pragmatic usefulness.
Alan Watts, et cetera,
and Sri Yukteswar.
Okay.
That covers the great majority of questions
that we get have to do with various spiritual teachers
and whether that person calibrates well.
And, of course, what we mean by well is over 200, you know?
There are some well-known spiritual teachers,
but they do not calibrate over 200,
and we won't mention them.
Okay, next slide.
People question divinity of Jesus Christ.
The great avatars, the great spiritual teachers of all time,
all collectively calibrate around 1,000.
On our scale of consciousness,
Jesus Christ at 1,000,
the Buddha at 1,000,
Krishna at 1,000,
Zoroaster at 1,000,
the Apostles,
the name of God is Om,
John the Baptist,
Moses, Abraham,
St. Paul,
Muhammad after, before, and after age,
certain age, yeah.
All right, so this really confirms
the level of spiritual truth
taught by some of the most famous
and greatest teachers throughout all of time.
We'll go to the next one, huh?
This is all about love.
Love is warmth, appreciation,
forgiving, inclusive,
cordiality, it's uplifting.
So love is giving, uplifting,
generosity, sharing.
There's an inner humility,
gratitude,
and a certain sweetness to love.
We'll move to the next slide.
Who could that be?
That's today's media.
This is Washington, D.C.
The wolf in sheep clothing.
We're here, we're from the government,
and we're here to help you.
We're from the government,
All right, so illusions versus reality.
So one thing that's useful about
the scale of consciousness
and the calibration technique
is that you break through illusion.
You break through the illusion,
the whole world can be convinced of something,
and yet your arm tells you that it's otherwise.
Should you believe the whole world
or your own self?
Well, you recheck your technique
and make sure you're correct.
And if the arm says something,
that's the reality,
and what the world believes is not the reality.
Therefore, students of this work
are in a unique position.
Being sometimes the only people on the planet
that really are aware of what the truth is
or have access to it.
Frankly, nobody else does.
Because they are persuaded by the media.
And the media can be very convincing.
The media and the politicians
and all the publicizers
can be very convincing.
And yet somehow they make your arm go weak.
So it's very useful.
It's a great gift to have.
To be able to tell the level of truth,
whether a thing is real or not real.
To understand whether...
So you can also say, you know,
this is a good neighborhood to open a hardware store.
And you've got a weak arm, no.
So you can see its pragmatic usefulness
in everyday life.
This is a good lady for me to start dating
and going out with.
This is a good gentleman for me to date.
Yep.
Useful in every area of life.
Personal relationships, business, politics,
scientific truth, et cetera.
Let's take a current scientific doctrine.
We have permission to ask this here.
The Earth is warming up due to human...
due to human influences.
Wait.
You hit me wrong.
Earth warming...
Let's see.
Earth warm...
Let me ask you a different...
Okay.
Earth warming is due to the magnetic electrical activity
of the surface of the sun.
Resist.
All right.
Earth warming is due to sunspots.
Resist.
Earth warming is not due to human activity.
All right.
Because that is always in the news recurrently, you know.
That if you...
Humans can only change their lifestyle,
then the Earth...
the Earth would cool down.
And we know that it has to do with magnetic activity
of the surface of the sun,
the so-called sunspots.
And when they shoot out zillions of volts
of electric...
electronic radiation,
that's what influences the temperature of the Earth.
Okay.
All right.
So that was the picture of Earth warming
we just had there before.
All right.
Now we're going to get to the subject for today.
So...
What we're going to be talking about
is today.
What time is it?
Fifteen minutes.
Huh?
We have about fifteen minutes.
And then what?
A break?
And then a break.
All right.
Okay.
Pepsi Max, boy.
Pepsi used to give me a buzz,
but Pepsi Max, wow.
I can leap over mountains.
What we're talking about today
is we're going to go through the human lifetime
from beginning to end,
looking at the stresses,
the spiritual challenges
of...
of human life.
So we're going to cover
the entire human lifetime
and see how best to handle
the various stresses
to which humans are automatically subjected
from the very moment of birth.
Okay.
So the stress.
In early life,
birth itself is a sensory overwhelm.
I frankly remember my own birth.
I remember it.
I remember the powerful,
the powerful contractions
going down over me.
I remember then emerging
out of warm darkness
and safety and security
into bright lights.
First of all,
the lights were so bright
it was blinding.
And it was cold.
And it was loud.
Voices.
The voices of people
were overwhelmingly loud.
The environment was cold.
It was no longer
strong.
It was cold.
And then you're no longer safe
and warm and secure.
No.
So you start out
like behind an eight ball.
And a negative sensory overwhelm.
And,
of course,
you haven't eaten yet
and you're hungry.
It's cold.
Noisy.
The lights are blinding.
Then you go through
separation anxiety,
the emotion of fear.
Suddenly you go from
a familiar,
quiet,
dark,
warm place.
And,
we can assist this delivery
the early life by midwifery
so nowadays
midwives birth the infant
child into a warm
tub of water
a warm tub of water
one of the first phenomena that happens
as soon as you're born
is the phenomena of imprinting
whatever you're surrounded with
you imprint
and that becomes your mother
this has a profound effect on the rest of your life
because what you imprinted on
is there relatively
permanently
and you will always associate that with
safety and security
in whatever went on
at that moment
or if it was the other way around
your midwifery was bad and they weren't put in warm water
and
made to feel secure
you're going to be afraid of every new
situation
every new situation
you're going to be afraid of
and you'll be afraid of every new situation
I had a baby duck
I had some fertile duck eggs
back home when I was a kid in the midwest
and the duck eggs were due to hatch
and so this one
the mother duck got off the eggs
and wouldn't sit on it
so I took the duck egg
which is ready to hatch any old day
and I stuck it in my pocket
and kept it warm that way
so I kept the duck egg in my pocket
for a couple of days
finally I could feel the pecking feeling there
and the ducky wanted out
so I took the little duckling out
and set it down in a nice warm place
and I thought the duckling needed some help getting out of the shell
so I cheated a little
and I cracked the shell with my thumbnail like that
and here's this little wet little duckling
well the little duckling
I dried him up and warmed him up
and carried him around where it was warm
so the little duckling grew up
from early life
right next to my chest
where I kept it warm under my sweater
or my scarf, whatever
so the duckling's name was Peep Peep
so I would go out in the backyard
and when I went out in the backyard
the little duckling would come racing across the lawn
Peep Peep Peep Peep Peep Peep Peep Peep Peep Peep Peep Peep Peep
because it thought I was its mother
so what we imprint on then
then
we tend to hold that as a mother
that's a very interesting thing to know
so whatever you are strangely attracted to very often
you ask yourself what could I have imprinted on
in early child, in childbirth
so imprinting then lasts a lifetime
and will always be a very warm source of
so mothers are traditionally
because that's usually the first person you see is your mom
nobody else
so the mother has traditionally been
that which sustains
creates and sustains life
so the mother is greatly revered
in all cultures, especially our culture
not especially but in all cultures
the mother
really reigns supreme
the mother is necessary for a few seconds
and you can get rid of him
thanks a lot George
many months later he's off on the other side of the world
with some other bimbo
and his mom
everything relies on mother
so the mother in our culture
the mother on a certain level is almost divine
to speak against or turn against your mother
and she's extremely unthinkable
and not thinkable
so midwifery tries to overcome
the negative impact
and out of this you arise with an attitude
either an optimist or a pessimist
life is either half empty
or half full
I you see so
the birth phenomena then determines
whether you're going to be an optimist or a pessimist
whether you're going to be secure and feel safe or you're going to feel that life is dangerous.
So we see right from birth itself, from the first few hours of life, it already sets your attitude.
This is a safe world, life is safe, or it's a dangerous world.
And your whole idea of security, half full or half empty, is life half full or half empty?
The optimist versus the pessimist.
So here this attitude is already set practically after birth.
Let's go to the next one.
Then after the birth phenomena comes childhood itself.
What has been your experience of affection?
What has been your experience of trust?
Then what has been your experience of siblings and rivalry?
To be an only child is much different than being one of two children,
which is much different than being...
being one of three, which is much different than being one of five.
The next thing that sets our attitudes is the kind of discipline involved.
Some people use positive discipline, other people use negative.
Our sense of confidence arises out of our childhood.
If you got strokes, for being good and productive, or whether you were just ignored.
So this whole idea of good versus bad.
Whether you're a good person, whether life is good, or you're a bad person, life is bad.
Having bad circumstances at birth very often leads to the chronic criminals.
Life has been bad from the very beginning.
Bad mothering, bad environment, bad companions, bad energy.
The next thing that really influences us considerably is birth order.
Were you the oldest of all, the youngest of all, the middle child?
You know?
The...
Traditionally, certain phenomena happen.
If you're the oldest child, or if you're the youngest one, what the birth order is.
The next thing that sets up our attitudes is our experiences.
Our experiences in schooling.
Our experiences in religion.
Our knowledge and awareness of having a soul.
The capacity for reverence and for spirituality.
The preoccupation with heaven or hell.
Are you...
Are you really energized by the desire to move to heaven?
Or is it merely a fear of hell?
So sin and guilt then bring up all the whole fears of hell.
Parenting skills then and bringing these things across to the child.
And the physical health and heredity are profound factors in influencing our...
Our attitudes throughout all of life.
So the reason we're looking at these things is because these are life...
These are life attitudes.
Everybody sitting out here in the audience right now has been profoundly interested by all these things in their life.
And a self-aware person looks at all these various phenomena in their life and comes to a certain understanding about why they are the way they are.
Does everybody here know why they are the way they are?
Anybody don't know why they are the way they are?
You don't know why they are the way they are?
Where'd you go?
Ha ha ha.
Well, you need a psychiatrist.
That's where the psychiatrist comes in.
To help us to adjust to the phenomena that we don't seem to be able to just grasp in ordinary life.
So then we'll move on from childhood to the next level.
What happens after childhood?
What happens after childhood then is adolescence.
So if we can successfully come out of childhood then...
We come out into adolescence.
Where again we are in a world of world events.
It's either a dangerous world or a safe world.
It's an emotional climate.
Then adolescence financial adequacy of the family and yourself.
The amount of social acceptance.
The education that you receive.
Your friends and comrades.
The emergence of sexuality and hormones.
And your preparation for it.
And here of course we're profoundly involved in heredity.
So the attitudes that we grow up with then are, as you can see, the result of a complex interaction of biologic and social and family, cultural and relationship.
Next.
Then the next thing after you've been through that battering ramble.
That battering ramble of whammies.
You now become an adult.
Oh my God.
And now the problems really start.
What am I going to do?
What am I going to be in this world?
Am I going to be getting married or be single?
Am I going to be heterosexual or homosexual?
Am I going to be part of a group?
Am I going to be isolated?
Marriage and the family become extremely important.
And again, adverse effects can happen to you in searching for success.
And we're all affected without our really being aware of it, of world conditions.
I tend to keep my eye on the news and periodically throughout the day catch up with world events.
Because world conditions affect your own emotional attitudes and expectations without your being aware of it.
You say, well, that's all happening out there.
But out there is actually where you live.
Out there is really you can turn the TV set around and see that you are the out there.
Of course, your health profoundly affects you and your financial situation.
Aging has its own profound effects on attitudes and your politics, political, your intellectual capacity and interests.
If your interests are in the 400s.
If you're intellectually interested in the great books of the Western world, you will end up more philosophic and sophisticated.
We have the introvert versus the extrovert.
And of course, we're all profoundly affected by our physical appearance.
Some people like myself are good looking.
I have to fight off the women.
Some of us have to adjust to the fact that we are not looking like Hollywood.
Yeah.
But does happiness depend on that?
No.
I've known some ugly, really ugly people.
They're hard to look at.
We're extremely happy.
And some beautiful people, extremely miserable.
And as a psychiatrist, I saw them all.
Handsome young men have a negative self-image and should be out there and successful in every area.
Lovely women who...
So we have to surmount.
These are the things that we have to surmount.
And by our spiritual evolution, we transcend these things which to other people are limitations.
So I don't want anybody out there to have any limitations.
Cross out all limitations.
You're an unlimited being.
You're subject only to what you hold in mind.
You're only subject to what you hold in mind.
If you think you're stupid and ugly, I got news for you.
You're stupid and ugly.
If you think you're lovable, then you are lovable.
If you think you're not lovable, then you're not lovable.
So we really become that which we hold in mind.
And that's why we went through these things.
These are things that people just take for granted without thinking about it, unless you're in psychoanalysis.
And have to lay there and discuss all these things with your analyst.
And the average person then has to surmount all these obstacles to fulfillment.
And go through these obstacles in order to reach enlightenment.
So we're interested primarily in reaching the levels of enlightenment.
And therefore we want to successfully transcend all these stresses of ordinary life.
Good enough?
Everybody for enlightenment?
So you work like a dog to reach enlightenment.
And then you realize there's nobody to become enlightened.
You thought there was somebody or some individual that's going to become enlightened.
And you find out that that's fiction.
You wasted your life pursuing fiction.
That you're going to become enlightened.
And then you discover there is nobody to become enlightened.
What a relief.
Nobody here has to become enlightened.
You don't have to buy into that goal of life.
You say, heck with enlightenment.
I just want to be stupid and ugly.
To be happy if you're stupid and ugly means you're enlightened.
Alright, so we're going to take a break for how long?
For about 15 minutes.
We're going to take a 15 minute break.
I want everybody to stay out of trouble for 15 minutes.
Can you stay out of trouble for 15 minutes?
That's the question.