Oh, my goodness sakes.
I'm trying to be serious.
This is a very serious meeting today.
We're going to be talking about God.
Who warned me he was listening?
In which case I will take care.
Not to say anything stupid or foolish.
Which is impossible.
We say glory and excelsis Deo.
All praise and glory be to Thee, O Lord, Most High.
Amen.
What?
Well, I don't care.
If they can do so, if they wish.
I forgot what we were going to talk about today, honey.
Do you remember?
Do you remember what we're talking about today?
Oh, what are we talking about today?
You said God.
God?
Oh, yes, I thought so.
Well, we have slides that guide us on our journey.
And so we have a number of interesting things.
People have opinions.
You know, we have opinions.
It has to do with spiritual reality, spiritual reality in today's world.
In today's world.
So we're going to look at a number of things about today's world
and try to see the truth within them or the falsehood, whichever it may be.
So how to tell truth from falsehood is a great gift.
It was a gift.
It was a gift I received that suddenly I saw how to tell truth from falsehood.
And it certainly makes everything in the world much easier to comprehend.
And things that we condemn as a moral problem, we find out with a little research or biologic,
biologic fate, biologic.
And it clarifies like 6.5% of both men and women are born.
And it clarifies like 6.5% of both men and women are born homosexual, right?
6.5% is genetic.
So it's not a moral problem.
It also occurs in the animal kingdom.
It occurs in the animal kingdom 6.5% no matter what culture or what nationality.
So that totally changes the whole scene.
So calibrating the energies of things within the world helps us to clarify our understanding.
So that totally changes the whole scene. So calibrating the energies of things within the world helps us to clarify our understanding.
We don't know if there's something we're supposed to forgive or something we're supposed to worship or something we're supposed to pay money to.
So by using the air and we clarify things that man has never known before.
And it changes our attitude towards the world and what our spiritual responsibility is.
All right.
So now if we're going to have questions later.
So we'll just start with the slides.
We have interesting slides that we put together for today's lecture,
and they will appear someplace.
Do you know where they're going to appear, honey?
Oh, my gosh.
I was a little frightened there for a second.
Looks like somebody spilled paint on here.
Map of consciousness.
Oh, yes.
We always start with this.
How many people are here for the first time to one of my lectures?
All right.
So God bless you all.
My sympathy is with you because we're going to explain
and comprehend things that have never been explained
or comprehended before in the history of mankind.
So that gives us something entertaining to do today.
We start with the map of consciousness,
which has become pretty much world famous.
It's in all the major languages,
in the world,
and is a basic map to which we can refer to clarify.
If we know what a thing calibrates at,
we can tell the degree of truthfulness.
And so truth calibrates on the scale of one to a thousand.
Truth calibrates 200 and up.
And,
uh,
that which is negative or false or untrue calibrates below 200.
So the villains of history you'll find if you calibrate them.
Here's where the villains of history,
Adolf Hitler and all the people that have caused so much damage and suffering in the world,
uh,
tend to calibrate down here.
Um,
in world leaders is very often calibration level about 170 or so,
uh,
pridefulness and contempt for the ordinary person.
Yeah.
All right.
So yes,
that's surprise.
Yes.
So the president is here after all.
And here he comes.
Uh huh.
Um,
the Sedona study group has,
um,
they have,
uh,
delegated and they're having a bagpiper come in for you.
Oh my God.
My favorite.
So he's going to start playing for you.
Oh my God.
The bagpipers are going to be here today.
Yes.
We hit,
we have a bagpiper.
Oh my God.
So this is kind of a surprise.
I just calibrated 500,
550,
500 Celsius deal.
All praise and glory be to the old Lord.
Who is Ty?
I'll have to recover from now.
You know what calibration 500 sounds like.
That's 500.
The language of the heart,
the language of the heart of mankind.
That's why it brings tears to the eyes of most people.
And it brings terror to the heart of the enemy.
When they hear that sound coming over the hill because it means either victory or death.
So there isn't going to be any in between.
So I wouldn't start a fight with anybody at that sound unless you're willing to either win.
Win the fight or die one or the other.
You're not going to have any choice in between.
All right.
So we thought you might like to know what 500 sounds like.
So there it is up there.
Huh?
The 500 is up there and the essence of it is reverence.
Uh huh.
Reverence and reverence brings,
uh,
that's what brings tears to the eyes of people when they hear that because there's a mysterious,
energy decalibration level 500,
especially when it is played on bagpipes.
That's a super special.
So that was a surprise to me and I thank you very much.
And I think the Piper,
God bless you.
Uh huh.
So we start with this famous map of consciousness,
which is they say no one throughout the world.
Now most of the world's languages and is a common point of reference.
If we say,
I think calibrates at a certain level,
that tells us really,
uh,
what there is essentially to know about anything.
So let's go to the next slide.
Let's go.
That's the map of consciousness.
Oh yes.
You want to know the distribution of the world's consciousness and we find that 85% of the world's population calibrates below 200.
Is that right?
It says 85% of the world's population.
Calibrates below 200 well the level of reality and uh sanity it starts at 200 so if 85% of the world's population calibrates below 200 that would explain the history of mankind let's see if that's still the same we have permission to ask this 85% of the population of mankind overall.
Uh huh.
Calibrates below level 200 resist.
My God is true.
Huh.
How do we survive?
So you would expect if 85% of the world's population is below 200,
which means non integrates means they'll commit war and steal and stab you to death and cheat you if you don't want your money.
So watch your money.
Keep a hand on your money when you walk down the street.
That's funny,
but I've walked down the streets of some foreign countries and the little street urges would crawl all over you when you walk down the street,
you see about six or eight of them and they run past you and they run past you.
Their hands go everywhere.
They're in your socks up your pants leg in your in your crotch under your arm looking for your money and I found the simplest way.
Is to take a bunch of dollar bills and when they little urchins street urchins come for you,
you throw them this way.
You throw the money this way.
You run this way.
That's the secret of travel in certain foreign countries.
Take a lot of single dollar bills,
throw them this way and run this way.
Yeah,
otherwise you won't return home with your wallet.
So you see,
you can accept that.
That is,
once you know the facts,
once you know the truth of it,
you can accept the reality without being upset emotionally without morally condemning it.
You can say,
well,
it has to do with the evolution of mankind.
The evolution of mankind is such that only 15% transcend consciousness level 200.
All right,
so and of course,
the high,
consciousness levels what you're over here,
you can see here's the majority of mankind from this point over the majority of mankind.
Now what remains of mankind calibrates 200 and over as you can see becomes very,
very few.
So 250 300 400 by 500 the sound of the bagpipes we've lost most of mankind and very few people will
resonate at at 500 and over.
So these are the levels of unconditional love,
unconditional love.
So love is 500 and over.
Yes,
unconditional love is 570 and over.
All right,
unconditional love.
So here we see what mankind looks like.
So you feel more compassionate towards the world and its events when you realize people can't help but be the way they are.
Only 85% of the world's population calibrates below 200 only 15% are above so ethical ethical intelligence and sanity.
You can only expect from about 15% of the world's population and that 15% seldom become dictators or something like that.
You know Adolf Hitler is not in the 15%.
Some researcher recently wrote that he was the most evil man that ever lived.
I don't know.
Anyway,
he caused the death of millions of innocent people for no apparent reason other than self-glorification.
Yeah.
Okay,
the next slide up there.
We distribution of the levels of consciousness of mankind a different way of portraying it.
So you're looking at a world in which 85% over here.
And only 15% over here.
The thing is this 15% are so powerful.
This 15% is so powerful that it totally cali counterbalances the 85% who calibrate below 200.
So we give thanks then for the 15% above 200.
Now this audience here.
This audience here is part of the people responsible for the survival of mankind.
That's a fact.
Thank you.
All right,
this audience here counterbalances the negativity of tens of millions.
This audience right here present you folks sitting in the chair are counterbalancing the negative effect of tens of millions of people who are nefarious and evil by intent.
And action.
Uh-huh.
It wasn't for you.
Society would probably collapse.
Society would collapse.
Yes.
So we thank this audience here present for helping to hold up the world.
Thanks again.
You knew you were here for some reason today.
Keep the world humanity going.
All right.
What's the next one?
We got here.
The evolution of consciousness in over time.
You see that the evolution of consciousness percent of elapsed time.
And here you see it doesn't even start till you get over to here.
The consciousness level barely moves at all for millennia.
The age of the dinosaurs and the animal kingdom and the beginning of primitive man.
Neanderthal man.
And so over 85% of elapsed time finally 80 about 80% of elapsed time the consciousness level of living things begins to rise and then suddenly it goes up.
So here's where we happily are now where the consciousness level of mankind is skyrocketing skyrocketing and we'll go on to the next thing.
Yeah.
Let's see.
I'm trying to read this.
Oh, these are the a specific ages Jurassic and all such.
We don't need to go into that.
That's too academic.
Uh-huh.
But we can look at the animal kingdom.
That'll give us an idea of where we stand whether we're more intelligent than the animals or not.
Everybody thinks anybody think we were more intelligent than the animals raise your hand.
Anybody think we're not as intelligent as the animals raise your hand.
That's true.
My dog is smarter than a lot of people.
She knows goodness from badness and friends from foe.
And so it's interesting the animal kingdom as we see the evolution of consciousness then throughout time throughout creation.
And on this scale of the.
Animal kingdom bacteria start at one and then insects are six fish are up to 20 the octopus is at 20 the shark is at 24 the Komodo dragon is at 40 the reptile kingdom calibrates at 40 the hyena the lions and the tigers calibrated 40 we have a lion that lives around our house.
Let's calibrate that lion.
That guy I saw.
When I see around our house is a mountain lion who it calibrates over 40 45 that mountain lion calibrates at 40 that mountain lion would eat me if it had a chance.
Okay, I'll mind you after this honey.
I will not go out after dark all by myself and.
Yeah, that mountain lion.
I'm holding him in my mind.
Right now.
I see him on back number of times and the only calibrates at 40 alligators are not too friendly either there.
And a dinosaur is not too friendly and whales start getting a little more friendly at 85 the dolphin at 85 and the migratory bird calibrates at 105.
That's very interesting now birds of prey 105.
Rodents 105 like mice mice songbirds are up to 125 the dove.
Interestingly the symbol of peace calibrates at 145 polar bears are very smart creatures 160 grizzly bears so polar bears and grizzly bears.
You got to be sort of careful because their consciousness level is 160.
And at 160 they're capable of figuring out what you're up to.
So if you think you're setting him for something the bear has already got you figured out the water buffalo is the most dangerous animal.
They say a water buffalo with no warning will suddenly turn and attack you with no advance warning.
The wolf is at 190 the hippopotamus.
I like the old hippo calibrates at 190.
Now we get to the.
More friendly animals you see this is below 200 the wolf the jackal the fox and then we get up to 200 and we we change the whole attitude the animal kingdom below 200 is dangerous to hang out with 200 and over the ambience changes dramatically.
So consciousness level 200 you get to the animals that are not predacious.
You and they are the grazers such as zebras gazelles giraffes the deer at 205.
I have never been an enthusiast of killing deer.
If you want some meat for dinner go to the Walmarts or go to the supermarket and buy it.
I grew up in a in Wisconsin and getting a deer was people's biggest ambition to get a deer for Thanksgiving.
And I could never go for it.
My father was the same way he wants.
Got a deer in the sights of his rifle and he couldn't pull the trigger.
He said I got I got the essence of that deer's innocence.
And I couldn't pull the trigger.
He says I can just go to the supermarket and buy a steak.
At domestic Piggy is 205.
And the elk we have a lot of elk around.
Where we live are at 210 and elk is a very big animal and elk stands about seven feet tall.
Doesn't it?
They're Giants out there.
I look out the window and I say my God.
There's there's seven feet.
Those Elk are seven feet.
Wow, don't mess with an elk seven feet.
If he gives you gets mad and gives you a kick you go flying.
I belong to the Elks so
they have a great Thanksgiving dinner.
I like to go over here.
All right.
So now we're going through the animal Kingdom just so we get a sense of the energy fields.
What they calibrate and what kind of life that represents the cattle the elephant the farm horse and my favorite kitties.
How many kitty lovers are there here?
Oh ready for kitty lovers.
I've got three kitties and they calibrate at 240 the family cat calibrates at 245.
Then we get up to dogs 245 is still family dog.
No family dog is a 250.
Okay.
How many people here love dogs?
Oh any dog haters here?
No, they don't dare raise their hand.
No.
Yeah, family dog is guarding our house right now.
And everybody knows how intelligent and wonderful.
So the dogs interesting and played a very important part in man in mankind.
Now all kinds of rescue dogs and here heroic dogs and the family dog at 250.
The monkeys are also very intelligent.
I used to have a monkey gorillas even smarter and the chimpanzee is smarter yet.
Here's some famous animals here.
Oscar the cat remember is Oscar the one who knows when somebody's going to die.
Yeah, he's at 250 Oscar is that famous cat that if a patient is going to die within the next 24 hours Oscar climbs in bed with them.
And so far he's scored a hundred percent.
So if you see Oscar.
Wanted to get in bed with you.
You know that your time has arrived.
Uh huh.
We have a trained African.
We have a African gray parrot at home.
And what can you say about our our African gray parrot?
So intelligent.
I keep thinking there's some kind of human consciousness behind this parrots talking because you'll say things that just knock you over.
So if you've got three cats a dog and a and a parrot, you're pretty well loaded with the animal kingdom.
Here's our famous trained gorilla Coco Coco's story is a very heartwarming on.
I don't know if you remember when Coco saved the baby's life of baby at the zoo with the mother.
Huh?
It wasn't Coco.
It was a different gorilla.
Huh?
A zoo gorilla, but not Coco.
Oh, okay.
But you remember when the woman dropped her baby into the
where the wild animals were and the gorilla went over and picked it up and carefully saved the baby's life and put it by the door.
So the mother could come and get it.
All right.
So the songbirds song is that 500.
So that's the same energy then as we heard with the bagpipes 500.
Here's some other mystical things.
Cats purr.
Calibrates at 500 cats purr at 500.
So having kitties around the purr tend to make you happy and a more benign person.
It's hard to kill people when you're a kitty lover.
If you love dogs wagging tail and kitties purr, it's very hard to kill people.
Yeah, you got to keep them out of the barracks.
The dog's wagging tail is at 500.
So here's the world of pet lovers.
And I used to treat a lot of patients.
You know, I had a huge psychiatric practice.
And when I got a single person who was depressed and all that, I told him, I won't treat you unless you get a kitty or a dog.
And they all thought I was a little bit crazy.
But if you're not interested enough in love to enjoy a cat's purr, a dog's wagging tail.
Then all your problem is you're just completely egocentric.
Everybody needs something and someone to love and to love back and to reflect that love as a prevailing reality.
Okay, what's next here?
Oh, wow.
This must be the great books of the Western world.
Is that what it is?
Yes, great books in the Western world.
There's a university based on the great books of the Western world.
Which we'll mention again later.
The most important thing on this for our for our culture is where is Marx and Engels?
I wonder.
Yeah.
Oh, here.
Yeah, because that demarcates a certain level.
A very important level in the evolution of our world and our culture and politics.
So that'll arise later.
It's important to know that Marx calibrates at 130.
Yeah, because later on we're going to calibrate institutions, which have become sort of programmed with Marxian concepts.
And we'll notice that they calibrate very low.
All right.
So the reason is Marx is at 130.
That's why they calibrate low.
Uh-huh.
All right.
And here we got market market.
Machiavelli and various bad actors over time.
I think it's very interesting to look at the great books of the Western world.
Plato at 485.
Shakespeare 465.
Adam Smith.
That's the wealth of Nations or the wealth of Nations.
Adam Smith is very important in America.
Uh-huh.
Although you may not have heard of him.
But he is of great importance.
So I think this is of extreme benefit to students to be familiar.
To just know that such a map, such a map of the great books of the Western world exists because it gives you something.
Freud is at 499 or Freud was at 499.
Let's see.
Freud was at 499.
Yeah, that's the top of the intellect.
My psychoanalyst, when I was in analysis, calibrates over 499, 500.
He calibrated 499.
So my psychoanalyst, I had a classical psychoanalysis going on four or five years.
I forget what.
And that was at 499.
It's good to know.
Hmm.
That's where it is.
Yes.
All right.
We'll move on to the next.
Uh, hmm.
This has to do with the way the brain functions.
You see, throughout evolution, we have inherited a left brain and a right brain.
And it makes quite a bit of difference.
Whether you process things through the left brain or the right brain.
And below 200, below consciousness level 200, the left brain is in charge.
And it's mainly concerned with fight or flight.
And, uh, has to do with stress and disease and negative muscle tests.
Below 200, then.
Below 200, when I press down on her arm, if it calibrates below 200, her arm goes weak.
So it's a biologic response.
Biologic.
It's not arbitrary.
A negative muscle test response indicates below 200.
All right.
That's very important.
That's very important to know.
On the positive side, above 200, is the right brain.
Now, the right brain, the left brain puts out, uh, alarm reaction, adrenaline.
And, uh, things having to do with fright and rage.
Above consciousness level 200, the right brain dominates.
And you have, uh, positive emotion.
You also have greater healing, greater immunity.
Therefore, the higher the level of consciousness, the greater your resistance to disease of all kinds.
You know?
Okay.
We'll go.
Any questions about, uh, what we've said?
Better not have any.
Better not, yeah.
The impact.
The levels of consciousness and the social problems.
See, so it's not just academic.
It's of great importance.
As you can see.
The level of consciousness is 600 and over.
Unemployment is zero.
Crime is zero.
Poverty is zero.
Happiness is 100%.
And the rate of criminality is 0%.
Uh-huh.
So, if you got somebody working for you, the best thing to do is calibrate them.
Tells you whether you gotta lock up your money or you can leave it around loose on the table.
Level of consciousness.
Uh, as you.
As it goes up, you see, unemployment becomes zero.
Poverty is zero.
Unhappiness is zero.
And as the level of consciousness goes down, you see the rate of unemployment, uh, uh, skyrockets.
When you get to the lower levels of consciousness, you see that unemployment is about 50%.
The rate of poverty is already about 25%.
Low.
Only 10 or 15% of people think life is okay.
And the rate of criminality is about 50%.
Uh-huh.
So you can see, not all of mankind's problems can be solved by passing a law.
Uh, passing a law.
Uh, committing a crime is already against the law.
It's already against the law.
Alright, next thing.
Next thing.
A rate of happiness, as you can see.
Uh, so the, the level of consciousness, uh, here, it runs up to a thousand.
Enlightenment cali, it calibrates 700 and over.
700 and over.
Uh, mental peace calibrates 600 and over.
Joy is at 570.
Reason is the consciousness level of four hundreds.
So our, uh, world, uh, celebrates the intellect, the capacity for reason and intelligence, ca, capacity to see the logic and the proof of things.
And very often people want to apply reason to things that are not really, uh, within the realm of reason.
They're within the realm of the heart and not of the intellect.
Uh-huh.
Willingness is 310.
Calibrates 310.
Uh, neutrality.
That's, life is okay if it goes this way.
It's, it's okay if it goes that, that way.
So, uh, that's the best way to be about politics, you know.
If they win, okay.
You sleep better, anyway.
Courage is consciousness level 200 and over.
Alright.
Now we get to the levels below 200.
So, the positive levels calibrate 200 and over.
And as you get less than 200, you get down to.
Pride calibrates at 175.
Pride goeth before a fall, yes.
Percent of people who calibrate there is about 22.
So about a quarter of the population is operating off pride.
Uh, a smaller percentage live in the world of anger.
Uh, they're always angry about something.
Calibrate level 150.
About 12% of the population is angry all the time.
Angry all the time.
So you want to avoid them on the road.
You want to avoid them on the road.
They're mad all the time about everything.
Then, then we hit desire at 125.
Is a, is really sort of a cravingness.
It's, you're constantly wanting something.
Constantly craving and wanting.
Uh, so that's desire.
Consciousness level below desire is one of fear.
So about 10% of the population live in the world of fear.
They're afraid of everything all the time.
Uh, and their whole life is based on defending themselves against their fears.
75, consciousness level 75 is grief.
These people are sad about something all the time, sad.
And if they can't think of anything to be sad about, they'll remember something sad in the past.
So they're sort of hooked into, uh, sadness.
Um, less than that is apathy.
Apathy, it, what's the use?
It's, it's useless.
And then a certain percentage of the people, uh, live in the world of hatred all the time.
And at the bottom of the,
the bottom of the list, the calibration level 30,
are the people who live in, uh, guilt all the time.
4% of the people live all the time feeling guilty about something.
Mm-hmm.
All right.
That's, uh, uh-huh.
So the calibrated levels of consciousness,
I've been asked to do them on many, many famous, uh, spiritual teachers and gurus throughout history.
And, uh,
so we made a, a list of them for ready reference.
And periodically, in fact, that's the big, the biggest, uh, problem we get coming in the internet,
is, uh, some of you will find a spiritual teacher who's not on the list
and ask us to corroborate whether that person, you know, is, is over 200 or not,
or whether, what their level of consciousness is.
Because, uh, there, there are a number of fake gurus out, uh,
out there, and, and a lot of them are into making money in fake, fake gurus.
So we have, uh, for reference then, uh, the reference level of spiritual teachers.
And you'll find it's quite interesting.
Uh, Bodhidharma, Black Elk, uh, John Calvin, Confucius, uh, the current Dalai Lama.
Um, here we have, so if you haven't looked it up in the book, if you're interested in,
you can see Mahatma Gandhi, Mahatma Gandhi who stood off the British Empire.
So as you see, as the calibrated level goes up, the power goes up.
The power goes up to the point where Mahatma Gandhi, standing alone, half naked, uh, calibrating at 760,
beat back the entire British Empire.
Without firing a shot.
How could that skinny little guy stand off the power of the British Empire?
The British Empire was the greatest power the world had ever seen.
And Mahatma Gandhi knocked them on their tail because he calibrated at 760.
Now we have all the other great teachers here.
Uh, and if there's any you need to know, uh, if they're on the list,
if there's anybody that you want to know and is not on there, uh, we'll be glad to do them right away.
Uh-huh.
And here we have Mutkananda, people that are well known.
Uh, Dogen.
Okay, we'll go on to the next.
St. John of the Cross.
Famous spiritual leaders from past life.
And I like Huang Po.
Huang Po was at 960.
Uh-huh.
Yeah.
So here we have all the famous popes.
All the famous, uh, spiritual teachers of the past and the present.
Very interesting thing to know.
Uh-huh.
And here's Master Suzuki.
And who else is up there we know?
Well, we know all of them, actually.
We, anybody who is a student of spiritual reality is probably familiar with almost all these names.
At least you've run across them.
But it's very nice to have a point of reference.
Uh, point of reference so you know what you're talking about.
Uh-huh.
What's next?
Yeah.
Avatars and great spiritual teachers.
Oh, yes.
We did the greatest teachers of all time.
Yes.
Jesus Christ calibrates at a thousand.
The Buddha at a thousand.
Krishna, one thousand.
Zoroaster, a thousand.
The Christian apostles are almost all at a thousand.
The name of God is Om 975.
John the Baptist, Moses, Abraham, Saint Paul, Muhammad at the time of, he dictated the Koran.
And Muhammad after age 38 changed.
So, that's why when we talk about the Koran, it's important to know.
Muhammad, at the time he dictated the Koran.
With 700.
He had temporal lobe epilepsy.
And after the age of 38, he suddenly went to 130.
So, that was one of the spiritual disasters of mankind.
It happened to a number of other great teachers too that they crashed later in life.
Uh, for some reason.
So, it's necessary to know the writings of some great teachers.
At what age was that?
And what year was that?
Because you'll see over time that it suddenly changed.
Yeah. Okay.
What else have we got?
The great spiritual writings. Great spiritual writings.
Course in Miracles, calibrated 550.
How many people here have done the Course in Miracles?
A lot of people, huh?
Yep.
Course in Miracles is fun to do.
Those of you who haven't done the Course in Miracles,
you better do the Course in Miracles.
The Course in Miracles is really fun to do.
You get one lesson, one sentence, one sentence a day.
And anybody can handle one sentence a day for a year.
So, you don't have to spend all day poring over very learned, complicated texts.
All you need is one simple sentence a day.
One simple sentence a day.
So, I want you all to promise to do the Course in Miracles.
Then do the Course in Miracles.
Promise me.
It's great fun.
It's great fun to do the Course in Miracles.
And interestingly enough, as you do the Course in Miracles,
the miraculous begins to occur.
People will say, I've never experienced a miracle or seen one.
Well, do the Course in Miracles.
And then come back to me a year from now and tell me about that.
Nobody's ever done the Course in Miracles who has not experienced a miracle.
So, you could be the first one, of course.
Could be God really thinks you are a creep.
You suspect you're a creep and God agreed.
Yes, you are.
I always like that joke.
I've told it many times, you know.
The guy, everything happens to him.
You know, his wife leaves him.
He gets sick.
He loses his job.
He gets a case of the crud and it won't heal up.
And he goes out on the sidewalk.
He says, God, why me, God?
Why me?
And the voice comes out of the heavens and says, I don't know, Rudolph.
There's just something about you that pisses me off.
That's such a funny joke.
These are the great spiritual writings.
Anybody who's been into spirituality are familiar with them.
The great, the Book of Kells, we went to Ireland.
Was it Ireland or Scotland?
Ireland, yes.
To the university there to see the Book of Kells.
And then the Book of Mormon and all.
So, a person who is spiritual.
If you're spiritually interested, we'll get a lot out of looking at all these things.
And which Bible, you say the Bible.
You'll notice the Lamsa translation of the Bible calibrates much higher than the King James Version.
So, if you're interested in the highest truth, try to get that translation.
Oh, and then here's the Talmud and the Torah, the Tibetan Book of the Dead.
And the Bible.
The Vedas, the Vedanta, and the Yoga Sutras of Patanjali.
Okay.
So, this list covers a great many of the world's most famous spiritual writings.
We wanted to write, you know, say something about love.
Love is consciousness level 500 and over.
And we saw that 500 was the level of the bagpipes.
Isn't that interesting?
Yes.
So, the sound of the bagpipes is the sound of the heart of mankind.
The reason everybody cries when they hear the bagpipes coming is because it's the sound,
the energy field of the heart of mankind.
And so, classically, the people who have been in the service especially will have the bagpipes at their funeral.
Yes?
Because it expresses that kind of love.
Love consciousness level 500.
It starts out as feeling warmth.
Warmth towards other people.
It expresses appreciation.
I know somebody who is very demanding and disliked as a consequence.
And she never expresses appreciation for anything.
You know, would you mind when you go to town getting me 52 pounds of potatoes?
52 pounds of potatoes and hauling them home.
And then when you get them home, she doesn't even say, gee, thanks.
Consequently, as time goes on, people are less and less willing to do things for her.
So, a simple thank you makes a tremendous difference.
People say, well, that's just being polite.
No, it's not just being polite.
It's acknowledging the worth of other human beings in your world.
So, you appreciate and you give thanks.
Love level 500 and over.
It shows appreciation.
Love is supportive.
You know, mutual support.
Love is also forgiving.
So, if the world makes a mistake, you're willing to forgive it.
If people make a mistake, you're willing to forgive them.
So, the willingness to forgive marks a truly spiritual person.
The willingness to forgive.
To let bygones be bygones.
And I think the 12-step group emphasizes the same thing.
Live one day at a time and let bygones be bygones.
Somebody did you a bad term, the people in the group will tell you, well, that was yesterday.
That was yesterday.
Love is also inclusive.
It's not exclusive.
It's also affectionate.
And it has to do with being cordial and gracious.
And gracious.
So, to be cordial and gracious and acknowledge other people and the gift of their presence.
When you say thank you, people think that's just manners.
It's not just manners.
When you say thank you, you totally change the energy field.
You totally change the energy field.
You become uplifting.
So, people above 200 are supporting all of life.
And below 200, they are dragging down on it.
So, when you're uplifting, you are adding to the energy field of all of life.
And especially of human life.
Love is also heartfelt.
It's called heartfelt and nurturing.
Love is also understanding.
It's protective.
It's dedicated to goodness.
It's dedicated to purity.
It's dedicated to giving to others.
Love is generous.
Love is also capable of sharing.
It's also nonlinear.
It's holistic.
It arises from the heart.
In lovingness, we join with other.
And we diffuse that love.
And set it up around us.
It's a way of being aligned.
It's also humbling.
When it's humble and not prideful in lovingness.
And we express our gratitude.
And when we do that, there's completion.
When you express your gratitude and say thank you, that completes the transaction.
So, the failure to say thank you means rejecting the other person instead of accepting them.
Their donation of love.
There's a certain sweetness to love.
Love has a certain capacity to attract affection.
Yes?
All right.
Oh!
How'd he get in there?
There's the sheep in wolf's clothing.
Yes?
When do we take a break?
In about three minutes.
Oh, okay.
All right.
This is important to know in today's world.
We haven't gotten around to today's world yet.
This is important to know.
Because one of the ways negativity tends to prevail, how it gets such a hold in life,
is because it misrepresents itself as sheep.
Uh-huh.
The sheep.
Don't bother about us.
We're just a happy religion.
Yeah, right.
Until you hear the gunfire.
Thank you for all those love fellows.
So, this is our friend.
And this is a good one to keep in mind.
Because when we get to talking about today's world,
we are going to be indirectly in love.
Unconsciously referring to situations that today prevail.
We're just innocent do-gooders.
Yes.
Thank you.
Put away the machine guns and I can believe you even better.
Yeah, what do we do now?
Turn me on?
You turn me on, sweetheart.
You got to put a dime in the corner of it.
All right.
I have to do this announcement.
We're going to take a quick break.
And we'll see you back here in about 15 minutes.
Thank you very much.
And now, I don't know what happens next, but they'll let us know.
What do we do next, sweetheart?
Continue the lecture?
She's my living, breathing teleprompter.
Beats Obama's hands down.
She knows what's going on all the time.
Spiritual survival in today's world.
Uh-huh.
The realities of the levels of consciousness.
Reality is a subjective mental presumption.
Wow.
Reality is a presumption.
You ever think of that?
You presume that what you're seeing is real.
But you could be a lunatic.
In which case, nothing that you're looking at is real.
You made it all up.
Therefore, is reality a subjective mental presumption?
Huh.
Reality.
Linear versus nonlinear.
What does that mean?
Logical or not logical?
Well, you notice the field of consciousness is neither logical nor is it nonlogical.
It just does not address the problem at all.
One just experiences what you experience.
And making a conclusion about it requires thinkingness.
Consciousness itself is not the same as thinkingness.
Thinkingness is something else again.
So reality is a subjective mental presumption.
We presume that what we see is what is, what really is.
And reality is one thing, truth is another.
Existentially, is the me real?
You presume you're real, but are you?
You never worried about that before.
Oh good, now there's something new to worry about.
Is the me just my imagination?
There are levels of consciousness where that really becomes a problem.
Is there actually a me or is that just some kind of a delusion?
And what is this I?
What is this I, everything that I call I?
Why do you call it me or I in the first place?
Well, is the I that which witnesses the world?
Is the I that which experiences the world?
Is the I that which makes choices?
Has to do with the human will and volition?
Then there's the I as a social personhood.
People say you are.
You are what?
Then there is I as my feelings.
Am I my feelings?
Or am I my thoughts?
How do I know that I even am?
How do you know that you are?
Well, I know I am because I think and because I feel.
And because other people seem to think that I am.
That's reassuring.
What can a Roman people say?
Roman people say hello.
You say, oh boy.
What a relief.
I wasn't sure if I was or not.
Is the real self just a blank screen on which everything is reflected?
Is the real self the content or the context?
Descartes' proposition.
Is reality res interna, that is the way I experience things?
Or is it res externa?
Descartes differentiated between the world as I experience it versus the world as it is.
I may experience it as safe and it could be quite dangerous or vice versa.
So the self knows from one moment to the next.
The mind thinks.
So thinkingness is one thing.
Experiencing reality is another.
None of these things become very important
unless one is seeking enlightenment.
And if you seek enlightenment,
that you're letting go of many of the things that the world presumes are necessary.
And you let them go.
And one thing you let go of is the mind's thinking.
Therefore, if you can't think anymore,
you're only left with knowing.
How do you know without thinking?
Well, you discover that you know without thinking all the time.
And that thinking is just added as a frill.
Thinking is a frill in an entertainment.
Can you get along without thinking?
Well, I'm not going to think about anything.
I guess I should have thought.
There is a chair there.
Well, I don't think about the chair.
But I know.
I know it's there.
So most of real knowingness goes on without thinkingness.
Thinkingness is something we add.
The human adds thinking.
The animal knows without thinking.
It knows its friend from foe.
The dog's hackles goes up if it's foe.
And its tail wags if it's friend.
So the dog doesn't have to think about it.
It just knows right off the bat who is the friend and who is the burglar.
A burglar.
That's such a funny term, a burglar.
Isn't it funny?
What does a burglar do?
He burgles.
You can go to burglar school.
They do that in jail.
Prisons are really burglar schools in which they trade information
so they're better at it next time.
We saw a movie the other night about it.
A true case of a guy who really learned how to rob banks.
He had an excellent technique.
He was so good at it, he couldn't stop robbing banks.
He robbed 12 in a row before the banking system became aware of its existence.
And they put a loaded money.
So in a bank teller, a guy holds a gun on her and says,
Give me your money.
She gives him this pack of bills and this pack of bills.
If he takes it out, it's got a timer on it.
And the timer is released and suddenly red ink squirts out all over.
And the cops have no problem finding him.
So it's best not to burglar banks.
Is reality, therefore, the essence or the appearance of a thing?
Remember Alice in Wonderland?
So that's all based on opinion.
Opinion.
Virtual reality of the media.
The world is a projection, an illusion.
The sense of reality occurs in one ten-thousandth of a second.
Within one ten-thousandth of a second, your mind is already aware
of whether it's an illusion or a reality.
So the mind by itself really is without a compass.
The mind has no capacity to tell truth from falsehood.
In the United States, 55% of the people are unable to differentiate reality from illusion.
What do you know about that?
55% can't tell reality from illusion?
Is that a fact?
55% of the people in the United States cannot tell reality from an illusion.
That explains the Daily News.
That explains the Daily News, yeah.
The mind does not have a compass to tell it.
Therefore, the system that we have evolved of how to tell truth from falsehood
is of very great pragmatic value.
In the United States, belief systems tend to get politicized.
Not only in the United States, but all around the world.
And...
Narcissism is the presumption that the way I look at it is correct
and the way you look at it is incorrect.
Yeah.
Indoctrination, we find, trumps reality.
In other words, if we indoctrinate people, they lose the capacity to discern reality.
Indoctrination University is a book called Indoctrination
that documents how it's brought about.
Therefore, we could say all information is presumptive.
It's best to send your kids to Yavapai College.
Calibrates 440.
What did we calibrate Harvard Law at?
Didn't we have Harvard Law on here?
What's the next slide?
Huh?
Yeah?
No?
Okay.
All right.
Let's go back to the last one.
Last one.
Therefore, reality is the essence of a thing versus its appearance.
Okay.
Mind is without a compass.
All right.
So, therefore, the technique that we have evolved to discern truth from falsehood
is of very great pragmatic value.
I don't know what happened to Harvard Law.
Yeah.
All right.
Okay.
That's a 440.
Yavapai College.
Yavapai College calibrates at 440.
Harvard Law calibrates over 200.
Send your kids to Yavapai College.
Much to the shock and dismay of all the people I know who are lawyers,
that Harvard Law would someday calibrate so low it wasn't even thinkable.
And it has to do with Marxist indoctrination.
It has to do with social justice.
That's what did it.
The whole belief system of social justice is what brought Harvard Law down from what
once was the most respected institution, presidents, cabinet members, etc.
All right.
It's better to send your kids to Yavapai College than Harvard Law.
It's great to know that Yavapai College calibrates at 440.
I think that's tremendous.
All right.
So where is the next slide?
Uh-huh.
What you consider reality is really the product of a whole set of paradigms and presumptions.
Marx said religion is the opiate of the people.
Religion is the opiate of the people.
All right.
Alice in Wonderland is the internet and blogosphere.
The internet and blogosphere has totally dominated our sense of reality.
55% in America exhibit damaged capacity to discern reality.
Oh, wow.
In the average police lineup to identify suspects,
the rate of...
error of identification is 50%.
So it gives us a certain idea then that about 50% of what we see on television
and our presumptions about it are not real or not reality or are not truthful.
All right.
So what we could say about 50% of what we see on television news is false, incorrect.
Incorrect.
Distorted.
50%.
Well, that's a big input, isn't it?
50% of what...
If 50% of the food you ate was bad, you'd be in bum shape.
So mental food, 50% is defective.
Hmm.
All right.
Let's go on to the next slide.
Practical spirituality.
So our lecture is really not about how crazy the world is,
but practical spirituality.
What do we do about it if the world we see,
if the world as it is reported to us is 50% incorrect?
What is our salvation then?
What can we do to protect ourself from such deviance from truth?
One is to stay with holy company.
All right.
What does that mean?
It means that if people who are dedicated to spiritual truth,
who are spiritually oriented then,
themselves are constantly looking to verify the truth.
And when a whole group of people consistently verify certain teachings or teachers,
it's presumably safe.
Stay with holy company.
There's an energy field effect.
Alcoholics Anonymous is...
One of the best known levels of consciousness in actual daily practice.
AA calibrates over 450, 500, 499, 500.
Calibrates right at 500.
Yep.
All right.
So you stay with holy company.
People who have dedicated their lives to God,
to love,
to transcend human error,
then are the people that you would look for.
A group such as this, for instance,
a group such as this,
is made up of spiritual seekers.
Spiritual seekers.
Most of the people here have studied with a number of teachers,
read a lot of books,
traveled and met,
been in various ashrams and various religions.
I myself have been all over the world.
Susan and I visited the great places of worship here and in Europe, etc.
All right.
Stay with holy company.
There is an energy in the field itself.
The relapse experience of AA is when one violates certain basic spiritual principles.
A very interesting TV series is The Band of Brothers.
Which reflects the bonding that goes on between men during war.
Cultural paradigms of reality tend to alter how we see and feel and experience and remember things.
And of course the karmic influences,
which are not familiar to Western society,
are presumed to be of extreme importance.
Then there's spirituality versus religious.
Religious is one thing, spiritual is another.
Paradoxically, a religion can become a source of evil, actually.
Some religions are taken over by forces that are then using them for other purposes than what they originated.
Spiritual, then, stays with truth.
And religious can be influenced.
In today's world, you see that very markedly.
And what's the next one?
Practical spirituality.
In other words, how do you survive in a world where at least 50% of what you see in here is fallacious?
Or twisted, anyway.
So you find a primary teacher.
One that you can...
Whose capacity to discern truth from falsehood can be verified.
And this primary teacher puts principles above personalities.
Personalities are interesting, but it's basic provable principles.
We have that chart of authenticated teachers, which we showed you before.
It's best to avoid new ageism.
The popularity comes and goes of new age gurus and popular teachings.
Some of which take you far afield.
What appeals to lots of people are things that are exotic.
You know, shave your head and walk around barefoot and half-naked and just live on bananas or something.
Join an ashram and fast around the clock for seven days.
I always say, fasting as a spiritual principle heals itself in the end.
If you fast long enough, you don't have any further problems in life.
I once tried to see how long you could go without eating.
I forget, I think after three weeks or a month I gave up.
I don't remember why I ate something.
But it was either that or croaks.
I guess my mind decided...
It's best to avoid, you know, channeled entities.
People who are channeled, some of them calibrate over 200.
A lot of them do not.
And I would not pick a channeled entity as my guru, as my teacher.
And sometimes they are useful and practical.
But you have to really test them out.
To see whether or not that's true.
You know, you channel Master Buha from Waggi Waggi Land.
And he once lived 2,000 years ago.
It's anybody's guess whether it's going to be of practical use to you or not.
So avoid the attraction of that which is exotic.
And channeled, as I said, channeled entities are buyer beware.
And avoid self-styled masters.
You know, some guy used to come around and he called himself Master so-and-so.
Why does he call himself Master or something, rather?
He didn't calibrate over too impressive, much less Master, you know.
I am Master so-and-so.
All right.
Master is a title that society gives to those who have proven themselves to actually be a Master.
Master over periods of time.
You ask him, when did you become a Master?
Well, last Tuesday.
Last Tuesday.
All right.
So the way that we have all traveled of practical spirituality is by study.
We all study the great teachers of time.
We study the holy books.
So we use our intellect to study.
And then we contemplate it and meditate.
So you may read one sentence and spend a week contemplating that one sentence.
You just hold that in mind.
And I ask God, what does that mean, what I just thought, what I just said in my mind?
What does that mean?
And I turn the problem over to God.
And in a non-verbal revelation, it suddenly becomes starkly obvious.
So you balance faith and reason.
You can't be foolish and stupid, and neither can you can't just trust reason.
It's one thing to become a spiritual goal, and it's another to know about it.
Many people who speak know about it,
but as yet have not become it.
Avoid all hatred doctrines.
Right now, the hatred seems to be quite popular in the media.
Hate groups seem to be specialized, in politics especially.
Hatred seems to prevail as a current fashionable style.
How can you tell
when a politician is lying?
When you see his lips moving.
Oh God, that is so funny.
And yet if you test it with the arm,
if you test it with the arm, you'll find that very often your intuition is correct.
Very often your intuition is correct.
All right.
Through study, through contemplation, through meditation,
I ask God to lead me to the truth.
And
by faith in the process,
and faith in God and a spiritual teacher.
Of course, in today's world we can calibrate a spiritual teacher.
Yeah.
And so therefore we calibrate them and see.
Recently we did a whole bunch of them.
A couple of students and myself calibrated a whole bunch of well-known teachers over great periods of time.
And actually they all came out pretty well, actually.
So their reputation was pretty aligned with truth, you know.
Spiritual ego meaning is holier than thou.
To believe that you're holier than other people.
Or that you're more advanced or you're more enlightened.
And as I say, if you're enlightened, you wouldn't know it anyway.
That's something that other people say about you.
Many things inspire us.
Beautiful music.
The giant cathedrals.
Beauty.
As you spiritually evolve, you find you're more and more attracted by beauty.
And you begin to see the beauty of all that exists.
The inspiration of great music.
The great cathedrals of the world.
See how many people here have visited the great cathedrals of the world?
Yeah?
Quite a few, yes.
And right near Cottonwood here now there's a new beautiful cathedral.
A new beautiful church.
With an incredible stained glass window.
I didn't expect anything.
I thought out of curiosity I pulled over and we went inside to see what it looked like.
And wow, here was a whole window.
A stained glass window that was just incredible.
And some of the great cathedrals of the world.
I remember visiting and they had disassembled the great stained glass window.
And were cleaning it.
It hadn't been cleaned in 500 years or something.
And they clean it every 500 years whether it needs it or not.
And it costs over one million dollars to disassemble that giant stained glass window.
Disassemble it from the lead and clean each little piece of glass and put it back again.
And that in itself is reverence, is it not?
And when you look, when you visit the great cathedrals you go into an overwhelm.
When you realize that what you're looking at often represents the life work.
One human being spent one entire life carving this, the beautiful carvings around the pulpit.
One entire life carving this beautiful carving around the pulpit.
And that you might say is devotion to God.
Devotion to God in its practical application.
Rather than abstract.
So we avoid all hatred doctrines.
We follow the inspiration of music at the great cathedrals and beauty.
And we verify the level of consciousness of our teachers.
And we don't go on glamorization or just reputation or enthusiasm.
Okay, what's the next one?
Yeah, religion isn't.
Religion itself.
Religion gets away with murder all the time.
It really does.
Religion, if you look at it over the centuries, it's been hijacked.
Hijacked by politicians.
And very often religion is then used.
It's really become a political.
It's a politic, not a religion.
Our intention helps us to stay on the straight and narrow.
Various religious practices.
Tend to reinforce our spiritual dedication.
The practice of the great virtues.
The practice of the great commandments.
The avoidance of the deadly sins.
And the de-glamorization of that which is of passing attractions.
So our idea is how can we stay on course in a world which is dedicated.
To the glamorization of falsehood.
Yes.
Practical spirituality.
Basic to it is our own goodwill.
Goodwill towards life.
Goodwill towards all that lives.
Sensitivity to the beauty of all that exists.
Avoid the ancient mysteries.
It's always somebody poking around through ancient mysteries.
Ancient mysteries uncovered in the tombs.
And there was a period of time where I visited all those things.
Myself to verify them.
I got to see the sarcophagus of great beings.
And I got to meditate in the great pyramids.
Spent all night meditating in the great pyramids.
How can you get a whole pyramid to yourself?
It was ten bucks I think.
It was ten bucks.
I said to the guard.
I want to meditate there all night.
And his hand almost automatically went like this.
I crossed his palm with silver.
I think ten bucks or five.
I forget which.
And he stood guard at the door to the pyramid.
And by God I had an entire pyramid to myself the entire night.
I could study.
I could meditate all night long with the whole pyramid all my own.
How many people get a whole pyramid just to itself?
I thought that was a great opportunity.
And it was a very cannot be described kind of a night.
All right.
So we want to avoid high price gurus with specialness.
Friends of mine were spiritual seekers.
And they made the rounds of all.
Or many of the very well known gurus.
And what it cost them.
It cost them at a return.
Yeah.
And so avoid high price gurus.
Okay.
Especially when they are.
They note themselves to be special.
Yeah.
Avoid the evil of the seduction by glamour.
I don't think evil.
I don't think evil is the right word there.
I just say avoid the seduction by glamour.
The glamourization.
And I notice many of the so-called spiritual teachers who calibrate extremely low.
Come on with sort of a theatrical glamour.
You always have to have the sandals or the bare feet and the long robe.
And a big cross hanging around your neck.
And holy signs hanging off of you.
Actually a true spiritual teacher probably looks more like a business man than anything.
He's got a shirt and a tie on.
So you want to avoid that which is fallacious and special.
And you want to avoid the seduction by glamour.
Glamourization means exaggeration of that which is ordinarily considered attractive in our world.
Of course in miracles I recommend to people.
People rather generally.
Because it sets you to an inner direction.
You're not beholden to anyone.
And if you check it out you'll see that it calibrates at 600.
And the workbook calibrates at 550 or so.
But I think the workbook of A Course in Miracles calibrates at 600.
I forget now.
I want to make sure.
The workbook of A Course in Miracles.
I have permission to ask.
Calibrates at 600.
Okay.
The workbook of A Course in Miracles.
So people say well I don't know where to go for spiritual teaching or teachers or congregations or something.
I think go to church.
Go to church and study A Course in Miracles.
That combination should do it for everybody.
Everybody.
How many people here have been A Course in Miracles?
Yeah.
Oh pretty good.
Thank God.
Thank goodness I'm saved.
Yeah.
A Course in Miracles people are safe to be around.
Safe to be around.
And it's a fantastic experience.
Especially when the so-called cities hit you.
You do A Course in Miracles and all of a sudden the miraculous begins to occur.
And it's rather jarring in the beginning.
You begin to think the thing and it happens.
I use it at home.
It's very practical.
We've got one cat that has to have something put in his eye all the time and we never can find the cat.
So I ask the Holy Spirit to guide me to the cat and there he is.
He's under the table.
So the Course in Miracles is good for finding lost cats and various things like that.
You don't know what you did with the keys to the car.
There's a lot of glamorization of ancient mysteries.
You see it on television all the time.
And prophecies.
Prophecies of the end of the world.
And we all know what is the next end of the world.
I forget, 2012?
Everybody's ready for the next end of the world?
Oh, that's based on the Mayan calendar.
That's right, I forgot.
The Mayan calendar.
The world ends in December 2012.
I have the arm.
It's fallacious.
All right.
So the Mayan calendar is fallacious.
The Mayan calendar is not calibrating mankind.
It's calibrating an era.
So the Mayan calendar calibrates the calendar of a whole end of an era.
So like what we would call the end of a century.
What we call the end of a century doesn't mean the world's going to end.
It just means that our means of keeping track of things
will come to the end at the end of December.
Of course, a miracle leads you back to inner direction.
Okay.
What's the next one?
Flexibility protects you from making serious errors.
Stores us within of happiness.
We got rid of that in a hurry, didn't we?
And here's one I made.
Want what you have instead of having what you want.
Yeah, that's a good one.
Just because I made it up, it's excellent.
Want what you have instead of what you want.
Want what you want instead of what you don't have, yeah.
Happiness is an inner decision.
And you have to give up self-pity.
Oh.
I don't want to be happy then.
So I got to give up self-pity.
That's too much.
All right.
The next one is a really important one
that we can get psychologically adjusted to and get our teeth into.
Make choices instead of craving, wanting, desiring, clutching.
Choose things instead of craving them.
I choose to be happy.
I choose to buy this new car.
Without craving it.
So decide, I'm going to give up all craving-ness.
Craving-ness.
Craving-ness is I cannot be happy unless I have this new hat.
I cannot be happy unless I get to see this movie.
I cannot be happy unless...
So you're putting your happiness on something outside yourself.
So you can't let your ego get away with placing the source of happiness outside yourself.
The source of happiness is only within.
And if you win a million dollars, the only happiness is that it makes you happy within.
It's not going to change your life much generally.
People who think a million dollars is going to make a big change in their life
are surprised to find that it makes very little change after all.
Okay.
Surrender all cravings to God.
Whatever you find yourself craving.
Women and booze.
I got a mug at home when I chose the guy with his thing on him.
Talking to the bartender.
I spent all my money on women and booze.
The rest I wasted.
Eventually, with a spiritual orientation towards life,
you develop a certain joie de vivre.
A certain joy.
A certain joyousness about being alive in the first place.
And who was the French entertainer asked about that?
When he was asked, how do you feel about being 77?
He said, considering the alternative, very good indeed.
That was that French...
Who was it?
Maurice Chevalier.
Yeah, yeah.
Considering the alternative, I feel very good about being 77.
He says.
So joie de vivre is a certain attitude that is independent of events.
Yeah.
A certain happiness, the joy of life.
One can quickly get there by gratitude for life.
Oh Lord, I give thanks that I have had this privilege to experience life.
Because for all the millions who are experiencing life,
there are ultra millions who are not.
So we are very fortunate then.
Karmically, we have inherited the gift of experiencing life.
Joie de vivre is independent of events, is a certain attitude.
When we get caught into craving, the thing to ask yourself,
who is it within me that is wanting?
Is it the child?
I want to be famous.
Okay.
Is it the child that wants to be famous?
The adult?
Is it the parent?
Who is it in you that wants things?
Very often we'll find it's the child that wants to have their own way.
Is it the child, the adult, or the parent?
It's always a good thing to ask yourself when you're in any kind of a jam.
Differentiate the actual from that which is symbolic.
Winning or gaining in our world is often symbolized.
Symbolized by a certain address.
Symbolized by a certain car.
Symbolized by a certain title.
Job description.
And these things are all symbolic.
And in and of themselves have no particular worth.
The fact that you're president of the company is very gratifying.
All right.
So we'll go back to the next one.
Differentiate narcissistic from mature goals.
To become rich and famous.
Becoming rich and famous seems to be the preoccupation of everybody.
When you watch the TV news, the rich and famous parade before the camera.
They do everything to stay in the news.
Commit crimes, violate the parole, repeat the same mistakes over and over again.
Until they don't get any more publicity out of it than they give it up.
If they don't get back on TV by relapsing drugs and getting rearrested, then they give up the drugs.
I'll say the way to get these movie stars to give up their drugs is to ignore them in the media.
In fact, they're back in jail again.
Ignore it.
They will actually get themselves back in jail again so they can get on the news that they're back in jail again.
It's hard to believe.
Do anything to stay in the news.
Stay in the news.
So that's narcissism.
Be pleased with the direction and alignment of how you are now.
And some people are not satisfied until they have achieved a certain goal.
In other words, they're not enjoying the journey.
So you learn to enjoy the journey of life.
All right.
So let's say you're seeking enlightenment or at least an advanced state of consciousness.
And there isn't any, this is no good and this is all good.
The process, the process may take you all around the world, may take you to see and hear certain teachers,
may take you to great cathedrals, may require a sacrifice, walking barefoot across the desert, whatever.
I've told this joke before.
This guy is very enthused about religion.
And so he visits the Holy Land.
And he sees this fisherman out there.
And he says,
And the fisherman looks over at him and he says,
What do you want, sheet face?
I've told that joke before.
But it's because of our, we are enamored of the glamour of religiosity.
We ourselves become glamorized by it.
Be pleased with the direction you're going and not just a goal.
The practical reality versus fantasy and the glamour of success.
Success is an inner, is an inner condition.
Success is an inner condition.
What the world calls success may have little or nothing to do with what you consider it to be.
And vice versa.
You may consider what you have as successful.
Successful in the world completely ignores it and considers that it's nothing at all.
Choose and make decisions instead of just hoping.
Don't hope to go to college.
Bust your chops until you get there.
And bust your chops to do the best while you're there.
So, just hoping is not enough.
You have to back it up with effort.
Okay, the next one.
What?
We're breaking for what?
Lunch.
These people want to eat on top of everything else?
Good God.
Okay.
We'll see you again at what time?
What?
Two o'clock.
What time?
We'll see you again at two o'clock.