I got more humility than anybody in the
place.
I don't know where you sit. How do you
get here, honey?
Is that the chair there? Yeah. Oh, okay.
>> Here's your coffee and drink. We're
done.
>> Oh my goodness. This is exciting.
Who knows what could happen next?
>> Careful. That's a little cool.
>> You know what's happening next?
>> Yes.
to you.
>> She's my living breathing teleprompter.
>> The one and only super super Susie.
>> Super Suzie.
>> A lot of Suzies, but not a super Sizzy.
>> What happens next, Tony?
>> Um, there. Well, I guess we'll kind of
wait for people to kind of follow follow
come back in and then we'll start. Let
me see.
>> Do we have more slides to do or what?
>> Well, we're about one minute early. So,
what would you like to talk about while
we're waiting for people to get here?
>> Uh, do we have more slides to do or
what?
>> Yes, we do.
>> Oh, we have more slides.
>> So, what would you like to talk about?
>> I'd like to talk about whatever people
are interested in.
How to get rich and famous and even with
your enemies.
Okay,
I better use this or they're gonna get
mad at me.
>> Okay,
>> let me see if I can get it off.
>> Is the battery dead on this again?
>> Okay,
>> I can't. Um,
where's German?
>> All right.
knew better.
>> As we know from previous lectures, it
isn't the wealth and the fame of being
famous. It's the glamour of that,
>> right?
>> The glamour is a specific energy that we
project onto things. It's not intrinsic.
It's projected onto it.
>> Okay. So, glamour glamour you would is
that would you cons classify eagle as
the ego as glamour?
only in a sideways kind of a way that uh
because I think it it's important.
>> Okay.
>> So, you're sort of glamorizing your own
thoughts.
You know, what I believe or what I think
is what's important.
So, there's a certain egocentricity to
that. The world, the universe doesn't
care what you think.
What?
The universe doesn't care what you
think. it. Don't give everybody damn.
>> Okay. Um, what about we always talk
about the what in kind of entrapment
there is for say a high spiritual being,
you know, that you would refer to as
quote a guru. Um you we we talk quite
often about what the three entraments
are of of them you know such as sex,
money,
um
>> fame.
>> Fame. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Sex, money, and fame
>> are the three entraments that you
>> Yeah. Because gurus fall right and left,
>> right?
>> And and they also fall for peculiar
things like sex with little boys.
which sounds so bizarre that it's
unimaginable, but it is a fact.
>> Well, I was just wondering, you know,
can you kind of um when is it they don't
really start out that way. It just seems
that they develop these tendencies
later. they seem to and uh
>> so they start out at a high and then
>> yeah to to the most surprising people
and uh then later on you feel they've
fallen into the trap
and as I say I can't imagine who would
find all that attractive but some kind
of malevolent negative energy comes
around
>> to so because you if you're standing for
truth then you're the uh the enemy of
falsehood
and evil sort of ferrets around trying
to find a crack in your armor.
Uh it it's a actual literal
literally from the demonic realms.
Demons literally look for cracks in your
armor that they can get in. Let's hold
the arm on that one. That's actually a
fact, right? Not only that, but I saw I
saw the demons. You could actually see
them.
And I remember somebody who was
supposedly a pretty high spiritual
teacher
and I said, "Why don't you just give it
away to the world? You know what you've
learned? Give it away. Write a book,
whatever."
And uh the demons flew out of his head
and they were furious.
I actually saw them, but I'm not
clairvoyant. I mean, I don't see
entities. Well, the Buddha had demons
that tried to
>> That's true. Right. And he said that
when he uh that the demons came and
>> I remember being attacked by demons. And
uh it's it's literally a fact. The
demons look for any crack in your armor
that they can get in. Vanity or
sexual proclivities or wealth or fame.
all the traditional
um traps that the guru still called
gurus fall into.
>> I remember when I wrote the last book or
two
u I wasn't allowed to even use the word
guru. Remember that I used the arm and
said do not even use the word because
the word itself has fallen into
defamation.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Yeah. I think I thought that was very
interesting that we needed to share that
um with people because um you know just
because you followed someone when
they're first starting out doesn't you
know they can change and it can
>> Yeah. You wouldn't think they would
but u if there's a crack in the armor
the demons find it.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. We have friends that were really
taken to the cleaners financially
by big names.
More and more money, more and more
money.
>> And every time they turn around with
more money.
>> Well,
>> I don't know what in the hell you do
with all that money if you had it all. I
mean, it would be a plague. You'd have
to put it in the closets or under the
bed or I don't know what they do with it
all.
I don't know what good it would do you,
you know.
>> Well, I think people associate money
with power that gives them power.
>> Oh. Uhuh.
>> So, it's kind of like an ego power trip,
too, because the more money they have,
the bigger their place they can do, the
bigger, you know, following. So, they
attribute that to I think that type of
feeling is what comes up maybe. And the
people I knew a lot of people back east
that came from you know longtime wealthy
families
and uh they were just uh very simple
plain people and never put on the dog
for anybody and uh
uh just simplicity of life because
you know once you've already bought a
couple expensive cars and cruising
around in them and you lived in a fancy
address.
I mean I lived on Fifth Avenue. You're
looking at a Fifth Avenue socialite.
I lived at 958 Fifth Fifth Avenue it
was. Yeah.
Yeah. And uh so it doesn't do you too
much good. You say, "Well, that's that's
good. That's nice.
That 10 bucks will get you in the door
of the theater."
>> Okay. Hey, are we are we all ready?
>> Yeah, we were just chatting, right?
>> Yeah, we're just chatting. I want to be
back from lunch before we really start.
>> Oh. Oh,
>> we're back from the front. Okay.
>> Okay.
>> What comes up next now?
>> Uh, we've got more slides.
>> Oh, we have more slides.
Slippy slidy. Here we go. Slippy slidy.
Okie do.
Take that.
Narcissistence,
rich and famous
uh is narcissistic
and uh be pleased with the direction
you're going and your alignment instead
of just where you are on the on the
trail.
If your life is dedicated to truth and
purity and goodness and being benign and
uplifting towards all of life, uh you're
already there.
There's no point in seeking there is no
end to a spiritual alignment because
it's a way of a way of being. It's a way
of being.
So it doesn't have any beginning point
and it doesn't have any end point. Uh
and I think it has a lot of karmic
propensity.
A lot of karmic propensity.
Uh let let's see is um a high percentage
of spiritual
evolution and commitment is primarily
karmic resist. Uhhuh. So you got bad
karma. Jeez.
bottom of the barrel for you.
Well, you climbed up from the bottom of
the barrel. That's the way you get good
karma. You could get even with somebody
and instead you forgive them. You
forgive people because they don't know
any better. They don't realize any
better. They haven't evolved to a higher
level. So, in a way, people can't help
being who they are.
A nasty burglar is a nasty burglar. And
that's about as good as he can get right
now. He could learn to be a nice
burglar,
a pleasant burglar.
Straighten up the house after you mess
it up.
Well, we know somebody who interviews uh
criminals and burglars and people like
that.
And uh so it's it's a very interesting
adventure.
Uh so be pleased with the direction that
your life is going.
Don't be concerned about being
enlightened. Just be as loving and
forgiving towards all of life as you
can. Cherish all of life and all of its
expressions.
Cherish all of life and all its
expressions. So you walk over the beetle
instead of stepping on it. Uh because it
has life and you cherish the life in
that little beetle.
Yep. So you give up the glamour of
success
and especially if you are successful.
I mean if you're successful and live in
certain areas and you're
multi-millionaire
so is everybody.
So what else is new?
choose to make a decision instead of
just hope hoping to choose and make that
decision now that I've made a decision.
I want to live my life to the highest
level that it's possible and fulfill my
potential
uh via divine grace. So we ask God's
help, we ask God's help to lead us in
the direction through divine grace to
our ultimate goal. All
right. What's next? Anything you learn
to become flexible instead of rigid. If
it doesn't, if you can't go this way,
you go that way. So you're there's an
easy malleability.
Cancel and then I'll be happy. In other
words, happiness is nothing that you can
set as a goal in the future. If you're
not happy now, you're not going to be
happy later.
If you're not happy now, then you set up
goals for yourself that are not
achievable
and then I'll be happy. If I'm rich,
then I'll be happy.
Let go of clutching and grasping. In
other words, trying to seize things. So,
this has to do with grace. With
gracefulness,
the person as they spiritually evolve
become gracious.
gracious and graceful and gracious
towards all of life in all of its
expressions. So as you're walking down,
you see the little bug, you walk around
them, you don't walk too close to the
bug because you'll scare them. Yeah. I
don't want to scare the bug. So I walk
all the way around and
then the little bug is happy.
If the little bug is happy, then I'm
happy.
So if we get flies in the house, what
you do is you open the top of the window
and lower the screen until the flies fly
out and then you close it up again. Now
that the flies are free and happy.
Let go of clutching and grasping.
Clarify your goals and your ideals.
Realize that all value is or arbitrary.
All value is arbitrary.
What value you add to a thing is
uh an arbitrary selection.
Whether you're rich and famous or
whether you're poor and humble, in the
end it's all the same because all value
is arbitrary. All you can buy in the
meantime is comfort and style.
Comfort and style.
Happiness is a map on a train
of a plane.
on the train.
A train.
A train for a plane.
>> I got it.
Being happy means that you take a nap
when you're on a train or a plane.
I remember being grounded for six hours
in Greece one time. They're having air
maneuvers of the military. So we got
grounded for six hours. Six hours on the
ground was very boring.
So happily after half an hour I fell
asleep.
But six hours sitting there frantically
trying to push time. Huh. Okay. a nap on
a plane or a train.
Live one day at a time. That is
certainly part of the 12step program.
Yesterday is over and tomorrow never
comes. You realize that tomorrow never
comes because tomorrow it'll it'll be
the next day will be tomorrow. So
live one day at a time.
Happiness is in the small things of
life. the sound of a kitty's purr or a
dog's wagging tail. I mean, what could
be happier than hear a purr kitty? So,
our kitties in the morning, I got three
of them on the bed. They're going
purr purr. Three of them are doing that
at the same timer.
And then the dog comes around and puts
her nose over the top of the bed to make
sure that all three kitties are where
they're supposed to be.
her dog, she's a hurting dog. So her job
is to make sure all kitties are where
they're supposed to be. And then
so just living with animal life, I
think, is very beneficial. And as I
said, I used to have patients who lived
alone and were depressed. And I told
them, unless you get a dog, I can't
treat you because otherwise you're just
egoentrically
concerned about yourself all the time.
Me, me, me, me. And uh having a pet of
any kind or a canary or a bird or a
kitty or a doggy, you start thinking
about something other than yourself. Is
the doggy comfortable? Did the doggy
have his dinner? Did the doggy go out?
You see, you're thinking about another
living thing and its happiness and its
success.
Okay. Happiness is a kitty's purr or a
dog's wagging tail.
I used to have a monkey and the monkey
and I had a kinkaju. A kinkaju is a
South American honey bear and I had it
in a cage hanging over a bathtub in some
place I lived. And the kinkaju's uh fur
got dull and his eyes got dull and he
lost his appetite.
So intuition hit me. So I went out and I
bought a monkey and I hunked in the
monkey in a cage over the bathtub and
another hook. So here was the kinkaju
here and the monkey there and they hated
each other.
The king of Jew hated the monkey and the
monkey would throw things at the king
but the king of Jew's fur got shiny and
glossy and his eyes sparkled and he was
quite happy.
So my intuition was right and so the
happiness is a is to be related to other
living things and uh to love the woods
as you go through the woods to love your
garden as you love. So faith versus
skepticism
gratitude for what you have and have
become
uh
it's better to be detached than to crave
things. People, some people think if you
want a thing, it's because you don't
crave it one enough. And instead, the
thing is to become lighthearted,
lighthearted about it and detached. If
you w the lottery, you win it. And if
you don't, you don't. But if you get
hung up and craving to win the lottery,
even if you win it, your life's going to
be horrible.
There's stories on television. The lives
of people who have won the lottery,
every one of them was a disaster. I
think the divorce rate was 100% suicide
rate
and these are the people who became
instant millionaires
to see the whether the world is glass is
half full or it's half empty. So that's
optimism versus pessimism.
So if you're not too far along in life,
be grateful and say, "Thank God I've got
plenty of room to grow and gain and lots
of pleasure to look forward to." If
you're already rich and famous and
happy, you haven't got too much left,
right?
Well, you can get a bad cold and wish go
optimist versus pessimist
and to have spiritual rather than
material gains. It isn't the material
gain. It's the spiritual significance
that God has seen to it that you are
well provided for.
uh is like by good karma and grace. So
I'm grateful that we have what we need
to live life in a satisfactory manner.
Yes. Okay.
Live one day at a time. This is again
out of the 12step program. Uh yep.
Detach versus craven glass half full.
Spiritual versus material goals. Okay.
What's the next slide?
Is there another one?
Is there another slide?
>> Is there another slide waiting for us?
>> Oh boy. Oh boy.
Good for us.
Good for us. We made it through all the
slides.
That's my main ambition when I got up
this morning.
Dear God, please help us get through all
the slides.
>> What? A new one. We're not done.
>> We're not done.
>> All right. It must be God's will that we
have another
slide to go.
Surrender to God's will.
The capacity to let go to let go.
Surrendering to God's will is is
successfully letting go of things.
Letting go of thinking that you have to
do a certain thing that you must do a
certain thing and seeing to it that
however it goes is going to be fine.
Capacity. So the learning how to let go
then anybody knows how to grasp and
grab. Everybody knows that. Even an
idiot knows how to grasp. But to know
when to let go is something else. Huh.
>> You might mention we're doing a book on
that.
>> We're doing a book on letting go. Yeah.
That's the name of the book. In fact,
let go. Yeah. How to let go. Because
then you drop the book. You let go of
the book.
I let go of the book and it's on the
floor now.
Well, because uh society drives us in
the other direction, we learn the
spiritual technique of uh letting a
thing go, surrendering it, and uh open
your hand and let it. So, we want to be
pleased with our progress wherever we
are. You don't have to become a Buddha
now. And uh you may never become a
Buddha. And uh Buddha, last time I spoke
to him, says, "I don't really need any
help.
Once you're detached from the world, you
don't really need much help." Okay? You
want to avoid self- judgment.
You know, where am I? Am I being good?
Am I being bad? etc. That doesn't mean
becoming unconscious.
Self-aware.
So become self-aware rather than
self-judgmental.
Realize that the terms good and bad are
all circumstantial.
Good as compared to what? Bad as
compared to what?
Okay. Realize that in life winning is
provisional.
Winning is only temporary. Winning is
how you ever define it.
Winning is not desiring fame or money.
How's that? That way you can be piss
poor and win.
Take vows of poverty. The less money you
have, the better you're doing.
All right. Winning is a is provisional.
It's however you define it. And the
shortest avenue is through simplicity
rather than complexity. Yes. All right.
Realistic expectations of yourself and
the world
and uh realistic expectations of what is
common in human consciousness.
We would like our governing body to be
better than it is. We would like our
politicians to be better.
Everybody and his brother should be
doing a better job.
If it was possible, uh, it would be so.
Value is in the eye of the beholder. So,
whatever you think is valuable out there
is a projection. So, that's similar to
the whole concept about glamour.
The g value which you know glamour is in
the eye of the beholder.
If you think it's wonderful and
valuable, it'd be great. My father had a
great big heavy gold ring with a great
big amethyst in it. He just loved that
ring. And he was a piano player. So he'd
play the piano and here it' be this big
gold ring with this big amethyst. He
just loved he loved the amethyst stone,
you know, and he wanted to leave it to
me.
I said, "Dad, I'm never going to wear
that.
a big gold ring that weighs a quarter of
a pound for God's sake with a big
amethyst.
I said, "I hate to decline it, but I'm
never gonna wear it." Uhhuh.
So, the value is in the eye of the
beholder. Just like
give up skepticism.
Give up skepticism.
Have a sense of humor.
It's hard to beat anybody who has a
sense of humor because no matter what
you do, it appears comical because how
you hold it in mind is what creates the
sense of humor.
Accepting karmic propensity, in other
words, if things are not going your way,
you say, well, uh, it could be well be a
reason for that. People who do past life
regression often find what the karmic
propensity was and it makes it extremely
acceptable.
You know what what happened in that what
lifetime and what you did about it and
uh one time I was having surgery relying
anesthesia and in the middle of it I
went back to that lifetime and I thought
good God what did I ever do and suddenly
I like relived it. I actually like
relived what had happened and I think
I've told that story before and uh I was
a warrior and I profoundly wounded my
enemy
and instead of killing him I left him
there to die of his wounds
and in this lifetime I then had to go
through ingal surgery without anesthesia
and during that surgery I thought
karmically I must have done something to
warrant this and I did I did not give
him the cudigra. I left him to die of
his wounds. So the code of the warrior
is to finish off your opponent if he's
unable to finish himself off. And I
didn't have the moral courage to do that
or wasn't trained enough to realize that
was my responsibility.
When he's laying there crippled and and
horribly wounded, you say to the guy,
"You want to leave?" And the guy says,
"Yeah, you let him leave." If he says,
"No, I'll stay." You let him stay.
A severely wounded warrior does not say,
"I think I'll stay except once in a
great while."
All right. Give up skepticism. Have a
sense of humor. Accept karmic
propensities. See essence rather than
perception.
What is the inner core reality that this
thing represents?
So you can't reject a diamond just
because it's a diamond because the
diamond could well be, you know, a
keepsake left to you by your mother. So
the value of that diamond is not the
monetary value of the diamond, but the
the fact that it was your mother's and
she wore it during her whole life. So
you want to see the essence of a thing
rather than the story that you project
onto it. and jocular instead of morose.
To be humorous and see the funny side of
everything
is uplifting.
Sometimes it's hard to be serious.
In the middle of very serious things, I
have to watch myself.
You have to watch yourself because
you've taken a more lighthearted view
instead of being heavy heavyhearted.
Are there any more on this one? This
slide, honey. Is there more? Hey,
good will regarding all of life. That's
the most important one of all, I think.
To be of good will towards all of life
and all of its expressions.
Of goodwill towards the woods as you
walk through the woods. of the little
bugs that you try to step around so you
don't squish them. Of good will towards
everybody.
Good will regarding all of life in all
of its expressions. To love life as life
as an expression of divinity. So one can
see life is the radiance of divinity and
it it's good you know a good thing to
love and guard and and cherish to be
easygoing rather than rigid if it
doesn't work this way you let it go that
way
and then a person will say but the ego
says isn't that being wishywashy
wishywashy
I'd rather be wishy-washy and and
enlightened than tough minded and going
to hell eventually.
Reduce expectations of yourself and
others. If you find a seat on the
subway, so much the better. Yeah. Yeah.
I like that story of the of uh the woman
in in the subway and she says this
gentleman's sitting in the seat. She
said, "Would you mind giving your your
seat to a pregnant woman, expectant
mother?" "Oh, no." He said, "No." He
looked at her. She looks at her as slim.
He says, "How long you been pregnant?"
She says, "Oh, about an hour and a half.
Be gracious to yourself and to others.
Surrender the need to control." That's
the biggest one I think that people
have. They want to control every
everything.
Yeah. wanting to control others uh other
countries etc. calibrates about 180.
So certain organizations some of them
religious etc some political some
combined the two uh want to conquer
other countries just to control them.
The desire to control others just for
the sake of control calibrates at 180.
They can try to convince themselves that
they're saving your soul, but the
reality is they just want to control
you, that you got to see things their
way. Yeah.
Let let go of the desire for applause.
Nobody's going to applaud. When you're
out in the woods and you save the life
of some little animal, there isn't any
applause. You see the little rabbit, you
take it home, you nurse it, bring it
back to health, it becomes a pet rabbit.
Uh so the thing is self-rewarding. You
don't have to look for extraneous
rewards. The reward is in the
gratification of the desire to be of
assistance to that which is living.
I like be glad instead of mad.
Be glad instead of mad that this
incident has allowed you to realize
something about yourself and about life
that you didn't know before. So you're
glad. I'm glad that I realize that now
about myself. Yeah. I'm glad I realize
that I'm selfish. Yeah.
I didn't realize I was selfish before.
Didn't want to put that much money in
the plate at church. No,
you put a fiverr in the plate and then
you take three singles back out.
Acceptance instead of resistance.
generous instead of stingy,
candid with yourself, honest, openly
honest with yourself and others.
You have to learn how eventually to
silence the mind and give up
thinkingness.
That's very difficult to do. How do you
silence the mind
and give up thinking?
Well, you do that by looking at the
space around a thing instead of the
thing itself.
So, I get this table as a generality
in a in a greater generality.
Do I have any thoughts about this table?
No, I don't have any thoughts about it.
It just is. So you can look at a thing
and let everything just be as it is
without dis dissert dissertation in your
head about what it is and what you
should do about it and should you move
it and shouldn't that be a different
color tablecloth etc etc. You can learn
how to accept life on its own terms just
as it is. What's the point of doing
that? Because then you live in a free
state all the time. You're going if it
rains, it rains. And if it doesn't rain,
it doesn't rain. And it's all the same
one way or the other. If it rains, you
get to experience a rainy day. And if it
doesn't rain, you get to experience a
sunny day. So, you can't lose. If you
accept all possible alternatives,
if you die poor, you you get put in a
cheap grave. And if you die rich, you
get in a fancy cemetery.
A fancy cemetery is better, right?
All right. Acceptance instead of
resisting. Being generous instead of
stingy.
Honest with yourself and with others.
Learn how to silence the mind. Give up
thinking. This means to look beyond it.
Look beyond it. To be forgiving instead
of vindictive.
All right. All right. Work on your inner
traits instead of the external ones.
Yeah. Whether your shoes are shined is
sort of interesting, but not really.
It's your inner traits rather than your
external ones. It only takes a bone to
make a dog happy.
realize that it only takes a bone to
My dog is happy all the time. I can hear
munch, munch, munch
all night long.
It only takes a dog, I mean a bone to
make a dog happy.
And it only takes hiding the bone from
the dog to make your wife happy.
That dog's going to chew on that bone
all night. Okay. Okay. All right. All
right.
You can hear the dog gnawing away on the
bone. But after a while, I guess it does
get irritating. You're trying to go to
sleep and the dog's going crunchy,
crunchy, crunchy, crunchy.
But what we really mean by all this is
the small things of life are fine. Small
things of life are fine. I don't see
very well. And so when I can't find my
cane, somebody says, "Here it is. Here's
your cane here." I say, "Oh, God, thank
you. Thank you." I don't know where the
thing was. And this the small things of
life make all the difference in the
world. You know, uh there's a song used
to be don't worry, be happy.
Do you remember that song? Don't worry,
be happy.
Anybody remember that song?
>> Yeah. Don't worry, be happy. Make that
your your s song and you can play that
in the background. While you're having
breakfast, play don't worry, be happy
and you and you go to work humming as
you drive along in the car. Choose
spiritual values and goals instead of
material ones.
Like your ambition should be to be more
forgiving, to be more loving, to be more
generous,
uh to be of greater assistance to your
fellow man. All the things to make other
living beings happy whether it's animal,
human, vegetable. Yes.
All right. Choose spiritual friends and
groups.
Go from complete to complete. Oh yes.
Choosing spiritual friends and groups
makes a difference because you tend to
become that with which you align. So if
you align with a strong spiritual group,
you tend to become more and more that
way yourself. If you align align with
the sort of intemperate, hostile,
violent or relig hyper religious group,
you tend to become like them, sort of
spiteful and angry and
they actually have hate brigades. I
mean, I can't believe it. I see it on
television. And uh some poor guy who's
been shot overseas is being put in the
ground. And there's a hate group with
hate signs.
I don't know how you get to get heaven
with a hate sign. You have to leave your
hate sign here to get into heaven. But
anyway, they do. They have hate groups.
Oh, that's hysterical. Identify with the
greater self rather than the small self.
Accept the limitations of humanness.
All right. So you say, how can so much
negativity and hostility?
It's because of the evolution of human
consciousness. Mankind does not evolve
to the angelic viewpoint to the angelic
point of being an angel. A human can
become more and more angelic and
eventually if you become sufficiently
angelic uh you don't need to come back
here. However, you can if you wish and
uh I have met angels in bodies. I have
had angels stop and help me. I'm
thinking now about the guy who circled
around, circled around, came and got me
out of the fig out of the figure eight
highway and went and got it changed and
brought back. That man was a saint. I
was a
>> angel.
>> Huh? Angel. Yes. So, there are angels in
bodies.
That's something people don't really
know. This man um I was on a clover leaf
in my old truck and it broke down. There
I am stuck on a clover leaf with a
broken down truck. Oh god. In the middle
of nowhere. And this car pulled over and
the guy says, "You in trouble?" I said,
"Yeah." Won't start. He says, "Here, let
me help you." Complete stranger. He got
out the lug lug wrench and took the lugs
off the tire through the tire and all in
the back of his pickup truck. He drove
half a mile away, went around to Clover
Leaf, took took the truck tire to a
repair station, had it repaired, came
back to Clover Leaf, came back to Clover
Leaf, came back to me. It all took about
an hour and a half. Plus, he had to put
out the money to get the fire fixed.
And of course, I gave him the money and
I thanked him profusely.
But that's the first one I ever did the
arm on. uh that man he was an angel
angel in a human body. So there are
there are actual angels within a human
body. Uh we can evolve to that ourself
by our own inner decision. Resist. Wow.
You can become an angel. You don't have
to croak
get run over.
You can become angelic while you're
still in a physical body.
Wow.
We will become the first angelic group
in the history of mankind.
A group of angels.
900 angels all at one place. Honey,
some people in this group are already
angelic. Resist. They already got that
ready. We already have angels sitting in
the audience.
or $5. I'll introduce you to him.
>> No, not $5. A generous donation,
>> huh?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. But, uh, that's a discovery we
made. I think it's pretty original with
us our work that um there are literally
angels
incarnate actually angels here living
amongst us and radi radiating out
goodness uh to mankind. So we are very
fortunate then in this group there are
angels that have returned to a body.
Uhhuh.
Okay. Realize that life is a learning
curve. So you never have to be
dissatisfied with yourself because
you're doing as well as you can at this
moment.
If you could be doing better, you would
be.
So being self-critical then is always
arbitrary.
If you could be better, you would be.
The fact that you're not means you can't
right now
because you haven't reached that goal
yet. to be forgiving towards people who
cut in on you on traffic.
Uh just as you're pulling up a car,
pulls right in front of you and you have
to be angelic not to curse the guy, you
know, right?
How many of you bless a person who pulls
in front of you in traffic?
Any hands?
Well, this is a truthful group.
a truthful group. Uh it's hard to bless
the person who pulls in in front of you,
but let's try that as a group
experience.
Henceforth,
if somebody's rude to you in traffic and
pulls in in front of you, forgive them
for being somewhat impaired.
Well, they they they lack being gracious
and thoughtful.
On the other hand, maybe they got to go
to the bathroom. You know what I mean?
Maybe they're intoxicated as
but we could practice in traffic. See,
it's one thing to be spiritual on Sunday
morning in church with all the hymns and
the music and all that.
It's another to be spiritual uh when
you're in the middle of traffic.
So, that would be a good exercise we
could do as a group.
saying that because you don't drive.
>> Well, I was a cab driver for years. I
drove a cab. I drove a truck. And uh All
right, we could do that. Is it because
you know being holy being all holy rolly
in church is easy. The hymns and the
music and the organ and everybody's all
so goody pie goody goody goody pie.
Next time. All right. So, that could be
a practice. It could become our a
practice that we recommend. New people
want to come in the group with them.
Yeah. Well, listen to what the rules
are.
You have to be loving and gracious and
forgiving towards everybody in traffic.
No matter what they do, even if they
pull pull up in front of you and slam
the brake on,
you still have to be forgiving.
That's a good discipline, right? Anybody
can be forgiving in church and pious and
holy and all that rolly holy poly.
Happiness is a destination. It's a
direction. It's not a end point or
there's no beginning and no end. Being
happy is a lifestyle.
It's a way of being in this world to
make the best of every situation to the
best that you can.
The spiritual lifestyle is reflective
versus impulsive.
It tends to be reflective. It sees how
you were rude to that person in traffic
to get even with them. So, it's
reflective and it says that was pretty
rude on my part and at the time you did
it, you justified it. But now when you
reflect on it, you say that really
wasn't a very gracious or
um wonderful thing I did there.
And so you decide to do better. So
you're constantly learning. A truly
spiritual person is constantly wor
learning and uh
get something out of everything. It's
reflective versus impulsive.
It's thoughtful rather than critical.
And it tends to be content instead of
complaining.
So instead of complaining
about circumstances, what we do is we uh
commit to a style of life that will
bring us closer and closer to our goal.
Uhu to be more and more self-forgiving
instead of uh self uh critical.
And you say, "Yeah, I was selfish right
there. I did take the last donut.
I did take the last doughnut.
I went out for lunch. I did not take the
last doughnut.
I was gooder than them.
All right. So, we get a sense of what
spiritual means. It's a whole style.
It's a way of being in the world.
It's a way of holding
values of yourself and the human
condition so that you're forgiving at
all times no matter how life goes.
That you did the best you could.
You can always attack yourself with the
hypothetical and say, "Well, I could
have done better." If you could have,
you would have.
The reason you don't do things is
because you really can't in a certain
state of mind. It's only when you're in
a different state of mind that you can
do it. So self-criticism,
self-awareness is different than
self-criticism.
To be self-aware,
you realize you could have been more
generous. Self-criticism is attacking
yourself for not being more generous. So
it's easier, it's better to be spiritual
than self-critical.
Life is a learning curve. All right. And
do we have any more slides? Oh my
goodness.
When in doubt, pray. Okay.
Pray.
Uh
when when I think of the times in my
life that I really prayed other than
going to church and some great
cathedral, you know, that's a certain
style of praying. Uh but when uh certain
death is looking you right in the eye,
that's when you really pray
when you're about to explode. So here's
his mind floating next to the ship and
it's about to explode and he's a second
and he says he was scared to death and
and I said to him, "Don't worry." I
said, "It's not going to go off." And
besides, even if it does, the only thing
that can happen is you'll die. And he
said, "Yeah, you're right."
And instantly his fear left him.
Instantly his fear left him. And uh it
was huge mine that was starting to bump
against the side of the ship and we're
trying to hold it away with this gaffing
gaff hook. And he says, "What if it
explodes?" And I said, I said, "Well,
then we die." He said, "Yeah, right. End
of fear. end of fear. When you accept
the worst possible scenario, accept the
worst possible scenario. That's another
way of uh getting rid of fear. Someday
you're going to be old and ugly and
blind. And I said, "Well, I guess so.
I'm at least halfway there, one eye
blind, and I ain't so good-looking as I
once was."
Uh
all right. So we seek through prayer and
contemplation.
Uh affirm that God is my source and my
solution.
Sing an inner voice. Now that's
something you don't read about, but you
pick an inner an inner song that pleases
you. Uh, I I like what the uh
what the bank piper played today.
>> And therefore
I could play his song that song within
my mind.
>> Amazing Grace.
>> Amazing Grace. Yes.
Amazing Grace. And uh so that that's my
song and especially on bag pipes.
Amazing grace is great. And I I have
great hopes that my funeral, the bag
piper will be playing Amazing Grace. If
not, you'll hear about it later when you
come over.
Okay. Where was the bag piper for God's
sake?
Sing an inner song. I think Amazing
Grace makes a beautiful song that that
type of an uplifting
purely spiritual. The Amazing Grace
itself is you know strictly uh spiritual
not religious spiritual. Okay. When
feeling down say to yourself
yours is the saddest story I've ever
heard.
Every once in a while, I give you little
clues about things to to write and put
on your mirror at home.
Things that you can post in the corner
of your mirror. And one of and this is
one of them. Yours is the saddest story
I have ever heard.
I've recommended that before. How many
people have yours is the saddest story
I've ever heard on their on their
mirror?
Hey, a few.
All right.
Best thing to do is write it down.
Yours is is the saddest story I've ever
heard. You can underline is.
We already said it's the saddest story,
but we should underline is. So after
this lecture, I want you to underline is
yours is the saddest story I've ever
heard. After the next lecture, we'll
underline saddest
is the sad. The was good, too. Is the
saddest story I have ever. You got
underline ever.
Okay. So, if you're poor, dumb, and
ugly,
and hopeless,
and everybody hates you.
When we were a kid, we sang a song,
"Everybody hates me. Guess I'll go eat
worms.
Everybody hates me. Guess I'll go eat
Guess I'll go eat worms. That's another
handy sign. So, you could change signs
during the moment so you don't get
bored. Like, here's the saddest story.
Uh, I think I'll go and eat worms.
I like even God feels sorry for me.
You remember that song, that story about
Wallaby? Everything goes wrong with his
life.
>> Yeah. He's poor and crippled. His
girlfriend leaves him. What is it, God?
The voice that comes out of the heaven
says, "I don't know either. Just
something about you pisses me off."
I always like that story.
Okay. Play the role of martyr and
justice collector. Play the role
happiness is a sessation.
Pray and contemplate.
Insist on.
>> Okay.
>> Why me? God, why you
why do my slides slide all over?
However, it doesn't bother me because I
am courageous and I will succeed no
matter what.
>> 79 up there around 74. All
right. When you're
down and out,
what's wrong is you fight it.
When you're down and out and you're
fighting being miserable and gloomy,
insist on being miserable and gloomy.
Your socks don't match.
You got a hole in one of them.
All your shirts are dirty and wrinkled.
The bed clothing fell on the floor
during the night and the cat slept on
it.
These are all very handy things. I've
done them all.
Make faces at yourself in the mirror.
That's a good one.
Anybody done that?
Oh, that's a good one. It's a great one.
I mean, that that one you can't you
can't beat make faces at yourself in the
mirror. You know, you look at the Z, you
go.
It's hard to say depressed and visible
when you make faces at yourself in the
mirror because the whole thing is I have
a hard time seeing myself in the mirror
now. So, I have a hard time making faces
at myself in the mirror. I go like this
and I got the lights on myself trying
I'll have to find some other way to
torment myself.
Be grateful for the gift of life when
everything else settles down and you
say, "Well, this is wrong. This is
wrong. These things have happened to
me." Uh, but I've had the gift of life.
And by living the gift of life in a
certain way, I have great hopes of uh
and looking forward to the afterlife.
So we live one day at a time and do the
best we can and try to be your own best
friend.
Yes,
you have to choose whether you're going
to expand on a problem or diminish it.
Are you going to be a diminisher or an
expander?
Oh my god, we're out of eggs, you know,
or we're out of eggs, so we'll have
cereal. I mean, which which way you can
have it either one way. Your day is
either ruined, we're all out eggs, or
you can be happy, oh great, it'll be
have cereal for a change.
Clarify the confusion of your capital S
self with your social role. The self is
one thing. Your social role is another.
You know you can be in the higher self
and fulfill any social role without
changing identification.
Play the role of martyr or the injustice
collector.
Play the role of the hero. You have the
option to play the role of the victim or
the hero. Play the role of morally
superior.
goodter than you. Yep. Let go of being
an injustice collector. Oh, how unjust
it is. Hey, we watch that all day on
television. When it's a competition for
injustice collectors, who's the most uh
martyed, you know, let go of being
provocative to others. Every time you
see yourself getting provocative, you
say, well, I may be triggered that. So,
see yourself as the trigger of events.
So if you see an event happen in your
life that you're not happy about, ask
how could I how could I have been the
trigger of that instead of blaming it on
the other person. The other person's
impatient.
So you get mad at them for being
impatient. Then you realize you've been
kept them waiting for 10 minutes while
you stood there and brush your teeth.
Stop pushing your luck. Avoid
catastrophe. Do not buy a house in the
flood plane.
or on the edge of a mine mud cliff.
Every day there's a sad story. Went out
all by himself in the jungle and got
lost.
Built a house on the edge of the
mudcliff and the mud cliff slid down and
along with your house.
Ask yourself, who in the world would
build a house on the edge of a mud
cliff?
They do it all the time. You can drive
down certain places in the California
coast. Sure enough, mud cliff house,
the house is just edging itself closer
and closer to the edge.
I'll say to Susan, I don't know how
people can live
that close to a cliff in in the mud mud
cliffs. All right. Let go of being
injustice collector. Let go of being
provocative. Stop pushing one's luck.
Avoid catastrophe. People like to say
they're they're not guilty. They're not
responsible for it. Last week, I had a
doctor's appointment at 9 in the morning
and and the weather news said there was
going to be what do you call it?
>> Tornado.
>> Tornado. Right. The weather news said
tornado. Stay off route 89A.
So instead of pushing our luck and then
blaming it on the weather, we just
cancelled the doctor's appointment.
Simple enough, isn't it? But you can see
how many people would push it, keep the
doctor's appointment, go off the road,
be taken away by a a tow truck, and have
a long sad story.
So, don't keep pushing your luck. Avoid
catastrophe.
Do not buy a house in the flood plane or
the edge of a mud cliff.
Do not win the lottery.
You ever see the story what happens to
people's lives who win the lottery? The
divorce rate is close to 100%. Murder,
suicide, divorce, and uh surprisingly
half of them become bankrupt. How can
you win the lottery and go bankrupt?
They they figured out how to do it. Do
not ski in an avalanche area. These are
the things that drive me crazy when I
watch the news. I can't stand watching
the news.
Some idiot goes up to the avalanche area
and of course he almost dies. His skis
turn over and they got to send an
ambulance
and a plane to get him. Anybody who
wants to climb uh you know great big
climbers, I would make them post a bond
with the state. You have to post a
$10,000 bond if you're going to climb
Mount Everest.
The 90 people who didn't make it have
cost the taxpayers a fortune.
If you're going to climb Mount Everest,
you have to post a 10,000, you know,
million-doll bond with the parks
department,
obey the law, be polite to the police.
All these things seem so simple, and yet
every day on the news, I see people
mouth off to the police.
A cop is the last person I think I would
mouth off to.
Stop demonstrating.
Oh god, there's another one that gets
me. Every day you see demonstrators out
there, they've got these big signs. Uh
because they're going to demonstrate.
And I always think, uh, who cares what
you think?
They're pro this or they're against
that. Why would anybody care what you
think about it?
Anyway, they take it very seriously.
Stop demonstrating.
Uh it's a good idea to give up saving
the world.
It's a really good idea to mind your own
business.
The ego doesn't want to hear mind your
own business. It's my responsibility as
a citizen to get out there and
demonstrate.
my responsibility to get out there and
demonstrate as a citizen.
Yeah.
Give up being important. Oh, that's it.
Demonstrators. I think what goes on with
demonstrators? Well, you get a feeling
of being important.
Oh,
another idea is pay your income taxes.
This never seems to dawn on the leaders
of our country.
There isn't the bigname leader out there
who isn't behind in their income taxes.
You have ever noticed that? That's the
funniest thing. No matter who they are,
the president's cabinet is made up of
people who do not pay their income
taxes.
And the head of the tax department
hasn't paid his taxes.
All right. Lastly, smile and the world
smiles with you.
uh cry and you cry alone.
Dedicate all your actions to God. Well,
what happens if you dedicate all your
actions to God is they automatically
become changed and purified.
If you dedicate this demonstration to
God, you have to fool yourself into
thinking that your ego is divinity
because nobody's going to be pleased
about your demonstrating except you.
Uh so all of these steps that we uh talk
about uh bring about an inner humility
and it's the inner humility you stop
listening to the voice of the ego and in
its place reigns the silence of God
and that God is all that is becomes
readily apparent without a single
thought. The divinity of all that exists
shines forth.
All that exists is divinity.
Nothing else except divinity exists.
Without divinity, there's no sky.
There's no earth. There's no table.
There's no Suzie. There's no audience.
The only thing that exists is divinity.
Period.
Nothing else exists except divinity.
God in the infinite number of
expressions as people, as stage, as
sorne, as cane, as a cup of coffee.
The capacity to exist
is solely that of divinity.
What I just said is the truth. Zoe,
that ought to do it for today.
Everything that is
everything that exists
is an expression of divinity.
Divinity as this cane, as this table, as
this Kleenex.
There's only two things. One is
existence and the other is
non-existence.
All that exists is divinity.
That makes life simple. Amen. Thank you.
Ah, boy.
Thank you, honey.
I can't see.