real quick there is a jacket left in the bookstore with a it's a black jacket and
it has a cell phone in the pocket so if anyone's missing their jacket it's in
the bookstore give you a dollar for a cell phone yes I thank you for pressing
through you and I love you and all people here I would like to bow you nine
times he wants to bow to you I understand yeah yeah yes God bless you
amen God bless you oh no become Christian it
saves you a lot of work
God bless you
hello doctor hello dr. Hawkins I don't have a question I just wanted to say I
thank God every day for your teaching and the effect that it has had in my
life and now I want to thank you and as
you know I'm a Christian I'm a Christian I'm a Christian I'm a Christian I'm a
Christian I'm a Christian I'm a Christian I'm a Christian I'm a Christian I'm a
Christian I'm a Christian I'm a Christian I'm a Christian
I ask to be in your presence and hold your hand
yes tell you thank you thank you so much
God bless your sweetheart Oh
sure Thank You yes hello hi I tell myself I was gonna cry but I want to
thank you in this and I just want to give you helping and that is all I can do just
thank you yes oh Thank You so much and bring all of you home all of you have been
And just, I just wanted to be here in your presence.
And thank you for everything.
And I'm so grateful that I have found you at this time in my life.
And I love you.
Thank you for coming up and meeting us.
Thank you.
What did you say?
I'll leave it.
Thank you.
Oh, thank you.
First of all, I'd just like to thank you for your teachings.
And I have a question.
I'm having trouble with karma, understanding karma.
Is there a point where, in an incarnation, where you have, there's a delineation between you have now gone beyond your karmic debt.
Yeah.
You now are in karmic destiny.
That's true, yeah.
Is that true?
Oh, yeah.
So that may happen.
That's one of the great purposes of reincarnation.
So without being enlightened.
Right, yeah.
That may happen.
Yeah, you'd like to get over that karma without necessarily becoming enlightened.
Right.
So that may happen.
Fantastic.
That was my question.
And could I also get a picture?
You bet.
Yeah.
Okay.
Thank you, Doctor.
Hello.
Thank you, Susan.
Yeah.
I would like to say thank you for guiding us on this life and making it a little easier to get by.
My question is, the last time I was here, I was sitting in the audience.
And I wasn't sure if I was going to make it back.
So I was trying to absorb.
As much as I can out of you, because I watch the lectures every time, and I listen to them.
On the next day, as I was, I work as a flight attendant, and as I'm trying to get on the plane, walking back,
I couldn't look at people in the face because I kept feeling these emotions in my heart.
And when I got to the hotel, I couldn't stop crying.
So I was calling all the other spiritual students to help me understand what's happening.
The next day, I felt numb, like I couldn't practice all the books I've read.
And I'm thinking, do I have to read these books all over again?
I don't understand what is happening.
But on the third day, I felt a spiritual high that I couldn't control.
And the continuous miracle is just multiplied by plenty.
In your view, can you please tell me?
He said a...
He's having, like, the first, second, and third day, he was going through all these different things.
And the third day, he had the miraculous start to happen, and it kept happening and happening.
And, you know, he's confused because he doesn't really know, you know, why it's happening.
He doesn't need to know why.
What do you want to know why for?
To see where I'm going to go.
Huh?
To see where he's going to go.
You're trying to control the whole phenomenon instead of letting it just unfold of its own.
Thank you.
Could I have two seconds of transmission?
Huh?
He wants to just be with you.
Come over here.
Yeah, you don't have to understand what's happening.
Thank you, doctor.
First of all, you can't understand what's happening.
You're too dumb.
Thank you.
Thank you, doctor.
It's because the ego is dumb.
The ego is all he's talking about.
He's not talking about his real self.
Because his real self is what's concerned about it all.
We always call the ego the dumb self.
You know, that's your dumb self.
I don't have a question.
What do we need?
I just wanted to...
Yeah.
There we are.
God bless you.
Okay, I got another announcement.
Uh-oh.
What's wrong with you people?
You're losing everything.
I've never had this many announcements in all the lectures we've had,
but everyone keeps leaving stuff.
Okay, now we got keys for a sob in the bookstore,
and there's a pendulum someone left.
So if you could please go to the bookstore and pick that up,
we would appreciate it.
Thank you.
I could use an extra sob.
I'm not here to ask any questions,
but I'm here to say thank you.
Yes.
About four years ago, God guided me to you in Atlanta,
and I've been coming here for three or four times every year since.
But I'm here to say goodbye because I'm not coming back.
But I'm going to take my information that I've got from you,
and a year ago, I asked you,
should I run for mayor of my town and back home
to 12,000 people in the Cajun country?
And your answer was, yes, by all means.
So I'm bringing you my campaign card here.
Right.
What is this?
Campaign card.
His campaign card.
He's running for mayor.
Oh.
The election, the voting is 10-2-10, October 2nd of this year.
Where, where?
My campaign slogan is, we're all in this together.
Where, where, where is it?
This is in what city?
Eunice, Louisiana, in the Cajun country.
You ain't.
In the Chapelleye Basin.
Eunice, Louisiana.
Where they have the crawfish and the alligators.
What's he running for, mayor?
Mayor.
Mayor of the city.
It's a really good town with a community college that calibrates high,
and a mayor that's from another country that doesn't understand Cajuns.
So I thought I could do a better job.
Cajun?
Yes, Cajuns.
Oh.
They're a mixture of lots of good people.
Yes.
They have good music.
Good music, good food, good attitude.
They also cut up a lot.
They also what?
Cut up a lot.
They can cut up a bit.
Oh, the Cajun people.
Yes.
Oh, yes.
I want to give blessings on the race, on the election,
and maybe the blessings of all the people here.
See, I want to stack my courts.
He wants some blessings of everybody here so he can stack the deck.
Oh.
I'm not going to play fan.
Thank you, then.
Well, at least he's a jolly mayor, a jolly mayor.
He'd be a good mayor.
We'll have fun.
You'll have fun.
He's going to be a jolly mayor.
Merci.
Merci beaucoup.
I hardly ever get to meet a mayor.
What?
Because I can take all these teachings.
That's the first mayor I've met all year.
Oh, right.
Hey, that's a positive statement.
He said, call me mayor already.
Yeah, I never get to meet any mayors.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
Yes.
Hi, Susan.
Hi.
I don't have any questions.
I just want to thank you both for leading me to these teachings
and for helping me find so much joy in existence.
It's really a gift.
Thank you.
Okay.
Thank you for thanking me.
Yes.
Thank you for thanking us.
Thank you for thanking me for thanking you.
Thank you for thanking us for thanking you for thanking us.
Bye.
Thank you, Dr. Hawkins.
Yes.
And thank you, everybody here.
Thank you.
Just like a blessing to shake your hand and get a photo.
Yes, indeed.
It's my pleasure.
God bless you.
Show that picture to St. Peter when you get there.
Okay.
Just one second.
Sure.
The bookstore is closing, so if you have any more lost items, they're going home.
Thank you both so much.
I have a question.
In recent years, I've experienced very powerful shaking in my body.
Very powerful.
Shaking.
Oh.
The shakes.
The shakes often are accompanied by challenging emotions of terror, sadness, isolation, as
well as physical pain.
At times, I also speak in an audible voice in a language I do not know.
I have sought medical as well as spiritual support, and the shakes just keep going.
Can you help me understand what I am experiencing?
Do you have any advice on how I can relieve?
Can you help me relieve the suffering?
It's got a whole lot of stuff on there.
What's number one you're experiencing?
What?
Shaking.
Huh?
The shaking.
Shaking.
Along with some pain.
Pain and shaking?
It's what I think it is.
Do you have a psychiatrist?
I have in the past worked with a psychiatrist, yes.
It was quite a while ago.
Did she say yes or no?
She doesn't have one at this time.
That's all I want to know.
Uh-huh.
Have you ever had hypnosis?
No.
Did hypnosis help?
No, she's never had hypnosis.
I did not have hypnosis.
Oh, no.
Hypnosis would help that.
Okay.
You could maybe cure it in one session, really.
Great.
Thank you.
Yeah.
You could probably cure that with one session of hypnosis.
Peace, calm, relax.
Yeah.
Deeper, deeper, deeper.
Mm-hmm.
Peace, calm, relax.
Deeper, deeper, deeper.
Like so.
I turn this over to my Lord today.
Thank you.
We begin our prayer of Jesus to heal with peace and calm.
There you go.
Okay.
And if you do that, calmly, repeatedly, it will disappear.
Amen.
Thank you.
Well, by using the name of Jesus Christ, you will chase out any negative energies
that you might have picked up.
Yes.
Inadvertently.
Yeah.
Okay.
Okay?
Yes.
Thank you.
Yeah.
I am a Christian minister raised by a Christian minister father.
had three incredibly
scary
experiences with the devil.
Once when I was six
for four days.
Once when I was 25
and I knew what to do
but I
was fighting my
intellectuality like
this can't be true. Oh, I see.
And then again when I was
44 and a pastor.
Yeah. My question is
is it real?
Because I do have to talk about this
and what is the
meaning of it in my own
journey? What's the meaning of real to you?
Experiencing it in my own
body. Yeah. So it's real.
I mean it's a real sensation
and it's probably a
lower astral entity. A lower astral
entity resistant. Okay.
So it's coming. He's pulling it
in with guilt.
You're pulling in a lower astral entity with
guilt. Now at six it was
the devil as we, with the horns and the
pitchfork. At 25 it was
a demonic energy that I
could see. Well you get whatever
you know, visuals you want out of it.
But it's the same
guilt
and
you know
the, what do they call it, the
challenging of spirits
and if they are not of God
you have the right and the power
to order them
to leave. That's
given to you by our Lord and by our
Lord Jesus Christ.
He has the power and the right to
order these spirits to
leave. And they must then
do so. They must
do so. It's called
the something or other of spirits.
I forget the name of it. The something or other of
spirits. The challenging of spirits.
If it is not of my Lord Jesus
Christ I order you
to leave.
And they must then obey.
Is there any meaning to the fact they happen every
19 years? I don't
know. You know, we'd have to have
a whole session about that.
It's that particular
cycle. You know, it could be some
lifetime. At the age
of 19 you
expired and cursed somebody or something
and brought in that negative entity.
He cursed somebody.
It was just...
Alright.
Forgive me God.
Thank you.
It's best not to curse
people.
I wanted to ask, you had
said in a video that
you spent an 11 day period
letting go of
everything, surrendering things
and then subsequently
at Rothman's restaurant in Long
Island you had a
profound
experience.
I was just wondering if you could talk about that.
No. How about if I give you a dollar?
I don't remember
the experience.
That was the one
where you had that entity come.
No, that was a different one I think.
I remember
the seriousness of the incident.
The importance of it.
But I don't remember exactly what the incident
was.
But I remember the rest. I remember where it was.
And it was rather
profound except that I've forgotten it now.
How about the letting go
for 11 days? Could you talk about that?
No. Wanting to please
people is one of the things I let go.
Okay. That's cool.
Wanting to fulfill their curiosity
is something I let go.
Allowing them to seek
a similar experience
on their own. Really
using my experience as an inspiration.
An inspiration. Yeah.
So we serve as an inspiration
to each other.
Yeah.
Even though we may not duplicate the same
exact experience.
The degree of commitment
energizes other people
to make an even greater
commitment and effort. Spiritual effort.
So we help each other
one way or the other.
Thank you.
Can I shake your hand? Indeed.
God bless you.
God bless you. Yes.
Hi Dr. Hawkins. Yes.
It's a great honor
to be here and to meet you sir.
Meet you both and all these
great people. Thank you to whoever
turned in the Toyota keys.
Go ahead.
He says thank you to whoever
turned in the Toyota keys.
Oh.
I wanted to ask
as I study your books
and aspire
spiritually. I was
wondering if you recommend
or if it's beneficial
for an aspirant to
calibrate his own level of
consciousness or if that's something
that would be an egotistical
desire.
Can one calibrate their own level of consciousness?
Not really.
No. Not really.
That's kind of what I was thinking.
Is that something that...
It would be better to
go over the spiritual teachers and see
which ones would be the best for you.
Which ones resonate with you the most.
Because it doesn't
correlate
mathematically necessarily.
Right. Because you may be very
compatible with this spiritual teacher
and not so compatible with this one.
And the numbers may not match
what you're thinking.
I see.
Because some teachers will inspire you
and others will not.
So others may seem boring.
Right.
Because they are dullards.
That's perfect. I appreciate that.
Thank you, sir.
May I shake your hand?
We get sort of attracted to the right teacher.
Yes.
God bless you.
Thank you, John.
First, I want to thank you for your
absolutely delightful sense of humor.
I've had more belly laughs
and I feel like it is really
it opens the heart
to be able to be in that space
to receive what you say.
So thank you so much
for being who you are.
I would say joy is closer to God than guilt.
A lot of people try to get to God
through guilt.
Oh, Lord, how ungrateful.
How unworthy I am.
What a worm.
I am such an unworthy worm.
In the back of his mind, God's saying,
you're right.
Come back when you give up being a worm.
Thank you.
My question is,
I'm so aware that I want to live my life
from my heart.
And I was wondering what you would say
to be able to help me maintain that
and to be able to be more in that place.
Why do you want to make it more?
Because I know I'm not always there.
That's what I mean.
Because what?
She knows she's not always in there.
I'm not always coming from my heart.
She's not always coming from her heart.
Oh, yes.
You're a human being.
That's right.
Not everybody deserves your coming from the heart.
Sometimes you should tell them,
you've been mirroring underneath it
and I'm calling my lawyer.
That's right.
Our, what's her name?
Parrot.
Our parrot at home.
She's teaching them.
I'm calling my lawyer.
It's hysterically funny.
Call my lawyer.
So whatever anybody complains about,
it sounds comical.
Nobody's coming in there
blubbering about this and that and the other
in the background of the birds saying,
call your lawyer.
I'm calling your lawyer.
It's just comical.
A good sense of humor is really useful.
It's really important.
Is that it?
What's happening?
Nothing.
Are you speaking to me?
Yes, is that your response to my question
of how to be in my heart?
Sometimes you can't always be there.
Yes.
Well, you do the best you can
and the rest is up to God.
People are always trying to tell God how to do things.
I want God.
I want enlightenment.
God, I want to be from the heart.
God, I want to be from the solar plexus.
God, I want to be from my child.
God, I want to be from my chest,
my arms, my elbows.
Poor old God.
Thank you.
Okay, we're going to do five more minutes
and then we'll take a quick break
so everyone can break
and then we'll come right back.
Oh, is that true?
You're not pulling my leg, are you?
No.
No?
Okay.
Hi.
I just wanted to thank God and you
for transforming my life.
Thank you.
Chris.
My name is Chris Ranoway
and I'm walking between
the
and the
So is there anything beyond selfless service to others
that can help us be prepared for that?
Oh, your intention, your daily routine,
what you read, who you pray to,
it all sums up, you know, by the end of the day.
By the time the market closes, you know,
the Tao has said so-and-so.
Your spiritual Tao for the day.
You know, it all sums up, it all sums up,
and then averages out.
You got up days and down days,
and days where you feel you make a great progress,
and other days where you feel you went backward or bad.
You ever feel like you're bad?
Yes.
No, you don't, okay.
So the kid in you is still active, huh?
Who is bad? Kids are bad, right?
That's right.
Yeah, all right.
Thank you.
Yes.
That's great.
He just became invisible.
Hello?
Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
Yes.
I don't have a question,
but I just wanted to say namaste to you all,
and namaste.
Thank you so much.
I'd like a picture.
Thank you.
Okay, we're going to take a quick break,
and we'll be back in about 15 minutes.
12 and a half minutes.
Okay.
God bless you all.
Amen.
In the name of the Lord, amen.
Remember, major boats amateur are.
Then they would have a hook.
They hook and pull you off the stage.
Hi, teacher.
Hi, Susan.
My question is really simple.
It's when a student, a spiritual student,
is going through transitions.
I'm not hearing what she's saying.
You have to speak slower.
Okay.
When a spiritual student going through transitions.
She's a spiritual student?
Yes.
Yes, going through transitions.
Okay.
And then when you value seeing things quite different,
sort of make my loved ones nervous.
Like.
What'd she say?
Her family's a little nervous, you know,
because.
Going through changes?
Yeah.
Yes.
Oh, yeah.
Okay.
Yeah.
And I just wonder if there is a way of communication
that to comfort them so they don't get so nervous
about you getting become a weirdo or something.
They're a little concerned about her going
into a spiritual state so she's.
Well, just behave yourself.
If you sit quietly in a meditative state,
there's nothing for them to panic about, is there?
No.
Okay.
So what are they panicking about?
You're standing on your head or what?
I wish just that.
I was wondering because when you're ready to give
up a high-paying job, they get really nervous.
What?
When you're willing to give up a high-paying job,
they get really nervous.
It's your money, huh?
It's your money.
So you tell them you have to decide between money and God.
What about if they don't understand God?
Huh?
What if they don't understand God?
That's their problem.
Okay.
You know, spirituality is a phenomena in all cultures.
So, I mean, they don't live out in the middle of deserts separated
from mankind, do they?
No.
So they must know that spirituality attracts a certain percentage
of the people and they should have the tolerance.
They're your parents, right?
Yes.
So if they don't like what's happening, you just say,
well, you brought me up.
Okay.
That's their problem.
If my mom asks, I'm going to say, my teacher told me that.
Thank you so much.
They brought you up.
Yes, they brought me right up here.
Thank you so much.
That's funny.
Yes.
Hello, doctor.
I've been planning quite a bit since the last time I came
for this experience to be spontaneous.
Was this your first time?
What's he saying?
Nothing.
It was just .
And because of that, people have asked me,
what question am I going to ask you?
And I've continued to just want to be in your presence
and be spontaneous about, you know, what that was.
But I guess my question is, are you the ideal spiritual teacher
for me?
I don't know.
You're the only one who knows.
I feel as if that's true.
Well, then it's true.
Are you going to be giving lectures on the other side?
And if so, can I sign up?
Well, I haven't been back there for a while,
so I don't know what to do.
Check the weather pattern back.
Heavenly weather patterns.
And can I shake your hand and have your blessing?
So what do you need to know?
You have to shake your hand and ask for your blessing.
OK.
That's fine.
That's good indeed.
That's simple.
Yes.
As long as you're simple, keep it simple.
Keep it simple.
Easy does it, and keep it simple.
Yeah.
And live one day at a time.
I'd like to say thank you for the teachings
and the impact they've had for my life.
And I'd like to shake your hand.
Yes, indeed.
May I hold your hand and receive a blessing?
God bless you.
Is there any more coffee anywhere?
Yes.
Hello.
Hi.
I just wanted to say thank you, and I'd
like to shake your hand and say thank you for your blessings,
and thank you for your teachings.
Is that the end of the coffee?
No.
OK.
Hi.
I, too, just wanted to say thank you for your love and energy,
and shake your hand for a blessing.
God bless you.
Yes.
Hello.
Am I OK like this?
Yep.
OK, good.
OK.
Nice to see you both.
I wanted to thank you for giving me your blessing a few years ago
and allowing me to quote from you in the establishment of my website,
the God Anti-Defamation League, which I was inspired to do because
of one of your DVDs a number of years ago, one of your lectures,
where you said, I am, you know, about all of the bad words
and the bad usage of the word of God and all the things that have been attributed to God,
and that you had come down, and you are the CEO of the God Anti-Defamation League,
and you aren't going to take it anymore.
That's right.
You're the God Anti-Defamation League.
Oh, yes, I know who you are, no?
Yes, thank you very much.
Defend the good name of God.
Yes, exactly right.
Good for you.
Thank you very much.
And I had a question about marriage.
About what?
Marriage.
Marriage?
Oh.
I'm curious.
I've never been married.
And here I am at 61, and I've actually
been thinking about it a little bit.
He's never been what?
He's never been married.
He's 61.
Oh, I see.
Thinking about it.
Oh, yeah, uh-huh.
And I'm curious to have your thoughts on what
might constitute a truly an ideal union, if you will,
or a workable unit at any rate.
And further, if you had any words that you might suggest as a vow that.
Two people want to be together with each other.
That's all it takes.
And therefore, it must be significant.
Yeah.
Because you enjoy being with each other.
See?
And you love her.
Yeah.
Most of the time.
That's the way it is, generally.
Yeah.
After a while, it's all the time.
I guess it is for me, frankly.
I guess that's about it.
I did have a couple more questions, but they limited me to one.
So that's all I'm going to do is one.
Can I ask you this, though?
Oh, you want to do it?
Yeah.
You once mentioned that you were really looking forward,
when you get to the other side, if you were
going to be able to talk to and be around Socrates
and all your old buddies.
Oh, yes.
And I'm wondering if, when I get to the other side,
I'll be able to chum with you a little bit.
Oh, of course.
Hey.
Hey, can we have a picture, please?
Oh, you bet.
Yes.
Thank you.
Socrates was short and ugly, and that always made me feel good.
OK, make sure he's smiling.
Thank you.
Short and ugly.
Yeah.
He was short and bad-looking, ugly, Socrates.
Hello.
Doctor.
I was wondering if you and I and all these people here
could say, om, together.
Well, you can do the om.
Together?
Well, if you want to do the om, start.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Thank you.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
Hi, Mrs. Hawkins.
I want to say thank you for all your wisdom
and for the powerful force that you are in all of our lives.
And my question is, could you calibrate chiropractic
philosophy?
Is there such a thing?
The what?
Yes.
There is no such thing as chiropractic philosophy.
Yeah, there is.
The founder of chiropractic wrote numerous books
and in order.
The founder of chiropractic wrote several books on it.
There is no such thing as chiropractic philosophy.
What about, I can ask you a question,
because what we are taught in school is that there is an inborn intelligence in our body
which is part of universal intelligence which is God and through the power of an adjustment
you're able to connect innate with universal or bring it closer together if that's is that
you're able to what connect what innate intelligence with universal intelligence yeah to universal
intelligence yeah that is so resist thank you may I take a picture with you all forms
of healing are inspirational
there's great
care I'd rather have a great chiropractor than a lousy MD what kind of treatments do I get I get
some kind of treatments what are those those are kinesiologic are they are they so I go for
kinesiologic treatments otherwise they'd be limping all over limping with a cane and now I
walk pretty straight yes yes my question is about deja vus are they the experience I've had are they
just illusions that my ego makes or not there for real I
get confused about she talked about the future and you can predict the future
what's the question did he asked about déjà vu yeah if the deja vus you want
to know if deja vu are really experience yes and I think if you have you know if if there's same thing with deja vu or you go and, contacting companies but I also see like you know if you wanted to talk about your
create your own journey through
yesまで awesome ritual that's incredible yeah but like you know when you back in the good old days we need to maintain this сейчас
I think it's due to a dualistic firing of neurons.
Usually when you have an experience,
only one neuron pathway is carrying it,
and an alternate pathway is damped down,
so it's not responding.
If it fails to damp it down,
then you're getting the same information,
but via two different neuronal pathways.
That is correct resistance.
It tends to come in episodic.
Okay, so it has nothing to do with me thinking like it's...
I dreamed about the future, and then it happened.
It's just...
His deja vus come in the form of his dreams about it,
and then it happens in real life,
a repeated conversation or something.
Oh, yeah.
Just for like one second or something.
Yeah, as Yogi Berra said,
it's just deja vu
over and over again.
It's an interesting phenomena,
which I myself have studied a little bit recently,
and we got...
The messages are coming through two different circuits,
and normally one circuit is supposed to damp down,
but for some reason, which I haven't had a chance to check out,
and it's probably not important anyway,
it reports dualistically from two different background time scenes.
Yes.
Seeming different scenes, yeah.
There's nothing to worry about it.
Okay.
May I kiss your feet?
Yeah.
He wants to touch your feet.
Yes.
Kiss your feet.
Okay.
Yeah, deja vu is very interesting,
and it tends to come and go of its own accord
with no particular reason.
Maybe I haven't spent enough time checking it out,
because it has a limited value, I guess.
I had deja vu, and it only happened in restaurants.
Every time I was in a restaurant, it was like,
I've been in this restaurant before,
and the same thing is about to occur.
The same waitress would come up and say the same thing.
From what I understand,
there's a point where we stop seeking information
outside of ourselves as far as spiritual truth is,
and we ask the field, and it's supposed to come in.
Yes.
What I'm wondering is if my intention is to find the truth
and to come closer to God, but I'm worried that I'm really naive
and that I'll be easily led astray,
how do I, do I just walk through that fear and go?
And led astray by what?
By like the astral circus or something,
or like some sort of trick.
The astral circus.
Or some sort of trick, like I won't understand, and I'll...
Oh.
Well, the way to avoid the astral circus
is avoid anything that is other than you, other.
In other words, it's only yourself at all times.
So otherness indicates a separation
or some other spirit entity.
There is only the reality of yourself.
Yeah?
Yes, sir, thank you.
She had something else to say.
Yeah, what?
Yes, indeed.
Oh, thank you.
So my question is, in healing and recovery,
you talked about how to heal eyesight,
and I wanted to know more about what is needed,
because in the book you say, I am an infinite being
and I'm not subject to poor eyesight.
What is this question?
So what would you recommend?
What would you recommend?
What is there a...
What would I recommend for what?
Is there more?
To improve the eyesight, though you say that you're an infinite being,
you're not just a mere being.
Yes.
So he wants to know what you did for your eyesight at the time...
Oh, you just reaffirm that your reality is perfection
and that you only see what you need to see when you need to see it.
So it's not necessary to see everything all the time.
It's only necessary to see what you need to see when you need to see it.
You don't need to know where the edge of the cliff is
unless you get close to it.
Now, if you're...
Where do we go with the...
To fall off the cliff?
Where is it in Arizona?
Grand Canyon, right.
You need to know where the edge is.
So don't try your first experiment.
You notice about nine people a year go over the side of the Grand Canyon.
For many years it was reported.
I think it was...
Let's see.
It was about nine people a year.
Where is this?
Yeah, about nine people a year fell off the...
Grand Canyon.
Grand Canyon for years.
And the paper would always report it, you know, nine people fell off.
The next year it would say eight people fell off.
The next year it's eight, ten people.
But at Gradsley it was around about nine people rather consistently.
Now I've noticed that the paper, they no longer report it.
They haven't reported people falling off the Grand Canyon for about over five years.
Over four years, over five years, okay, over five years, over six years.
About five years ago, they stopped reporting how many people had fallen off the side of the Grand Canyon
because it finally had dawned on them that this was really suicide.
These are really people that didn't slip and fall.
It was their way of committing suicide without being blamed for being suicidal,
either spiritually or legally or financially or whatever.
Yeah.
I thought it's very interesting that they no longer report it.
So do you recommend walking without the glasses on?
Like, I understand.
Not around the Grand Canyon.
Yes.
Can I shake hands?
I did many things that I probably should not have written about.
The reason was I lost my fear of fear.
So fear would keep most people within certain boundaries, but I lost fear, and I lost my fear of fear.
So the fact that I was afraid, I would just do it anyway.
You know, you walk through the final door, it was more than fear, it was like terror, but you just do it anyway.
So fear keeps most people from approaching the edge, you know, the experiential edge,
where the Grand Canyon only is symbolic of being close to the edge of what you're able to tolerate.
Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
I just want to, first off, express my gratitude for being in your presence today.
My question is, if we have permission, at what level on the map of consciousness does coffee calibrate at?
It doesn't calibrate on the level of consciousness, talking.
Coffee.
Oh, coffee.
Oh.
Never calibrated.
Just a beverage, huh?
Do we have permission to do so?
Calibrate coffee?
He wants to know what coffee calibrates at.
Why do you want to know what coffee calibrates at?
Well, green tea apparently calibrates at 300-something.
What is he saying?
I'm sorry.
What is your question?
So my question is, I guess I'm curious as to what level coffee calibrates at.
Coffee.
As coffee, the beverage.
Why do you want to know that?
As in, there are so many health beliefs regarding coffee, and I suppose, like, some people say it's bad for you,
some people say it's good for you, and I was sort of curious.
It's probably the same thing.
Coffee's good for some people, but not everybody.
Yeah.
So it doesn't have to be.
It doesn't have to do with the calibration of coffee.
It has to do with the person's tolerance.
Whether or not it's good for that person.
Right, yeah.
So that would be impossible to tell.
That's a different question.
Yeah.
Okay.
So it'd probably be hard to calibrate that.
Yeah.
Because if, you know, if you were saying, is coffee good for me, we could calibrate that,
but if you said calibrate just coffee, well, it might be coffee probably calibrates
at a certain level, but that's not necessarily.
Probably calibrates the same as vegetables.
Coffee calibrates.
Let's ask the question.
We have permission first.
We have permission to ask about coffee.
It calibrates about the same as vegetables resist.
Calibrates over 200, 205, 202, 203.
It's a little over 200, yeah.
Thank you.
And if I may shake your hand and receive your blessing.
Yes.
As well.
Mm-hmm.
Where's my coffee?
Someone forgot this.
Okay.
Someone forgot this at the bookstore.
We do not have a name on this.
What is it?
It's, they bought a bunch of stuff.
Like what?
Like.
DVDs?
February's, Satsang.
We have CDs, DVD, audio, CDs, DVDs.
Somebody must have forgotten something at the bookstore, so speak up.
There it is.
CD.
DVD.
Double Dasher 2, 1-1-1.
Ah, theizzy?
That's promo 2.
Does somebody recognize her?
Well, all right.
Sorry, if everybody isn't able to hear you, somebody may know who's there.
Okay.
And they're going to be horrible, but I just want to tell them what they can do.
And then you're going to have some talk later.
Thank you, sir.
Someone's noticed me.
Yeah.
That's chewing gum.
Yeah, that's chewing gum.
Well, I'll take a, and that's chewing gum.
Thank you.
Rest on your feet.
Thank you, sir, and good night.
Good night.
Thank you very much.
yes thank you yes you bet i'll be happy to yes yes god bless you god bless you thank you so much
and this is his book this is your book yes oh i see it's in korean yes that's a beautiful book
yeah i mean it's well published smile that costs extra there we go thank you for asking me
yes hey dr hawkins hello i'll tell you i don't have any uh questions but i just want to tell you
how much i appreciate the work you've done and uh i would like to comment that uh i picked up
power versus force about uh three years ago quite by chance at a bookstore i almost didn't
pick it up at all and even to this day some as much as i but anyway i did pick the book up and
since then i've read everything
published through veritas and uh there are times when uh when i think of how close i came to not
even touching that book at all it it scares me yes i'm a little frightened myself a little
frightened myself but uh i just wanted to make that comment and uh see and i appreciate uh i
want to shake your hand and receive a blessing and yes have a picture if we can thank you very
much guys i have to read power versus force myself i've forgotten what the heck i said in the book
i've got it in all the world's languages or most of the world's major languages
stacked up in my office i forgot what the heck i said in there
hello dr hawkins i like just i would like to express my gratitude for helping
for showing me the way back to god yes thank you thank you may i shake your hand yes god bless
god bless you amen
look at that i think i'll sign it back because it doesn't stick a little bit are you sure
yeah all right hi my question is about co-creation um as far as uh through my level
when I was growing spiritually
as I grow spiritually
I believe that
we co-create with God and in the eye of the eye
you said that we don't
in the eye of the eye what?
you say we don't co-create with God
oh yeah that's sort of self-flattering
well I was just wondering
I was wondering because of the
disease process what we
hold in mind tends to manifest
yes that's true
that's a negative
yeah
so the negatives that you hold in mind
tend to manifest
if you believe you're allergic
to something then you become
allergic to something
and if we hypnotize a person
and tell them you're allergic to roses
their nose will run when they're around roses
but then if we tell them you're
not allergic to roses
they will not get that
reaction around roses
so
suggestion and belief systems
are
are powerful
but only up to a certain point
they're not infinitely
powerful so they're not
you know like the power of God
within them
you can even calibrate
at what level
a belief system fails to actualize
within the physical
body
generally if you believe you have allergies
you have allergies
and if you generally
if you believe you're immune to allergies
then generally
you have allergies
you are immune to them
but that is not an absolute
it's a likelihood
the options that we're
able to have
don't affect
creation like whether you
write these books
or whether you do
something else with life
the options
I don't know what he's asking
part of creation, part of co-creating
co-creating
with God is a sort of a new
equation
a new age cutesy kind of an idea
okay
God doesn't say
I invite you to come and help co-create with me
thank you
it's because of the power of divinity within you
that any action occurs at all
so you could say that God participates in every instant
everything that you do every instant
because without divinity you wouldn't have no existence
it's the divinity within
thank you
it's where the rubber hits the road
you know what I mean
thank you
oh picture yes
I like that
individual human beings
like where the rubber hits the road
some of us go 80 miles an hour
and others go 22 miles an hour
you bet
like they say
it isn't the fall
it's the sudden stop at the end that gets you
yeah
peace and blessings to you Dr. Hawkins
I had a whole lot of questions for you
but I'm just going to say
may I shake your hand
and take a picture
thank you
okay
God bless you
God bless you brother
great
thank you sir
he's a fullback
I'm a quarterback
just saying hello
and thank you
thank you
yes
glory to God in the highest
thank you
yeah
uh-huh
my pleasure
yes
here we go
thank you
hi Dr. Hawkins
hi Susan
hey
we are just asking for a blessing
as a spiritual couple
and my wife is first time here
she is asking for holding your hand
what
she wants to hold your hand
okay sweetheart
yes good to meet you
God bless
thank you
thank you so much
oh we're gonna do a blinky blinky
okay
blinky blink
where are you from
Germany
of Germany
von Deutschland
yes
he speaks over
yeah where
where
Frankfurt
oh Frankfurt
I took 12 years of German in school
oh
well
I was reasonably fluent after a while
and I lived in Milwaukee near outside Milwaukee
a lot of German people
so you can speak German a good deal of the time
mostly grocery stores
stores and everybody can speak german then i moved away from there and nobody speaks german
so now through disuse the german is getting let's see what does that mean
yes hi i don't have a question i'd just like to
receive your blessing and say thank you and to shake your hands yes
ah god bless god bless you amen that's it okay hello hey dr hawkins i just like to uh say thank
you for everything and i'd like to shake your hand and receive your blessing yes indeed uh-huh
thank you for asking me and god bless you amen i know it's a short chair short chair yeah hi hello
um yeah
just like to shake your hand
uh no i couldn't couldn't think of anything he wants to shake mine yep oh that's fine
that's fine thank you thank you for coming up to meet me thank you mr bobblehead
i want to say
how are you today i'm very well actually yeah i want to say oh okay i'll stop being mr bobblehead
thank you so much for coming here i want to thank you as well thank you for enabling this place for
Thank you so much for your work.
It's pulled me out of many, many dark moments in my life.
Yes?
Yeah.
That's good news.
And I have a question.
I have, ever since childhood, had night terrors.
I'll wake up in the middle of the night in a mindless terror that doesn't have, it doesn't
matter what's going on in my brain, there may or may not be thoughts there, but it's
just stark, raving terror.
And there's a sense that there's something on the other end of that.
There's something on the other side.
And I've read all of your books, almost all of your books, and the story that you tell
near the end where you say that at a certain moment comes a terror where the ego is basically
trying to pull out all the stops to not, because it's afraid of not existing anymore.
Yeah, yeah.
A fear of death, yes.
Yeah.
I guess my question is, is there some misstep that I can take during that experience?
Some what step?
Misstep.
Is there?
Some error.
Error.
Is there a potential error on my part when that, when that experience is happening?
No.
Not necessarily, no.
You know, and don't forget, a lot of things are just, the result of brain physiology,
nothing personal about them.
Mm-hmm.
You know?
Everybody else has nightmares.
So it ain't me, it ain't you.
It's the human condition, yes?
Mm-hmm.
That there's suppressed energy during the day and it discharges at night.
That's the human design, you know?
Okay.
Mm-hmm.
Thank you.
Can I come and shake your hand?
Yes.
You know, many of these questions could be answered.
Thank you.
You bet.
If you want to take the time and the trouble to research them, so many of the questions
that people bring up, which I can't give you a ready answer, you know, within five
or ten minutes, Susan, I can track it down because this question leads to this, that
leads to this, that leads to this.
And so you can research any question until you reach the state of satisfaction.
Namaste, Dr. Hawkins.
Namaste, Susan.
We have a first-time visitor here, my 14-year-old daughter.
Oh, 14?
Yes.
Where are you from, love?
South Carolina.
Oh-ho.
We were watching a DVD of yours, and she takes classical Indian dancing, and you were
doing the dance of Shiva, so she really appreciated that.
Oh, the dance of Shiva, yes.
I did have a question.
About a year ago, I had this strong vision of Christ, a vision of Christ in this radiant
yellow light, and needless to say, life has never been the same since then, but ...
She had a vision of Christ?
Yes.
She had a vision, and it was exceedingly bright light.
A vision of Christ in a bright, yellow light that was just extremely loving.
Yes.
Extremely loving.
And I was expecting to see somebody holding a flute, so that was a perception on my end,
so ... I was expecting to see God holding a flute, so that was a little bit of a shock
on my end.
There's been a lot of changes going on over the last year, the last of which was, you
know, a little bit of a change in my life.
Yeah.
The other thing I want to jumping in, it was during Easter, I kind of didn't, you
know, know what the whole Good Friday, Easter, what it meant, and I had this overwhelming
desire to just attend Catholic Mass on Easter.
To do what?
To attend Catholic Mass at Easter Chetesh Tube.
Yes.
Okay.
So ...
So, and I'm not Catholic.
Do you believe in the Christian Faith at all?
Yeah.
And so, I left it in the hands of God, and I said recipe why I have this overwhelming
desire to attend a Mass.
and what is the meaning of
Good Friday and what is the meaning
of Easter
what is the meaning
what is the meaning behind Easter
well didn't they explain that to you in church
I was raised Hindu
so this was all a new thing to me
she's raised Hindu and all of a sudden
she has this overwhelming
desire
to check out Christianity
and I
put it out there to be revealed
why this is happening
and that night
at first it came to me
that you know it was
a knowing to just
it said not to attend
the mass on Sunday
for me to
tend to the altar within
that was the first message
and the second message
it was just
it was like maybe 3 o'clock in the morning
and I was just
these overwhelming number of nails
just kept hitting me
and kept hitting me
and it was um
nails kept hitting me
and it was like
it just appeared like
every time I
would use my eyes
or use my ears
or anything to deal with the body
I was getting hit by nails
and so to me it was
just anything to do with this body
created our suffering
and it was a knowingness
to don't look over here
look over here
and when I looked over there
I was expecting to see that radio
I was expecting to see the radiant light of Christ again
and I didn't
it was just this white radiance
a radiance
yeah
so what is the question
what is the question
I just don't know the
I don't understand
the meaning of all this
doesn't have any meaning
no meaning
no
what does the sky mean
what I think it means
doesn't mean anything
it just is
what does this table mean
doesn't mean anything
it just is
so by meaning it
you're trying to add
an intellectualization to it
what does it mean
the feeling of light
and the presence of God
and a feeling of high inner joy
you know
has occurred throughout
the history of mankind
to a variety of people
under various circumstances
it seems like man is
you know
vulnerable to spiritual energy
and when it comes
it very often comes
in a very similar experience
to whether it was somebody
walking in the desert
2000 years ago
or Bill Wilson
the founder of AA
in a room all by himself
said unless you believe in God
you will surely die
of this illness
and he said
well I'm an Atheist
so he just got
ready himself
ready to die I guess
and suddenly
the room lit up
and there was the knowingness
oh this is the God
of the scriptures
that they're talking about
talking about and susan also had a similar experience the room lit up of its own she
wasn't thinking about god or nothing like that suddenly the room lit up an infinite presence
you see so it comes to each of us in a different way some people it might come intellectually you
know they read a book suddenly they get inspired by the book and the truth of the book so each one
of us it comes in in its own good time in its own way you see the karmic propensities are so
complicated variable energies from variable lifetimes that you can't really go back and
dissect it and say well it was this thought in this lifetime in the year 1620 you know what i'm
saying it's a collective energy and it's really not uh linear it's not linear you can't track
its exact
you know any longitude and latitude or something like that you see yeah it's more diffuse and
spontaneous the white light or the yellow light any the light that you experienced was there an
energy behind that yes a good yes yes what have you done with that there's been i was restricted
to one question so i just wanted to ask that but there's there's other since that occurred
there's been more like popping just
i don't know i'd be sitting there and then all of a sudden i just there's just like this vibration
going out or i was at the grand canyon and i almost sprained my ankle because i was i don't
know it was like i was i was going and then the body was coming and this kundalini is going up
and down and like it's just fire it's just fire and i so i got the kopi krishna book
don't experience it though you're gonna have to go with this for a while because it's gonna lead
you somewhere so i don't know what you're
supposed to do with this but i don't you'll probably have well you have to you know with
with prayer you ask with prayer for understanding and that's all you have to do you ask god for
understanding of that experience and it'll lead you uh-huh can you repeat that um that we were
always safe she wants to know that she's always safe because this is both not only an uh a holy
energy experience it's also was frightening with the nails coming out of her nose and she's like
that her too so are those the nails pulled out of the hands and the feet of jesus christ
that was my question yeah yeah i would say it's the you're you're freed by christianity
pulling out the nails that nail you to the cross yes i was watching one of your 2002 lectures and
then there i think you pretty much said that that's anyone find it but um you had it was it
was like the consciousness of mankind the suffering that we were going through and i
had was due to these to the belief in the body and that's what i was getting from that
yes what's the question i still don't get what's the question i've already you've answered the
question huh she just answered it was both frightening and confusing oh oh yes yes
no i just wanted you to say that all fear is an illusion that i'm always safe
to repeat that i didn't understand what she said she wants to hear you say that all fear
is an illusion and that she's oh oh fear yeah well fear itself is an emotion but fear itself arises
due to an illusion yeah you know the illusion that you can die well you can't have you can't
die it's not possible you know i mean you can only move from this body elsewhere but you can't
actually die yep we wanted to get a group picture and blessing from you they want a group picture
okay
okay who we got here oh yes uh-huh here's all these cutie pies here
look at all these cutie pies here my cutie pies hi sweetheart
they're adorable children of adorable yes god bless me yep god bless you both yes god bless
yeah one more oh oh oh
oh my goodness look at what a bunch you got here ah look what i got here all collection
i got a dozen things here all at once
yes
good afternoon um thank you for taking our questions today dr hawkins
my question pertains to um a spiritual teacher um i'm thinking of becoming a disciple as it were
and disciple
of a spiritual teacher yes somebody in the united states or where um currently he's in the united
states um i believe i have a great deal to learn from this person every time i'm doing the kinesiology
i'm getting a positive test but that might be just my love for this person oh sure i would just ask
that maybe you could check for me with kinesiology let's see we have permission to ask about this
this would be a good teacher for the for him you'd be a good teacher yeah thank you
that's it and your blessing hello dr hawkins hello thank you again for your presence
for your teachings and your inspiration so grateful to be here because of your guidance
uh my fiance has and norman has just been accepted to yavapai college yeah my college yeah that's a
good cause to get there we calibrated you by college today didn't we right golly yep
and so we're set to be moving here i'm also being i'm also set to be married to your husband you're
in May and so just to ask you blessing for our marriage just a blessing okay
okay yes because of the time limit we're going to have to close lecture at this
time and we want to appreciate everybody who's come from so many ways I'm sorry we
couldn't do all your questions we did in the lecture a little
bit early so that we could try and get everybody in and doctor did you want to
take over and what oh this is the end of the day yeah we have to be out of here
right at five o'clock so we're we're gonna end this just a little bit early I
wish we had more time I'm sorry there's never seems to be enough time oh I give
thanks to the Oh Lord for the profound blessing
of
the people here present whose mere presence together it is so heartwarming
I'm very thankful then that you have chosen to come and be with me this day I
am greatly honored and I bless you all in the name of the Lord the Father the
Son the Holy Ghost and all that is most holy amen I am very thankful but what
가는
report
thank you
applaus
applause
pieces about disaster
we were very grateful and I couldn't have Dale can you walk out there and say hello we were going to try and do where you know the music and go to the edge of the stage please we're going to try and you know the edges so shape us and go to the end of the stage please we were going to what we're going to go to the end of the stage please we were going to great work for us we can't tell me where to go you're not on everybody can bad oh oh bless everybody woah now these pictures are going out on the internet you better behave these pictures are going out on the internet you better behave
Well, we're all blessed by St. Bobblehead.
St. Bobblehead.
Thank you.
Okay, yes.
Yeah, I get what you're saying.
Yes.
God bless.
Look at all these beautiful people.
Look how beautiful they are.
The divinity within shines forth.
So the love you feel is that of agape.
It's an impersonal, unconditional love.
It radiates forth from the heart of man.
When we walk through the woods,
do you know that the trees realize that you have walked by?
Where's the lady?
Oh, I need the lady of the house.
Come here this instant, please.
Or else.
Okay, she's distracted by things.
Well, I want.
I want to show the universality of divine consciousness.
I want to ask this question.
When you walk through the woods, the trees know and are aware that you are walking by.
Resist.
How could that be?
A tree is deaf, dumb, and blind.
How does it know knowing this?
The tree knows that you are there.
Incredible.
I.
It came to me.
One time.
I was in a very high state.
And then I walked through the woods.
The trees almost like genuflected.
I said, oh, my God.
Then it dawned on me that I was aware of the divinity of the life within the tree.
So the tree was really acknowledging my awareness of the divinity of its own.
The essence of life is divinity.
So life as it expresses as a tree, as it's human, is still just life.
Even a little mosquito has life.
So life recognizes life and unconsciously, without saying anything, recognizes that it is a reflection of divinity.
So know that when you walk through the woods, the trees all know who you really are.
That is a fact.
Resist.
That sort of enhances the significance of your own existence.
Because wherever you walk, you shine forth that light.
I used to live in New York City in the Upper East Side.
And I had a certain way to go every day.
And I was in a pretty high state in those days.
And as I would walk down the street, the doorman down the road would start to beam.
And everywhere I went, people would beam.
And you'd walk into the hardware store, and they would all shine forth.
It's because when you're in a high state, you pretty much.
When you shine that energy forth.
And people just feel a gladness when you come up to them, to the doorman.
You look to the doorman, and he just loves opening the door for you.
He doesn't know why.
So that's all beyond the intellect.
That's the energy field that we've been talking about today.
That energy field uplifts and radiates forth.
So people say, what can I do to help the world?
And I say, just be who you are.
Just being who you are is what's uplifting the world, for God's sake.
Without you folks here, the end of the world would just fall over into the ocean, wouldn't it?
All right.
He said, greetings and love from Australia.
What did he say?
Oh, from Australia.
Oh, God bless us.
We love you, too.
God bless you all from Australia.
I've never had a chance to go to Australia.
I'd love to go there just to see the kangaroos.
There's nothing else.
I had a great, great pleasure to bring you to Australia.
Okay, what are we doing now?
It's time to go.
Okay, time.
Thank you again so much.
I am truly blessed.
I am truly blessed by your presence.
I am profoundly blessed by your presence.
I thank you now and forever.
Because we will be forever.
Forever.
Thank you again.
Oh, I probably missed one.
Okay, here, I got a pen here.
Here we go.