We have a little treat for you today.
A friend of ours has prepared sort of a slide presentation
of what our life is like on the ranch.
So a lot of the pictures that you're going to see
were taken of our personal life.
And in the bookstore, if you purchase $100,
you get this video free.
So we wanted to give that to you.
It's wonderful, and I think you're really going to enjoy it
and get out the Kleenex.
For all of you that aren't familiar with our work
and our first-time comers, this is our ego.
And we did a whole series on that in 2002.
And this is our little ego that we carry around with.
And we don't oppose it.
We just embrace it and love it and know that it's there.
So that is what the teddy bear represents.
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
Oh, good God.
Where are we?
There must be somebody out there.
Hello?
It's a sing-song kitty.
Sing-song kitty, won't you kind me, oh, keen.
I learned this from my father 80 years ago.
Sing-song kitty, won't you kind me, oh.
Keem, oh, kind, oh, dar, oh, ah, many, I, many, oh, many, rum,
stum, fum, me, diddle, soup, peck, fetty, won't you lick them,
mick them.
Sing-song kitty, won't you kind me, oh.
Ha, ha, ha.
Keem, oh, kind, oh, dar, oh, ah, many, I, many, oh, many, rum,
stum, fum, me, diddle, soup, peck, fetty, won't you lick them,
mick them.
Sing-song kitty, won't you kind me, oh.
Ha, ha, ha.
That's the love I got from my father.
He was that.
And then I'd say, say it slow, Dad.
And I memorized it.
Ha, ha, ha.
So that was love 80 years ago.
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
Yeah.
Thank you so much.
Keem, oh, kind, oh, dar, oh, ah, many, I, many, oh, many,
rum, stum, fum, me, diddle, soup, peck, fetty, won't you lick
them, mick them.
Sing-song kitty, won't you kind me, oh.
The mind is willing, but the body is tired.
So we have to say goodbye to all of you.
We will carry you in our hearts and in our prayers and hope
that we meet again in the hereafter.
Um, we're going to start the lecture at this time.
Fran will read the slides.
Doctors, eyesight.
Isn't very good anymore, and so he can no longer read the slides.
So I've asked someone to read the slides for us.
And, uh, we are going to go continue with the lecture and, um, bless you all
for coming such a long way to see us.
Take that.
If you won't take snuff.
Our love for you is eternal.
Thank you for being here.
I'm in the next honey.
She's going to start the lecture.
The map of consciousness.
A logarithmic.
Scale from one to 1000 where courage is the critical factor point of integrity at 200 below which all the energies are negative and above which all the energies are positive love calibrates 500 and over unconditional love.
Calibrates.
Calibrates at 540.
Next slide, please.
Oh, there's slides.
Distribution of the levels of consciousness shown in a pyramid showing that 85% of the world's population calibrates below the level of integrity at 200 and at the top of the pyramid, 15% calibrate above 200, which is the level of courage.
An integrity.
Distribution of the levels of consciousness shown.
And a fulcrum where the 15% of the world's population that calibrate in integrity over level 200.
Counterbalance the 85% of the world's population that calibrate negatively or below level 200 of courage and integrity.
And then 20% of the world's population that calibrate negatively or below level 200 of courage and integrity.
Exaggerated.
And we have the animal kingdom. I'll mention some of Doc's favorites. Bacteria 1. Octopus 20. The Komodo dragon at 40.
And at level 200 in the animal kingdom, we reach the grazers, those who do not kill as a means to survive. So the zebra, the gazelle, the giraffe, the deer, the elk, and the family dog at 250.
And we have certain exceptions, such as the kitty's purr at the level of love, 500.
And the doggie's wagging tail at 500. The level of love.
And we see from this next chart that as consciousness level moves up and rises in the map of consciousness, rate of unemployment decreases, rate of poverty decreases, happiness increases, and rate of criminality decreases.
So for example, at the level of 50, which is apathy and below.
97% of people are unemployed.
65% are in poverty.
0% are happy.
And 98% criminality.
However, by level 200, which is the critical point of integrity, where the valence of the energy shifts to positive.
It's only 8% unemployment.
1.5% poverty.
40% happiness.
And 9.0% criminality.
At the level of love, 5 to 600.
Unemployment is 0.
Poverty 0.
Happiness, 98%.
Correlation of the levels of consciousness and the rate of happiness.
At consciousness level shame, at the bottom of the map of consciousness, only 1% of people are happy.
By the level courage, 255% of people are happy.
At the level acceptance, which is logarithm 350, 71% of people are happy.
At level 500, 89% are happy.
And by the time of joy, which is 540 to 599, 99% of people are happy.
99% of people are happy.
And here we have one of the doctor's favorite slides.
The wolf in sheep's clothing.
Things are not always as they appear.
Calibrations of the great avatars and spiritual teachers.
Jesus Christ, 1,000.
Buddha, 1,000.
Zoroaster, 1,000.
The 12 Christian apostles, 980.
The name of God as Om, 975.
John the Baptist, 930.
Moses, 910.
Abraham, 850.
St. Paul, 740.
Spiritual teachers in the 500s.
The energy field of love.
These are historical examples.
Brother Lawrence, 575.
Father Pio, 585.
Confucius, 590.
Rumi, 550.
Jesus, 540.
Dilgo Khyentse Rinpoche, 575.
Swami Prabhavananda, 550.
Love.
Love is the ultimate law of the universe.
This statement calibrates 750.
Love God with all thy heart,
all thy soul,
and all thy mind.
Love thy neighbor as thyself.
Love makes the world go round.
Love is a many-splendored thing.
Love is a way of being in the world.
Love is a way to God.
Love facilitates healing.
And the famous duck story.
I wanted to ask a question.
When you say,
Love God with all your heart
and all your soul,
what does that mean to you?
What does that mean to you?
Love God with all your heart
and all your soul
and all your mind.
How do we apply that to everyday living?
You become that love.
And then everything happens
appropriately,
automatically
due to what you are.
So if you approach a group of people
and the love of God
is what motivates you,
all the people in the crowd go,
How do they go, folks?
Hey!
That's telling them, buddy.
That'll show the devil where the hell to go.
Love God with all your heart
and your mind
and you will be wonderful
to your fellow man.
And love thy neighbor
as thyself.
How would you interpret that?
You don't have to interpret it.
You become that.
As you become loving,
it's your way of being.
So lovingness to me
is a way of being.
It's not an emotion.
It's a way of being in the world.
It's like, how can I be
of help to you?
How can I comfort you?
How can I loan you some money when you're broke?
How can I help you find a job?
How can I console you when you've
suffered a major loss in your family?
Lovingness is a way of being
in the world.
And that way you light up the world.
Love is the way
to God.
That is true.
How do we apply that to our everyday life?
I don't.
You don't?
No.
Is it because that's what you become?
That's what you become.
Because you become loving,
you radiate the energy of God
wherever you go.
Some people are a blessing to be in the world
and other people are like a curse.
Yes?
And love
facilitates healing.
Huh?
Love facilitates healing.
That is true.
The more loving you are,
I used to love all my patients.
I didn't tell them that.
But I loved them all.
And I used to have a patient,
he had a picture of me
and he would go home and he'd put my picture
on the wall and he would say when he feels
bad he looked at the picture and feels better.
So that gave me the hint
that love heals.
And so as a physician
I loved all my patients
but I didn't tell them.
Might make them nervous.
So as a physician
then you sent love
to the patients you were treating.
I loved all the patients that I treated.
So that's why you were such a success
as a psychiatrist
because you were sending them love
and thinking about them.
I had the biggest psychiatric practice
in the United States
for 25 years or whatever.
We treated a thousand patients
a year. A thousand patients.
And I loved them all.
So if physicians
would say a prayer for their patients
to get better then that would help them
recuperate
most of the time.
I prayed over all of them but I didn't tell them I was doing that.
It might make them nervous.
We have up here the duck story.
Can you tell us the duck story?
About the hunter who
no longer would hunt?
Oh it makes me cry to say it.
I don't know if I can tell it or not.
But anyway it's a relatively
well known story now.
This guy hunted ducks.
He was a duck hunter.
Just a normal everyday duck hunter.
To me it seems like
an abomination to say it.
He went duck hunting.
And he shot this duck
and
the duck wasn't killed.
I mean it was
badly injured and the duck
fell to the ground.
And after this duck fell
to the ground it's mate
it's female mate
flew down on top
of the injured duck and she put her
she put her wings over him.
After that he never killed
another duck. Okay we'll go on.
What happened to the hunter?
Yeah his heart
changed.
He had a transformation
within his own heart.
And he gave up hunting
as a sport.
But the female duck
fell on top of the male
duck and she
shelled her like this.
And he never hunted again.
So love has a
transformative power.
Once you become loving
there are certain things
you can never do again.
But you can also perform the miraculous
without labeling
it miraculous.
You can do things other people cannot do.
And people will do things
for you they would not do for others.
So love has a very
powerful transformative effect.
It's best not to tell
a lot of people that you love them
because they'll get scared.
They'll think you have
designs on them.
So loving this is a way
of being. It's a way of being.
And it transforms
everything around you
because of the radiation
of that energy.
People that are hateful
in your presence will suddenly
become willing to forgive others.
And I'll say
if you go back over that
how would you do that?
And you can see the person
transform right in front of you.
And they'd say well I wouldn't have been
too young to know better.
They would find an excuse
to defend the person instead of attack them.
So we become defenders
of love and life.
And we stop being
attackers.
Yes.
I was glad during World War II
I didn't have to kill anybody.
I had to maintain this ship.
I was a bosun's mate.
And I brought the ship through
all kinds of terrible
storms.
The ship went over 90 degrees.
I was standing on the bulkhead
with one foot
on the bulkhead and the other
at the wheel.
And I stayed at the wheel for 12 hours non-stop
because everybody else was sick.
Everybody was terribly seasick
and laying on the floor throwing up.
And so I just stayed
at the wheel
I guess 12 or 20
I don't know how many hours.
It was a long couple of days.
So love empowers us.
It allows you to steer a ship for
close to a whole day without food
or drink or
anything.
It must have had water or something
but I don't remember.
So love empowers us.
Forgiveness
and love is
transformative.
And we also have to forgive ourself
for our trespasses.
I forgive myself for the errors
I have made, oh Lord,
when I was less evolved.
Amen.
Love calibrates
500 and over
on the map of consciousness.
The heart chakra
calibrates 505.
Bagpipes
are an example
of the energy of the heart.
There's love of pets.
Love of freedom.
Romantic love.
Loveless
equals flat.
Love of purpose.
The golden rule.
Do unto others
as you would have them
do unto you.
Love of attributes.
Love increases
perceived value.
happiness.
Love as
agape,
which is universal love,
calibrates
570.
Love
as virtue.
Love as
enthusiasm.
I love doing this.
Love as
forgiveness.
acceptance.
Okay, in this last
slide, you have given
several examples of love.
You know, different types of love.
Like
enthusiasm,
the forgiveness,
the acceptance.
So each one of these is an
aspect of love, yet
in a different form.
Is that correct?
What's the last thing I said?
But in a different form.
Different forms of love.
These are all different forms of love.
Well, you can encourage your
fellow, you know, to make life better
for everybody around you.
That's always been my ambition.
To make things go better,
or the eggs got fried better,
or the duckies got saved,
or the kitty got fed this morning.
Before we left the house
this morning,
it was very important to make sure the
kitties had enough food.
So we had three kitties all lined up,
waiting for their breakfast.
And before we left,
we had to make sure the doggie
had enough food and happiness.
So to share your love with
everything around you,
kitties and doggies,
and other people,
and even villains.
A captured villain,
it's up to you
to make his life tolerable.
Say, I'm sorry that I have to
hold a gun to your head,
but that's my job.
Don't make me pull the trigger.
Thank you.
Love as motivator.
Love
of creation.
Life.
Existence.
Love as appreciation.
Love as
kindness.
Love as essence
of relationship.
Love as group
energy.
Example.
Alcoholics Anonymous.
540.
The level of unconditional
love.
Now I want you to
explain to everyone here
what is the difference between
love at 500
and unconditional love
at 540.
I don't know that it's that easy
to differentiate.
At 540,
you love everybody and everything.
And
even Adolf Hitler.
You look at him as a person
who was taken over
by negative energies.
And you're willing to
forgive Adolf Hitler
who couldn't help what happened
to him. That he was
overcome by evil.
So instead of hating evil,
you feel sorry that people have
become overwhelmed by evil.
And
Adolf did what
he thought he was required
to do by honor
and in its
contextualization at the time.
You can love even Adolf Hitler
in unconditional love,
you would be able to forgive him
and accept him.
You'd forgive even Hitler, yes.
Because he was captured by certain
ideals. Captured by
the thinginess of the time.
Okay.
You can see that everybody
who violates the law of love
is really a victim of
some other
societal belief system
or the pressures of the time.
During the World War
II, I didn't hate the Japanese.
Even after
Pearl Harbor, I didn't hate
Hitler.
I didn't hate anybody.
So
you still had to conduct yourself
but without hate.
You did it out of
a sense of duty and
loyalty to your fellow man.
The people on the ship,
the only way they got through the
Okinawa Typhoon,
turned over something like
90 ships. 90 ships went down
in the Okinawa Typhoon.
And I was at the wheel the whole time.
Yeah. I was just thankful
that, Lord, I could
sustain
the life. Everybody was seasick.
They were all laying on the deck. It was pathetic.
Everybody laying on the deck throwing up
for days. It was really something.
And so steering the ship was up
to me because I was
the only one, apparently, that wasn't
seasick.
But we hit 90 degrees because
I can remember I was standing on the bulkhead.
Standing up straight on the bulkhead.
So we were over 90 degrees.
So we serve our fellow man
out of a commitment
and understanding
our human nature
as God would have us
understand it. We thank Thee,
O Lord, for our life and we dedicate
it to Thy service. Amen.
Laughter.
Love as admiration.
Love as respect
as in love of
country and countrymen
in the military.
Love as valor.
Love of shipmates.
Bonds
of unity.
Fraternal love
as in buddies,
classmates,
teammates.
Love as friendship
and loyalty.
Love is letting
go of fear.
Jerry Jempolski's book.
Love as affection.
Honey.
Sweetheart.
Love as cherishing.
Maternal love.
Self-sacrificing.
Lovingness
as an existential
style.
This lecture is the
result of love
and the miraculous.
I was speaking to
some ladies who were up front here
before the lecture started
and we were talking
about what it is
for us to be wives and mothers
and how important it is
to each one of us
to hold that spiritual
torch
in our family
and how it's up to us
to keep that spirituality
strong
as women of the world
should be.
So I just wanted to
pass that along to everybody
that we as women
as wives
and mothers
need to inspire
our children and
mates to
take up that torch
and follow God.
I love you baby.
Every morning
I give thanks for your love.
Every night
I thank God for it.
How animals
affect your life.
The songbird's song
calibrates at 500
the level of love.
The kitty's purr
calibrates at 500
the level of love.
The doggy's
wagging tail
calibrates at 500
the level of love.
The family cat
calibrates at 245
the family dog
calibrates
at 250
and having
a dog
increases your lifespan
by 10 years.
You hear that?
10 years.
If you own a dog
you will live 10 years
longer.
When you think of all the idiotic
exercises, crazy diets
people go through,
why don't you just buy a dog
and live 10 more years?
Save yourself all those horrible
low cholesterol diets and crap.
You get to die of cholesterol
poisoning when you're 90.
I don't know, I'm over
How old am I now? I forgot.
Do you know how old I am?
How old am I? 84.
Is that so?
Well without a dog I would have been
dead already.
So Kelsey my doggy at home
who I love and adore.
This is Kelsey.
Where is Kelsey?
She's on the screen.
Is she on there?
We went to the pound
and adopted her.
Dave went in and
all these dogs are jumping around
pick me, pick me
and here she was just sitting in the corner
and he says I want that one.
And Gabe and I looked at each other like
I don't know about her.
She's not doing it.
He goes no I want that dog.
And we came home with her and she has been a joy.
She herds the kitties.
All the other dogs jumped around.
And Kelsey just lay in the corner
like this.
Looking out like this.
So she got me through the heart.
Love me, love my dog.
But the fact that owning a dog
adds ten years to your life.
I mean that's just a major issue.
Ten years is quite a while.
Thank you.
Okay.
Kelsey asked me to bring that up.
So I said
I'll bring it up Kelsey.
That was my promise to her.
Calibrations
in the level of love.
The statement
love is the ultimate law
of the universe.
Calibrates at
750.
Sat Chit Ananda
Calibrates at 600.
Agape
taught by Jesus
Calibrates
570.
Susan Boyle's
voice
Calibrates at 550.
Unconditional love
Calibrates
540.
The movie The Pacific
Calibrates
500.
Wisdom
Calibrates at 430.
Mother's Day
Calibrates
300.
Solar plexus versus
love.
Love is from the heart.
Attachment and
ambitious craving
are from the solar plexus.
Examples
love of wealth.
Love of fame.
Love of power.
Love of being right.
Love of glamour.
Publicity.
Love of stardom.
Love of public attention.
Words that describe
the level of 500.
Love.
Warmth.
Heartfelt.
Join.
Appreciation.
Nurturing.
Sensual.
Forgiving.
Protective.
Benign.
Inclusive.
Goodness.
Alignment.
Affectionate.
Purity.
Humble.
Cordial.
Giving.
Satisfying.
Gracious.
Generous.
Passion.
Uplifting.
Holistic.
Sweetness.
Love is a progressively
unconditional energy field.
Lovingness is a way of being
in the world.
Love is forgiving.
Nurturing.
And supportive.
Love emanates from the heart.
That first statement you said
is that love is
progressively
unconditional.
The more you love,
the more you can love.
That's one reason to have a dog.
You live 10 years longer
because it brings up
the energy of love
and the energy of love heals
and prolongs life.
And you're thankful for your life.
You're thankful to God
because of your life.
And you say,
I thank thee, O Lord, for my life
and the miracles of this life.
And I always thank God
for our dog and our kitties.
I said, I thank you for the dog
and the kitties.
Why? Because they represent love.
The kitties purr, purr, purr, purr, purr, purr.
I got a kitty that climbs on the bed
as soon as we're in bed
it starts to go purr, purr, purr, purr, purr, purr.
So we surround
ourselves with love.
Yes?
You're always saying lovingness
is a way of being in the world.
How do we apply that to our daily lives?
You just become,
you become that.
Everything you do and say,
every movement,
then is energized by the lovingness
which you own within yourself.
Everything I say as I talk
to this audience,
I feel like an energy running out.
I want to share
what I hold in my heart
as a knowingness
experientially
and I hold it in my heart
for all of them
that they should all be feeling it.
I pray for the inner experience
of divine love
for everyone here present now.
God bless you, in the name of the Lord,
the Father, and the Son of God.
And love is forgiving, nurturing,
and supportive.
Indeed, as a woman you know that.
In our society we look to the woman
as the representative
of maternal love as the ideal.
Yes.
It emanates.
What?
It emanates from the heart.
Love emanates from the heart.
Oh my God, is it emanating someplace here?
It's emanating.
Folks help!
Call the emanator squad.
I can't say it.
I couldn't say it.
It emanates.
Alright.
Go ahead.
What?
What are you asking me?
Nothing, nothing.
So what we're feeling up here
between you and I,
I know that everyone's picking up out there
our love for each other
and everyone is seeing and picking up out there
that vibration.
I share with everyone present
that which I feel
within my heart
every night when I go to bed
I thank God
for Susan's love every night.
Thank you oh Lord.
And because of your presence
I feel God loves me.
So I'm surrounded by your love
and the kitty's love
and the doggy's love
and the love of all our friends.
The telephone rings all day long
with friends.
So she's on the phone with friends
half the day.
Yes.
Alright.
What's next?
We're gonna take a real quick break here.
It'll be about 15-20 minutes.
And we'll be right back.
I let it go a little longer
because we're slow in getting started.
But we'll take a quick break
and we'll see you back here
in about 15-20 minutes.