I'm gonna sing something funny and then you I want you to say get lost bum. Oh my god is love
All I got is love you say get lost bum. Okay
Well, baby, all I got is the love. All I got is love
Ain't got nothing but love honey
We thought we'd have fun with that one
I know I can't give you anything but love baby
Get lost. Oh get lost
If all love is all I can afford get lost
I think that's funny
I'm trying to get people a chance get back from
The bookstore and things I know everybody I don't know if everyone got
Through everything. It looks like quite a few are here. So I guess we'll go ahead and start
And please no video taping
No video taping and turn off your cell phones if you caught someone on the break, please
We have complaints every lecture because of that so I have to announce it after every break we take
people forget
It's a way of life now
Cell phone cell phones are connected to our ears
Okay
Thank you so much again, we appreciate you coming and
Dave and I would
Hope that you carry on our work
And that what we have
Brought to you that you remember and teach others
continuing the doctors teachings on love
Reason deals with particulars
Whereas love deals with holes and essence
love
accomplishes great feats because of its purity of motive
love takes no position and
is
inclusive
love augments the positive
love
focuses on life's goodness in all
of its expressions
David yes, when you say that love takes no position
What exactly is meant by that?
that
you love them if they do do this and you love them if they don't or
Love is a primary is a primary in my my personal experience
and then the
conditions are irrelevant if you've decided
to love
Uh
A certain situation
Then it's unconditional
Even if they hoot and say your you're terrible. You still love them because they're so dumb
Anybody doesn't think I'm the greatest needs help
Well, a mother's love is unconditional
yes
and I
remember as a kindergarten or a first grader
We wore long stockings when I was a kid.
Long stockings in the wintertime.
You're dating yourself.
Huh?
Well, anyway, we wore long stockings.
And I went to school, and that day I had diarrhea.
Well, I was one unholy mess.
Long socks and diarrhea.
Somebody had to clean me up when I got home.
That's love.
Because I remember being told,
don't feel bad about it, you couldn't help it.
So it wasn't not only the cleaning me up,
but the relief of my guilt that I had done such a terrible thing.
Yes.
So we bless others by our forgiveness.
I realized that in a certain way,
nobody can help being other than they,
considering the world situation at the time.
Adolf Hitler did what he thought was the most necessary thing to do.
Nine attempts to kill him all failed.
And so even with Adolf Hitler, I say he was dedicated.
He thought he was being of service by what he did, you know.
And I did the same thing in World War II.
I thought that,
the kamikaze pilots are doing what they think they should do for their country.
And even though they're trying to kill us and bomb us,
I did not hate them.
I did not hate the kamikaze pilots.
I respected them.
I respected kamikaze pilots.
Willing to give up their life for their country.
And I thought that's,
so I respected them.
And I still do.
Yeah.
Can I tell a funny story about diarrhea?
I can't hear you, no.
David had a little bout with an intestinal bug here about two weeks ago,
and so we kept talking about this problem he was having with diarrhea.
Well, we have an African Grey, and she picked it up,
and now she runs around saying diarrhea.
Our parrot says diarrhea, diarrhea.
So when he's telling this story just now about it,
I couldn't help but think of broccoli going diarrhea.
You can't say anything in front of our African Grey parrot.
The parrot will pick it up.
So anything you say, you better be prepared to hear it back for another 50 times, you know.
Including phone numbers.
And credit card numbers.
I mean, this bird is sharp.
I got so I'd go in the other room to place a mail order,
you know, by phone,
because I know she's going to remember the credit card number
and start blabbing it, you know.
She's got all but the last four digits.
Yeah, the African Grey parrot is.
So each being in an African Grey parrot is very much a being.
Each being I love and respect for what it is.
And they bring joy to our life, you know.
And that's part of having them with us, too,
is the joy they bring to us.
Even when they're being bad, they still.
Even when you're being bad, I love you still.
That's good.
At 3 o'clock this morning, we have a white kitty,
and he's my little stinker.
He gets into things.
And he went tearing through the house several times,
and he runs the whole length of the hallway into the bedroom,
around the bed, and back out.
And so this morning, at about 3 in the morning,
he was doing that.
So I grabbed the water bottle I keep by the bed,
and sprayed him to stop him.
It's pretty bad.
He gets, just once in a while, not all the time.
He gets bad.
We have three kitties, three kitties and one doggie.
They're fun.
It's like us talking about our kids.
Anyway, let's go on.
Thank you.
By level 500, approximately 90%
of people experience happiness as a basic quality of life.
With spiritual intention, love becomes a way of life.
The capacity for love is limitless.
The more one loves, the more one can love.
That's my sweetie pie.
Do you want to say something about the capacity for love?
The more you love, the more you can love.
Because it's a non-physical thing.
And because it's non-physical,
the infinite love of Almighty God is the ultimate expression.
Yes?
Yes.
Okay.
It is discovered that to be loving is also to be lovable.
Love appears in the animal kingdom,
the birdsong,
the dog's wagging tail,
the kitty's purr.
Love heals.
Love uplifts others.
Love is present everywhere.
Its presence only needs to be realized.
The teaching of Jesus Christ
was essentially to avoid negativity
the levels below 200.
The goal of his teaching
was for his followers to reach
the level of unconditional love
which calibrates at 540.
Now I want to ask you this.
Unconditional love.
What?
Yes.
Is that a love
that doesn't expect anything when given?
Yes.
It's because it has become what you are.
When you have become loving,
then you have no limitations or demands
on people out there
that they should be this way
so they can be loved.
You love them no matter how they are,
even though they're obnoxious.
And you feel sorry for the criminal
that they didn't know any other lifestyle.
I always feel sorry
that their life was so pathetic
that this is all they had left.
You know?
Run down the street
and grab the lady's purse
as they run down.
I taught people how to handle it.
I taught people how to handle a robber, you know.
And what you do is you take your money,
you take your money
and you throw it on this side of the sidewalk
and then you run that way.
And they will go for the money
and you're free.
Always give the robber your billfold.
That way you save your life.
So many people when they are,
when they say, you know,
they may say that they're being unconditionally loving,
but there's always a hidden agenda behind that.
You know, there's always a hidden agenda.
Oh, if I do this for them,
they will love me.
If I do this,
then they'll react like this.
And so that's why I wanted you to clarify
unconditional love,
that there is no attachments.
Yeah.
Your love for whatever you are,
whatever that is.
Even though you're stupid enough,
and obnoxious.
You're stupid and obnoxious,
but I still love you.
Thank God for me.
But unconditional love,
unconditional love is given without attachments.
Without requirements, yeah.
Yeah, there's no strings attached
to unconditional love.
That's true.
Okay.
It's just what you have become.
You become that.
You're becoming loving.
You become lovable when you are loving.
The more loving we are,
the more lovable we are.
Even my dog knows that.
My dog loves me a lot,
and I say she loves us both very much,
you know.
Thank God.
I just wanted to make sure
that we got that unconditional love down,
because there's so much out there.
It's used as kind of a flippant term anymore,
you know, to describe love,
and that's why I wanted to clarify that,
because it's with no strings attached,
not to expect anything back when given, right?
Even if there's no coffee in the morning.
Where's the coffee?
There isn't any.
Oh, okay.
No, you would never do that.
No.
She would never get me up without coffee.
Thank you, sweetheart.
Okay.
Jesus Christ knew that at the level of unconditional love,
which calibrates at 540,
the soul's destiny was certain.
This is taught by the world's great religions,
such as Lotus Land Buddhism.
Diagnostic differential between infatuation versus love.
Infatuation, passion, and attraction calibrate at 145,
whereas love calibrates at 500.
Wow.
The locus of infatuation is the self with a small S, the ego.
The locus of love is self with a large S, or the spirit.
The origin of infatuation is the animal instinct,
whereas the origin of love is a spiritual state.
The mental function of infatuation is impaired,
whereas with love,
it's uplifted.
The intention of infatuation is to mate,
to get,
whereas with love,
it's to bond and to enjoy.
The duration of infatuation is transitory,
whereas love is permanent.
The emotions of infatuation are in excess and imbalance,
whereas with love,
the emotions are calm and balanced.
The brain physiology of infatuation
is the left brain, the physical,
whereas with love,
it's the right brain, the etheric.
The emotional process of infatuation is frustration,
frantic, fearful, tormented,
whereas with love,
there's gratitude, peaceful, self-fulfilling.
Stability in infatuation is desperate,
whereas with love, it's enhanced.
Body functions in infatuation are impaired,
loss of appetite, loss of sleep,
whereas with love, it's improved.
The description of infatuation is craving,
whereas with love, it's contentment.
Pathology in infatuation is suicide,
despair, stalking,
whereas with love, there's well-being.
Judgment in infatuation is impaired,
whereas with love, it's improved.
Perception in infatuation is exaggerated,
whereas in love, it's illuminated.
The intention of infatuation is to possess,
to own, to control, to capture,
whereas with love, it's to be with.
Productivity in infatuation is disrupted,
whereas with love, it's enhanced.
The self-image in infatuation is inflated,
whereas with love, it's positive.
Balance in infatuation is erratic,
whereas with love, it's steady.
The hormone and endocrine in infatuation
is adrenaline and the sex hormones,
whereas with love, they are endorphins and oxytocin.
The social image in infatuation is inflated,
whereas with love, it's enhanced.
The intellectual function in infatuation
is to romanticize and lower mind,
whereas with love, it's realistic and higher mind.
The level of consciousness in infatuation lowers,
whereas with love, it raises.
The style of infatuation is involvement,
horizontal,
whereas with love, it's alignment and vertical.
Did you want to say something about this,
the horizontal and the vertical?
That when you're in love, it's vertical,
you're lying together.
When there is, when there's,
when it's involvement, you're horizontal.
Yeah, because that's the difference
between an attachment.
An attachment is something different.
You know, you're attached to somebody.
That doesn't mean you're aligned to them.
You might even kill them, you know.
I was so attached to her that I had to kill her
when I started flirting with somebody else.
You know what I mean?
So alignment means that your purposes are aligned.
So that's why a spiritual overall field in a relationship,
a relationship ensures its longevity
and the positive effect it has on others
so that you become an example.
The more you love, the more you can love.
Mm-hmm.
Sometimes love is misconceived as an attachment.
Attachment is one thing and love is another.
You can love something and either be attached
or not be attached.
Yes.
Okay.
Relatedness in infatuation is demanding,
whereas with love, it's harmonious.
The goal of infatuation is to satisfy and to own,
whereas with love, it's to fulfill.
The pattern of infatuation is individualism,
whereas with love, it's concordance.
Loss is experienced in infatuation
with depression, rage, hate,
and blame,
whereas loss is experienced in love
with grief and regret.
The ego dynamics of love.
The capacity for love increases
as positionalities are surrendered.
Love is a quality of divinity
and emerges in accord with spiritual practices.
For example,
be kind to everything and everyone,
including oneself,
at all times with no exception.
Wow.
Love illuminates the essence
and therefore the lovability of others.
Do you want to comment?
Yes, because it opens the heart.
Instead of perception,
the heart knows.
So the mind thinks and argues
and carries on like that.
But the heart just continues.
So even when you're very, very bad,
I love you.
So you're saying that the brain
or your thoughts would tell you one thing,
but the heart would tell you something else.
That's true.
So the mind could be critical
and disagree,
but the heart is loving no matter what.
So the heart does not put any conditions
on what's out there.
Only the mind does.
The heart, I love you no matter
whether there's coffee in the morning or not.
No conditions.
Love makes no demands.
Transcending level 500.
A key to making love unconditional
is the willingness to forgive.
With forgiveness,
events and people are recontextualized
as simply, quote, limited,
not bad or unlovable.
Forgiveness ensues from the willingness
of humility to surrender the world
and its events to divinity.
Pray to the Holy Spirit for a miracle
to see the truth about the situation
or the person.
And surrender all perceptual positionalities
and their egoistic gain
to the revelation of truth.
When you say,
pray to the Holy Spirit for a miracle
to see the truth about a situation
or a person,
are we to forgive that person
if there was a conflict?
Or just accept them for what it is?
No.
Because you're still seeing them the same way
or you wouldn't be forgiving them.
Through the course of miracles, for instance.
The miraculous occurs
but not as a consequence of how you're seeing it
because you may still see it the same way
and yet it happens.
So, when I ask for a miracle,
I'm surrendering my perception
of how I see it.
And then it's transformed.
And when it's transformed,
I see that it still is lovable.
Yeah? Huh?
I see that somebody I'm angry at
cannot help but be that way.
So now instead of hating them or being angry,
I feel sorry for them.
And I say, it's too bad
that they can't see it the way I'm seeing it.
See? Because I know their life is painful
the way they are seeing the world.
And when they see it my way,
the world stops being painful.
Yes? Uh-huh.
Okay.
Remember,
this domain is one of maximum spiritual opportunity
with a multitude of options
which aid the evolution of consciousness.
Therefore, one can be grateful
instead of resentful about the past.
The Buddha said,
Rare is it to be born a human being.
Rarer still,
to have heard of enlightenment.
And even rarer still,
to pursue it.
Unconditional love,
words that describe this energy field.
Only 0.4% of people,
miraculous, inclusive,
inner joy,
Kundalini energy,
non-selective,
healing,
vision,
merciful,
faith,
essence,
transformative,
ecstasy,
beauty,
selfless,
kindness,
synchronicity,
radiant,
siddhis,
perfection,
effortless,
patience,
surrender,
unlimited,
persistence,
emerging Self with a capital S,
diffuse,
compassion,
devotional,
openness,
saintly,
rapture,
way of life.
Wowzy.
Unconditional love, joy, and ecstasy.
As love becomes unconditional,
it begins to be experienced as inner joy.
Joy arises from within each moment of existence,
not from any outer source.
The hallmark of this state is compassion.
At this level,
people have a notable effect on others.
David, when you say that you experience joy,
what type of joy,
or when you say joy,
what do you mean by that?
Joy is, to me, not just an emotional thing.
Joy may occur as an emotion along with it,
but joy is like,
you thought the dog was run over and killed,
and when you get there,
you realize that it was only hurt a little bit,
and it's still living,
and its tail wags,
and your heart just jumps with joy.
The doggie's okay,
not really badly hurt,
and so you jump with joy.
You jump with joy.
I jump with joy when I get up every morning.
I'm still alive.
At my age,
you're glad to see yourself in the mirror every day.
Hi, Dave, how are you today?
Oh, boy.
Joy arises within each moment of existence.
I can't hear you.
It says joy arises from within each moment of existence.
Yes, it's from within.
It's not dependent on anything.
It's something out there.
Whether the audience laughs or not is irrelevant.
Whether they're enjoying what I'm saying is irrelevant.
That's their problem.
To be self-sufficient,
because the radiance of divinity,
the experience of love,
love is everywhere present.
It's like the sun just shining everywhere on the desert
no matter where you go.
Yes, uh-huh.
Everything happens effortlessly
by synchronicity.
One sees the world and everything in it
to be an expression of love and divinity.
This state is impersonal, not personal.
It represents the power of the energy field,
not of the individual.
Yeah.
There is the capacity to love many people simultaneously.
Love has no limits.
Yeah.
The more people you love,
the more you can love.
Yes?
Unconditional love is the goal
of the majority of spiritually committed people.
Unconditional love at 540
is a practical and reachable goal.
The goal of unconditional love
is reachable by very simple means.
For example,
quote,
to live with care and kindness
on a daily basis without exception.
A lot of us would like to give that example
of living with care and kindness on a daily basis,
but when we try to apply it,
it just doesn't work.
So can you give us some tips
as to how we can achieve that?
Well, it's because of how we are viewing the world.
In other words,
when we place expectations on the world,
then we set ourselves up for disruption.
You know, I have no expectation
that there will be coffee in the kitchen
in the morning or not.
I have great hopes.
It may or may not be there.
You know what I think?
I have great hopes that when we get home today,
the doggie will not have had an accident
in the living room.
But if doggie had an accident,
I'm prepared to forgive her.
So unconditionally loving means
no conditions, no conditions,
because it's the way that I am
and not the way the world has to be.
The doggie doesn't have to be the way I want her to be.
I would prefer it,
but she's only a doggie,
and if she's got to go wah-wah,
she's going to go wah-wah.
Hopefully not before we get home.
All right, yes.
Okay.
Huh?
There is a silent nonverbal benefit
of being in the actual presence
of such a teacher.
The silent transmission
of the high frequency energy
of the teacher's aura
is referred to as the silent teaching,
the transmission of no mind,
the grace of the teacher.
The benediction of the teacher.
It happens of its own
and is not personal.
That's the transmission of grace
by virtue of the energy field
of the teacher,
which radiates forth
unconditionally.
The grace of the guru, yeah.
Well, when we did the calibration on this
to see if that was true,
you know, we both kind of said,
oh, that's,
that everyone had to be
in the presence of a teacher.
Doesn't mean to be in your,
any teacher's presence, isn't it?
Well, the Buddha transmitted it.
Right.
Yeah.
And so it's giving them a flower.
It's symbolic of the transmission
of the energy.
To have been in the presence
of a great teacher,
you'll never be the same.
The most beneficial thing
that can happen to you
is to have been in the presence
of a great teacher
because you pick up the vibration.
Which cannot be taught
via words or lectures,
but actually the field.
I was hopeful that it could
be transmitted otherwise,
but it is not so.
You pick up the energy field
of the teacher
by the physical presence
within the aura, yeah.
But then it lasts a lifetime.
So the teachers that I have
encountered in my lifetime,
I've already incorporated
into my brain function,
their energy.
Yes.
So then it is worthwhile
to go from long distance
to see a teacher that
would have that.
That's true.
Many of the people we see,
any seekers,
travel long distances.
I mean, they're coming
from Australia and South America
and Africa and all.
And all they want to do
is pick up the energy field
of the teacher.
And then when they go
home, they bring it back
to where they came from.
So they come from all
different countries
around the world.
And I feel greatly honored
by their request to grant
whatever their request may be.
Mm-hmm.
And I've been requested
to go certain places
in the world because what
they wanted was my energy there.
What's that country that
all is questioning us to go there?
And we went there,
and it was just for our energy.
It was just for our energy field.
Not you, you idiot.
We just want your energy field,
you know.
South Korea, I think.
Yeah.
Okay, honey.
But, all right, so...
It was a great privilege
to go to South Korea
and be able to be of service.
Yes.
We prevented a war
from happening there
by virtue of our having been there.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
That was a great privilege.
So how long does this...
Did you carry that aura
of the teacher with you?
Lifetimes, you know?
How long do you carry that?
You carry it for a lifetime.
I carry it for a lifetime.
Mm-hmm.
Because you become that,
and then you yourself
also become the source
of it to others.
So your kindness and lovingness
then becomes a pattern
for somebody else,
and it's transmitted out.
It's because it is transmitted out
that mankind is still alive.
It would have destroyed itself
a long time ago.
I got it.
So that's why you say
that it's not the ship
on the ocean.
It's uplifting the ocean.
Right?
It's not the ships
that you're...
Remember when you said that?
Am I saying that right?
Yes.
It's the ocean
that's uplifting the ship.
Yes.
Mm-hmm.
So is that
how one raises...
That's right.
That's your universal lovingness.
So being unconditionally loving
as a way of existing,
as a way of being in the world,
uplifts everyone,
no matter who.
I can remember
walking down the street,
complete stranger
walking towards me,
and I felt the aura
of that person
coming towards me.
And as that person
walked by there,
they got this profound
whap of love.
And they experienced
the miraculous.
That complete stranger
who I'd never met
experienced the miraculous
to doing,
counting that energy,
resist.
The miraculous occurred
without the person's awareness,
and without my having
to acknowledge it or so.
I looked at him
in the eyes
and he looked at me
and it was profound.
Whammo.
We both became different
as a consequence
of that moment.
One moment
is all it took
to transform
the world.
And that's
why I'm here today.
Thank you.
And that's how
I transformed
in the heart
of the city
of New York City.
So we are uplifting
by us being
unconditional loving
for everything.
We are actually
helping mankind.
That's so.
So,
I can remember
meeting the doorman
at a very high class
apartment building.
And as I came
to see him
I saw him transform.
As I came to speak
to him,
I saw him
transform
as I came
to speak to him.
to him I saw him go from bored and disappointed or you know bored I would say to happy because
I could feel the energy just pour out and I just adored this guy I just loved him
and he was transformed so we were both transformed in the instant by the presence of of divine love
it was divine love that brought about the transformation the world did not look the same
so is that what all of us are supposed to do is to go forth from this lecture and
project this type of love towards mankind is that what what you're saying
is everyone here willing to be unconditionally loving towards all of life in all of its
expressions yes see because from you it is transmitted to others
it is runway so you only look like a thousand people but you're going to be influencing
millions as a consequence during your lifetime resist okay not because of what you do
but because of what you have become what you have become transforms the world what a great blessing
oh Lord amen what it's time to stop now because it's time for lunch everybody wants to eat lunch
his stomach is growing where's my lunch god bless you all we'll see you after
the break what time do we see them again what time we will see you again at two
o'clock anybody who tries to escape we've notified the police god bless you
all I love you so much too much loving you fall over I almost fell over and be
your fault what happens next we're gonna do any question oh okay oh okay now if
you'll talk into the mic
okay my question my doctors have not been able to give me a diagnosis I have
had this condition for 10 years but this allows me not to accept a label I've
been studying your work and also a course in miracles I'm addressing the
physical mental and spiritual aspects of this would you tell me if I continue to
try and raise my calibration can I heal the body or is this a karmic death for
me
you
, well I wouldn't differentiate between the two everything is both what's your
question whether this is karmic this karmic I have no diagnosis from doctors
karmic or what or whether this is some kind of physical physical that she can
heal oh this is something that she can heal resist Wow this is something she can heal wow this is something she can heal wow this is something she can heal
was physical therapy plus intense spiritual work okay better get better
what's up doc she you one last time I struggled to let go of guilt specifically
guilt around sexual behavior this is not very
good
this thing is going in these lights really in my eyes right I'm having
blinded and deaf other than that I'm fine
Other than being blind and deaf, I'm doing fine.
Okay, make it brief so she can relate it to me, please.
I would like some tips on letting go of guilt
and a sense of wrongness for particularly sexual guilt.
For some reason, no matter how much work I do,
it seems like it's still there.
It gets deeper and deeper.
I have a sense that...
He has a problem with sexual addiction.
Okay, give me the arm.
He can undo the sexual guilt by forgiveness
for his limitation of being the victim of his gonads.
I forgot to tell him the solution.
The solution is the removal of the gonads.
Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
Of course you would be willing
to do that.
You would be willing to do that, wouldn't you?
He'll get back to you on that one.
He's drawing the line there, I think.
It seems like I get stuck out of my body much of the time,
and I was wondering if you can teach us something
that would allow us to learn how to stay in the body.
You do what now?
I have an experience where I feel like I get stuck out of my body,
and I was wondering if Dr. Hawkins would teach us
something that would help me learn how to stay in the body.
What?
He feels that he gets stuck out of the body,
which is opposite than everybody,
and he wants you to have, is there something
that you can tell him to stay in the body?
In other words, he's having experiences.
Why does he go out of the body?
Why do you go out of the body?
I'm not sure.
Oh, does it happen spontaneously?
Well, I guess for as long as I can remember.
He's hemming and hawing.
Do you go out of the body spontaneously,
or is it something that you do?
Not something I'm conscious of doing.
You just go out of the body.
Well, what's your complaint about it?
I think it would be terrific.
It does seem that way sometimes,
but I associate a lot of experience of suffering with that,
with the way I feel when I'm like that.
What?
He experiences suffering,
like he relates suffering to that when he's out of the body.
Oh, because it's against his will?
Is it because it's against your will that you feel the suffering?
Lots of people study and spend all kinds of money
learning how to leave the body,
and you're complaining about it.
You get it for free.
I don't know what to say to that.
Well, what's he saying?
It's more about, I guess, functioning in this world.
Like, as long as I'm trying to function in this world,
I have a lot of friction.
He's trying to function in this world.
Yes.
And he can't because he keeps going into this outer body,
this outer body experience.
When you go out of body,
what does your body do while you're out of the body?
If you're sitting in a chair,
and you go out of body,
what happens?
Doesn't the body just stay sitting in the chair?
It does, but it's, um,
my ability to function is,
it feels inhibited.
Huh?
His ability to function is impaired.
What do you do for a living?
Um, I work,
I've been working in restaurants recently.
He works in a restaurant?
Uh-huh.
Mm-hmm.
Does this happen while you're at work?
Uh, yes.
Yeah.
Is it stress-related?
Not, no.
Well, do you fall over?
I mean, when you say, you know,
what are you talking about?
It's kind of, it's like, um,
I'm kind of, uh,
straining to use my body,
or to think, or to feel things.
What?
He's straining to think or to feel things.
He, what?
He's straining?
He's straining to think or feel things
when he's out of body.
You know, it won't function.
The body won't function.
So what is it?
You just leave it where it is.
If my body goes to sleep,
I just walk away
and wait till it wakes up.
In other words, to follow,
to follow what the body's doing.
Okay.
He should adjust himself to what the,
he thinks the body is doing.
Okay.
Instead of the other way around.
Yeah.
You should adjust yourself
to what the body is doing
instead of the other way around.
Yeah.
So.
Thank you.
Okay.
Uh, no, we don't,
we're not gonna do that.
It takes too much time
and we have so many people
that are asking questions today.
Hi.
Oh, I'm so nervous.
You better be nervous.
I'm never nervous.
Um, thank you.
And I wanted to give you this.
Um, Veritas Pub actually helped me
pick out the color of the shirt for you.
Oh.
It says,
trust me, I'm,
I'm a doctor.
That's cute.
Let me see that.
I thought you,
I thought you could wear it while watching.
Oh, that's cute.
I like that.
I thought you could wear it
watching Animal Planet
with Susan on the couch or something.
I like,
I like that.
Yeah.
Um, I,
I have a question.
Um, I was wondering
if you could explain to me
like I'm three,
surrendering.
I don't know if I'm doing it right.
Explain surrender?
Yes.
She wants to know
how do you go about surrendering?
Quit trying.
Can you quit trying?
I'm not gonna surrender.
I'm gonna fight, fight, fight.
No, I'm gonna surrender.
Oh, oh, oh.
That means letting go
wanting to change something.
And, um,
it means acceptance.
Acceptance.
I accept the fact that,
I accept the fact
that I'm old and ugly
and I can't help it.
I blame it on God.
Oh, no.
If God wanted me
to look like a fish and swim,
I would be.
If he wanted me
to have wings and fly,
I would be.
If he wants to be old
and somewhat falling over,
that's what I am.
So I accept what is
as how,
how we're created.
We're created
that as the years go by,
we get older and older.
So I accept what is
as how,
how we're created.
We're created
that as the years go by,
we get older and older.
So I accept what is
as how,
how we're created.
We're created
that as how,
how we're created.
When we age and go by,
we get older and older
and finally we get weaker
and weaker
and then finally
we just fall over.
So we have to accept
it that's the way it is.
Uh-huh.
Acceptance means
a little willfulness,
willfulness.
And one can pray for grace.
I pray for grace,
thy grace O Lord,
by which I can accept
thy divine will.
Amen.
You have to get that
God's not going
to change the entire human race
just to please you.
so you accept the common fate of being human all of us are mortal mortal and human and if that
god wanted a different it would be different when we go upstairs we're no longer mortal
when we go upstairs we're no longer mortal that ends it
that's nice thank you very much now everybody contemplates this periodically in their life
what it'll be like at the end and what is god's will in the manner and it's part of the human
condition to be uncertain about such matters and to see a variety of teachings out there in the
world about it so that's the common human experience that you're having yes thank you
are we allowed to do pictures is that okay yeah just quick because um we have so many people
i'm trying to get through as many as we can
so
mortality to accept man's mortality is uh what's hard for the ego okay good thank you
last year i had a psychotic break since then i have to repeat the year in high school
the junior year because my school is very demanding and because i had a hard time concentrating
can you calibrate if it is aligned with the highest good for me to stay for
in school or to change to a less demanding school okay
let's say she should stay in the school she's in resist thank you so much thank you so much thank you
oh man we have some blessings too sure blessings dear god we good let's see in the name of the lord
amen thank you yeah you might have something to prove to yourself by staying in that demanding
school so you might have something to prove to yourself by doing that thank you so much okay
you ginseng from korea they have the best ginseng in the whole world
they have the best ginseng in the whole world
thank you i feel gratitude for you because whenever we are in your presence
we have evolved and changed could you please bless my spiritual pathway your spiritual
pathway what she wants you to bless them spiritually please i have permission to give
them my blessing resist i bless you in the name of the lord
now and forever amen thank you so much my question is in your prayer and presence
i progressively set my intention to dedicate my life to the korean army as a servant of god
but i think my capability is insufficient holy smokes what
um he he was dedicating his life to the korean army
dedicating his life to the army yeah boy oh boy you must love the army yeah but now he feels
that it's inadequate but my capability is insufficient that i think
right all right you want to dedicate your life to the korean army it's a servant of god but i
haven't become a chaplain for the army yeah you can dedicate servers you can't dedicate your life to the korean army
army the army don't want your life wants you to go to work you're trying to get out of work by dying
lizzy bumming he's what he's what
corley what i can't understand it i can't understand you i don't understand corley what's
corley um you gotta speak english i don't know what corley does what is she saying oh he wants
you to calibrate okay calibrate calibrate what
i'm talking totoshi
clerical
general on?
ah
no
uh i'm a know general i'm not a general soldier like uh fighting in the battlefield i'm uh i'm in charge of uh ideology
education oh he's in charge of education so he's not a soldier he is an educator in the army so what does he want what does he want but what do you what what is your question
what does he want what-
what do you what what is your question
but i don't have to guess
uncle
.
He doesn't have the confidence to work in the army as efficiently as what he would like.
He doesn't have the confidence to work in the army?
Well leave the army.
He's teaching.
He's teaching right now in the army and he feels like he isn't doing a good job at that.
Well you ought to quit teaching then.
If you do a bad job as a surgeon, you don't keep doing surgery, you give up surgery.
How many dead bodies do you need before you get it?
I guess surgery ain't for me.
That may not be your calling.
That's not, that's not his calling.
No because he would have inspiration otherwise.
So maybe you should look into it.
Look into other things.
Okay, what else?
Come on.
Could you bless my life?
Okay.
I don't, I don't know.
I don't know what you're saying.
He, what?
Oh he wants the, he wants us, our blessing.
He wants our blessing.
You can have our blessing.
God bless you.
Amen.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Thank you sweetheart.
Thank you.
I'm sorry we couldn't do better.
Hi.
Come on up.
Don't hold.
I'm gonna go.
I'm gonna go to close focus.
Go ahead.
Thank you, Dr. Hawkins.
Will you help me to release obstacles in the way of knowing God?
She wants you to help her release obstacles that are blocking her way to knowing God.
Obstacles in the way of what?
Obstacles that are in the way of her knowing God.
What obstacles?
Fear.
fear of what fear of what i would say the unknown what the unknown the fear of the unknown oh the
unknown well you cannot know god unless you get over that fear how do i do that by your own will
thank you people make god out to be a big ogre the big invisible ogre in the sky
hello dr hawkins can you hear me congratulations on your retirement i can't hear i can't hear
that's right congratulations on your retirement so now you can go to a bench at a park and feed
the pigeons but instead you don't have to do that i brought you something i don't know what she's
saying you can feed chickens you can feed chickens instead and you don't need to put food in it oh
that's funny
thank you that's funny i'm grateful for your existence for what you have taught me what
you're teaching humanity the incredible effort that you have put forth to bring the truth to
the table thank you very much thank you thank you thank you that was so cute we have chickens
in bulgaria we have chickens good you got extra ones to feed yeah
you
she bought it in bulgaria
that's cute um dr hawkins um i'm experiencing so much energy right now it's it's so strong
sometimes i just feel like screaming it's to the we'll go outside and scream no screaming here
no screaming folks yeah it's to the point where i can't sit in meditation um it's so strong
anytime i'm in stillness even at work
it just it comes and it the energy is so strong my question is am i experiencing this energy because
i have a high level consciousness or do i just need to play disco music when i meditate i don't
know where this question is really he he says he's experiencing a lot of energy right now okay and he
is right for him to sit and meditate it's okay it's physical energy it's a psychological energy
physical energy yeah you better go out and just sit and meditate if you're tired just sit and meditate
it's hard for him to sit and meditate he's okay it's physical energy it's psychological energy physical energy yeah you better go out and get up and help out
exercise exercise not spiritual energy then don't don't meditate till after you
exercise exercise not people have to do that they have to go and exercise first
and for they can sit quietly sit quietly okay I can sit for days without moving
but takes years to get there all right well thank you both so much for
everything yeah do funny that's very funny
what do you got now is that right honey oh yeah that is a big yeah she's asking
for a special blessing on her journey to enlightenment we are here blessing a
month her journey to enlightenment so she would like your blessing on her
journey to enlightenment
journey to enlightenment hi god bless your endeavor towards enlightenment amen and she
wishes to choose better things to follow the path of enlightenment to choose what she she
wishes to choose better things better things yes like what like a coffee cup choices better
choices what kind of things on the path to enlightenment I don't know what the question
is she's just saying that she's making a statement that she wants to choose a better better choice on
her way to enlightenment she wants to have a better choose a better choice well we do prayer
and meditation is that what you do I can't see her she said yes
yes so what else do you want she wants something special everybody wants to be special she she
just wants to know what she what path she should take towards enlightenment I don't know what you
mean by what path well she wants to make better choices in in what better life choices yes on
her pathway
like course of miracles what would you suggest that she do any legitimate pathway if vigorously
followed will get you there doesn't make any difference with which one stay on the path if
you're scheduled to get there you'll get there no matter which path will you follow through prayer
meditation self-sacrifice yes thank you did you want this back okay hi hi Susan I'm Susan I'm a
citizen hello Dr Hawkins uh I just want to say I love you and thank you and uh please uh ask for
your blessing thank you so much Dr Hawkins I love you so much thank you thank you Jaya comes to us
clear from Dubai is that outside Chicago
I I know so many of you have come from such a long time
yes and we appreciate it so much we have so many countries that are represented here tonight and
it's so wonderful to know that the work is that far reaching I mean it's just amazing to us uh
we've been doing this for 10 years over 10 years and to have all of you come for some
so many different countries uh it's just amazing that the work is being studied that way and we
appreciate it so much
Dr Hawkins our groups in Dubai send you lots of love has he heard it uh in May you guided me
to the completeness of the silence
in May you guided me to the completeness of the silence you declared it complete however on my own
I still
face a knot of fear like I'm on the edge of the precipice and I can't jump off uh please help me
melt this knot what is it she she's taken herself to the point that she has you know she's right on
the edge edge of what well she feels like she's on the edge of a precipice that's in your mind
there's no edge and there's no president there's no president there's no president
well anyway she's right on the edge and she can't she feels like she just can't get there
okay the last time you took me into the silence would you please take me again into the silence
last time you took her into the silence and she would like you to take her into the silence one
more time because she wants to be able to become enlightened if that's at all possible in this
lifetime nobody asked you to become enlightened who asked you to
be nobody okay that's the answer my own intent nobody asked you to become enlightened this this
lifetime um forget about enlightenment I just want the silence she wants the silence she wants to go
into where the silence is what she wants to go into where the silence is she wants to go where
her she wants to go to where the silence is again the silence how would you know where the silence is
me huh you have you helped her go there one time where you go into the silence
you did this and you said it's complete so can you do that again please tiptoe
back out tiptoe tiptoe that's a great great piece of advice thank you thank
you so much I never think if I can avoid it what'd you say I said I never
think of unless I have to yes let's go all right here he's got it
yep thank you thank you thank you now they tell me there's nobody sitting there
okay so we're gonna have to speed this up we only have 15 minutes left in the
Q&A so we have to kind of speed this up thank you yes your work is in your
presence is it's been such a gift to the world oh thank you so much hello thank
you thank you thank you thank you thank you thank you thank you thank you thank
you so much I I don't really have a question but can I please have your
blessing thank you what does he want oh hi dr. Hawkins thank you so much for
your teaching I'm ever so grateful and my question to you is do you have any
advice to heal trauma from sexual abuse willingness to forgive that's all other
than the willingness to forgive
I can't think of any how to know what sexual abuse means pretty broad term
covers yeah as a child or what are you talking about so what's the problem with
it now so how many years ago was that come on 42 perhaps huh 42 years ago 42
years ago so what's your problem if you haven't gotten around to it in the last
42 years well you're not gonna get around to it for two times you die right
you're pretty lazy girl no you know how long it takes to forgive forgive that
person now you're done if you didn't then you're not willing to okay thank
you in life we forgive each other for being human that's what it is human
weakness the limitations of being a human are extraordinary
My question is concerning your pictures and photos.
Like your patient, I keep your pictures and photos around my house,
and I feel a very profound, pure, unconditional love coming from those.
And so that reminds me of the statement of Krishna that says,
those who are devoted to me are mine.
And so my question comes to this.
Is this profound love because of the love you have for your students,
the profound love coming from your pictures?
What is he asking? I don't get it.
Can you radiate?
He feels like we're radiating love from our photos.
Yes, that's true.
And so he wants to know if that's true.
It is true.
That's out of the love for your students.
Yes.
Okay, thank you very much.
He's loving everybody that he looks at.
Is that a kitty there?
That's the dog.
That's a doggie.
It's all about love.
Kids, kitties, doggies.
Hi.
Yeah.
I have a guide from New Zealand.
Thank you.
Did you put your name or anything in here?
Yes.
Because I'm asking everyone.
And we get kind of confused, so we can't.
All right.
We'd like to ask for a blessing.
What?
They would like a blessing.
Yes.
God bless you in the name of the Father, the Son, and the Holy Ghost.
Amen.
And I'd like to ask how not to doubt, doubt of God.
Well, you do prayer and the same thing everybody does.
Dear God, please help me to understand my relationship to thee and thy infinite nature.
Just with prayer and supplication.
And going to church or whatever devotional activities are part of your life.
Yes.
Service to the poor.
Service to the sick and dying.
There's miracles every day.
You just have to slow down enough to recognize them.
Yes.
To be aware of them.
Devotion.
We have a friend now who's sick.
We pray every day to God for the alleviation of this person's illness and their recovery.
And that's all we can do.
Now it's up to their karma.
Okay?
That's all we can do.
All right.
Could you please bless my mother?
She's sick.
Bless your mother?
Yeah.
Her name is Veronica.
Veronica?
Yeah.
And she has cirrhosis.
Cirrhosis?
Yes.
We have permission to pray for her mother.
We pray to thee, O Lord, for her mother's recovery.
Amen.
Thank you.
Hi, Dr. O'Keefe and Susan.
Thank you for your existence.
Could you bless my parents and my family?
Could you bless his family?
Let me ask.
It's okay to bless his family.
Resist.
Yes.
God bless your family.
Amen.
Thank you.
Quick.
We're almost out of time.
Let's go.
Hop, hop, hop, hop, hop.
The what?
What?
They won't be able to record it if you're not talking.
Nothing.
We're discussing logistics.
During the lecture and through teaching, talking about being loving to everyone, including ourselves.
I grew up in an environment that seemed to tend to have me repress anger, emotions,
and so it would come out sideways a lot of times.
Do you have any suggestions for the better, more loving ways,
or the most loving way to process out those emotional things that seem to be in my body?
They're not in your body.
They're in your mind.
They're in your memory.
So you remember angriness, is that correct?
Mm-hmm.
And the thing is to forgive it and let it be that that was their karma, that was their way of being,
and then be done with it.
You can't think about it around the clock seven days a week, right?
No, and I don't.
It's not even as much the people.
It would be in a situation, you run into a person, that stranger on the street,
and that's what if they, like if I'm by myself, I can detach from the emotion.
Somebody, I'm in a car, and the person cuts you off.
I can realize I'm angry, but I'm not really angry at them.
But if I get confronted, it's been those times in my life that everybody loves Troy
except those times when Troy flips.
What is he saying?
He just says it's a split reaction.
You know, it's like a knee-jerk reaction when he goes off.
Yes.
And so he's trying to avoid that.
He wants to avoid normal human emotions?
Well, is there a more loving way to...
To approach it.
If I ignore it when it happens, it feels like I'm not loving myself.
If I stuff it down, I feel like I'm not loving myself by getting it out.
But if I...
It's not loving to...
Why don't you just get mad at a person?
Okay.
I mean, someone cuts you off. That makes me mad.
Why don't you just get mad and be done with it?
It's not going to be the end of the world.
Okay. Okay. Thank you.
I just want to say thank you.
You just don't become violent.
Just be normal and don't worry about it.
It's okay to get mad.
Dear God, I'm sorry that I lost my temper. Amen.
Okay.
God don't care anyway, so...
You were created as a mortal.
Hi.
Yeah.
Could you tell me that all fear is an illusion?
Is all fear an illusion?
No.
So, if you had a fear, should you confront it and address it?
I don't know what that means.
All right.
If all fear...
All fear is illusion at a certain level.
Level.
Yes.
Because you're karmically destined and nothing is going to make it any...
So, depending on your level of spiritual reality, your level of consciousness,
you'll either be affected by it or not affected by it.
If you've transcended it, you won't be asking the question.
Okay?
I think.
Okay.
Okay, we'll take one more.
That's it.
Quick.
Bum, bum, bum, bum.
Make it short.
I got four people up here.
Okay.
Let's go.
Bum, bum, bum, bum.
Could we get your grace?
Dr. Hawkins?
They want your blessing?
Yeah.
Grace.
They want your grace?
Blessing.
Oh, no, no, no.
Grace, please.
They want something.
What?
All right, here.
Give me your arm.
Okay, God bless you in the name of the Lord.
Amen.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Okay, we're going to take a quick break and then we're going to do testimonials.
And we'll have you line up on this side for testimonials.
Please.