Susan has taught our African bra parrot
to say I'm calling my lawyer.
>> That's why I'm laughing.
>> I'm calling my lawyer. The birthday
>> I'm calling my lawyer.
>> Oh god.
>> Hi Dr. Hawkins. Yeah.
>> Um I have a practical question. Um, I'm
wondering if it would be in the highest
good for me to go to school to study
Chinese medicine. And
>> are you Chinese?
>> No,
>> not in this life.
>> What do you want to study Chinese
medicine for?
>> Um, I just have a a drawing to it. Um,
>> oh,
>> but I also am a perpetual student and I
don't know if that's pathological or
not.
So
>> yeah.
>> So what's the question?
>> So I'm just wondering if it would be in
my highest good to go to school and
study that. And if so, I have a
>> be in his highest good to study Chinese
medicine. Resist.
>> There you go.
>> Thank you. Would you mind checking a
school that I have in mind? If it's best
>> food dump up that place.
>> Yeah, that one.
>> The place he wants to go is okay.
>> Thank you very much.
You bet you. Yeah. Good for you.
Good for you.
Who is that on the front there? Who's
that?
>> Who Who is that? You
>> is that myself?
Is that what I look like?
Whatever you say, baby.
You say that's me, I'll take your word
for it.
>> Yeah.
Yes.
If everything is God, if all of us um
and the you know omnipresent and
omnipotent,
what is the purpose of God experiencing
itself in
>> there is no purpose. It's a human
notion.
A hemlock tree does not grow just in
order to experience itself. It grows
because it's a hemlock tree. It's
designed to do that.
You're asking me why is God like God? I
don't know why it's God.
Why is God like God? Gee, I don't know.
But
you're looking for human rationality
where it's not really appropriate.
Everybody likes to presume that God has
human notions and motives
and that's not so.
Okay. Thank you.
>> The ocean isn't there just so you can
swim in it.
>> Okay.
>> The ocean's there because that's what an
ocean is.
>> Thank you.
You see there's subject, object, and
verb. You know, God
does this in order to do that. You know,
that's trying to put it in within a
human dimension.
>> Yes.
>> Hello.
Uh you mentioned the quality of intense
prayer today.
Um my priest many months ago gave me
this rosary as a gift.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And before I came I had it for many
months and before I came to Sedona this
weekend I realized I had never said a
rosary. So yesterday
>> Yeah.
>> at the Chapel of the Holy Cross. Wow.
>> I dedicated my first rosary to God.
>> Good deal.
>> And I wept the entire time
and then said three more. And I just
wanted to thank you for this
inspiration.
>> You enjoyed the chapel of the Holy Cross
>> very much.
>> Yeah, I love that place.
Then the world found out about it. So
the end of that
>> I'm very grateful. Thank you.
>> At 3:00 or 4 in the morning, usually the
traffic dies out.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you.
>> It used to be open all night.
>> Ah.
>> And so
>> Oh, do they lock it at night now?
>> Yeah, they lock it.
>> Oh,
>> but it used to be open all night and you
could go in there and just sit anytime
you wanted to. But
>> I don't know. I guess I shouldn't have
mentioned it so many places. I should
have kept it to myself.
>> But it was it was really it was really
beautiful.
>> Loud mouth.
>> Thank you. May I shake your hand?
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you. Love you. Love you.
A good place to find solitude is Time
Square.
You can spend years there and nobody
says hello to you.
>> That is for you. Yes, they're
chocolates.
Doc, I just wanted to thank you for
being such a rich blessing in my life
and um
can't express it.
>> So if I have contributed to your
happiness, then that makes me very
happy.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Yes, you have.
>> And that your happiness made me happy
should make you happy.
>> And it does. May I shake your hand?
Bless you. Bless you. Bless you.
>> Thank you. Oh, picture, huh?
>> A little bit.
>> Befuddled.
>> Yes,
>> that's a nice word. I like that word.
Befuddled.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Befuddled brings about befuddlement.
Befuettlement.
Thank you.
>> Befuddled.
>> Here we go. Yep. Yep. Here we are.
Ready?
>> Okay.
>> Hello.
>> Hello. In March, you have prayed for me
to continue to come here. uh by virtue
of that I could come here again without
troubles. All circumstances have
changed. Thank you for that very much
and thank you for your protection,
guidance and all other helps which I am
aware of or not.
>> Thank you.
>> And I have a question.
>> Uh oh.
>> My right my right eye has very different
from uh my left eye. The look of the uh
face is different left and right. In
daily life, my left one is always
healthy uh smiling and strong. But my
right uh right part is uh depressed,
weak, exhausted.
>> Yeah.
>> And become easily become sad,
embarrassed. Uh and when I meditate
sometimes my whole body gets lightened
except my right part of my head except
for what?
>> He seems to feel like his right
everything his whole body becomes
enlightened but the right side of his
head you know like there's a block
there.
>> Oh no okay
>> get lightened.
>> Whole body get lightened
>> except this part. Yes.
>> Okay. He's got
>> what what is it he say? Just a minute.
Go ahead.
>> Uh
and on meditation it seems like dark
clouds start touch from this part and
spread veil my whole head.
>> He feels like there's like the right
part or the left part of his face is
>> happy welling just and the right part is
not
>> and he says it
>> yes that's a uncommon condition but it
has a name actually. Okay. When he when
he meditates,
>> it he feels like this
>> the the right part is where the darkness
comes from.
>> Yeah.
>> And everything else he feels becomes
enlightened. But this there's this
darkness.
>> Yeah. That's just a natural phenomena
with him.
>> So what could he do to change that?
>> Why would he want to change it?
>> Well, he would like to have that feeling
all over of in his body rather than
just, you know. You mean my right foot
should always feel the same as my left
foot?
>> I guess
>> two different feet.
>> Okay. So, what is it? Could it What
could that represent then? That that he
has that
>> uh nothing in in particular. Okay. It's
not necessarily
significant or meaningful.
My right eye is considerably different
than my left eye,
>> but that's just the way it is. The way
the retina is, you know.
And so you just accept nature how it is
and how it is. See
thank you.
I am a doctor.
Could you please bless on myself on my
patients and on my practices?
>> What's a blessing of
on to have more patience and
>> practice
>> and on her practice. She needs a
blessing on her practice. She's a
doctor.
>> You want me to bless your practice
>> and patients
>> and patients?
>> My patients.
>> Her patients.
>> I can't bless all your patients.
>> I don't know who they are.
>> What do you do to be the best doctor you
can be? What do you do?
>> What What do you do to be the best
doctor you can be?
>> Prayer.
>> Do you pray for your patients?
>> Yes. Yes.
>> Yes. That's what you do. You do the best
you can
because you know you're karmically
responsible.
And every patient I saw and I saw many
for 50 years, thousands.
Every patient would to me was
uh that God's intention was for me to be
as helpful as I could to this patient.
Yes.
And I found it very fulfilling.
And I only gave up practice because I
had to.
I'd still be seeing patients, but the in
malpractice insurance became so
expensive.
I was spending all my time just working
for the insurance company. And finally,
reluctantly, I just had to quit.
But I really missed it because it's very
gratifying
to be able to help people and to relieve
suffering and
and bring forth their gift to the world,
you know. So I missed the practice of
medicine. I really enjoyed it.
And also the fact it was psychiatry gave
it another dimension besides just the
physical.
>> Mhm.
>> Could you hold my hand for us again?
>> Yeah.
>> Do you want pictures?
>> Come over here.
>> Yeah. I miss my old patience.
I didn't quit until the last one died.
I said, "I'll stay in practice as long
as they're still alive."
He was in his 90s and he teetered in and
fell over. That was the end.
I said, "Well, God, I guess I can retire
now."
I didn't want to leave him leave the
practice
>> because he was being kept going by
positive transference
and uh so I kept I thought it was my
duty to stay as long as I could walk
around and stay in practice which is
what I did. Finally he died and so I was
relieved and I could close my practice.
>> Yeah.
>> Hello Dr. Hawkins.
>> Yes. My goodness. where all these books
come from.
>> First, I ask for your blessing.
>> And uh second, um my question is
um in your work, I've read that love is
innate to the capital S self from
within.
>> Yes. Uh I want I'd like to understand
that and uh
>> that that its quality is divinity which
is radiates love towards all that
exists.
>> The problem is that I tend to
um
uh treat
love as if it's some sort of currency
that uh goes from one person to the
other that it comes from an external
source.
>> No, it's a way of being in the world.
It's a way of being. It's got nothing to
do with anything else out there.
The way as you walk through the woods,
it's your way of being with the woods,
being with the trees, being with the
rabbits
to radiate
appreciation. So love has many forms
other than you know affection. It it can
be appreciation
and acknowledgment of the significance
and beauty of the existence of the
other.
I've got three kitties at home.
Each one is divine.
There's divine.
And then I have a doggy who is also
divine.
>> Would you suggest I get a pet or
>> Huh?
>> Would you suggest getting a pet?
>> He I think what he thinks is sense if he
gives love then he expects love in
return. So he hasn't learned to give
without
>> So no no it's a way of being. It's a way
of being with the world. It's a way of
being.
So the doggy sits next to me. I look at
the doggy and if I look at the doggy,
her tail starts going.
I haven't touched her. I haven't spoken
to her.
But I can feel the love for the dog and
the doggy's tail starts to wag.
So that's the way to be in the world
that all the people around you are
wagging their tails that you're there.
Oh,
>> okay.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you.
Can I have a picture?
>> Is that his pen?
>> Can I have a picture?
>> It's my pen. Yes.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> I didn't want it drying out.
>> That's fine. Yes. You want a picture
or is he growing? Sorry.
>> Okay. You want it with or without a
waggy tail?
>> A waggy tail, please.
>> You want some waggy tail? Okay. Take
that picture. God bless you. Boom.
Where'd he go? Here you go. You a
picture.
>> That's your waggy tail picture.
>> Hi
uh in my home um trying to have
aesthetics but a portion of the home has
a lot of clutter.
>> Is that indicative of something on the
spiritual
>> path? Yeah, it's significant that part
of your house is cluttered.
>> That's true.
Y
>> I feel like I'm stuck in something with
my partner and myself and I don't know
if you have any insights what the
clutter
what it would take to move that or what
could be underlying it or
>> laziness.
>> Laz
takes time, thought, and energy to clear
up clutter.
>> Okay.
>> And you're too lazy
>> to do it.
>> Yes. You're lying in bed sleeping when
you should be clearing up clutter.
>> Okay. Could be true.
Is it indicative of anything in the
relationship that we're both doing it?
>> No.
>> No. Just laziness on both parts perhaps.
>> No. Clutter is part of the human
condition.
>> Thank you. Okay. Work on that.
You don't have to work on it. If you
work on it, it won't have clutter
anymore.
>> All right. Good. Thank you.
>> Clutter is good.
Tell yourself clutter is good. What I do
is I confine my clutter to certain
areas. So like this table from here to
there, this can be clutter and this is
not clutter.
Isn't that nice?
That sound good?
Hi, my question is uh pornography. How
do people overcome pornography?
>> How people what?
>> Pornography.
>> Overcome it.
>> Yes.
>> That's my question.
>> Oh. Oh, shock treatment. How's that?
>> Shock treatment.
>> Oh, you got it. Is there any other way?
Ah, castration.
What about something else?
What's wrong with castration?
Are there other options?
deconditioning yourself which takes time
it because it's also just a habit. It's
a habit,
>> right?
>> It isn't just pornography. It's a
pornography habit like the fixation on
it. And you don't find it's boring after
a while.
>> I do.
>> You do?
>> And then I stopped
>> and that's a problem. But I had I have
uh relapses like for four months I would
not do anything and then I relapsed.
>> How'd it get the lesson?
>> He said four months he would not do
anything and then he'd have a relapse.
>> Oh. Oh.
So it'd be like a a huh
>> right.
>> Yeah. You give it up one day at a time
which is the only way to do it.
>> Okay. Give it up one day at a time.
And as you get older and older, it'll be
less and less interesting.
>> For sure. For sure.
>> The novelty wears off.
>> Thank you, sir.
>> The first derriè is fascinating, but the
thousandth one is the thousandth butt
you've looked at.
>> May I have a picture?
>> Derriè turn into butts.
Boom.
>> Well, yes,
>> Dr. Hawkins, I am grateful for your
teachings and grateful to be here.
>> Yeah.
>> Um some time ago, I was sitting in a
Mexican restaurant not long ago and um
it was just a small restaurant and out
of the side of my eye, I caught sight of
a
>> right.
>> I caught sight of in this restaurant
totally unexpectedly the sight of a a
being of light who asked, "What have you
learned? How well have you loved?" And
it was such an astonishing experience. I
tended to believe it, but it remains
astonishing. And I'm wondering
>> Mexican restaurant sitting in one when
it happened.
>> I was sitting in a Mexican restaurant
when I had this experience of this being
of light. Uh
>> of what?
>> A being of light.
>> A beam of light. So it got nothing to do
with a Mexican restaurant, right?
>> A being of light.
>> A beam of light.
>> A being
>> a being of light. So, it's got nothing
to do with Mexican restaurants.
>> Okay.
>> I don't care what street it was on, what
city, what year.
>> Sorry. And um
>> a a light lit up in the room.
>> A being of light appeared in the room.
>> A being a being
>> and the the being of light asked, "What
have you learned? How well have you
loved?"
>> Yes.
>> And it was such an astonishing
experience.
>> I would think so. I'm inclined to
believe I'm inclined to believe it would
be true. And I wondered if you might
test the veracity of that.
>> It's an it was an angel.
>> It was an angel.
>> All right. It was an angel. Yeah.
>> Right. Thank you.
>> So what why would he why would he ask
that question?
>> Because it's significant in her level of
consciousness.
>> Okay.
>> If I'm an angel, I'm cruising along and
I get this lady's asking a certain
question. I shoot over and I say, "Try
pork and beans." You know what I mean?
Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Well, that um uh high higher angel that
heard my prayer
>> Yeah.
>> was just I always say cruising around,
>> right?
>> Calibrating at 6,000,
>> And all of a sudden, my prayer went up
with great intensity.
So, this
angelic being that calibrates it at
6,000 and we verified it many times over
the years, you know, heard it and was
there to respond, you know,
>> and gave me a zap that totally changed
my life. Yes.
>> Well, thank you.
>> I'll say the angelic being was cruising
cruising by when my
uh appeal shot up into the cosmos. Okay,
go ahead.
>> Thank you, Dr. Hawkins. Thank you,
Susan. It's great to see y'all again.
Uh, my question and a blessing, please.
Uh, my question is, is the soul the same
thing as the self with a capital S?
>> No, the self is more inclusive generally
speaking.
And the soul is is usually
delimited to to
not not including the personality as
such.
I mean just in general parlance.
Yeah.
Thank you.
You can tell when an angel's around you
or I can tell when an angel's around
because it smells like perfume.
When there's an angel in the room, it's
like there's a flowers in the room or
something. You can smell them.
>> Yeah, you said that before.
>> Yeah. And that's why we have it at home.
And uh and if you smell rotten eggs,
that that's an entity from the lower
lower dimensions.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Thank you very much for uh being
here and for all you're doing. Um I have
a question about suicide. Um the what
happens to the soul and suicide?
>> Question. What
>> about suicide? Um when someone commits
suicide, what happens to their soul?
I really don't know because I don't know
that it's a very specific thing
spiritually speaking.
Suicide can be a you know in
desperation. It can be in a fit of
psychosis, a fit of madness.
>> Can be a way of getting even with God.
It can be
>> this is a case where uh I think the
person may have Alzheimer's disease and
they don't want to go through the
suffering themselves and cause suffering
for others.
>> They don't want to what? go through
suffering and
>> they don't want to what?
>> They don't want to go through put other
people through suffering and
>> Oh, yes. Well, that's very considerate.
>> So, it's okay.
>> Yeah. Remove yourself instead of making
people carry you away. You know what I'm
saying?
>> Uhhuh.
>> Like digging your own grave. Save
somebody's job.
>> Thank you.
Suicide can be rational,
intelligent
and making availing oneself of the best
possibility in the situation. Resist.
>> This is what
>> this is the water. I've come from India.
Thank you.
>> It's water from the ganges.
>> Yes.
>> From what?
>> It's water from the Ganges.
>> Okay. Put it right there.
This calibrates over
700. Resist.
It is from the Ganges.
>> I've I've been
>> You realize water from the Ganges Cal is
700. You all know that.
>> Yes.
>> Okay. All right. So, she brought me some
water for the Ganges.
This water calibrates over 700.
This water is from the Ganges River.
Fantastic.
I'll have a glass of it for breakfast.
>> David has often said that if he ever
went to India that he wouldn't come
back.
>> Yes, I have watched a number of his
videos. I've died by the Ganges many a
time.
>> Bodies burned up in the gats.
That's a
>> This is from the
>> That's a fact.
>> The what? The beginning.
>> This is from the source of the Ganges.
>> The source.
>> From the source.
>> Yeah. We've watched a number of your
videos back in India. We watched a
number of videos, your videos, the
lecture videos. And I always um saw you
talking about Ganges whenever any Indian
would come up. So I said that would be
the best thing that I could get here for
you.
>> Oh, that's so sweet.
>> She said this she said this is the best
thing that she could bring you that
>> Oh, that's wonderful. Okay, this
calibrates 700. The Genji River
calibrates 700. all the dead bodies and
stuff, you know,
it's a holy it's a holy river purified
by the spiritual devotion
of the people in India there. Mhm.
That's a lovely gift. Thank you so much.
>> I just wanted to know uh how do I keep
track of myself whether I am on the path
or no? Because you know in in my
day-to-day life there are a number of
instances when I get angry I get upset
about things I am so fearful I have so
much of anxiety for my children so you
know all these things calibrate below
200 and I keep wondering whether I am on
the path or am I getting away
>> what is your question
>> she feels like she's like below 200
because she has all these anxieties
about her children and dayto-day
daytoday life and you know
>> number of fears coming up all the time
>> and fears coming up. So
>> she has all these emotions about her
child,
>> right?
>> Children,
>> right? And so
>> that's normal. Yeah,
>> it's just normal.
>> Yeah.
>> It's not that she's below 200. It's
>> No, it's because she's maternal. She's
over 200.
>> Maternalism.
I don't suffer from maternalism.
I love you.
>> I'm glad I'm not a woman because
maternalism
would be endless, wouldn't it?
As it is, paternalism is
trying to be the best you can be to
other people. You know, maternal doesn't
mean necessarily one's own uh physical
children.
You can be very maternal towards, you
know, if you're a clerk in the drugstore
to be solicitous that everybody's being
taken care of and happy. And so th those
are character traits. Character traits.
Very good.
>> Can I sign please?
>> And what
book.
>> You bet, honey. You bet.
>> I'd sign in the front here. Right.
>> Just anywhere.
>> Anywhere.
>> Yep.
>> There. Right in the middle. How's that?
>> Perfect.
>> Can I shake your hands?
>> Uhhuh.
>> Can I touch your feet?
>> She wants to touch your feet.
>> Yes, madam.
God bless you. Thank you.
>> God bless
>> photo.
>> Uhhuh.
>> I love you so much.
>> Oh yeah.
>> Thank you so much. Such a lovely
It's our
>> That was wonderful.
>> Yeah. Adorable.
Mhm.
Um, let's leave it here just in case I
get
>> Hello, David Hawkins.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. I was here uh two years back and
you said my eyes were gloomy and also
you said I was in depression. You
calibrated and I just want to see am I
still the same or
>> what is this question?
>> He he wanted to know if he he was here
before and you told him that he was
depressed and now he looks he isn't
depressed. You can tell by looking at
him.
Yeah.
>> Can you please calibrate at?
>> He wants to know where where he what he
might calibrate at.
>> Oh. Oh.
What What does he want to know about
depression?
>> He was depressed.
>> Oh, he was depressed and saw.
>> Well, let's just ask something.
It's okay to ask this. He's over 300,
350, 380,
375,
370, 370. That's good. That's
willingness.
>> That's being willingness.
>> Yeah. Enthused about life. Do doing good
with life.
>> Thanks so much.
>> Yeah.
>> There's a presidential wouldbe candidate
who calibrates 380.
>> He changed his mind now. You know,
>> uh, all right.
>> I just want your blessings for me and
and rest of the world with right
knowledge.
Please
>> what?
>> Please bless me and everybody on the
world with right knowledge
>> with the knowledge. He wants just a
blessing on him and the world if you
could.
>> I don't get the question. What does he
want?
>> He wants to be blessed by you.
>> Okay. God bless you. Amen.
>> A picture
>> a picture. Oh. Oh. Oh. It's different.
God bless you. Yeah.
God bless you.
>> Thank you.
>> I give everybody a big hug, but I'd fall
over in no time.
>> Dr. Hawkins and Susan. It's a great
blessing to be in your presence today. I
thank God for this. And uh Dr. Dr.
Hawkins, I understand blessings of a
teacher protects a seeker from many
traps and uh pitfalls.
>> Mhm.
>> And I would like to
pray in your presence
to have your blessings
to protect me from any pitfalls in my
journey so that I am on the path in this
lifetime and the lifetimes to come.
Um he understands the blessing of the
teachers
>> uh protects them from pit pit pitfalls
in their on their path and he would like
you to bless him.
>> God bless you and protect you from any
pitfalls
>> that you may go integrously to reach
your spiritual destiny and ambition and
and capacity.
So we uh we'll try to bypass any
pitfalls.
>> All right.
>> Okay.
And one small uh thing, my my my cousin
and her husband were here in your
presence seeking your blessings for a
child. They gave birth to a baby boy
last month.
>> So
>> they gave they were here asking your
blessings.
What was it last year? uh for a child
and and she gave birth to a baby boy
last month.
>> Oh, good. That'll be a dollar.
>> That's wonderful.
>> God bless you and the child in the baby.
Cute baby. What's the baby's name?
>> What's the baby's name?
>> Uh Chin Maya.
>> Ching Maya.
>> Chin Maya.
>> As a girl,
>> it's a boy. a boy.
>> Ching Maya.
>> Ching
>> Chin Maya.
>> Very good. God bless you.
>> Everybody's having babies lately. Gee, I
better look out here.
>> Um, for those of you that don't know, if
you remember Gabe that used to be here,
um, he just had a baby girl and she
weighed weighed six pound seven oz or
something like that. Anyway, um they
just had a baby girl and they haven't
selected a name yet, but as soon as we
know, we'll let you know.
>> Thank you.
>> Hello.
>> Yes.
>> Um I just uh I just graduated from
college last week and my graduation gift
was to come out here and meet you.
>> Oh.
>> So I just wanted to uh Thank you.
>> What did you graduate? What you degree
with? um a degree in music.
>> In music.
>> Yeah. So, looking to be a full-time
musician.
>> So, I just wanted to come and meet you
and uh shake your hand and ask for your
blessing on my
>> What kind of musician do you want to be?
>> Um I play the drums.
>> Oh, the drums. Yes.
>> And I'd like to uh I play I have a Yeah,
I play jazz and R&B and rock and funk. I
like all that. So
>> yeah,
>> just
>> that's I'm starting that journey now is
>> being you know that's my job. So
>> yeah, I'm glad to meet a musician. My
father was a famous musician.
>> Yeah, his dad was
>> Yeah. Yeah. A great following. All kinds
of music.
>> And I almost became a musician.
>> And I played drums.
>> Yes, I did.
almost a musician.
Thank you.
>> What's that uh thing in Edinburgh every
year when they
>> tattoo? Yeah.
>> Wait, we're going to do one more here.
>> We're going to do one more.
>> It didn't work. Sorry.
I'd come back in March in the Edinburgh
parade. I was a musician.
Yep.
A trumpet.
>> Did it work?
>> Drums.
>> Yeah.
>> You got it.
>> Don't forget your books.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Oh, you're welcome.
>> Hi.
>> Um I'm a little bit nervous, but um I
just wanted to come and be close to you
guys.
And um um I don't have a personal
question, but um I just met somebody
that wanted me to ask if you guys have
calibrated Carl Jung's work.
>> Carl Young.
>> Carl Jung.
Yeah.
>> Oh, yeah. I calibrated him before. Uh
>> his work.
>> His work.
>> Yeah.
>> Well, let's see if I remember what it
was. Carl Young calibrates over 500,
550,
545,
540.
>> I can't remember.
>> 535.
Yeah, he's Yeah. Low 500s. 535. Girl
young. Yeah.
>> And so the calibration of the person
would be the same as the work.
>> Yeah.
>> Their body.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Right.
>> Most of the time it is. Sometimes it
differs, but most of the time it is.
They go up.
>> I've calibrated young before.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Let me have it one more time.
Young is in the 500s.
Over 25. Over 525.
Over 530.
>> Yeah, he's around 530. Right in there.
>> So, is it like a good a good one to um
study, I guess, is kind of what she was.
>> What's the question?
>> Would he be someone to study? Carl
Young.
>> Oh, he is indeed. Oh, sure. Yeah.
>> Okay. Thank you. And
>> young Carl Young was a genius.
>> Yeah, because I think it's Freud was
below 500.
>> I don't remember now.
>> Yeah, he was like 499, I think.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah, that's right.
>> May I shake?
>> I remember now. Carol Young calibrated
higher. Yes, because Young had a
spiritual orientation.
>> It was Carol Young because of him that
AA started.
>> Yeah.
Hello. My question is um I'm wondering
since I'm pregnant
>> if my consciousness is different now
than it would normally be.
>> I'm sorry. What? I wasn't I was
>> I'm pregnant and I'm wondering if my
consciousness is different now than it
would normally be or how it how it
>> What's your question?
>> She's pregnant and she wants to know if
her consciousness is different now or
how it changes. how it changes. Would it
change?
>> No.
>> No. Your consciousness doesn't change
because you're pregnant.
>> Nothing different happens when you're
carrying a child.
>> Well,
there's lots of changes.
>> Well, of course, there's a connection
between your consciousness and your
pregnancy. But what specific question
are you asking?
>> I'm just wondering if if you calibrated
me, would you calibrate myself or would
it calibrate the child and myself? Would
it be different now since I'm pregnant?
because the baby's is different than
what you are.
>> The baby's different. Okay.
>> And I also just wanted to ask for a
blessing on this baby and my
four-year-old who has a fever who it's
hard for me to be away from her while
she's
>> Let me have the arm. It's okay to bless
this baby. God bless this little baby.
Amen.
>> Thank you.
>> God bless that baby.
>> You're supposed to say
>> We've been busy blessing babies lately,
haven't we?
>> It's spring. Yes.
>> God bless his little baby.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Yep.
>> You're supposed to sign this to your
>> I don't know what this is.
>> Sign it anywhere.
>> What is this?
>> It's a computer.
>> A computer.
>> Yes. Just a minute. He's got to sign it.
Okay.
>> Anywhere. Just sign it. He wants you.
>> I don't understand anything about
computers.
>> I got as far as the abacus and that's as
far as I got.
>> What? Yes. Yes.
Jai is here.
>> What?
Ja got to come all the way from Dubai.
>> Ja's here.
>> I'm trying to listen to what you're
saying. What did you say?
>> Ja is here. She's come all the way from
Dubai again.
>> Oh, from Dubai. Yes. Yes.
Oh, hi, sweetheart.
That's the lady from Dubai.
>> The the lights are too bright.
>> She comes such a long way.
understanding. So I delete this.
>> Sure.
>> Now I know what you're doing.
>> Try and read you read it and if he
doesn't understand it, I will repeat it
because I have to do these things or he
won't sign them where I want him to.
>> Um Dr. Hawkins.
>> Yeah. Thank you for your teachings
and I'd like to convey the love and the
gratitude from all the members of the
two groups in Dubai.
>> Uhhuh. Great.
>> Each of them has sent you lots of love
and uh you they're pranam.
>> Very nice.
>> Um
>> how many people get blessed from Dubai
to today? Just me. I'm the only one.
Could
you please give them give these two
group members your blessings, please?
>> Wow.
>> Yeah. She wants you to give the group
members your blessing.
>> How many members are in the group?
>> Uh,
I'd say about 15.
>> God bless that 15 members of your group.
Amen.
>> Thank you.
>> Who is this here? Oh, that's myself. Oh.
He's signing in.
>> Is that what the book looks like? Yes.
Oh,
>> and
>> Oh, I didn't know that.
>> I think she's going to ask a question
now.
>> Yeah.
>> In your DVD, The Mystic,
you speak of diving into the silence.
Mhm.
>> Uh I have been practicing this for some
time and the practice has deepened quite
a bit.
Uh my request is could you guide me for
a few seconds into the completeness of
it now please?
Could you guide her in if she was to go
into meditation, would you guide her in
this practice uh into the diving into
the
>> silence?
>> The silence. Could we do a just a minute
of silence?
>> That'll be it.
It's complete.
>> Thank you.
>> I appreciate your presence in my life.
I can't get up.
>> I know.
>> It was the thump on the table that did
it.
Okay. Thank you so much.
>> Love you.
>> Yes. Here's a tall gentleman. Would like
to get close to the table.
>> He's getting older by the minute.
>> Older.
and older and older
>> and older and older.
>> Oh, yeah. I feel sorry.
>> But yes,
>> it's about 10 after 3. Did you want to
take a quick break and then we'll return
and finish?
>> What time is it?
>> 10 after 3.
>> You want what? Five minutes. Yeah, just
a like a five minute break and then so
everyone has a chance to go
>> a pedal break.
>> Yeah.
>> You're such a doll.
>> Thank you.
>> Ah, yes.
Now
let us resume now
>> or forever hold your pieces.
Okay.
>> Scoot you forward a little bit.
>> Yeah. Thank you. Thank you. Mhm. Okay.
We're all set to go.
Don't lose this. I don't want to forget
my water from the ganties.
That's great.
Yeah. So I don't forget there. Thank
you.
You drink it and you're dead.
Pour it over your head and you're
blessed. Drink it, you're dead.
>> Bless you both.
>> Yes.
>> Dr. Hawkins, I have a very painful and
dis uh de debilitating nerve disorder in
my head. Um, and I wonder if this is a
karmic debt or perhaps if increasing my
level of consciousness will pro will
promote healing.
>> Can't handle the whole conversation.
She's hitting me with a broadside. Speak
slowly. What is the problem?
>> I have a very painful and
>> just a little bit.
>> I have a very painful and debilitating
nerve disorder in my head. A painful
nervous disorder in your head.
>> A nerve disorder.
>> A nervous
>> A nerve. A nerve
>> nerve disorder. I told you you got a
nerve disorder.
>> Several different specialists from UCLA
to Vancouver. It's called atypical
andalgia. It's a nerve disorder of the
trigeminal neuralgia family.
>> A nerve disorder
like a neuritis. I have a burst nerve in
my cheek that runs all through the
trigeminal nerve area and it's extremely
painful and I have 247 pain and nausea.
>> You have to sit back.
>> You get a pain on one side of your head.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> One side of the head.
>> But it run No. Now it's running over to
this side as well. But it's the
>> Now it's bilateral.
>> Yes. But it's mostly here.
>> All right. It's not hemi crania because
it
is unilateral. This is bilateral.
>> I have a burst nerve in this area.
>> What?
>> She has a burst nerve in this area.
>> A burst nerve.
>> Who told you that?
>> Um I've been diagnosed by
>> a burst nerve.
>> Yes. I have atypical onalgia
which is a nerve burst in my trigeminal
neuralgia. This entire nerve is
>> I get what you got. Yeah. Okay.
>> Yeah. Okay. So, I'm wondering if this is
perhaps a karmic debt or perhaps if I
increase my level of consciousness, it
will help promote healing and just any
suggestions you might have to help me
cope.
You merely do all your spiritual work
the same as usual and pray
and that's all you can do.
>> That's it.
>> Okay. Will you touch my head?
>> What
>> will you touch your head?
>> Yes.
>> Show me where it is, please.
>> Right here.
>> All right.
I have permission.
Resist.
Heal, heal, heal. We ask for a miracle
in thy name, oh Lord
Jesus Christ, most high. Please crash
yourself. Please crush yourself. Thank
you.
>> Thank you.
>> Sign this.
>> Yeah.
Let's have the arm.
Her uh vascular disorder in a skull is
better. There's this. All right.
>> Hi. I just wanted to hold your hand and
have my picture taken.
>> You're a celebrity.
>> Can I hold your hand, too?
Oh, wait. Let me go.
>> My god, you got cold hands. Holy smokes.
>> Well, you've been holding ice cubes.
>> Yeah, your hands are cold.
>> Your hands are cold.
>> Warm heart, I hope.
>> Oh, yes. That's what they say. Cold
hands, warm heart.
Want to make sure she wasn't nipping on
my Genji's water.
You nip on this and bye-bye.
I want to put it where I'm not going to
forget it.
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. I don't have a
question. I just want to express my
deepest gratitude for your teachings and
have a picture taken with you and Susan.
>> Thank you.
>> I can't hear what she said.
>> That's okay.
>> This was picture taken.
>> Thank you.
>> Oh, okay. Picture
smile.
>> Oh, thank you.
Wow.
>> Well, we've had a wonderful day.
>> These all pictures of myself.
>> Is that me?
>> Yeah. Isn't he a handsome guy?
>> I never paid attention to him.
>> These are all the same guy.
>> Yep.
>> I'll be darned.
Well,
>> go ahead.
>> I'm very grateful for this opportunity.
Thank you. Um, I'd like to hold your
hand um if possible. Um, silent
transmission and your blessing, please.
>> Hold your hand for a silence
transmission
>> and a blessing.
>> That's greedy, isn't it?
He said, "That's creepy.
>> I'm trying to get all areas covered."
So,
>> are these all your books?
>> No, these are someone else's.
>> Oh, okay.
>> I have all your books at home.
>> Well, have her come around the here. One
second. clear. Just sign that
anywhere.
>> I don't know if I can see. I can't see
what I'm doing.
Oh, God can see where it is.
>> Okay.
>> Yes, madam.
>> She's gonna hold your hand. She wants to
hold your hand. You have to come over
here.
>> Oh man, what cold hands. Holy cats. Or
have you been sitting on a refrigerator?
Thank you, honey.
Warm hands. Think of warmth flowing into
your hands.
Think of God's love as a warm toaster
oven
warming and toasting these cold little
fingers.
Good gosh. All right.
>> Sure.
>> Yeah. I feel our hands. to tell me is it
me or there
>> greedy but um I wonder if you can um
just calibrate if it's in the highest
good for me to remain at um the sang
that I belong to
>> the what
>> the sang the spiritual group that I
belong yeah that I've been
>> she wants to know if she should remain
with the saying a spiritual group that
she belongs to
>> uh let's see we have permission to ask
this it's in her highest good to remain
with her spiritual group. Resist.
Yep.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> Hello. I uh just would like to request a
blessing and to hold your hand.
>> A blessing? What type of blessing?
>> Blessing for me.
God bless you, sweetheart.
>> Thank you.
>> Are her hands cold, too?
>> Her hands are not cold, though.
>> No, her hands are cold.
>> No, her hands are warm. The other people
I don't know where they must have been
sitting on an ice cube.
>> Uhhuh.
Dr. Hopkins, here we are. Yes.
>> Thank you. First of all, just want to
say thank you for sharing the gift that
you have with with all of us. It means a
lot to me.
>> I got to hear what you say.
>> My question is about raising levels of
consciousness. Levels of consciousness.
>> Sit back just a little bit because
that'll pick you up.
>> Okay.
Sometimes when I'm listening to a
beautiful piece of music or I'm
performing a beautiful piece of music or
I'm praying to God, I feel this very
intense feelings of love and bliss. I'm
wondering if when I feel those kinds of
feelings if that is raising my
consciousness level and if so if it is
just a temporary
rise of a consciousness level or is that
just feeling
>> what
>> she wants to know if whenever she
listens to a beautiful piece of music
she feels her you know the consciousness
level rising within her
>> and is it just temporary or is it
actually
>> Yeah it's temporary yeah
>> but but is Is it actually rising? Is it
actually raising my
>> You're the one that just told me that it
is.
>> And so praying and listening to music
raises consciousness level.
>> So would praying and listening to music
raise your consciousness level.
>> Sure.
>> Okay.
>> People have been doing that for
thousands of years.
>> And it would that be the way that
someone would be able to write a work
that calibrates higher than they
themselves calibrate?
Maybe I didn't hear it right. Did you
say
>> if someone if someone has a very high
experience
um it's possible that they can write a
work about that and it would calibrate
quite high. Um
on the other end if they can't live walk
the walk or talk the talk then they will
not remain there in that in that area.
>> Okay.
>> Of Yeah. Thank you.
>> You have to be loving towards all beings
and not think negatively
of those fumbling idiots.
>> So, keeping
>> Well, that's another way of putting it.
>> Thank you. Thank you very much. May I
have my question?
>> Compassion towards all of life in all of
its expressions.
Thank you.
>> Yes.
Hi
sign.
>> Yes.
>> Hello. How are you?
I like to ask about if there's such
thing as original sin.
>> Is there such a thing as original sin?
>> I don't know anything about original
sin, sweetheart. That's some kind of
religious belief system.
>> I mean, there was nobody around. So
where would the sin originate from?
I don't know.
>> And then he she would like your
blessing.
>> That's something different. God bless
you.
>> Thank you.
>> Well, that was a good question.
>> Original sin is a whole big
dissertation.
Take me an hour to explain it all.
What did you say? Is somebody here?
>> Hello.
Thank you for your work. It's helped me
a lot personally and professionally. Um,
thank you for getting him to do it.
Um,
I'm I'm a psychiatrist in Southwest
Georgia and I know you've already spoken
some about practices today, but I wanted
to ask you if you had any uh spiritual
or practical advice. Uh, I've still got
a lot of years ahead of me, assuming the
world doesn't end today, and it's after
3:00, so I think it's probably not going
to end. Um what uh do you have any
suggestions uh for someone practicing in
psychiatry? Now
>> you're practicing psychiatry.
You need God's help run the clock.
>> I agree.
>> No, I was always thankful
uh to be a psychiatrist because it was a
greater dimension than just the physical
body. I can include the person in their
personhood
and appreciate
them as a being. You know what I mean?
>> And I had some wonderfully interesting
patients over the years
and uh in which we had a very positive
transference and counter transference.
I would look forward to seeing them. And
one of them asked me for a picture of
myself to hang on the wall because every
time he looked at it, he felt better.
And a couple of patients were very old
and they'd been with me for many years
and I did not retire until they died.
You know, I thought I'll stay with them
to the end. Yeah.
>> Thank you.
But each of the patients I had I loved.
Not in a personal way,
but I loved each and every one.
>> See that?
potato chips.
>> No.
>> What doc doesn't tell you is that a lot
of the patients couldn't afford the fees
and he would see them for coffee.
>> Free coffee. No, they bring me free
coffee.
>> They would bring him coffee for the
bill. You bring me coffee and I'll take
care of you.
>> I didn't have have to have to buy coffee
for a year.
>> Did we sign all these? Oh,
>> would
>> Well, if they didn't have money, I'd say
I'd see them for coffee.
>> Yeah. Hi.
>> Thanks for being my teacher.
We have a study group that meets at our
house.
>> Where?
>> A study group that he he lives in
Planto, Texas. And he has a study group.
>> Plano.
>> That meets at his house.
>> Oh yes, we have a lot of people from
Plano. Yes. Uhhuh.
>> We ask for your blessings.
>> Yes. God bless you.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah. We got a number of you from Plano.
>> How many people do we have in our study
group?
>> It varies between
>> We had 15 in the beginning then it goes
up and down.
>> Oh yeah. Mhm. Oh yes. Oh yeah.
>> It's a great blessing. Your teaching is
so wonderful.
>> Yes. Plus
>> the path is long. So we ask for your
continued blessings.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Thank you.
>> May we have a picture?
>> Oh, of course. All right.
>> Photo.
>> Oh. Oh, yes.
>> Touch your hand. Yes.
>> Thank you.
>> Are you okay?
>> Bless my arm, please.
Bless my arm.
Dear God, I ask for thy blessing,
through thy love. Amen. Mhm. Yeah.
I ask for your blessing.
>> She asked for your blessing.
>> God bless you.
>> I I have a question.
>> Yes.
>> Um please me a phrase to meditate.
Please me a phrase to meditation
meditate on specific to me that I can
contemplate all my life.
>> What
>> she wants a mantra that she can use
throughout her life and we don't do
that.
>> I've never done that. No.
Um
>> I have never done that. No.
>> No.
>> Do something else. Pray.
>> So So how what would she do? What type
what can she do to um that would help
her in her meditation?
>> Why don't she just meditate
and pray? Why don't you just pray and
meditate?
Just pray and meditate. You don't have
to do something special, you know, dress
up or stand on your head or do a dance
or anything. Just pray and meditate.
Dear God, this and that and the other
thing. Yeah.
>> It's like you talk to God on your mind.
All right.
>> Okay.
>> Jeez.
>> All right. So, so what you want her to
do is just um meditate and then in her
mind ask
>> for the blessings or whatever it is that
she wants uh
>> Uhhuh.
>> God to help her with.
>> Tell God what you want. Yes. And what
the problem is and confide in confide in
God. Yes.
>> This is what I think. This is what I
worry about. And I pray that it will be
okay and whatever you want.
But there's doesn't have to be anything
special to do just that.
>> No, usually you wait till something
arises that you start doing that. But
then after a while you get to be in a
habit. Most people pray in the morning
when they get up and they pray at night
when they go to bed. Do you do that?
>> Do you do that?
>> She she has she has
>> what
>> she has she's having a language problem
here.
>> Yeah.
>> So
>> you pray in the morning.
>> She says to pray in the morning. Yes.
>> And then pray at night.
>> Yeah.
>> So this would help you.
>> You have to talk slow because she can't
understand. Um this would help you in
your meditation. So if you
>> get up in the morning and you and you
pray and meditate say for 20 minutes and
then pray and meditate say at night for
20 minutes that this would help you in
on your path.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay. Oh, my nephew is born just today.
>> So, could you uh could you blessing my
nephew and his family?
>> Oh, her she has is it your brother or
sister?
>> My my younger sister, younger brother.
Younger brother.
>> Um her brother just had a baby today.
So, can you bless her nephew?
>> No.
>> Can you can you send a blessing their
way?
>> The way of whom?
>> Of her new nephew. She has a new
>> A new nephew. I can't even handle the
people next door. And you want a new
nephew?
Complete stranger. Meaningless to me.
A good idea. Maybe
>> uh email us a picture. We'll have him
bless it.
>> Oh, she has a picture.
>> Oh, good.
>> Today. Today for
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Fine.
>> He's adorable. Look.
Oh, that is bless.
>> God bless this little baby.
>> Amen.
>> Thank you.
>> Now that's a baby.
>> Thank you. Take a picture, please.
>> Yeah.
>> That was a little little tiny thing.
>> Yes.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
>> Thank you.
>> Oops.
>> Bless that and pray for it. Okay. Thank
you, honey. My arm
pain and weakness. I never had it
before.
A we ask for thy blessing on this left
arm. Amen. Okay. That's your miracle,
God. Amen. Yes.
>> Uh, I'd like to thank you for all of
your inspiration and I'd like to have a
blessing and a picture.
>> And she'd like what?
>> Blessing and a picture.
>> You okay? And cracker jack too.
I like the kid. Everybody keep them all
laughing.
Keep laughing.
>> Yeah. Uhhuh.
>> Thank you.
Mhm.
Hello.
>> Hi. We just want to say how deeply
grateful we are for your work and your
presence
and we love you very much.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Thank you very much. Thank you very much
for all you're doing for the population.
It's so great.
>> God bless you. God bless you.
>> Yes.
>> Touch your hand.
>> Yes. Indeed. Uhhuh.
Uhhuh.
God bless you.
Are you doing anything?
>> Are you doing anything?
>> I think so.
>> Hi.
>> I I do have a question for you. Um, do
you have to go to church to worship God?
>> Do you have to go to church to worship
God?
>> To work with God?
>> To worship God? No, but it's an
embellishment.
It's an indication of the degree of
sincerity.
And in to to a certain degree, you're
like imploring divinity
through your own dedication and effort.
>> Thank you.
>> We recently went to a lovely church for
a very formal occasion.
There were a thousand people at the
church and two wonderful
uh bishops, two bishops. We had a
wonderful time with the bishops and with
the congregation and with the beautiful
cathedral
and the stained glass windows and the
totality of the occasion.
Yeah.
>> Thank you. Can I have your picture, too?
>> Oh, yes.
and
>> Oh, it is.
>> Oh, okay. Gary and Marie Shber,
>> what?
>> They're up in uh DC.
>> BC.
>> BC. Up in British Columbia.
>> Gary and Marie Schneider. They said to
>> They were in PA and they met at our
group.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> Way back when we were at Creative Life
Center.
>> Oh. Oh.
>> And they married.
We get emails from everyone.
>> Yeah. You better be careful who you
start coming to these meetings single,
next thing you know you're married.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> I think I'll be here in September.
>> Hi.
>> Hi, Susan. Hi, Dr.
>> Yes. Hi. Um, first I wanted to say with
what you said about the cookies in the
cookie store that um, the cookie monster
in me is in heaven today. So the cookie
monster
>> um, I was here in January and told you
that I am will be moving very soon to
India.
>> To India?
>> India. I'm going to be staying at Ramana
Maharish.
>> South of Ohio, huh?
>> A little bit. Yeah, a little west.
>> You're going to be staying where?
>> At Ramana Maharishi's ashram.
>> Oh yeah. and very possibly will have an
opportunity to uh serve as a missionary
with Mother Teresa's organization. So
that leads to a question and a blessing.
Um
>> question.
>> The question would be as far as vows,
there are vows which would be asked of
me if I were to join the missionary.
>> Yes.
>> Um poverty, chastity, obedience, and
wholehearted service to the poorest of
the poor.
>> Yeah.
>> Is there anything wrong with taking
those vows?
I mean in the highest good it's
altruistic. Another friend made a vow.
Altruistic.
>> So it's altruistic. So what is the
question?
>> Is there is that okay to take those
vows? I know you've said at times I
think to take vows you know don't take
vows.
>> Oh I see what you're saying. Okay. It
would be uh appropriate for him to take
these vows with
ashram. Is this
>> for you at this time? The answer is yes.
>> Okay. Um Mhm.
>> Oh. Uh, since this is or could be the
last time I get to be in your presence
based on what you said earlier today
too, would it be okay if first you said
to tip Jesus on the way? Um, give you a
little tip and um
since it's my tip to Jesus to you.
It's not much. I've got
>> he passes on the root of all evil to me
and then
>> but it's in God we trust right
>> but it says in God
>> maybe
>> I don't know
>> no that's very nice of you I have a
certain place I put such things yes
>> would it be okay if I look into your
eyes and hold your hand possibly one
last time in this lifetime to see
divinity reflecting back. He wants to
hold your hand and get a blessing from
you as he takes his journey onto life
onward into
>> his journey onward where
>> well
>> it's going to India and maybe
>> to Ramano Mahari's Ashra
>> right and maybe working with Mother
Teresa's Ashra
>> I've I've had some in over the last year
some very high
>> spiritual idealist come over here come
over here
>> you're a sp spiritual idealist Okay. And
may your dreams come true. Okay. God
bless you. He's got cold hands, too. I
get cold hands.
>> Cold hands. That gets his cold hands in.
>> Must be the meeting hall.
>> Well, we're up here on stage and it's
warm.
>> Okay, that's very good.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. Hello.
>> I just want to wish you guys much
happiness and many, many blessings.
>> Um, my question is, what's the
difference between an archangel and an
angel? And why an archangel calibrates
so much higher than Jesus?
>> Well, the question is obvious.
There's a hierarchy. Correct?
>> Is that correct?
>> Yes. Yes. So obviously
a bishop would be higher than a
clergyman and a cardinal would be higher
than a bishop.
So I guess and the pope would be higher
than a cardinal.
It's just rank and order
as a human custom, you know.
>> Okay.
And then I was going to ask you if you
could bless these for my four children
and bless this book. I never read any of
your books, but I know all about them
because I have a dear friend that would
read them to me and then explain them to
me.
>> To me, they're very hard reading.
>> And maybe you could put a little spell
on this that I could read this myself.
>> I don't get what she's asking.
>> She wants you to bless the
>> the uh
>> the what? the little
bracelets for her children and and bless
the book.
Oops. We got to get them all in there.
Here.
Oh, that's
>> I don't know how we could do this any
>> Oh, no, no, no. You don't sign it. Just
bless. Just put your hand on here and
bless.
>> Oh, God bless these beads in thy name.
Oh, Lord. Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Because those are going to your children
and then the book.
>> I see. Yes. Okay.
>> Okay. Now I get what you're saying. Yes.
Bum bum bum.
>> He does that in our bird now.
>> Our bird goes bump bum bum.
>> Thank you.
>> Yes.
B.
>> Yeah. My African gray parrot says bump
the bum bum bum bum bum.
Welcome.
>> That's very pretty.
>> Hi.
>> Yes.
Thank you, honey.
>> Hi. Uh my name is Mary and I really just
um wanted to thank you for the teachings
and the way they've changed my life. And
I really just wanted to spend a few
moments in your presence. And I want to
give you both a hug, but I know that
that's not really allowed. So, um could
I get a hug from you and a blessing from
you? Is that
>> just come over here and we'll
>> Yeah. Hold your hand.
>> Okay.
Oh, God bless you, sweetheart. God bless
you. And thank you, beautiful.
>> Thank you.
>> Those are indeed beautiful.
>> Oh, here. Did you want him sign?
>> Okay, I did it. Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you very very much.
Okay.
Um, did you want to It's It's 4:00 and
we have to stop at 4:30. So, we can go
another 15 minutes and then do our
ending if you want.
>> All right. 20 minutes, whatever.
>> Yeah.
>> This arm is feeling better.
>> Oh, good.
Hello doctor.
>> Hello.
>> Hello Susan.
>> Um,
every time I It's my fourth time here
and every time I think I'm going to ask
you a question, I look into your eyes. I
have no question for you.
>> I want to say thank you. And I
>> and
dur during the lecture you said you
liked coffee ice cream and then I heard
toffee ice cream. So, I got you both.
>> Be careful what you have.
>> And it says, and I got one. It's caramel
sutra. I'm not
>> Oh, he loves that.
>> Caramel Sutra. And
>> Oh, truly wonderful. Yeah.
>> And on on one of your videos, um, you
you in handling my major crisis, you
said that you were making chicken livers
for your cat, and then, uh, you
transcended the belief system about how
you can't eat chicken livers. Well, I
got you chicken livers, too.
>> There's And there's a lot of ice in
here, and I'm willing to carry it to
your car, to your house. I will cook the
livers.
>> I will scoop the ice. take it to the car
and we will take it home this evening.
>> Thank you very much.
>> That's so sweet of you.
>> Is it possible to
>> It is indeed to come and just touch you
both.
>> You come right over.
>> Is that okay?
>> That's so sweet that you thought of the
ice cream.
>> We'd have to have somebody show him
where to put it. I don't know where to
put it.
>> He He wants the
>> I don't know where to put it.
>> What?
>> It's in a We're okay. It's in a cooler
chest.
>> All right. His hands are very cold.
>> He's been handling ice cream.
>> Ice cold hands.
>> God bless you.
>> I remember you.
G. You touch that.
>> One day. My my father told me he fell
asleep. And when he fell asleep, he
didn't realize it, but his hand was like
this. Anyway, he woke up in the middle
of the night and he felt this ice cold
hand around his throat.
He was afraid to move for 20 minutes.
It was his own hand.
>> Hi doctor.
>> Hi Dr. Hawkins and Suzan. I'm very happy
to see you.
I wanted to give you a present for you.
It's money from 10 countries.
It's what?
>> Money from 10 countries.
>> Yes.
>> And all countries are calibrated over
300.
>> Oh, good.
>> Yes.
>> Oh, thank you.
>> This is u money from different countries
and they all calibrate over 300. So
they're different denominations of
money.
>> They come from all these different
countries.
>> Oh, I see. Yes. Currency of the
different countries. Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> So colorful.
>> Oh
>> wow. Just beautiful.
>> Different currency. Yes. A beautiful
beautiful works of art.
>> They are. Thank you so much.
>> I love beautiful works of art with a
thousand in front of them.
>> Thank you. That was a very nice gift.
Thank you. And may I ask you you for
blessing me on my way?
>> Yes. He wants a blessing for his way.
>> For what?
>> You come over here and we'll bless you.
>> Blessing for what?
>> For along the way. He wants a blessing
for him on his way. You know,
>> God bless you on your way.
>> I don't know what on your way means.
God bless you on your way. Whatever that
means.
>> He's right here.
>> On your way. There he is. God bless you.
All right. I know what you mean.
Okay. Yeah.
>> There. Good. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Where's my ice cream?
>> Hi.
I want to thank you for all your help.
You've helped me a lot. And I would like
to ask your blessing for our spiritual
group and our teacher.
>> Oh, where is your spiritual group?
>> It's in Rochester, New York.
>> Rochester. Oh, yes.
>> Well, God bless you. What kind of
spiritual work do you do?
>> We study the course in miracles. Or I
should let her talk. She's teacher.
>> We We've been working on the course of
miracles for quite a few years.
>> Yeah, that's great.
>> Including your work in it, too. What's
our lesson for today again?
>> What is your lesson for the day?
>> We forgot.
>> Got it.
>> No, there is there is no love but God's.
>> Ah, it's perfect but God's.
>> Okay. Yeah, that's a good way. Uh I
believe in the course of miracles as a
way of life.
every day you're dedicated to some
spiritual principle
and uh I think it's a wonderful addition
to one's life.
>> Thank you. Can we have our bless
>> right?
>> Okay. See, the women want you.
>> Oh, the women. They're after me again.
>> Thank you.
>> Now they're after my heart.
>> Oh, thank you.
>> Bless you. Came a long way.
>> Okay, I'm going to
go to
>> used to be there after my little body.
Oh god,
>> I just can't keep a straight face when
he says that.
>> Dr. Hawkins.
>> Yeah.
>> Hi,
>> I'm Pepe.
>> Uh I'm on the final run and uh I wrote
my question down just to be a little bit
more concise.
>> All right. uh it's the issue of
communication between the uh physical
brain uh where consciousness and the
athetheric brain when one is just
awakened and trying to refunction again
in the world via consciousness. Uh my
question is is this information now
available from an attractive field to a
newly awakened non-person at a more
rapid pace than let's say then might
have that it took you it took you
several years and is now you know more
people have been enlightened and and and
now is this available at a more rapid
pace. I'm 73 years old. If it happens to
me
I don't have all the time in the world
to to to wait that long if I can't if I
have to refunction again.
What's his question? He wants he wants
to know it is is um when you are
when you are in the final run uh is and
you know
there is a time when
you have to reawaken themselves and so
he's wondering is there a faster way of
doing that or
>> no no you have to refunction in the
world again
>> when you have to go into function in the
world again after you've been to a very
high state.
>> Yes. What about
>> a faster way of that happening
>> faster?
>> Well, the the communications between
consciousness uh the atheric brain and
the human brain in order to refunction
again since the mind has gone silent.
>> No, it all it all integrates itself. it
integrates itself and since that
information is now in an attractive
field, it's available via you and maybe
other folks. Is it is it available at a
more rapid pace now? It's not like we're
breaking new ground. In other words,
>> no, it moves at its own rate and uh
there's karmic influences that determine
many things.
>> Karmic.
>> Yeah.
>> So, it's an individual thing.
>> Some people got it already.
Other people years go by and they're
still working on it.
Fine.
>> So, it's a matter of readiness and uh
karmic propensity
and uh divine favor.
>> Divine favor.
>> God seems to like some people better
than others.
I looked at this guy says, "I don't
know, Howard. There's just something
about you that pisses me off.
>> Hopefully, I've been a good boy.
I hope I'm not one of those.
>> Thanks very much.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you. Thank you. Okay.
>> Thank goodness God has a sense of humor.
>> That's right.
>> Yeah.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Hello.
>> It's great to see you again. It's been a
while since I've asked a question and I
want to ask a question about marriage.
I have a boyfriend that wants to get
married real bad and I uh sometimes do
and I sometimes don't. So, I don't know
what to do.
>> What is her problem?
>> Her problem is she doesn't know whether
to get married or not get married.
>> Oh, that's simple. Yeah, good.
>> Don't do anything about it. Just leave
it alone.
>> Don't do anything about it. What?
>> No. No.
>> You'll get the answer eventually
>> in this lifetime.
>> Is this guy poor, mean, and ugly?
>> No. He's beautiful and sweet.
>> What is your problem?
>> Uh commitment.
>> Oh, no. You're too infantile to get
involved in a marriage.
Too infantile.
>> Yes.
>> I'm too infantile.
>> Oh, okay.
>> You're not even old enough to make an
adult commitment.
>> Mhm.
>> That's like you're not really out of the
juvenile years yet.
>> Uh-huh.
>> So then I shouldn't get married then if
I'm in
>> Well, you better wait till you're old
enough to make a commitment.
>> All right.
Whatever that means, I'll take it.
>> Well, it means I love you and accept you
as my adorable, sweet wife, and I want
to live with you and be with you. Amen.
>> Oh, okay.
>> Isn't that easy?
>> Yeah, that's easy.
>> There you go.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Can I just uh shake your hand?
>> Means some you love somebody enough that
you want to be with them,
>> you know, to the exclusion of others.
Thank you.
>> Yeah, that's an easy one.
>> The last one.
>> Yeah,
>> this will be the last one and then we're
gonna
>> Yeah, it's not an easy one because of
the incapacity to make that kind of a
commitment. Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Hi. Um, we're from the Cleveland Group.
>> The Cleveland Group.
>> Cleveland.
>> Cleveland, Ohio. Ohio. We spoke.
>> Oh, he ho.
Yes.
>> They send their love and thanks
and we ask you to bless us.
>> God bless you.
>> Thank you.
>> And uh could we have a handshake and a
picture?
>> You come right over here.
>> What you want?
>> Handshake and picture.
>> Okay.
Have we been in Cleveland?
>> Yep.
>> Oh. Oh, we have.
>> Thank you. We've been everywhere. So, we
must have been in Cleveland.
>> Thank you.
>> I don't think that worked.
>> Yeah, you got the first.
>> There it goes.
>> Thank you.
>> We were just looking at it the other day
and
>> we've spoken in n 90 cities.
90 cities.
That's a lot of moving around.
A lot of airports.
A lot of bus terminals.
>> Okay.
>> Yes.
>> We can say goodbye.
>> Okay. God bless us all.
>> Here. You want your cake?
>> Uh,
dear God, we give thanks.
God bless you all. We give you deepest
thanks in the name of God Almighty. We
bless you and thank you and we pray for
you now and forever. Amen.
Take a picture of you. Just
>> where?
>> Just right here.
Is this where we jump off the cliff
here?
>> No, it's not that way.
>> I just thought we'd bring you up a
little way so they can get some photos.
>> Oh, photos. Okay.
I I give thanks to almighty God for all
of you here
for you are my blessing
for which I am very grateful.
I am blessed by your presence
and uplifted by your goodwill.
And I pray that that intention flows
back and uplifts everyone here.
I guess it wasn't the end of the world
today after all.
I thought, "Hell, honey, it's going to
be a big day. It's going to be the end
of the world today. Kaboom.
>> Oh, well,
we're all still here. What can you do?
>> Oh, enjoy your ice cream. Right.
>> Here it comes.
>> Oh, look at that. They all look green.
Everybody looks green on that side of
the room.
>> The light.
>> I thought these were the green people.
You have to be very serious about life.
As you can tell by my demeanor,
life is a grim tough business and you
got to really knuckle down and not fool
around. You know what I'm saying?
No frivvality, please.
Mwah.
Thank you again. God bless you. Amen.
Gave me excuse to get kissed again.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> I know a lot of you. How many of you
have come from other countries? How many
of from other countries?
Wow.
>> Wow. Thank you so much.
>> Thank you.
>> Um, we're trying to put our books up on
Amazon so you can download them now uh
onto Kindle so we don't have to do all
the shipping for you that are out of
country. So, we're trying to put all the
books up on that.
>> Safe travel.
>> Hopefully, we're also going to get some
of our DVDs up there eventually so you
can download them directly from
>> Safe Travel. Yeah,
>> we're trying to save you on all your
shipping charges. So hopefully we'll get
that done in the next year.
>> Yes.
>> All right. Come on, sweetheart.
Helpless.
>> Help. Help.
>> Help.
Hallelujah.
Amen. Gloral.