beloved doctor and susan thank you for letting us say goodbye to you by expressing a gratitude
from our hearts i want to begin with the tribute to you from someone who couldn't be here today
but who loves you very much michael beckwith michael beckwith is the founder of the agape
international spiritual center here is his tribute to you it is my joy david to speak directly to you
on this extraordinary occasion of your last public appearance while you may think that you are
disappearing from the public eye the energy frequency of your love compassion and wisdom
remains in every heart you have touched throughout these
many years and certainly that includes my own and that of my spiritual community
you are a cosmic blessing on the planet a beneficial presence whose imprint is deep
and eternal i love you brother i love you god bless god bless michael beckwith god bless you
brother and now we have a ceremonial tribute from south korea they're going to do a special
what honey
oh boy
that's terrific
isn't that something
thank you so much i'm greatly honored that's beautiful thank you i'm greatly honored
god bless you ladies thank you very much are they from korea thank you ladies then the buddha called
and andah and said to him it may be ananda that after my passing away you might think gone is the utterance
of our master we have no master anymore but you should not think so ananda for the doctrine
and discipline which i've taught you and prescribed to you will be your master after my death
now amongst i exhort to you exhort you
all compounded things are subject to decay work for your salvation with honestness
these were the buddha's last words but for the presence of saints on earth the world
would burn to death we pray for you so long as we live we live in your remembrance
and on our death be blessed with your vision god bless his three hearts god bless this react
thank you i don't want to lose this stuff water from the ganges river as everybody
knows the ganges river is blessed and calibrates extremely high what is the
caliber that i forget 700 over 500 600 700 it calibrates at 700
ganges river calibrates at 700 because of the sacredness of its dedication thank you
on behalf of all the followers of dr david hawkins teachings from india
dr hawkins teachings have touched the beginners in the spirituality starting from the beginners
in the spirituality up to the scholars who spend years in studying the scriptures in
sunday
and then they become very exponents when we have distributed the books of dr hawkins
to the beginners they felt that it has cleared many of their spiritual doubts and it has inspired
them touched them and transformed them equally so when these books have been given to the scholars
who had spent years in the research in spirituality they also felt that it has touched and transformed
them and whatever they have learned all these years in their spiritual research they could find
the same teachings in dr david hawkins books and they felt touched and transformed what we have
done is we have integrated dr hawkins teachings along with the indian scriptures and then we have
spread this message to many youngsters and adults and old people alike and all of them have been
uplifted and greatly benefited by dr hawkins teachings which makes the scriptural understanding
much more simple much more easier and more clear so on behalf of all the followers i offer humble
prostrations and respects to dr david hawkins for making a great difference in all of our lives and
may your teachings be with us forever because we have already integrated them into our regular
satsangs and spiritual discourses and workshops and so on and so forth
and seminars and so on and so forth so we continue to feel your presence
and we continue to feel your blessings hario god bless you god bless you god bless you
god bless you god bless you god bless you god bless you god bless you god bless you
the water from the ganges as everyone here knows calibrates extremely high calibrates at 700
that's incredible incredible here's march brit it is such a great honor to be here with you today
dr david hawkins i'm dr marge britt i'm the minister senior minister of unity in tuxton california where
you came to speak at our center in 2003 you have been one of the most profound spiritual teachers
in christians day in the church you have been one of the most profound spiritual teachers in christians day
of my entire life, and your teachings from the moment that I found them have impacted
the teachings that I do in Unity and beyond.
As the vice president of our international seminary, I'm also aware of the impact that
you've had worldwide.
One of my fondest memories of you is when you came to Unity Village to meet with students
and with the hierarchy of Unity School of Christianity.
We were between meetings, going from meeting with the students to a meeting with the hierarchy,
walking quickly to get to the next meeting, and suddenly you disappeared.
Everyone looked around to try to find you, and we located you a few moments later.
In the rose garden, smelling the roses.
You have always brought beauty and joy.
Your energy, your consciousness, your vibration was a match for Unity, and is a match for
New Thought, and is a match for Christianity, and I cannot thank you enough for what you
have done.
You have given, in the world, how you have made the teachings of Jesus and other master
teachers literally come alive through your very being and your very consciousness, and
I will be eternally grateful for you and for Susan, who said to you, you must write, and
you must teach.
Thank you so much.
Yes.
Thank you.
Let me see you, I just don't remember who you are.
Oh, there you are.
Yes, I see you now, honey.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Huh?
He got me.
Call the police.
Yes.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins and Susan.
I'm from South Africa.
We have a few students from South Africa here.
Will you please stand up?
South Africa.
There's more students back at home, and your work is spreading slowly but surely, and I
just want to thank you from the bottom of my heart for everything that you've done for me.
Thank you.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
Thank you, thank you, Dr. Hawkins.
Thank you for everything you've given us and all of mankind.
Thank you very much.
Thank you, Lord.
Amen.
Hi, Doc.
I'm from the Channel Islands in the United Kingdom.
He's from where?
Channel Islands.
The Channel Islands in the United Kingdom.
Oh, the Channel Islands.
Yes, yes.
On behalf of the United Kingdom, would all the students from the United Kingdom like
to stand up?
What do they say, honey?
Yeah.
We'd like to say thank you and your work will live on in our hearts and it is a pleasure to live your truth. Amen. God bless.
Hello Dr. Hawkins, hello Susan. We are coming from Germany and also on behalf of all the German Dr. Hawkins students and the rest of the European students, we'd like to say thank you very much for all you have done for us.
You have changed our life and we are grateful beyond words. Maybe all the European students would like to stand up now and thank our teacher.
Guten Abend. Danke.
I work in the medical field and I've had the opportunity to see how much these ideas can help patients who are working on different issues.
And there's so many ways, but of them all, I think the main help they've given...
What they've got is to be introduced to the idea that the ego comes from the animal level, as so many are locked in guilt, self-hatred and judgment.
And when it's explained to them that the ego comes from the animal, that it's a very good animal, it's very good at what it does, there's no need to hate it or to destroy it, but to understand it and just disengage from it has been most helpful, probably of all that I've done with them over time.
And also they can make friends with their little animal, and I tell them that Dr. Hawkins loves talking to his little teddy bear, and he'll say to it, they cut you off in traffic, of course they should be punished.
So it softens it for them so much. Sometimes they go on and buy books and DVDs to study further, and then I know they're going to learn in a hundred different ways that all healing is possible.
For one reason only, the love of God. So on their behalf, and mine too, Dr. Hawkins, thank you so much for your life's work and for all you've given us. Thank you.
Thank you.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins. Hello, everyone. I was asked to speak briefly on what I witness as a psychotherapist, so I thought I'd ask all psychotherapists to please stand up.
Now if all psychotherapy patients...
If all psychotherapy patients can please stand up.
You know, there's so many things to say, but as a therapist, Dr. Hawkins, you give such reverence and respect for the full spectrum of physical, mental, spiritual.
So I can say as a therapist, so many patients have benefited from simply seeing a psychiatrist and getting on medication, and many more have benefited from availing themselves of 12-steps work and spiritual work.
One thing I'd just like to add is that Dr. Hawkins often says, of course, it's not where you are as a clinician, it's where they are.
And I've found your work profound in helping me to meet clients where they are.
And really the simple things, using humor.
I've basically pretended like every joke you've ever said is mine.
And I crack your jokes in sessions all the time.
And you also say, Dr. Hawkins...
That deep down what we all want is a recognition of what we truly are.
And I feel like as a therapist, I'm a witness to the truth of truth.
And that love really does heal.
And that we just really need to step back and allow love to do what love does.
So thank you, Dr. Hawkins.
God bless you.
Dr. Hawkins, we're here representing all the families who are raising children.
And doing the work.
I want to thank you.
And one teaching that's been very beneficial to me is knowing that all that I have to do is be the very best wife that I can be.
And be the very best mother that I can be.
And that is uplifting mankind.
Thank you.
Thank you for the truth.
And so parenting with Dr. Hawkins' work has meant...
It has meant for us that the kids never ask us to go on any vacation, but instead to go to the Buddha relics.
It has also meant that they always remind us to forgive everybody whenever they get in trouble.
And more than anything, it has taught us to practice unconditional lovingness and to see divinity in everything.
Not just on the isolated mountaintop.
Dr. Hawkins said one time...
That there is no greater gift to give to mankind than to perfect this state.
And the greatest gift we have received is to be allowed to witness that.
Thank you very much.
Namaste, Dr. Hawkins, Susan, and everyone at Veritas Pub.
In the Dubai environment of sophisticated slavery, no excuse, not even a lazy lie-in, prevents the members of the Two Friday and Society.
Dr. Hawkins, Susan, and everyone at Veritas Pub. In the Dubai environment of sophisticated slavery, no excuse, not even a lazy lie-in, prevents the members of the Two Friday and Society.
DR. HAWKINS
ART Cincinnati Press
The やة
The яв tä pencil
humility compassion and gradually waking up to the presence of God as the self we
thank God for illuminating our awareness in the form of our beloved teacher dr.
Hawkins and his teachings please everybody join me to the tune of he's a
jolly good fellow with the words we thank God we thank God for dr. Hawkins
so one two three we thank God for dr. Hawkins we thank God for dr. Hawkins we
thank God for dr. Hawkins and so say all of us thank you dr. Hawkins thank you
dr. Hawkins thank you dr. Hawkins thank you thank you thank you god bless you
durable adorable
God bless you, sweetheart.
God bless you.
Thank you so much.
My name is Luke Nakahara.
I am from Dallas, Texas.
And two and a half years ago, I was a broken, lost, and confused man.
And Karen O'Brien, a good friend of mine, was kind enough to introduce me to the teachings of you, Dr. Hawkins,
and to introduce me to Susan and the wonderful people at Veritas.
I just want to keep it brief, but I have dedicated my life to serving God,
to serving my fellow man, to serving myself, and to taking care of all the lovely creatures on this planet.
And thank you so much, Dr. Hawkins.
Hi, Doctor.
Hello, Susan.
I've been with no medication.
I used to suffer from depression, clinical depression, all my life.
And I read Power vs. Force, and I think there's a miracle.
I don't have to take any medication.
I don't suffer panic attacks anymore.
I jump, and I enjoy life, and I'm set free.
And I know that depression is a disease that we cannot see.
It's inside us, that hole that eats us up.
And I want to thank you for my freedom.
I want to thank you for my health and to show me the way out.
Thank you.
I'm a Canadian, and we have a bunch of Canadians here, Mexicans and Canadians.
Race, please.
Thank you, Doctor.
We love you.
We love you forever.
Dr. Hawkins and Susan, I come to thank you not by myself, for my wife,
for all the members of our church that are here today.
And, Lord, I come to thank you for my teaching from the consciousness of all mankind.
The only way I know how to do it,
is to express it from my heart, because words, language cannot do it.
So, Lord, I give you my heart.
Thank you so much.
Raise the mic a little.
I testify that you are the Lord, and I love you more than my own life.
Amen.
Just want to say, Dr. Hawkins, what a beautiful life.
What a beautiful life that you've shared with everyone.
And I think I speak for most, many people, all the friends that I know that follow your
teachings.
It's hard to separate where you begin and end in my life.
It's every single part of my life.
Every choice.
It's just there.
Because this life has been transformed due to being a part of this.
It is absolutely amazing, Grace.
And
Amazing Grace, how sweet the sound.
How sweet the sound.
That deed that's saved a wretch like me is blind.
But now that I'm saved, who can say
From a caver after a storm close to my house made in Minnesota, St. Paul.
Thank you.
Thank you so much, Dr. Hawkins and Susan.
It's, ah, maybe the last time that I see you physically.
But I meet you daily inside.
Thank you.
And my life has been changed in beautiful ways since I came to meet you.
So thank you so much.
Thanks.
Dr. Hawkins, my name is Marty.
I just want to say that the book Power vs. Force changed my life for the better,
as I suspect it did for many of the people sitting in this audience.
So I want to just express how profoundly grateful I am for it
and for your decision to teach it.
And I also want to thank Susan for the large body of work,
which will take me the rest of my life to study and comprehend.
So just thank you, and what a blessing you are to the world.
I don't really know where to begin.
The transformation from what felt like a weak, lost, messed-up inner child has been changed.
Your presence in my life has been.
The miraculous.
You taught me, among other things, how to focus, how to be strong, how not to crumble.
You taught me to be present, to walk through fears,
to walk right through the inner and debilitating emotional storms that once were overwhelming.
You have gifted me perseverance, but not the way that was previously thought.
Not.
As a dramatized endeavor, but you taught perseverance as in devotion and steadfastness
to the greatest love of all, and to facing life, and to learning to love.
You taught me how to love myself.
And above all, you taught me how to walk straight ahead, no matter what,
and allowing God to take care of the rest.
I love you, Dr. Hawkins.
You are my teacher forever, for eternity.
Thank you.
You are a treasured and beautiful lighthouse, and I am forever grateful.
Gloria in excelsis Deo, until we meet again.
Hi, my name is Brian Atkins from Austin, Texas.
This is some of the group from Austin, and there's several of us in Austin.
And Lubbock, where I'm originally from, and Dallas, and just all over Texas.
It's been amazing.
I just wanted to share the first time I came to Sedona to see Dr. Hawkins.
I'd seen you once before, but you came around and shook everyone's hand.
And as soon as you shook my hand, this incredible, loving energy just flooded through my heart.
And it just felt like it started expanding.
And, you know, I've been coming here as much as I possibly can for the past six years.
And each time I've had a huge shift like that.
And you've helped me through a lot of really rough troubles I had.
And you've helped me to love.
And most of all, you've helped me to not take myself so seriously and have humor.
But I just wanted to express my gratitude.
And I'm really going to miss being able to come here to see my teacher.
But I really feel now that you've also helped me find the teacher within.
And that's the most valuable gift I could ever have.
And I'm eternally grateful as well.
Thank you.
Dr. Hawkins, thanks so much.
When I first discovered your teachings, I was a person very devoted to the truth.
But I was following.
I was reading.
I was reading political works like Noam Chomsky.
Following that as truth, I was a very confused person.
I had had some spiritual experiences that I did not understand.
And just had a lot of emotional problems.
And over the course of the past six years, seven years, it's just been transformative.
And, you know, you've really given me, you know, like Ben said.
And, yeah.
I can't separate your teachings from my life.
And I've seen the impact they've had through me on my family, on my friends, on my work.
And, yeah.
You've given us the gift, me the gift of freedom to trust myself and to love myself.
And to live a life of service, helping others to experience joy.
And I thank you very much.
Thank you.
And I look forward to continuing being in the flock here in this life and hereafter.
Hi.
On behalf of Amsterdam, thank you very much.
On behalf of Iran, thank you very much for bringing clarity and happiness.
And making spirituality fun again.
Thank you.
Hello again, dear friend.
And my name in this lifetime is Stephanie, in an Atlantis that was Alta Hamir, and would
just like to wish you well.
And thank you for all you have done.
And I promise that I will continue to transmit your love frequencies everywhere that I travel.
Thank you.
Where is she from?
Here.
Okay.
South Korea, I think he said.
Thank you so much, Dr. Hawkins.
Yeah.
You've given me everything I've ever wanted for a whole lifetime.
Bless you.
Thank you.
Hello, I'm from Canada.
My testimony is two years ago, my best friend and I came to Conference on Peace, we kind
of bet a large, like a gamble on life because I believed in the truth that I heard.
So once we came here and had the effect, we went back home and we're very successful in
our training.
And we've both become very strong.
Um.
And we've got to share that love for the율 cars.
Thank you.
physical training with others
and a lot of
coherences come from that
thank you
pretty much just like he said
we kind of like
going on this path together like we're best
friends but
I'd just like to say thank you
Dr. Hawkins
and Susan thank you for your
divine energy
thank you for bringing sanity
into our family
it takes only one person
and through your divine guidance
I
have brought
peace and joy into our
family and my wife
loves you now
also thank you for
leaving love
and joy as a gift
to this creation
and to all of us
and
as a gratitude to your
work I would like
everyone to join
Mr. Hawkins and Susan
into a few moments
of stillness and peacefulness
thank you
Namaste Dr. Hawkins, Susan
my name is Judy
this is my husband Charlie
words could never express
my love and gratitude
for your work and for your presence
in this world
and there were two words that
you wrote in Power vs. Force
that changed my entire life
and those two words were
without exception
and it was how to walk on the path
of spiritual enlightenment
first you said you could only talk
from personal experience
the practice
the first was a desire
became intense
and then the practice of unconditional love
and forgiveness
without exception
and I thought
even my daughters and my children
you drive me crazy
and I kept hearing you say
without exception
that practice is a lifelong practice for me
I'm a psychotherapist
you've changed my entire practice
my entire life
and just as a regular person
on behalf of all of humanity
thank you so much for your gift
love you
Dr. Hawkins
my father was an Episcopal priest
and so I was raised in the Episcopal Church
and sang in choirs just like you did
but it wasn't until
I came into your presence
that I began to
take myself less seriously
and I just thank you
for your incredible lightness of being
for your sense of humor
for being the fool
in the divine court of our hearts
thank you
Dr. Hawkins
Susan
he who dwells in the protection of the Most High
shall abide under the shadow of the Almighty
thank you
Dr. Hawkins
thank you Susan
your work facilitated a profound spiritual experience
inside me
and from that I was able to stop drinking
and get into a program
and today I'm not the most loving person
but I'm going that way
I've got a God in my life
and what you're talking about
as far as God goes
I get to see and feel him in my life
and that's a result of everything you've given to me
and I'm eternally grateful
thank you
Doc
at age 18
I was kicked out of my house
I have five siblings
and mom and dad's still alive
I spent several decades
trying to overcome resentments and anger
and with some progress
until you know the next thing would happen
and I'd get kicked in the gut
and when I found your work
the map and your lectures
it became very obvious
that everyone's just doing the best that they can
and the transformation in my family
has just been phenomenal
I have the best relationship with my mom and dad
that I've ever had
in weekly communication or more
and with my siblings
and it's all gone just incredibly well
and I know I speak for many here
that you're a father figure to me
and have taught me a lot about strength
and courage and tenderness
and thank you very much
Dr. Hawkins
there are no words worthy of expression
of what I found within through your teachings
Doc and Susan
thank you so much
I spent
10 years of my life in addiction
over 5 years of that time
shooting heroin
in and out of jails, living on the street
by the mercy of the Lord
I was exposed to your teachings in rehab
a few years ago
I now live a sober life
full of joy
you brought me to Christ, you brought me to Krishna
you brought me to the rooms of recovery
and the steps of recovery
I wake up in the morning
grateful to be alive
I thought I was condemned to the life I was living
for the rest of my life
and I wake up a free man
by your grace
you saved my life
I want to thank you for your teachings
firstly they got me out of atheism
using logic
and reason
and also for about
25 years
I had a lot of panic and fear
which manifests itself
in irritable bowel syndrome
and using your
techniques that you
described in
handling major life crises
in about 5 minutes
I was able to handle that fear and energy
and just like you state
just look straight ahead
surrender to God and just ignore the energies
and they
they're not going to happen
they dissipated
and in about 5 years
I was able to transcend something
that had really ruled my life
for 25 years
so thank you so much for everything
thank you so much
dear Susan
and dear Dr. Hawkins
I thank both of you
from the depth
of my heart
and my soul
for what I have given
and what I have gained from you
it's incredible
my life has changed so much
it's indescribable
I thank you
and I love you both
and I love all of you too
I'm an alcoholic
and a heroin addict
and a crackhead
and my name is Danielle
and I heard one of your recordings
8 years ago
and your consciousness communicated with mine
and I received the gift of inspiration
and I couldn't stop drinking
and I couldn't stop using
but I also couldn't stop listening
and I couldn't stop reading
and then I came and I saw you for the first time
years later
and when I left
I left with the gift
of desperation
I don't think how I used to think
I don't feel how I used to feel
and I don't act how I used to act
and I know that you gave me those two gifts
and God did the rest
and today I love
and I give
and I tell people about the teachings
thank you
Dr. Hawkins
Susan
when I first came to your lecture
in 2005
you told me that
I was seeking a teaching
a spiritual teacher
and you told me that
what I seek I will find
and I'm grateful to God's grace
that he's brought Dr. Hawkins to me
as a spiritual teacher
I don't think I could have continued
this journey
this spiritual journey
without Dr. Hawkins as a teacher
and his inspiration
and his guidance
his divine guidance
and the incredible energy
the energy of the
I guess the divine presence
that emanates
it always puts me into
anyway
my life's been changed
through his teachings
I've been following a spiritual path
most of my life
and I was very fortunate
to have good teachers along the way
and I feel that Dr. Hawkins
is my last and final teacher
and I will follow his teachings
forever
thank you Dr. Hawkins
thank you Susan
we have to stop
greetings Dr. Hawkins from New Zealand
I'm not a poet
but the last few days
quite a few lines have been running around in my head
so I put them on paper
not knowing that this opportunity
was going to come
reflections on the impact
of the writings of Dr. David R. Hawkins
the clarion call rises
the challenge made in every book
straight and narrow is the path
waste no time
but dear friends
the path has been so brightly lit
by the divine words
within these works of devotional non-duality
for this life
the straight and narrow path
rises effortlessly
to meet every step forward
to comfort
every stalled step
and to guide the gathering pace
of growing consciousness
outwardly
a newly found
constant smile
echoes the flow of growing love
inwardly
peace and joy endure despite
the artful challenges of the ego
understanding shifts to knowing
and being
how pure
how true the experiences
of devotional non-duality
Gloria in excelsis Deo
my husband and I give thanks for you
every night in our prayers
but I feel compelled to express my gratitude
towards you in person
it is challenging to find words
to express how eternally grateful
I am for the both of you
and for the work
I know I must be blessed with excellent karma
to have found your teachings
so young in life
you have shown me how
to recontextualize my entire life
and that has made all the difference
it hasn't been an easy trip
but I feel that you have provided me
with the proper tools
to survive on the sometimes treacherous
but mostly beautiful journey
the tools you have given me include
a shield that cannot be punctured by doubt
a helmet full of knowledge
to know who and what to avoid
a compass whose only direction is truth
shoes made of courage
that only follow the straight and narrow path
and the greatest tool of all
love
a love that I can't even begin
to express in two words
I thank you with every ounce of my existence
and I love you both so very much
please wait for everybody in the audience
to get a full gear for ours
you're welcome
thank you
I'm going to say hello or goodbye
do you want to say goodbye?
do you want to just say goodbye to the crowd?
yeah
I give thanks to the Lord God
for the loving presence
I give thanks to thee oh Lord
for thy loving presence
for that is what you are
you are the loving presence
of God Almighty
for which I am eternally grateful
God bless you in the name of the Father
the Son
and the Holy Spirit
now and forever
Amen
the pipes stopped
can you hear the pipes?
they better
or I'll kill them
you know God bless the pipes
what do they calibrate at 500?
where are you?
where are they?
they calibrated 500 right?
so go out to the world
and spread the word
change people's lives like we have done
you've heard the testimony
you know the results
so it's up to each one of you
to change someone else's life
now that yours has been changed
the last 10 years that we have done this
has been so rewarding to us
and if I could just pass that along
how rewarding this whole change will be
for you to do the same
all it takes is just one person
to help one person to change one life
to change one life around
we love you all
we wish we could continue but we can't
you'll be in our hearts forever
and we will see your faces in our dreams
we carry all your spirits with us
and hope we meet again
love to you all
do I get up?
thank you
by your love
I'm greatly honored by your love
I love you now
and forever
in the name of my Lord
Amen
Jesus Christ