I'll just have one sip
of some good old
you know what
that'll
last me
I have to check with headquarters
to see how things are going periodically
alright we were going to
we're finishing up with the
last of the
valuable qualities of a
spiritual seeker
the qualities of a spiritual seeker
then takes advantage
of the consciousness of the
teacher aside from
what's said aside from
what you think is going on
none of that's happening
the field
the power of the field of the teacher
because the power of the field
of the teacher has come on
has come down through the centuries
so whatever is speaking to you
to you today
is the accumulation of the
influence of
speakers of teachers
going back to the Buddha
yeah
so the energy
the energy
of the Buddha
is there now available
resist
thank you
so every great teacher who ever lived
leaves the
power of the Buddha
the power of the Buddha
the power of that field
within the collective consciousness
of mankind
and that's why mankind
progresses
otherwise if you had to start
from zero every time
every generation had to start
from scratch
mankind would not be
where it is today
the power of the consciousness
of every great teacher
who has ever lived remains
and is still available
to focus on a particular
or a teacher
or their teachings
by meditating or visiting them
or going to lectures or whatever
the power of that teacher
you know is now available
to the seeker
alright so down through the centuries
the power of the consciousness
of the great beings
is now here present
resist
is now here available
to every student
and is the karmic or their
karmic right
their karmic right
it's your right
by virtue of your declaration
to benefit from the consciousness
of all the great teachers
who have ever lived
that's pretty good huh
what is today May 31st
May 21st
so the world's not coming to an end at all
oh well
I thought for excitement
it's
it's hard to beat you know
haven't they
for excitement
you can't beat
beat the end of
history
and the end of mankind
okay
it is the will of every truly enlightened teacher
that every student succeed
and not just limited
to a particular group
you will hear that weakness
and defect
in various world religions
and spiritual groups
that they are select
and it's only their enlightenment
they're worried about, and you're an infidel.
So beware of those who see everybody but themselves as infidels.
Yes, I think that's a good warning.
See, that is indeed a good warning.
Aha, those who think heaven and salvation is only for them
are in error.
Resist.
They are in error, yes.
Yes, salvation and enlightenment is for all of mankind,
you know, because it is the will of God, yes?
It is the will of every truly enlightened sage
that every seeker succeed,
not just members of your congregation.
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
Oh, well.
Let's move on.
Just as the individual seeker benefits mankind,
thus also.
Does the enlightenment of the teacher benefit the seeker?
Oh, good deal.
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
The teacher benefits from the student,
and the student benefits from the teacher.
I think that's pretty nice.
Okay.
The spiritual power of every great teacher
who has ever lived is currently available
through the consciousness of one's current teacher.
So therefore,
the consciousness that speaks to this audience now
is empowered by all the great teachers
that have ever lived.
Resist.
Thank you, God.
Boy, what a responsibility.
I thought I was going to take it easy.
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
So out of thanks,
you hold your own spiritual advancement
and intention and enlightenment
for the benefit of everyone.
Not just for the benefit of you.
What you're doing for yourself,
you do for everyone.
So be conscious of that fact,
that your prayers,
your enlightenment,
the progression of your level of consciousness
benefits all of mankind,
and it is your gift to mankind
that you share it.
Therefore, your being here today
is a gift to all of mankind.
The presence of all now present
Resist.
Thank you.
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
Mankind thanks you.
Well, good old Doc Hawkins.
He keeps going.
I don't know.
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
My job is to take care of him.
You know what I'm saying?
My job is to see he doesn't forget his cane
and fall over the edge of the front of your head.
He's a great man.
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
There are no requirements or obligations.
You don't have to sign up for anything.
Ha, ha.
You don't have to agree to anything.
You don't have to go into a contractual agreement.
Okay, there.
Now what's next?
God is both manifest as the totality and allness of creation
and same with God.
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
Same time.
Unmanifest as the Godhead, the source of all that is.
God is infinite beyond time or depiction of space or locality
without beginning or ending.
Gosh, I thought God lived down the street there.
Doesn't just live in church.
Well, probably yourself like all of us all his family
and friends.
All of us as kids thought that God lived in the church.
Did everybody think God lived in the church?
How is that God lived in the church, you know?
I was very careful when I got into the block that had a church.
I'd walk around, I'd be careful I didn't have any sinful thoughts or anything like that
because this is where God lived.
God lived in the church.
That's sort of cute in a way, isn't it?
God's house.
The church was God's house.
And I guess that's the way it's phrased so that children understand it.
But we're not children anymore.
Now we know that God is all the time everywhere.
Oh, poi.
Used to be fun walking down, getting closer and closer to the church.
Now God's everywhere. He's in the grocery store.
Let me see that.
God is in the supermarket. Resist.
Oh, my God. God's in the supermarket.
RGA. Markdown. It's on sale.
They let God in everywhere nowadays.
Supermarkets. Ladies' bathroom. Everybody's.
Parking garage. Sidewalk cafe.
Oh, well.
If God's going to have his way with us, I guess he will.
God is both manifest and unmanifest.
God is infinite beyond time or depiction.
Or space or locality and has no beginning and no end.
That which is divinity has no beginning and no end.
All right.
God is omnipresent, omnipotent, and omniscient.
The capacity to be everything, to be all that is, to know all that is knowable.
God is the source and substance of consciousness, awareness, knowingness,
and sentience.
The only reason anybody would be here today is because God is present in your consciousness.
If it were not for God as the presence in your consciousness,
you would not be at a lecture of this kindness.
So, God, make sure that you get here.
The only reason you're here is because God said you should be here.
Good old Doc Hawkins.
He's a favorite of God.
Because he knows you.
He knows I'll get busy with what I'm supposed to do.
Get busy with what you're supposed to do.
Write another book, give another lecture.
Boy, I'm getting pooped.
That's what I said about the last book.
I said, God, I don't know.
I'm getting pooped.
And a voice said, boomed,
No excuses from you, young man.
It boomed out of the heavens.
God is the source and substance of consciousness,
consciousness, awareness, knowingness,
and sentience.
God is the sole source of the energy of life.
The energy of life.
You mean a turtle has God's consciousness in it?
A turtle?
A turtle has God's consciousness.
Oh, a turtle is an expression of God.
Or is it?
Wow.
I'll be kinder to the next turtle I meet.
God is in the salamander.
God is in the cougar.
Wow.
We saw a cougar in our backyard.
Let's see.
That was a cougar, yes.
And God was in that cougar.
Wow.
God's cougar visited us.
We must be somebody.
Not everybody gets a cougar or a mountain lion in their backyard.
Anyway, God is the source of all that is.
God is the source of all peace, love, stillness, and beauty.
The infinite stillness.
So as you're walking through the woods, you're not thinking about God or divinity or anything like that.
And all of a sudden, the sudden stillness of the woods is like overwhelming.
And when it's suddenly in the presence of divinity, without being aware that it's divinity,
the stillness and beauty of the woods is the expression of God.
But God is beyond all universes or materiality.
But he's the source of all that is.
Beyond all materiality, yet the source of that very materiality.
Without God, nothing would be.
Wow, that's scary, isn't it?
If it wasn't for God, nothing would exist.
Well, therefore, God is the source of all existence.
God is the source of all existence.
God is the source of all that is.
Without exception.
Let's see if that's so.
God is the source of all that is, without exception.
Even you and me, baby.
Isn't that sweet?
You look at your spouse, you look at your mother, you look at your father,
your sister and your brother,
and you remind yourself that they are created by God
and that changes the way you see them and behave towards them.
Even the toad takes on a different significance.
Significance.
When you realize that even the toad is a creation of God.
So, all that is, is nothing exists except that which has been created by God.
God is the sole source of existence and the potentiality of beingness.
God is the ultimate context of which the universe and all the existence is the content.
God is the a-priority, formless.
Source of existence within all form.
So, within this cane, then, it comes forth as a cane,
feeding away children and dogs.
Get out of the way, children and dogs.
So, divinity is the source of everything that exists, without exception.
And meditating on that can have a quite profound effect.
It can have quite a...
To look about you and realize that all that exists is God.
God is not within the universe of the provable or the intellect.
Well, that's where I ran into trouble, when I was an atheist.
As a kid, I was very profoundly religious.
And one time I was walking along, walking along, not thinking about anything in particular.
And suddenly, the totality...
The totality of the pain and suffering of mankind, I became aware of the suffering
of all of mankind.
And although I had been a devout believer as a child and as I grew up, when I saw the
complete suffering, the totality of the suffering of mankind, I became an atheist.
And I became just as devout an atheist as I had been a theist.
Uh-huh.
And it took me some decades to transcend that transition.
God is not within the province of the provable or the intellect.
Therefore atheism and theism are both foolish.
Play with the intellect.
You can either prove God or disprove God.
God is the source and essence of the subjective state of I-ness called enlightenment.
The sense of I-ness is autonomous.
There is no entity or person that experiences one's existence.
One's existence is all that is.
There is no duality between a me or an I and consciousness.
And that is called the state of enlightenment, the realization that that which you are is
all there is.
That you are it.
Whatever there is is what you are.
God is the radical subjectivity of, and that's called self-realization.
The realization of the divinity, of the essence of your own existence, that nothing exists
other than God.
There is nothing that exists outside of divinity.
All that exists is divinity in its various forms.
God exists in its various forms, including atheism.
Everything that is capable of atheism is God.
To be an atheist you have to have consciousness.
To have consciousness, you have to have the presence of divinity.
Without God you can't be an atheist.
So thank God I am an atheist.
Do you say to yourself, thank you God that I am an atheist and I don't have to go to
church, and go to confession, and do all that stuff, you know what I mean?
Audience laughs.
I can eat mustaches.
Molly Also says to me, I'm a prosecutor.
meet on Fridays and use bad language yep God says yep whatever you want to be
baby it's you however don't forget the little story about karma don't forget
the little karma blanket that you took yourself in bed with a karma blanket
yeah God is in descriptively imminent and at the same time transcendent is all
that is and is is all that is not the human experience of the presence of God
is the same in all ages and cultures and all localities the expressions of the
awareness of presence of God is is part of all cultures throughout
all of time universality man intuits it if you live on a deserted island in the
middle of nowhere they have a belief in a Holy Spirit or in an animal spirit or
in the clouds or the Sun or the sky but every culture includes divinity in one
or another description or form yes and I've visited the various culture
so I visited God was encountered in each and every one of them yes all right God
is descriptively imminent as well as transcendent the human experience of the
presence of God is the same in all cultures all ages and all localities and
if you study anthropology in the history of all the cultures of the world you
find that divinity exists in various forms in every culture, age, colour, religion , safeguarding, your needs, identity , lineage unequal status , absolute choice, identity nodus, destiny is steak in nature , identityALIES.
every culture has a name for it name for it and they also have a name for that
entity for a person who doesn't believe in it and they become outcasts outcasts
outcasts okay right the effect of human consciousness on the experience of the
presence of God is subjectively transformative and identical throughout
all of human history you're sitting on the edge of a cliff you look out and
suddenly there's a transformation of the entire world transformation remember one
time you're walking down the side of a hill in your home and suddenly the world
lit up with the presence can you tell them what that was like the beauty of it
oh you don't have a mic mic
no she told me she was just walking along not thinking about anything and
suddenly the overwhelming stunning beauty of all existence hit her like a
huge thunder of beauty and light and it's like you see what you've always
seen but at much greater depth what you see is that the not only what exists but
the divinity of all that exists
how many people have had that experience you suddenly see the divinity of that
which exists huh hmm it leaves a timeless mark that is available as a
caliber as a calibration of a recorded level of consciousness no see let's see
all right so the calibration we can calibrate the level of consciousness
shall we do that of that vision yes we'll do it of that vision
it's over six hundred seven hundred six eighty six ninety six ninety that's a
beautiful level of consciousness enlightenment level of consciousness so
suddenly the world lit up it was transformed and what you became aware of
was the stunning beauty the incredible beauty everything was 3d everything was
3d everything was three-dimensional Wow mm-hmm
so
how many people have had transformative experiences like that yes a number of
people thank God we thank God for that for that gift that's how we call
enlightenment a gift it's not something that you've earned and acquired or paid
for etc it's like a gift from divinity suddenly you're walking along the street
and the street lights up and you see the miraculous you see the miraculous the
essence of God's
God's gift to you as a spiritual figure in your life and I think that that is
very important because it's the real gifts of the spiritual that God given to
you and would love to give you
I'm going to quote a quote from a famous poet named Brendan
says that rather than believe the supernatural I believe in a real being
but I believe in a real human being that is an individual that is so important to
me and I think that's very important to me as I'm a Christian woman I'm not just a
Christian I'm just a Christian woman and I believe in God and I believe that that is
retaliation. It is beyond locality. So consciousness becomes what you become. You become aware
that what you are is consciousness itself. Not the content of consciousness, but consciousness
itself. It isn't this body, it's the capacity to comprehend the existence of this body.
Hmm. So you can exist in different realms without a body. That is true. You can exist
without a body. Huh. The older you get, the less you need a body, right? What good is
it? Well, you know, I'd love to eat dinner. Loves ice cream. So we hang around for a few
reasons. What's the favorite ice cream right currently?
Coffee ice cream is our favorite. Okay. Anyway, as you see, that's impersonal. It just has
to do with realizing the value of all that exists and allowing yourself the enjoyment
and recognition of it. And so I thank God for ice cream. I thank God for ice cream.
I say, dear God, thank you for this wonderful ice cream. And the voice says, good deal.
Then tomorrow you shall have some more.
As you can see, the variations in the understanding, comprehension, and description of divinity
are widespread, widespread, depending on culture, time, age. But every culture has its own Holy
Spirit, sometimes considered to be nature spirits, but still of a spiritual nature.
When it's, when we need rain, I always remind the nature spirits that it hasn't rained for a month
now. Just in case God and the nature spirits hadn't noticed. I always remind the nature spirits,
when you get home, it hasn't rained for a month around here. You know what I mean?
Yeah. So the nature spirits sort of nudge God. And sure enough, within two weeks, it all,
it all rains, you know. Thank you, nature spirits. All right. The variations of the depictions
of divinity reflect the availability of human perception and the rejections of the impediments
of the ego as positionalities.
Okay. So we transcend all these limitations. All right. The purity of the presence of God is traditionally the essence,
of the ineffable quality called holiness, and is the basis for the depiction of the sacred,
that which is sacred. That which is devoid of content is the equivalent of innocence.
So, in a elevated state of consciousness, you see the beauty and worth and
beauty
an inspiration of all that exists.
And I always give the example,
as you're walking down the sidewalk,
there's this little bug walking along.
That little bug is now famous, famous little bug.
And therefore, the enlightened person carefully
steps over the little bug
and blesses it by your concern.
We bless the little bug because we realize
that it represents the evolution of consciousness
as life itself.
So we value life in all of its expressions.
We appreciate all of life.
To be appreciative of your own existence
and the existence of all that is,
is in itself a short course on enlightenment.
I am grateful to thee, O Lord,
for this stage, for this audience,
for this wonderful king.
I am thankful for the beautiful flowers.
I am thankful for a box of Kleenex.
Just think, primitive man didn't have Kleenex.
He just sort of blew his nose on his sleeve,
you know what I mean?
You know where buttons come from in the military?
Military uniforms, you see, there's always buttons.
It's because in cold weather,
the soldiers would all be going,
and the commander couldn't stand it.
They had buttons put on the sleeves of everybody,
so you can't rub your nose,
on your sleeve,
because of all the buttons.
So now you know what those buttons are for, huh?
There's a couple of them right here.
Thank God for buttons on our sleeves,
and we'd all be a mess to look at.
The self is God imminent,
shines forth of its own cord,
just as the sun shines forth
when the clouds are removed.
Therefore, you see,
enlightenment is a totally different thing
than what you thought.
Enlightenment is a goal that I will pursue.
Instead, you see that it is what happens
when you remove its barriers.
You don't have to do anything to become enlightened,
except stop being unenlightened.
How dat?
How dat, baby?
You is what is already.
I is?
Yep, you is.
I'm what is?
You're what is.
If you didn't is, you wouldn't be saying what is.
Something has to be there to question,
Who am I?
How did I get to be where I am?
How do I get enlightened?
Stop being unenlightened.
It's simple.
You all agree?
Everybody promises they will stop being unenlightened.
Stick by your agreement.
You're all that is.
You're all that there can be.
You're all that there ever was.
Wow.
You don't have to do anything.
Nope.
You don't have to go anywhere.
You don't have to read anything.
Nope.
You don't have to sit in yoga postures and go weirdy breathing.
It's a realization.
That's how long it took.
Before it snapped, I was unenlightened.
But since I snapped my finger, I've become enlightened.
Did you notice anything?
No, you didn't.
You're just making it up.
And you think it will make me happy.
It doesn't make me happy.
It doesn't make me happy if you become enlightened.
I couldn't care less.
You want to be unenlightened?
That's fine.
It's very enlightened to let it be all right that you're not enlightened.
If it's okay with you that you're not enlightened, you already are.
Quit worrying about it.
Why seek what is?
What is already is.
No point in chasing your tail.
I want everybody to relax
and to be totally complete, satisfied, and happy
with just what you are this instant.
Thank you.
Anybody not satisfied with who or what they are this moment?
Who wishes to be thrashed, trashed, and thrown overboard?
Self-awareness shines forth of its own accord
when the obstacles have been removed.
So you don't have to seek enlightenment at all.
Stop seeking enlightenment.
Give it up.
Forget it.
Is that okay?
Anybody disagree?
Any stupid idiot out there that wants to disagree with the great doctor here?
Who knows everything that was ever known?
Anywhere and everywhere in the whole universe?
That's where I started for starters.
That's just stars, folks.
To know all that's knowable.
All that's ever been known.
All that could be known.
That's enough to do before lunch.
You know what I mean?
In between a peanut butter sandwich and a root beer
is the whole universe.
When you eat that peanut butter sandwich
and you wash it down with root beer,
you've just experienced all that can be experienced
of the wondrousness and goodness of enlightenment.
That makes it pretty easy, doesn't it?
Therefore, I want you to realize something.
I'm getting tired out here.
That what you want to happen has already happened.
And your only problem is that you haven't recognized that it already is.
It's already happened.
It's not possible to exist and be conscious without being enlightened.
To see that you are all that is.
Nothing can exist other than that.
You are all there is.
There is nothing else.
The fact that you're just a little piece of it
may bother what remains of your ego.
But you can't be the entire Empire State Building at one time.
You know what I'm saying?
You can only be one floor at a time.
Some guy was gonna jump off the Empire State Building
and they buckled him to the building.
Remember that?
Yeah, he was gonna jump off the Empire State Building.
Well, he didn't do it, so...
That's what you can say for enlightenment.
You're the Empire State Building.
The wonderment of your own awareness,
of your own presence,
of your own existence
is your Empire State Building.
You're so used to looking at the Empire State Building,
you don't realize that it's one of the great wonders of the world.
Your existence is one of the great wonders of the world.
That you exist
is the ultimate miracle.
Because you can see
the opposite would be non-existence.
You've got your choice between existence and non-existence.
And it's only the presence of divinity
that accords you the capacity
to realize that you exist.
Other entities are,
but do not know that they are.
They do not know that they are.
It's taking multitudes
of millions of years
to move from being
to know that you are.
To be is one thing.
To know that you are
takes millennia.
Millennia.
Boy, oh boy.
Jeepers, creepers.
Takes millennia to exist.
Wow.
We're the product of eons,
millennia,
to move from that which is
to that which knows
that it is.
Whoa.
Billions of years
to move from being
to know that you are.
Wow.
Is that a good deal or not?
Mostly that which exists
does so and does not realize
that it exists.
To exist and know that you exist
makes you enlightened.
Therefore,
there's no point in seeking enlightenment
because everyone here already is enlightened.
Everyone here knows that they are.
Anybody here that doesn't know that they are,
get my gun.
Get me.
It's not possible to be here
and not know that you are.
The fact that you're here
means you know
that you are.
Therefore,
there's no point in seeking enlightenment
because you already are.
So the trick between the unenlightened
and the enlightened
is merely knowing the difference.
The unenlightened doesn't know
that they're enlightened already
and therefore they're unenlightened.
The enlightened knows
that they're enlightened already
and therefore is enlightened.
Wow.
Good deal, isn't it?
Anybody complain?
Anybody here who's not enlightened?
Hello?
There are no idiots here today.
Here's an audience
with no idiots in it.
How can that be?
Oh, I know.
It's our karma for being
the world's greatest teachers.
How many teachers have you heard
tell me what I've told you?
Anybody know of any?
Hey.
Speak up.
For God's sake,
don't be .
Don't be so niggardly.
Speak up.
Isn't there any idiots out there?
There's no idiots in this audience.
What can you do?
Yes.
So you're saying
that we're enlightened
even if we don't recognize it?
What we call enlightened
is a person who has recognized it.
People are enlightened,
but they are not called enlightened.
Just like if you're homely
but don't know you're homely.
One day you look in the mirror
and say,
God, you are one ugly son of a gun.
And now you're enlightened.
Well, what if you were a guy
and didn't even know you were a guy?
You know what I'm saying?
Someday somebody says to you,
you know, you're a guy.
Oh, geez.
I didn't even know that.
Or you say it to a lady,
you know, you're a woman.
I'm a what?
What if she never heard of that?
She just thought everybody's like she is.
So consciousness then
is the capacity to recognize
the essence of the reality
of one's own existence.
The capacity to stand apart
and yet be that which is perceived.
So you are both what is
and that which realizes what is.
The unenlightened person
does not have that recognition.
To be enlightened is to know that you are,
to know that you are,
and to know that you are all that can be.
Other than being the totality of knowingness,
nothing else is possible.
That has to suffice for now.
Yeah?
What?
Lunch.
Threats.
You see?
She uses threats.
You got to have lunch now.
This gentleman came,
he's 92,
and hello.
Okay.
Can you hear me now?
Yeah.
He is 92 years old
and he said he wanted to see you
before he left the planet.
Good idea.
He said good idea.
That you wanted to see him
before you left the planet,
so he said good idea.
Well, it's a race
to leave the planet.
You're ahead of me.
I expect everything
to be set up when I get there.
I like iced tea.
Wait.
He has a question.
Here, sit down
and they'll be able to...
And that way they can hear you.
Now,
my question is,
Eckhart Tolle says in his book
The New Earth,
He says what?
is what? That's not the new one.
Anyway, it's his latest
book. That
we will
stop destroying the planet,
live sustainably,
be
rid of
violence, and
kind of feel
along with the space brothers
from the different
planets of the Earth.
Now, I don't know if that's
in your field of
guessing. Eckhart Tolle said that
there would be a planet
with
little violence, and
that they would
I know it's hard for you to hear
me. It's a
there would be a planet with very little
violence, and
Yeah, and they
would live sustainably, stop destroying
the Earth, and start sharing.
And that people will
stop destroying
the Earth, and he wants to know if you
see that in the future, too.
People will stop destroying the Earth?
Yes. Eckhart
Tolle. I don't know who that is.
All right.
He wrote a book. Yes.
The New Earth or the New
Yeah, the New Earth or something.
And in this, he says that people
will start. Reach a state
of peace. Reach a state of peace
and stop destroying the Earth.
And he wants to know if you foresee that
in the future, too.
Uh, that is a fact.
Uh, that's a, that's an accurate prediction.
Resist. Nope.
We didn't get that. I thought it was wishful
thinking.
We gotta, we gotta know. It might take a
while before that takes effect.
Well, because the species would
have to change.
You know, you'd have to go through a
transformation evolutionary
where Homo sapiens becomes
Homo heavenly
or something. Right now, people
have, uh, adrenaline.
All kinds of hormones
driving them. Uh,
they're brainwashed by the media
constantly.
You have political subdivisions
that are not repairable.
The major,
the two major religions of today's
world are not
repairable. I hope,
sir, you're wrong.
I don't care about your hopes, old man.
That's idiotic.
So long as they teach that
killing other people in the name of
God is God's will, how are you
gonna have peace? No peace
is possible with the
teaching that the only way to please God
is to kill those that don't believe the way you
are. Now, you tell me, what's
the cure of that? It is my impression
that that, that attitude
is changing as the younger people
come along. That's not gonna
change because they brainwash them as soon
as they grow up. Well, I...
The way you get, you love God in certain
religions is by killing everybody who doesn't
believe the way you believe. Now, you
tell me how you're gonna have peace with that
kind of a teaching prevailing. Okay.
It's not gonna be possible.
Thank you. And what are you
whimpering about for peace for?
What do you have, peace think?
Everybody wants peace. For what?
So you can read the newspaper, watch television,
what? Listen
to the birds call and sing?
No, you have to learn to live
in a world of, you know, higher
adrenaline and
animosity.
Now, you look at nature.
You look at nature.
Everybody thinks nature is holy
and divine. The nature is full
of entities that have lived next
to each other for tens of
millions of years and
still hate each other. The cat will
still eat the mouse. The tiger will still
eat the mouse.
So it's better to accommodate
yourself to reality
than try to change reality.
Yes. I think I can
understand your answer. Thank you.
What did he say?
He understands your answer.
Thank you.
There will always be rain
and sunshine and hoping for
a world in which there is only sunshine
and no rain, you know,
as being grade school.
Well, I'm thinking, for example,
of Egypt
and how
that's going and the way it's
working in Libya and so on.
There is a
revolt of the younger people
against the corruption
and the
environment.
Environmental degradation.
Yeah, yeah. Corruption is good.
Okay.
Thank you.
No, I understand what he's saying.
I understand what he's saying.
Yes.
Well, I will retreat with my seven-year superior age.
He will what?
Retreat with his seven-year superior age.
Oh, oh.
I thought it was inferior age.
Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
Oh, my God, what a loud voice.
Hello.
Hi, Mrs. Hawkins.
Come here.
Speaking to me from outer space.
What's up?
Well, I'm nervous to be up here as normal,
but I have a question prepared.
Yes.
I'm wondering, you talk about how straight and narrow is the path and to waste no time
and to hurry up, basically.
But I also heard you talking in a lecture about how
a dark night of the soul will come from pushing the envelope
and trying too hard to push the evolution.
And so, when I feel like something like a dark night is going to happen to me,
I get self-doubt and I don't know whether to...
Let it be there. Just let the self-doubt be there.
It's normal. It's harmless.
Okay.
You know, everybody doubts everything all the time,
but they've learned to cover it over.
Condition reflex.
So, let the self-doubt be.
Let the self-doubt be there.
It resolves itself.
Okay.
It isn't anything you have to do anything about.
It'll resolve itself, yes.
Okay.
Uh-huh.
Okay, thank you.
May I shake your hand?
It's the nature of the ocean for the waves to slowly die down.
All right.
May I shake your hand, sir?
Oh, yeah.
Thank you.
Thank you, Susan.
Yes.
Hi, Doctor.
Hi, Susan.
Yes.
I don't know whether or not I'm integrous,
and I was wondering if you could tell me whether or not I'm integrous.
No.
It's like saying, tell me whether I'm hungry today.
I don't know.
Ask yourself.
How do I deal with the torment of not knowing?
Not knowing what?
Whether he's integrous or not.
Don't ask the question.
Okay.
Thank you.
That's like saying you doubt with your doubt.
You know what I'm saying?
Yeah.
Thank you.
No, you're okay.
Befuddled, but that's normal.
Befuddled, I like that word.
Isn't that a nice word?
Befuddled.
Oh, boy.
Hi, Doctor Hawkins.
Yes, ma'am.
It is wonderful to see you.
You have written in one of your books, oh, in one of your books, several of your books,
a book called The Life of the Human.
It's a book about the life of the human.
And it's about the life of the human.
I do have another reference about your driving the vehicle and having the Kundalini energy
coming out of you and into an
accident.
When the energy comes through the physicality, where does it go?
I don't know.
You don't ...
You mean when it ...
For instance ...
I said it went to an accident.
It went to an accident.
So, what is the question?
Right, but that was in your experience on other individuals who have also the
kundalini running through them does it go to all the accidents in the world does it go to
just the general consciousness does it go to the collective consciousness it may not go anywhere at
all okay it may not react to things that are going on in the environment if you're worrying about
your marriage you know you don't worry about somebody who has a flat tire alongside the road
because you're focused elsewhere so that you know energy goes to where you're focused
what's important to you what you see is important and a tiger walking through the backyard
would attract your energy not long ago a mountain lion is walking through my backyard
i'm looking out the kitchen window and here's this mountain lion
yeah that attracted my attention yeah okay thank you so much may i shake your hand
uh-huh
a quick question
okay
david at 18 i experienced the infinite presence and when i did it was like you said it was
overwhelming it was so complete there were no questions everything was known everything was
answered with so much love but when i walked into that light there was a doorway did you
experience a doorway or no no furniture no furniture there was no furniture no tv nothing
yeah i think you get a picture with you and thank you both very much
you want a photo photo photo photo yeah photo let's have a photo thank you for the photo
oh dear me photo you
first of all i just wanted to say how grateful i am to both of you for everything that you've done
for us um my question is how grateful are you for everything that you've done for us
i've heard that you say straight and narrow is the path waste no time and then i've also heard
that everything is perfect and unfolding perfectly at any moment and it seems to be a conflict for me
because when i think of straight and narrow is the path waste no time it makes me anxious
that i'm not doing enough you you think there's a contradiction between the two statements
to me there seems to be that's what i'm saying i'm not doing enough i'm not doing enough i'm not
asking for some clarification to me uh it means you have an overriding goal in mind overriding
as an intention for your own existence you don't have to verbally go through it
multiple times a day or something like you've got to reactivate it
the intention is almost a non-verbal unspoken it would be maybe more common parlance common sense
i don't have to say to myself verbally i think i'll try to answer this lady's question the best
i can within my ability within the state of time frame as they said they're in the end just say at
all in english that's not necessary got it the obvious is obvious why make it complicated
right okay i'm pleading with you to make it simple and easy to stop twisting your nose
that will not make it go faster I will give you a sore nose could I have a picture please you
can have a picture you can find one I don't know have you got a picture she wants a picture oh
there you are okay here we are boom it went boom here then