Oh,
Gloria and Excelsius Dio. All praise and
glory be to thee, O Lord most high.
Amen.
And if you forget to cross yourself,
you're in trouble.
Well, we were going to talk about
something interesting today.
I I don't remember what it was.
Honey, do you know what what it was?
>> No.
>> Oh, you
Well, we're up against it, Augustus.
Huh?
We'll have to uh innovate.
Look at the beautiful flowers. Aren't
they lovely? Oh my goodness sakes. And
here's Kleenex. Well, you can't go wrong
now.
All right. So we do have an interesting
uh lecture today has to do with the
characteristics
uh of the spiritual seeker
uh and those that uh I found to be most
useful
pragmatic is I'm a pragmatist. If it
doesn't get you to heaven, then heck
with it.
And if you tip Jesus on the way, it'll
help.
Now, we have slides, do we?
>> Yes.
>> Oh, boy. Oh, boy.
>> We're starting out with a review. A a
small review for people who who are
>> Oh, we're starting out with a with a
small review for people who have never
been here before. Will that come up on
the screen now? Yep.
>> Oh, that's exciting. Boy, oh boy.
>> Golly, I forgot what I knew already.
Wow.
>> Oh dear.
Oh, we start with a map of
consciousness.
Now, the map of consciousness is world
famous and uh a calibrated scale of the
various levels of consciousness.
And uh throughout the lecture, Susan and
I will very often stop
and uh calibrate something.
Uh
now the way we calibrate a thing is she
holds out her arm
and I press down and I say resist.
All right. Now if the thing is true her
arm stays strong.
If something is false, her arm goes
weak.
It's never wrong.
I could be wrong, but I never am.
Humility.
I've got more humility than anybody I
know.
We call this asking the arm. So we ask
the arm uh many questions throughout the
day and during the months and years that
have gone by.
And by using the arm, we discover things
that nobody else in the world knows and
nobody has ever known. And uh often
we're the only people on the planet that
know it.
If that doesn't do something for your
ego, I don't know what.
Well, uh I thought we'd start with one
that might be on some people's mind. Uh
the world is scheduled to end. I have
permission to ask this.
I have permission to ask this.
The world is going to end today. Resist.
Well, we thought that the lecture might
be interrupted by the world coming to an
end
at 3:00 today, but uh apparently
>> six o'clock.
>> 6 o'clock.
>> Oh, okay.
>> I don't know if that's Eastern time or
not.
>> Well, no. I think it was 3 o'clock. our
time here. Yes.
But we thought we'd just keep track of
whether the world is going to end today
or not. So
you know where you parked your car and
everything.
We'll have a lecture, we'll have slides,
then after that we'll have questions and
answers and a free-for-all.
Uh now the uh slides are very uh large
so that they can be read easily
from the back of the room
and they're also large
so that I can see them from right up
here.
Oh golly.
You'll find that the uh levels of
consciousness are extremely
useful, very pragmatic
and uh I can ask the calibrated level of
anything and within seconds no more than
all of mankind has been able to learn
about a subject throughout all of
history. That's convenient, huh?
It's like having a complete set of
encyclopedias in your hip pocket.
So
there's the view of God over on the left
hand side the map of consciousness.
It starts with the view of God and the
various levels give you the various
levels of sophistication.
Uh
and God either that cares about you or
let's say he's indifferent. you're
nobody at all and God couldn't care less
about you.
Then there's a whole lot of people on
the planet that view God is very
vengeful.
God gets poed at at you and strikes you
with lightning or something.
That's the quickest way to go. Get
struck by lightning.
So they see God as punitive
or they see God as indifferent,
uncaring,
and vengeful.
And so here's the vindictive, vengeful
God that sort of poisons many of the
world's religions and continues to do
so. Uh God gets mad at you.
God gets mad at you
and uh
God is also very demanding
disapproves. He's frightening
sees man is evil.
Here you see the emotional levels in the
middle is courage. So
200 and over is integrity. Below 200,
the integrity diminishes until you get
down to anger and finally you get down
to grief and guilt and shame and you
fall over in a pile of sad mess.
I practiced psychiatry for 50 years and
I used to see those at the bottom here.
Used to see people at the bottom of the
pile
uh year in and year out. Now the levels
of consciousness as you say are
calibrated
and
over on the right here is the total
effect the total effect of a level of
consciousness. So one of the major
things we want to do as spiritual
students is to advance our level of
consciousness
to substitute faith where there is fear
uh hope where there is sadness to uplift
those who are downtrodden
and to bring uh in classically good news
to the world. All right let's move to
the next one. Okay.
Yeah, we're going through these slides
sort of fast this morning because most
of you have seen them uh before.
But so this is just a review. Uh-huh.
Uh
these are the the various levels of
consciousness of the various entities.
It starts out of course with the supreme
godhead. Uh God is infinite.
Yeah. And then we move down to the
higher levels of the heavenly realms.
Uh
and here we have archangel.
Uh archangel.
Now let's ask
the misses some who's somewhere over in
the dark here.
Uh
that day uh in history I was hit by a
blast from an archangel resist
a archangel. The archangel I was
praying. I was in the pits of hell and I
had given up being an atheist.
I had given up all hope.
And as I wandered through the lower pits
of hell, which is a place you never want
to explore.
You really don't ever want to go there.
I said, "If there is a God, I asked him
for help."
And then I was struck by a
transformation.
And that archangel calibrated at 6,000.
6,000.
Wow.
You hit get hit by the energy of an
archangel at 6,000
and you are no longer what you once
were.
A total transformation took place and
that which was impossible became
possible
and the atheist
expired.
>> What what year did that happen? Well, in
in in world time.
>> Oh, honey, I don't remember now.
Thousand years ago. No, no, it was
I don't remember how many years ago. Uh,
we could ask. I forgot.
>> Well, you asked the question now. I
don't want to see how how we use this.
It happened over 20 years ago, 26 years
ago, 30 years ago, 36 years ago, 40
years ago, 50 years ago, 60 years ago,
55 years ago.
55 years ago. Okay. And seeing as I'm as
old as the hills now, I guess I was
55 years. Good God.
I didn't think people even live that
long when I grew up.
55. That's a grandpa or something.
Grandpa 55.
So an archangel is a absolute entity
calibrated at 6,000.
And you say,
"Dear God, I ask you for help." And
suddenly you're hit by like you're just
connected up to a high power
transformer.
All right.
Here we see the various levels of
consciousness that are possible from the
godhead, the archangel,
uh I as the ultimate reality,
you see Christ, Buddhahood, Krishna,
etc.
And then the avatar
self as beyond existence,
teacher of enlightenment,
uh the sage,
self as existence. We come finally down
to just saying I am and a condition
called enlightenment.
And enlightenment is
likely the goal of most of the people in
the audience here. How many people are
interested in enlightenment?
Hot diggity dog. You're in the right
place.
No, I'm in the right place. Thank you,
God.
They're not demons looking for hell.
Thank goodness.
Saved again.
All right.
The lectures are based on the
presumption
that the a person interested in our work
is interested in enlightenment
and spiritual progress beyond the
ordinary. To really understand the self
with a capital S, the relationship of
the self with a capital S to God and how
to become enlightened is what the basic
theme of all the lectures and the books
is about. Okay. What's the next uh good
news? Oh,
I don't know what this indicates, but it
looks interesting.
Do you remember what this is for, honey?
That's the scale of consciousness. The
distribution of the scale of
consciousness in mankind. Okay, we'll go
to the next one.
All right, this one is a little too
complicated. So, we'll move to the next
one.
This is the distribution of the levels
of consciousness in mankind.
Uh
85% of the people
uh are below the level of integrity. The
level of integrity calibrates at 200 and
over on a scale of consciousness.
85% of the human population
calibrates below 200.
85%
of
the population is non-integrous,
which explains history both past and
current.
Somebody's always looking to bomb
somebody.
Every day they're about out to bomb
somebody. I mean, this is the bomb crazy
world.
Bombs are going off in Grand Central
Station or Time Square or
uh some crazy religious group is always
going to bomb somebody.
All right? So, they belong to the 85%.
Uhhuh. So only 15%
would say
no, we're not going to bomb anybody
uh because they disagree with us.
We'll cut them off welfare. How's that?
Okay, what's the next one?
Uh this is again just uh illustrating
the cal distribution of levels of
consciousness.
85% of the people are below the level of
integrity. All right.
It sort of helps you watch the daily
news without getting depressed
because you realize that people if they
could be better than they are, they
would be that people are really unable
to help themsel.
They're born uh a certain way with a
certain karma.
All right? So that means that the people
who are spiritually oriented and have
made progress
are even more important than ever.
What's more important to be uh the man
who can see among the world of blind of
the blind. So those of us who have
endeavored in the spiritual dimension
have therefore an obligation to the
world. an obligation to share what we
have become with the world to share not
just what we know but what we have
become.
Okay. The next yeah
uh here again just a different
different way of presenting the same
information. Uh the next slide. Huh.
Uhhuh.
These are the epics of mankind. the
epics of evolution over great expanses
of time and the levels of consciousness
which characterize those levels and
epient epics. Okay. Next. Mhm.
Now we move the distribution of
consciousness in the animal kingdom.
Uh
and this is very interesting very
interesting the distribution in the
animal kingdom.
Aha.
That this is where consciousness first
begins to get to be a possible future
for man. Because evolutionary wise, we
start out with bacteria and the bacteria
have a consciousness level of one. You
can't expect too much from them.
Uh protozoa at two.
Uh, crustaceians at three.
Insects have a consciousness. They
actually do. A mosquito. Get away. Punk.
Six.
Arachnids. Spiders.
Amphibians. Fish. At 70.
The octopus is pretty intelligent. The
octopus calibrates at 70.
A shark is even smarter.
A viper at 36.
Komodo dragon.
I'm very interested in komodo dragons
here. Probably uh the height of
wickedness.
The reptiles calibrated 40.
The predatory mammals such as the lion
and the tiger calibrate at 40.
The snake calibrates at 45.
Alligators are at 45.
Dinosaurs are smarter than you think to
calibrate at 60. I always thought they
were sort of dumb, but they're not.
A whale happily is an intelligent being.
And a dolphin is very, very intelligent.
and migratory birds calibrate at 105.
From all of this, you don't have to
remember all this. It's just to give you
a feeling how evolution, the evolution
of consciousness has affected life uh on
this planet. All right. So, we see uh uh
the the the dove way up there. We always
say as innocent as a dove. And then we
say there's nothing more aggressive than
a grizzly bear.
And no, there's nothing more aggressive
than a water buffalo. I think they take
the water buffalo will just attack you
for no reason just cuz you're standing
there. You can't expect too much of a
hippopotamus.
And so now we get up to the grazers, the
zebra, the horses, the gazelle, the
giraffe, and the deer. At two, what does
that say? 2005.
Yes, indeed.
And let's not make a f fun of a pig. A
pig calibrates
uh way up there. Elk
and a dairy cow. Good old bossy. What's
bossy out there? 210.
Bossy. Bossy. Let down your milk. How
many people here grew up on a farm?
Buzzy, bossy, let down your milk on a
cold wintry morning. Oh boy.
Out in the dark barn. Milking the cow
before you go to school.
All right.
The farm horse calibrates quite high at
240.
Uh, kitty cats. What does it say? Kitty
cat 250. 240.
Kitty cats at 240.
Uh, dogs at 275.
Is that what it says? 275.
>> 245.
Let's see. Let's do Kelsey. Kelsey
calibrates over 245.
250.
255.
Our doggy calibrates at 250. That's cuz
she gets so much attention.
250.
All right. She doesn't answer the phone,
but
she hears somebody at the door. She
comes over and lets you know somebody's
at the door. The the family dog 250. You
can see why people love dogs. Every day
there's a heartbreaking story about a
dog. And uh I always say I can't take
another heartbreaking story about a dog.
I mean, I've just had it with
heartbreaking stories about dogs. You
know, the dog that meets the master
after work year after year, and then the
master dies, and the dog keeps going
back to the same corner, waiting for the
master to show up. And after an hour or
so, the dog gives up and goes home and
then goes back again the next day at the
same corner, same time where he met the
master for all the years.
So we're gripped by that which has
heart. So we like the dog because the
dog has a heart
and uh man is very susceptible to that.
All right. At home we have some other
more exotic pets. We have a gray parrot
named broccoli. Broccoli calibrates at
400. My god, does broccoli calibrate at
400?
Broccoli calibrates at 400 or this. Oh
my god. Yes.
Well, she tells you where to get off at
times. You know what I mean?
African great pair at 400.
Coco the train gorilla who was very
famous at 495.
A song birth song is uplifting.
Traditionally throughout history
calibrates at 500.
Uh, higher than that is a kitty's purr.
A kitty's purr is 500. Will you believe
that?
Let's see. I want to affirm that. A
kitty's purr is actually 500. Resist.
Wow.
Go to bed at night. The kitty's laying
on the pillow next to me going.
Oh golly.
So we love uh our animals, our pets, our
kitties and dogs, our song birds, and
our dogs wagging tail
calibrates at 500. Is that what it says?
The dog's wagging tail calibrates at
500. Wow.
How many people here have a pet that
wags its tail or that purr?
Well, we've got them all. We got things
that purr, things that bark, and birds
that talk.
Cover all the bases.
All right, our friends. To love the
animals, to love your fellow human
being. Can you do that without loving
animals? is not likely
because love goes to love and a loving
person tends to love everything about
life that's uh alive and wags his tail
and purr.
Okay, what's the next thing after the
dog's wagging tail? Huh? Well, we now
have the great books of the western
world.
The great books of the western world.
there's a university I forget the name
of it all the time uh where that is the
entire curriculum the entire curriculum
is the great books of the western world
period and that university calibrates
quite well what's the name of that
university
uh
that university calibrates over
>> what
>> no say something
>> anyway that university calibrates over
420 20
>> St. John
>> 440
>> 460
455 St. John's is correct. Yeah.
Minnesota is it?
>> Yeah. The whole curriculum is to study
the great books of the western world. Uh
because then you've really recapitulated
the evolution of man. And uh
I was always a great reader. I always
read a book a book a day. Uh for decades
I read 400 books a year. 400 books a
year. And I made notes on what they were
about. But I could have saved myself, I
suppose, by just reading all these here.
Wouldn't have had to bother
with all the details. But you can see
the impact that this has on the world.
The impact that it has on the world is
quite sizable.
Um let's take for example for example
uh the work of Carl Marx.
As you can see, the B of Carol marks
which calibrates at 4 something. 1:30.
Oh, dear God. No wonder. Oh, it's only
1:30.
I thought Markx was higher than that.
No. Okay. Okay. So, he's a dumbbell.
He calibrates as a dumbbell. Well, from
the history of the world, you can see
uh what happens to you if you're a
dumbbell.
Avoid being a dumbbell. It's better to
read Shakespeare
sophicles, you know, uh than it is
better to read Shakespeare
and uh hang out with the normal people.
Any
Marxists here?
Any Marxists here?
No Marxist. Oh well, it was sort of
classy for a little while. Sort of a
vantguard and oh, look how smart I am
ahead of the crowd uh to be a Marxist.
And it was sort of popular in Hollywood
and various places. is a bunch of pseudo
intellectuals.
So, it had a temporary hold.
All right. Right now, things that are
worse than Marxism are dominating the
daily news.
Okay. What's the next one then? We have
here
uh
characteristics of calibrations of
calibrations
below level 200.
There tends to be left brain dominance.
It tends to be linear.
The person who calibrates below 200 is
tuned up for fight or flight.
Uhhuh.
Below 200, the body is set up for attack
and defense with killer increased killer
cells.
And it's set more
to react with disease than with health.
So we want to advance our consciousness
for a number of reasons. One of them
just simply being that one will be
healthier and happier. Now above 200,
above consciousness level 200, there
tends to be right brain dominance.
It's nonlinear.
The body releases endorphins,
positive emotions.
The energy of the thymus gland is
supported.
The higher the level of consciousness,
the greater the likelihood of healing
from any disease, recovering from any
disease.
Now, the other day, I broke up. I woke
up with a terrible kink in my back.
Kink.
I still have a kink in my back,
but I'm walking around happy and
healthy. All right.
If the calibration level of this entity
here was lower, I'd be home with a hot
pad and a pillow and be unable to walk
and move. And instead, I'd just have a
cane
with which to beat off dogs and small
children.
When you get older, you need a cane. I
mean, it's that's part of the whole
scene.
What's an old guy without a cane?
Nobody. You know what I mean?
You can wave at a taxi cab.
All right.
So below consciousness level 200, the
psyche is set for fight or flight,
alarm reaction and dis and and disease.
So the lower the level of consciousness,
the greater the likelihood of the
negative effect of disease. Because
people say, well, what's the purpose of
spiritual advancement?
I'm not interested in becoming
enlightened.
Because the more loving you are, the
more spiritually advanced you are, the
greater your immunity to infection and
disease.
And
as you can see, the muscles the muscles
react differently. When we hold
something negative in mind and I test
Susan's arm, her arm goes weak. When I
test something that's true, her arm goes
strong. Was that invented by by Doc
Hawkins?
>> What was that? Yes. In the first book,
it
>> diamond.
>> Huh?
>> Diamond.
>> Oh, okay. Good deal. Anyway,
that which is positive makes your arm go
strong and what is negative makes your
arm go weak. And that's very important
to know. All right. So, we want to move
on to the next slide. All right.
the levels of consciousness and the rate
of success in this world.
The rate of unemployment
amongst people with high consciousness
is practically zero.
400 and over which probably
characterizes
the people in this level here
is practically 0%.
Anybody here uh unemployed? Uh
really unemployed? Is there anybody here
is really unemployed?
Anybody unemployed?
Oh boy.
Well, so much for that.
The rate of unemployment amongst people
of higher level is practically zero.
practically zero.
The rate of poverty amongst people of a
higher level of consciousness
is practically zero.
The happiness rate of people of a higher
level of consciousness is close to 100%
most of the time.
Uhhuh.
The rate of criminality amongst people
of a higher level of consciousness is
practically zero.
So advancing one's level of
consciousness
benefits all of mankind
benefits you personally
benefits your destiny when you leave the
body and go to various realms.
You don't want to go to the lower realms
at all.
Anybody here interested in exploring the
lower realms?
Nobody that's stupid. Eh,
well, I did explore the lower realms. I
forget what the circumstances were,
but I discovered I was searching for
truth and uh
I got to a certain level
and I saw that nobody really ever went
beyond this level. and I decided I would
explore it.
And so I began to explore the lower
levels of hell.
And oh yeah, that's when I gave up being
an atheist.
I gave I was a diet in the wool atheist.
You see? Anyway,
then I took atheism to its ultimate
level and took me took it to where it
would take me and I descended in and
explored the lower levels of hell. And
the lower levels of hell are so awesome,
somly, awesomely horrible that I cannot
really describe them. But it had to do
with eternal hopelessness.
You're hopeless, cut off from all love,
cut off from God
forever.
Well,
as you're there for a while,
for what forever means begins to dawn on
you.
And so I investigated Dante's levels.
Dante must I don't know how Dante knew
what it was like in hell, but his
description of hell was extremely
accurate.
eternal hopelessness
and what eternity means begins to dawn
on you and cold dread takes over. And I
asked God, I said, "If there is a God,
if there is a God, I ask him to help me
now." From the very pits of hell, I
asked God for help.
And suddenly I was struck by a
state of joy and higher level
consciousness.
And that's when the archangel responded
to my prayer. And I had enough good
karma left uh to get out of hell. And
that's why I'm here this morning.
If I had never come out of hell, I
wouldn't be here today. Uhhuh.
having explored the universe from
heavenly dimensions
uh all the way down to the uh energy
levels of hell.
All right. So let's we'll move to the
next scale. The next one
uh
correlation of the levels of
consciousness and the rate of happiness.
As we can see the higher your level of
consciousness
the greater the level of happiness.
people be want to become enlightened and
I say that's great uh also I want you to
be joyful and happy joyful and happy you
don't have to just you know uh bear bare
bones on your knees all day around the
clock kind of uh piety
uh the more joyful you are the closer
you are to God
as we see the consciousness level of joy
and lovingness is way up here. All
right. Reason is good enough. It's a
little on the dull side compared to joy
at 400.
Willingness at 310 makes for very
pleasant people to be with. It's nice to
be pe with people who are at least at
310.
Now the lower levels you see
we decline and we get to the level of
pride. Pridefulness
pridefulness is below the level of
happiness there at 200. Uh the prideful
are are easy to offend. Uh there are
world religions right now that threaten
the peace of just about everything and
everybody.
And uh pridefulness is one of the
characteristics.
Another lower level is angry. Angry
people are prone to sickness and uh all
kinds of disasters.
The fearful person only calibrates at
100.
Grief at only 75.
Apathy and hatred all the way down at
the bottom.
and guilt at 30.
So
this gives us a general feeling for the
range of the levels of consciousness.
Does it make sense to people? Does it
does it fall within a pattern of
recognizable sanity and practicality?
All right.
the rate of happiness and the level of
consciousness. As we see, the higher the
level of consciousness, the greater the
level of happiness.
Uh people who are peaceful, joyful, and
loving.
People who are rational and
reasonable.
Uh willingness, just simply being willy.
Willing brings you up above the line.
neutrality. It's okay if it goes this
way. It's okay if it goes that way. So
people at consciousness level 250
are easy to get along with. You say,
"Shall we stop for ice cream?" "Yes."
And then you say, "Well, I don't think
we will stop for ice cream." They say,
"Okay." In other words, there okay, ice
cream? Yes. Ice cream? No. It's fine.
And uh it works at home.
What's my favorite ice cream currently?
Toffee. Toffee ice cream. Can't live
without my toffee ice cream.
All right. Courage, pride, and all the
way down to anger. Now we get down to
cravingness. You see, cravingness is
only 125.
And the person who is always wanting
something, always wanting something
is very close to always being angry and
prideful.
So you see whole political major
political groups live in here.
Pridefulness, self-centeredness,
wanting to impose their way on others,
anger at people who don't think the way
they feel they do, and fear if they lose
control. Fear of losing control.
All right. Down even lower is grief.
Below grief is apathy
and hatred.
And at the very bottom is guilt.
And guilt calibrates much lower than
what you think it does. Guilt calibrates
only at 30.
So
the guilt peddlers then are have a
destructive influence on mankind.
The reason to correct your behavior is
not out of guilt but out of love.
not out of guilt, but out of love for
yourself and for others.
The reason to drive carefully is not out
of guilt, but out of caring for the life
and welfare and safety of others. And
not just guilt about speeding, breaking
the speed limit. All right.
And the next one has to do with some
uh very famous people. I thought this
was a very interesting set of
calibrations.
Uh these are the names of the people
with whom people in the audience are
most familiar.
Uh
we start I can't read the top one says
uh what's the top one there on the top?
I can't read it. Oh well, we'll let it
go. St. Augustine.
Uh
um Wallace Black Elk.
where is John Kelvin? Here he is.
Calvinism. Here's Kelvinism.
Here's Confucious,
the Dalai Lama. current Dalai Lama.
Uh
here are the current people that are
probably best known by people in the
audience. Ernest Holmes etc. The Carapa
Carapa is 630 I think. Yes, there it is.
uh mutananda
uh Robert Monroe
is probably well known by many people
here. How many people here are familiar
with Robert Monroe? Journeys out of the
body etc. Okay, let's move to the next
one.
All right, we're trying to finish up
just showing you that we've calibrated
all all the major teachers of uh the
current era. And uh it's sort of
practical because it tells you where you
are when you're reading something. Are
you close to where you want to be? So we
can look at some of the great names in
history. Uh, Socrates.
Socrates calibrated at 540.
Socrates
uh, one of the great greatest names in
history. Uh, Socrates,
Mother Teresa
Leu,
uh,
Yukafar.
It's hard to read from here. Okay, we'll
move on to the move on the list. Yes.
Yeah.
Here we go.
What does it say up there? Lock.
I can't read it from here.
No, we'll skip this one. We'll skip this
one. Too complicated.
Zoroaster calibrates at a thousand.
Jesus Christ calibrates at a thousand.
Krishna a thousand.
The 12 Christian apostles
980.
John the Baptist,
Moses,
Abraham,
and St. Paul, St. Paul of Tarsus.
Very interesting to give us a
perspective of the consciousness level
of mankind over the over the centuries
and the great names and teach the
teachings of religion. Okay, the next
slide has to do with
uh
spiritual writings, I think. Yes, I have
trouble reading without my glasses
today. The Book of Mormon, the cloud of
unknowing,
the Dharmapada,
the Gospels, Gospel of St. Luke, Gospel
of St. Thomas. Let's see what the
Gospels calibrate at. What does that say
there? Can you read that?
>> 660.
>> What does that say there?
>> Huh?
>> 660.
>> 650. Oh, okay. All right.
Cabalo. The heart sutra.
King James edition of the Bible.
Calibrates at close to 500.
The Quran
calibrates that close to
700. Yes. Okay. The lumps of Bible.
Yes.
And then we go over here to other things
people are familiar with, you know.
Yeah. I can't read it without the
glasses. I forgot my glasses today. I'm
screwed here. Ruby out of Omar. Cayam.
The talmet. How? What does the telmet
calibrate? What does that say? 595.
>> Huh?
>> What does it say?
>> 595.
>> 595. Oh, okay. All right. The Torah,
uh, the Aanashads,
Vidada, the Vas.
Uhhuh.
And the Zohar,
the yoga sutras of Parangeli.
It gives us a point of reference. When
you flip through all these things, it
gives you a perspective down through the
centuries and down through the history
and
learning of mankind. What's the next
slide? Huh?
All right.
We're interested in uh the level of love
and we're interested in maybe doing a
whole lecture on it.
Uh
love is level 500 and over. Love makes
the world go around. Yeah. Love is the
great uh the great healer and the great
promoter of all that is positive.
It is forgiving, supportive.
It's affectionate.
It's cordial.
Love is gracious. Love is forgiving.
Yeah, love is steadfast.
It's uplifting to be loved.
So if the doggy is laying there and I
send her a shot of love, I say, "Kilty."
Whoop! Her tail wags. Her whole life is
transformed by one shot of love. From
being nobody
to being delightful and happy in the
center of interest.
All right. So
love is nurturing
and it's filled with goodness and
purity.
It has to do with givingness. As you can
see, the other lower levels of
consciousness are interested in in
getting and controlling.
Love is interested in giving. What can I
do for you today? What can I do? It's
also a willingness to be sharing.
Love is joyful. It is also humble.
It is filled with gratitude
and it brings about vision
and
transformative.
So love is transformative.
So all that we can do to further further
our evolution in the field of love by
being loving towards all people at all
times even if you think they're dead
wrong. You see that what they are doing
is they're doing that because they think
that's the right thing to do. Even if
they think killing you is the right
thing to do. You can appreciate the fact
that they're doing it for a good reason.
World War II. I didn't hate the enemy.
Didn't hate them. And uh they were doing
what they could for the for their own
country. And um and blowing up our naval
vessels was part of their uh job.
And sometimes they did a good job of it,
unfortunately.
But I never hated them because I saw
they were doing it for patriotism,
for their country, for honor, for valor.
And even though they were killing us, I
respected them for what they were for
their integrity.
All right, that's Oh my goodness. What
is that?
What is that, sweetheart? How did I get
in here?
Uh, that's the wolf in sheep's clothing.
The wolf and sheep's clothing. And u
this is what you'll have to learn to
spot. You have to learn how to spot
the wolf in the sheep's clothing.
Uh there are many groups, especially
political, that promise you all kinds of
things. And uh when you uh calibrate
them, you find that they are quite low.
Yeah. Okay. Let's move on to the next
one.
Most valuable qualities for a spiritual
seeker. All right. We started with start
with the certainty knowing. Just know
that if you're spiritually oriented, you
will make progress.
Start therefore with a feeling of
security
of
instead of insecurity or self-doubt.
Tell yourself anybody who wants to
evolve spiritually will receive the
necessary assistance and success is
guaranteed.
Uh get rid of self-doubt.
any idea that you're not worth it or
you're not capable of it or that it's
not the right time in your life. Uh all
it's always the right time in your life
except without reservation that you are
worthy of the quest be resolved
to totally surrender to the truth about
God.
surrender to the truth about God and
that your spiritual evolution is aligned
with God's will for you. Resist. Um,
okay. Move to the next one. Uhhuh.
Start with a feeling of security instead
of self-doubt.
The facts that aren't to be unreservedly
accepted are simple and very powerful.
Surrendering to them brings about a
polit spiritual enormous spiritual
progress and advancement.
Okay, let's go to the next one. Right.
The living proof of God's love and will
for you is the gift of your own
existence.
The fact that you are
is the best evidence there is of God's
love and will for you. Amen.
Other valuable quality qualities for a
spiritual seeker. Do not compare
yourself with others regarding holiness,
merit, goodness, deservingness.
It's sinlessness.
Do not compare yourself to others. What
others are is irrelevant.
What's important is what you are.
Realize
these are all human notions you have
about being better. And God is not
limited by human notions.
Except that
the concept of the fear of God is
ignorance.
God is peace and love and nothing else.
There a lot of people talk about the
fear of God and use God as a threat.
Um,
God is nothing but love and peace and
and nothing else.
People think that they're being punished
by God and that's not the case. What
what they're being punished by is their
lack of uh alignment with divinity.
Realize that the dep depiction of God as
a judge is a delusion
is an ego fixation
arising out of guilt. Realize that God
is not a parent. So what what God
becomes in most people's mind is a
parent. Uh rewards you and loves you if
you're good and punishes you if you're
bad.
So that's nothing but apparent. So
realize that God is something greater
than a parent. Amen.
Okay.
Christ's teaching was essentially and
simply to avoid negativity
and
the purpose of Christianity was to reach
unconditional love.
calibration level 540 and over. So what
Jesus Christ wanted us to reach was
unconditional love, unconditional life.
Christ knew that once the level of
unconditional love was reached, the
soul's destiny was
certain and the soul was safe.
Uhhuh.
This is a essentially the same teaching
as the other world world's great
religions such as lotus land Buddhism.
U
sometimes spiritual seekers will become
confused. Are they following the right
teacher? Are they studying with the
right teacher? Are they reading the
right books? Are they going to the right
church? Do they belong to the right
religion? And what you do is you filter
through them and you see that the
essence of all of them is almost
identical. The essence, not the surface
of it, but the essence is almost
identical. All right?
Realize that salvation and enlightenment
are somewhat different goals.
Salvation is cons concerned with a yes
or no.
And enlightenment is concerned with uh
becoming
something beyond that which you have
been.
Salvation requires
purification of the ego. Enlightenment
is concerned with letting it go and
eliminating the ego.
The goal of enlightenment is
somewhat more demanding
than simply being a good person.
Enlightenment is something other than
good personhood.
It's advancing one's level of
consciousness
in the nonlinear realms.
Yes. And the next slide clarify that it
is not a personal you who is seeking
enlightenment
but rather a quality of consciousness
itself that is the motivator.
So you like to think of I am this or I
am that and actually
it's merely consciousness itself
uh and being what it is.
Spiritual inspiration and dedication
carry forth the work within yourself.
Your own spiritual momentum.
Everybody here has spiritual momentum or
they wouldn't be here. Anybody who raise
anybody who's not here raise your hand.
Nobody stand what up. Therefore,
everybody in this audience is safe.
And uh we throw all the bad ones out at
the door anyway. We can tell right away
that you're a deadbeat. And we have a
side door that says entrance, but
actually it's an exit to the alley.
Dead beats this way, enlightened people
this way. Yes. So our kindness and
humbleness,
we send them out to exit.
Comfort replaces insecurity when one
realizes that the most important goal
has already been accomplished.
The goal is to be on the path.
Therefore,
everybody here
is okay.
I know you wanted to hear that today. I
just
nobody would be here if they were not
spiritually aligned, spiritually
committed, and spiritually motivated
and had a good prognosis. Mhm. Let's see
if there's any dead beats here.
This This crowd is 100% okay.
100%, folks.
Nobody would be here that was not
destined for enlightenment and as well
as not only salvation but enlightened
because nobody else would be here.
Yeah. Nobody'd be in a cookie store if
they didn't want cookies. Okay.
Comfort replaces insecurity. When Ren
realizes the most important goal has
already been accomplished,
the goal is to be on the road to
spiritual evolution. Therefore, everyone
in this audience is on the road and is
already successful or they wouldn't be
here. That's a wonderful thing to know.
Also, it's it's sort of good the world's
not going to end today.
There was some clergy in blasting that
the world was going to end today, but
it's not going to end today. Okay. I
hate to disappoint anybody, but the
world is not ending today. All right.
Spiritual love,
spiritual development is not an
accomplishment, but a way of life.
It is an orientation that brings its own
rewards
and what is important is the direction
of one's own motives in life. So there's
no
uh value in keeping a scorecard on
yourself. A scorecard, how far have I
come or how far do other people think I
have come? Uh
the only one you have to answer to is
yourself.
And the motivation to seek God is God.
No. Nobody seeks God except under the
influence of divinity
because man left to his own device would
never think of it. Yeah.
All right.
Appreciate that every step forward
brings benefits to everyone.
So as you advance spiritually
it brings a value to everyone to every
human being because of the collective
consciousness.
Every single person who improves
uh helps elevate the level of
consciousness and as that elevates the
incidence of war, suffering,
ignorance, sagging and disease diminish.
So when you advance yourself, you are
helping everybody.
Appreciate that every step forward
benefits everyone.
Once spiritual dedication at work is a
gift to life and the love of mankind,
it's nice to know that what you think
you're doing only for yourself is
actually benefiting everyone around you.
To be kind to just one living being
benefits everyone.
All right.
There is no
timetable or
prescribed
route to God.
Although each person's route is unique,
the terrain to be covered is relatively
common to all.
So whatever torment you go through in
trying to perfect yourself, overcome
sinfulness and selfishness, etc. Realize
that this is common to all of mankind.
People troop into church Sunday
mornings, everybody working on the same
problem. How to be less selfish, how to
be more giving, how to be more loving,
uh, etc.
All right. The work is to surmount and
transcend the common human feelings that
are inherent in the structure of the
human ego. So whatever defects you have
are not just personal, they're not just
yours. They are the problem of the human
ego itself. And the problem is one of
evolution that mankind at this point has
evolved to a certain point and that's as
far as it's gotten as of as of today.
One would like to think they are
personal. However, the ego
itself is not personal. People would
like to think oh me and my progress or
me and my sins or me and my
difficulties. And what you're talking
about is not your personal self. The
problem is that of the ego itself.
The problem is the ego itself. And so
you stop taking the ego personally.
I blame everything on the brain.
It's the brain that takes the lumps with
me.
And I have a way of sort of cajoling
information out of the brain.
I speak to it as brain. I say brain. Now
you know who wrote wrote who who wrote
that? I can't think of who wrote it. Uh
who wrote it? Who wrote it? Let's see.
Uh, and then I asked my brain and I
said, "If you look a little straight
ahead and then start it to the right,
there is a neuron over there and if you
grab it."
The tale of two cities. I've been
grabbing its butt. Who wrote a tale of
two cities? And I kind of catch it
before it forgets it.
I forget his name now. Who wrote a tale
of two cities? Let's see.
Uh Dickens, is that right?
Now, that thought Charles Dickens was a
little to the right of the central
vision and over to the right
there's a neuron over there that knows
everything.
And I look at that neuron and I say,
"What's the name of who wrote that?
And then right away I got Charles
Dickens.
There you go.
That's the secret.
Uh
so you see that what we like to think
that we are our problem is personal but
it's really a collective problem that
you share with all of mankind
and that makes you feel a little less
guilty.
It's not the personal self. It's the
human ego which comes out of the
structure of the brain itself plus the
human experience of life on this planet.
We want to surmount and transcend the
common human feelings that are inherent
in the structure of the human ego. The
human ego. Not your ego but the human
ego. So you would say well that is
characteristic of the human ego
just like I blame blame my brain for
having defective neurons.
It's better to have poor neurons than to
be wrong and bad.
Okay. One see because it becomes the
fault of nature then. Okay. Next slide.
Okay.
The ego was inherited along with
becoming a human being. So the ego is a
product of the brain and the function of
the brain and
details
differ based on past karma of how this
is expresses itself. So the ego is one
thing, the brain function is another and
then you add to it past karma.
Now karma is not that well known in the
western world.
But um once you grab on to karma, you'll
find that it's a very handy tool.
Caramel. I'll have a chocolatecovered
caramel, please.
All right. What's the next story?
Intense prayer augments
dedication and inspiration and
facilitates progress.
So we do something we give
we give loving service to all those who
are around us
intense dedication
prayer and appeal to God. Dear God,
please help me
in this endeavor and you call upon all
the good camera you can think of. All
the people you've been nice to.
All the money you put in to play at
church.
All the old ladies you helped across the
street.
All the starving little doggies that you
gave something to eat.
All right.
What's the next one now?
The grace of God is available to
everyone.
That's the most encouraging one of all.
When you ask God for help, God's grace
is available to everyone.
We've been in there to some interesting
places in which the word grace, Grace
Cathedral,
we were in Grace Cathedral not long ago.
So the word grace is really really a
wonderful world word. The grace of God
is available to all.
Historically,
the grace of the sage is available to
the committed spiritual seeker. The
grace of the sage. Uhhuh.
So
the
consciousness of the spiritual teacher,
especially the sage,
radiates forth into the world,
radiates forth into the audience.
The grace of the sage is transmitted by
the actual physical presence of the
consciousness of the teacher.
I wish it would go via the written page,
but it the laws of consciousness are
that the power of the teacher transmits
into the consciousness of the student
and therefore unfortunately
one does have to go to the actual
physical presence of the teacher at some
point in one's spiritual evolution.
Yeah. Happily there's enough power
available
in the teachers that are available
because they it accumulates over time.
So the spiritual power of the great
teachers
who once lived but are no longer in the
living body
is still available because it's
transmitted down from one stage to the
consciousness level of the next.
But there is
a definite value to being in the
physical presence of the consciousness
of the teacher.
All right.
Uhhuh.
The strength of the ego can be quite
formidable
and without the assistance of the power
of a higher spiritual beings, the ego
cannot of itself be transcended.
So one indirect
benefit one gets from being in the
physical presence of the consciousness
field of a enlightened teacher is that
it diminishes the hold of the ego and
increases your power to transcend it.
This is because of your own intention.
A person who does not wish this to
happen, it will not happen. You say, "I
refuse to listen to this guy. I'm not
going to pay attention. He's full of
bunk. Then that is what it will be with
you and uh things will remain the same.
Skepticism and doubt therefore is not of
any great service.
All right. The strength, huh?
>> Oh,
she wants me to take a break.
All right. I'll get in with you in a
minute. The strength of the ego can be
formidable and without the assistance of
the power of higher spiritual beings,
the ego cannot of itself transcend
itself. Boppo,
>> what are we going to take a break?
>> Yeah, we're going to take about 15
minute break.
>> We're going to take a 15minute break.
Stay out of trouble.