All right. At that point, I want to introduce Dr. Hawkins.
Okay. Power to the people.
I hear a thumping. They're coming after me. Thump, thump. The thump, thumps almost got me,
but they did not succeed because I have a will of iron. I iron my will all the time.
As you can see, we're very serious about things this morning.
Well, I've greeted the people in my usual style of absurdity, which is the only sanity left.
Absurdity is the only sanity left to mankind. So we're going to answer any questions people
may have this morning. Is that what we're doing? I read that. You want to read that?
Okay. I thank you for your infinite love beyond the time and space.
He has to be closer to the mic. A little bit closer to the mic, yeah.
We came from Korea. We came from Korea, South Korea. We have gone through a hard time
to get permission to come here. They had a hard time getting permission to come here.
Yes. Because I am an army officer. Because what? He's an army officer.
Oh, yeah. To come here, I have to obtain permission from my four bosses.
It is so difficult and a complicated process. I intensely aspire.
He's got to be closer to the mic. It's all right.
I intensely aspire to attend. He's got to be closer to the mic, please. Your mouth.
Good.
Thank you.
What did you say?
It's very difficult for him to come from Korea because he has four different bosses,
basically, to get permission from.
Yes.
So he is thankful that he's able to get permission to come this time as well as he
wants to know if it's in the highest good that he come, if possible, to come here.
He wants to know what's in the highest good?
If it serves the highest good for him to come here.
Is that what you want?
It's a little late to ask that, isn't it?
Well.
No, he ...
My asking is prayer, your prayer for me.
He wants you to pray for him to be able to come.
To continue to come here.
It's in his own highest good to be here, Jesus. And we pray for his welfare, O Lord. Amen.
We want to come here.
We went to Korea, Susan and I, some years ago.
Was it once or twice?
Twice.
We went to Korea twice, yes.
And it takes too long to fly there now.
They were going to have supersonic jets.
Well, they never got around to the supersonic jets.
But I thought if they got around to supersonic jets,
we would fly there again.
And we had a wonderful time in Korea, yes.
Yeah, we loved the country.
I know right now that Korean is under great stress
as far as it goes with North Korea,
so we appreciate very much that you were able to come to this panel.
And this is a gift from me and my wife.
Next questioner.
Could you take a picture with us?
Well, thank you for coming all the way here.
All the way from North Korea to be here.
They're the Koreans, I'm not...
Thank you.
Yeah, we flew twice to Korea.
Met with a lot of government people.
Now, she's going to read one, too.
They already, because they speak very little English...
Oh, oh, oh.
I see.
I don't speak much Korean, either.
Yes.
Recently,
I have,
intensely prayed to dear Lord
to make me an instrument of the Lord
and surrender my life,
my being,
and my existence.
But when I pray to God,
your image comes to mind,
then I can't differentiate God from you
to whom I pray.
Your energy is closer to me
than even Jesus Christ.
Your voice rings in my ears.
And I am anxious without your picture in my sight.
I devote my time to listen to your DVDs
and read your books as much as possible.
Is it okay that I cherish you in my heart
as God's image,
or am I idol-worshipping?
Oh, my God.
What did she say?
Yep.
Huh?
What'd she say, huh?
Well, she...
I think it's because,
you know,
God and Doc are totally separate,
but his message is
a combination of
self-realization of your own spiritual worth.
So, basically,
the messages are all the same.
Yeah.
The messages are all the same.
What messages?
I don't know what he's talking about.
All right.
Well, you go ahead and answer it, then.
Answer it?
I don't know what the question is.
Well, she said she listens to your DVDs every day.
Oh.
And she cannot distinguish between you and God.
And is she idol-worshipping?
Well, God really speaks to all of us.
And it's only a matter of learning how to listen.
God speaks to all of us, all the time.
And then we learn how to listen.
We walk through the woods,
and we hear the birds singing.
And if you're naive, you don't realize
that's God singing to you via the bird.
Everything that presents itself to you
is divinity,
because nothing else but divinity exists.
Ha, ha, ha.
All that exists is divinity.
Nothing else exists.
Therefore, you don't have to worry about finding God.
God's everywhere.
What you have to come to is the realization
that the essence of everything that exists is divinity.
Nothing exists except God.
Therefore, we treat everything in life with respect.
We treat everything and everyone with respect,
because everyone and everything reflects
divinity.
Other than God, what could there be?
Non-God?
Ha, ha, ha.
This is God.
This is not God.
Ha, ha, ha.
Thank you for coming up.
Thank you.
Blessing for my spiritual pathway.
Bless for me.
Mm.
Oh.
What did you want to test?
Bless.
Oh, she wants a blessing.
I'm sorry.
She wants a blessing.
No, no.
Ha, ha, ha.
Please.
Well, maybe.
Okay.
God bless you, sweetheart.
Thank you.
Ha, ha, ha.
God bless your courage for coming up in front of the audience
and speaking to us all.
Mm.
Thank you for coming here.
May I hold your hand?
Now what?
Ha, ha, ha.
Now she wants a lollipop.
You want a lollipop?
Ha, ha, ha.
You want dessert on top of it?
What do you want now?
Ha, ha, ha.
Oh, thank you.
Okay.
All right, sweetheart.
Ha, ha, ha.
Thank you.
You're very brave to come up in front of a whole audience.
Yeah.
Hello.
I don't have a question, and I just wanted to meet you and to come up and to say thank
you for being a light in the world.
I can't understand what this microphone said.
What did she just say?
She just wants to thank you.
Thank you for being here in the world with the work that you're doing.
Oh.
Yes.
Well, I didn't have much to say about it.
God said, you're going now.
I said, okay, boss.
Ha, ha, ha.
Lovely.
Yeah.
Ha, ha, ha.
We incarnate when divinity wills it, when it's God's will for us to become a human again,
and we do so.
Mm-hmm.
And in the world of the physical expression, when we're done with that, we retreat back
to the world of spirit, and then maybe reemerge later again in the world of the physical.
So it's up to God's will.
Mm-hmm.
Thank you.
And if you don't obey God's will, uh-oh, you're in trouble.
Mm.
Ha, ha, ha.
And can I have a blessing from you?
God bless you.
Amen.
Thank you.
Thank you, Susan.
Ha, ha.
Hello.
My question is in regards to prayer.
In one of your lectures, you talk about clearing things using intense prayer.
And I'm wondering how one makes their prayers intense or how you make your prayers intense?
I don't understand the question.
Um, you talked about a clearing prayer, you know.
Oh, a clearing prayer.
Oh, yes.
And so...
you can minimize, I guess, through extensive prayer.
So he says, how do you do that?
Intense prayer.
How do you do that?
The clearing prayer, yes.
Well, when you say that you're intensely praying,
how is that different than a regular prayer?
Yes.
It's not really different.
It's a degree of intensity.
I don't know how to explain to people intensity.
The amount of energy and power that you give it,
and you invoke it.
If you invoke it in God's name,
in the name of the Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit,
now and forever, amen,
then you are invoking it very, very strongly.
And the intensity of your devotion
and
the level of one's own personal energy tends to increase it.
To pray intensely, in a way, redoubles it,
because in a way, all you're doing is reflecting back to God
that which is divinity in the first place,
which is manifesting as your existence.
But you don't have to figure that out.
Thank you.
I just want to first express my great gratitude to you guys.
I've had...
a lot of serenity since I've been coming here.
My question has to do with a potential university...
my potential university education.
Your potential university education?
Correct.
Yes.
You state that a true liberal education
is the great books of the Western world.
What?
You said that the great books of the Western world
is what you read when you...
Yeah.
That would be the equivalent of going to college, yeah.
I've been accepted into a program
where the curriculum is great books of the Western world.
Oh, yes.
At a small college.
Yeah, I forget the name of that college.
What's the name of the college?
It's St. John's College.
Yeah, St. John's.
That's correct.
Their curriculum is the great books of the Western world.
Great books of the Western world.
I remember calibrating it.
A calibrator is quite high, I guess.
Yeah, I guess that's my question is
you speak extensively in your lectures
and books about the fall of academia.
About what?
What do you think?
I don't know.
Something about academia.
What?
You've spoken extensively about the...
the...
lack of integrity in academia in today's world.
And I guess my question is I feel drawn to this study
and I guess I'm not...
I'd like to know if the integrity of the program is still intact.
At St. John's?
At St. John's, that's correct.
Yes, he wants to know if it's still...
All right.
The integrity...
We have permission to ask this about St. John's.
The integrity of their curriculum is still intact.
They follow the great books of the Western world, yes.
Thank you.
Yes.
It calibrates higher than Harvard.
That should be good enough.
Not that Harvard calibrates all that high, but...
Harvard's got the name,
but this other college has the integrity.
Okay.
Yes, go ahead.
Good morning.
In healing and recovery,
you have a chapter on death and dying.
And you describe one can use their imagination
to help those close to death.
For instance, someone in the battlefield
or even yesterday in Japan.
Can you clarify how to do this process
if you don't know anyone specifically
that you would be using your imagination?
In behalf of the people who are praying for help.
Japan's full of people.
People are praying for help.
And so you try to reinforce it
by collaborating with them,
adding the energy of your own psyche
to their intention
to increase the effectiveness of their prayer.
Thank you.
Yes.
It's like you're praying in their behalf.
In their behalf.
So you don't have to be specific.
No.
You can if you want.
But if you don't know an individual,
I don't know any individuals in Japan right now.
But I can pray on behalf of those who are suffering
and threatened for their peace of mind.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Good morning.
Hello.
Dr. Hawkins, my question is several years ago,
I was in, I had a rebirthing session.
Yes.
And I thought I had a question.
I thought I had a question.
I had a question.
What is your question?
I don't know.
I'm not sure.
You don't have to ask.
I don't have to ask.
I don't know.
But I had a question.
Yes.
And my heart opened up like a flower so slowly.
And I felt absolute, undescribable total peace.
You felt what?
Peace.
Oh yes.
Total peace.
Indescribable peace.
Yes, yes, yes.
It's a profound peace.
All over my body.
Completely.
Yes.
And it was residual.
It lasted for several months.
And I was just wondering if I could have that calibrated?
Would that be okay?
How?
What calibrated?
That, that event.
Yes.
Did she have that event calibrated that she had?
That spiritual experience that I had.
We have permission to calibrate that event.
It's over 500, 560, 580, 575.
It's a very high level of love, yes.
Thank you.
It's kind of like a peak at what could be.
Uh-huh.
Okay, right.
Did you re-experience your own birth?
No.
Oh, you didn't?
No, that's the only, I mean, that was wonderful.
That was what I experienced.
Oh.
And I wondered if I could receive the transmission.
I've heard people ask, and I'm not sure.
She wondered what?
If she could receive the transmission,
which is what you get when you see the teacher.
When you see the teacher, that's what you get,
is that silent transmission.
It's automatic, it's automatic.
It's a silent transmission,
and that's what you get when you see it.
It's automatic, yes.
Okay, thank you.
Mm-hmm.
And I appreciate both of you very much.
And the community that you have, too.
Thank you.
Some people experience their birth,
re-experience their own birth.
Hello.
Hi.
I'm in graduate school.
Mm-hmm.
She's in graduate school.
Oh, yes.
And there's something that's really been bothering me.
Something's really bothering me.
Something's bothering you.
Mm-hmm.
Yes, that's a statement.
You make it like a question.
I seem to have.
Make it a statement.
Is that a fact, or are you asking me?
It's a fact.
It's a fact?
Yeah, it's bothering me.
There's something that's bothering me.
Something is bothering me, not something's bothering me?
Something is bothering me.
Something's bothering me.
All right, thank you.
I seem to have a learning disability.
Yeah.
She has what?
She, I don't know if she has one or not, but she seems to think
that she has a learning disability.
Yeah, maybe so.
All humans do.
All humans have a learning disability.
They'd all be enlightened already.
The average person is pretty dumb.
You watch the evening news, you realize how dumb.
Well, anyway, go ahead.
Well, she buzzed me off there.
Okay.
Anyway.
I had to fly around looking at her.
That's a little better.
I'll settle down again.
What disability do you have?
I'm having a hard time learning higher math, understanding what my teacher is teaching.
Yes.
I'm having a hard time understanding when he's trying to teach me.
Uh-huh.
So?
So, what is the question?
I don't know what to ask.
Have you got a tutor?
I do.
Yeah.
Well, sometimes.
Well, you're going as far as you can.
You know, higher math is really not your subject.
You know what I mean?
What do you want higher math for, for God's sake?
Do you have to have higher math before you graduate?
You don't even like higher math.
You don't understand higher math.
You're not born for higher math.
What are you doing in a higher math class?
That's what I'm wondering.
Don't you have a student counselor?
Yeah.
Does your counselor advise that you take higher math?
Send the counselor in to see me, will you, please?
Okay.
Do you like sending me to be an artist?
Yes.
I'm a college student.
Do you want to be an artist?
You know what I mean?
Uh huh.
Um hm.
Ha ha.
Do you need this in order to graduate?
This higher math course or do you need, can you substitute another course?
I can check.
Yeah, check and see.
But ...
Well, I don't know if she needs this to graduate.
She's, you know ...
Oh, yeah.
... that, but she can sometimes substitute a different course.
You can maybe substitute something else.
Okay.
Some, I mean it's just, some of us just don't click when it comes to higher math.
the stuff try clay modeling or something it's not that you it's not that you have a disability
that's that's something that's another thing you don't have a disability it's just that some things
make sense to you other than others so it's not a disability yes when i go to the tutoring lab
and i point something out that i see the tutor will say how did you see that and i said i just
see that this needs to collapse to zero in order for this to be true and this to be true and he
goes how did you do that and i say i don't know but i have a hard time following their
logic and i guess i don't know yes uh-huh uh-huh it's not a disability okay you don't have a
disability okay thank you susan yeah it's not i have a ballet dancing disability myself
okay i've seen you dance you do not have that
yeah i'm going with the masculine
stereotype yeah oh yes it's such an honor to meet you both thank you so much for this time
thank you for all your work and your dedication and your devotion and just before i ask my question
i just want to say for quite a while now i've gotten to that point where the love is just
booming out of my chest you know that feeling where you just love you're just in that state
of love and if you go down a little you get right back up there and it's such a wonderful thing that
when you do the work you do get the result
god bless you amen and now my question is this i've read your books but i still want you to
please clarify for me simply what you see the connection between grace and karma well nobody's
ever asked me that it's been on my mind for a while certainly grace would be both dependent
and independent grace would
i've experienced that i'm blessed i'm blessed grace means that despite our stupidity our
our sins our errors of omission and commission that god is still the available to us god is still
available to us and uh the miraculous still can occur even though it would seem like
one is a great sinner and not deserving of a miracle so can grace cut out all karma that's what
i meant yeah grace can cut out all karma resist yeah hallelujah otherwise none of us would ever
get to heaven would we you think of all the karma of all your previous lifetimes that's what i
believe and thank you that puts you in prison for quite a while bless you bless you thank you
you're young you think god won't notice sometimes you're supposed to have two pieces of candy and
you take three and you figure god maybe god won't notice
yes hi dr hawkins and susan i have to read because i lose it as soon as i get up here
at the at the beginning of discovering your work and for many years after there is like this
intense inner angst to go home like i'd be willing to go home and i'd be willing to go home
and i'd be willing to walk through bullets this feeling of um that he that he talks about
and then over the years it's sort of dissipated and there's more balance and more peace but i'm
wondering if um if i'm distracted if this is a pit stop or if i've fallen for spiritual errors
what's she asking periodically she feels like she falls
from grief no um what it is is that um it's i'm trying to think of what how to put it
but um you probably had a high experience it's more of like the intent like right the feeling
but it's a that's a it's a feeling but it's more of a high experience where you know everything
looks beautiful to you and then all of a sudden it kind of wanes it was more like um
like a
this inner feeling of being willing to walk through anything to die for god and that was
a true um intention and feeling and over the years i don't know if i've gotten distracted
um or what but that feel that that feeling of the intention is gone not gone it's just not the same
that intensity
of focus is not the same that's what i'm asking well that's normal those things fluctuate normally
okay you go into very high states then you go into states where nothing seems to be happening
spiritually for years even and then you can suddenly unexpectedly go back into a very intense
state again so that it doesn't follow any rational reasonable logical course it fluctuates
like the weather you know what i mean there's intense sunsets
sunshine and then it's chilly and then and so there's no way to turn it into a rational expectation
the fluctuation depends on many things karmic and otherwise i have a question once you experience
a high state like that where you you know would walk through bullets for your faith yeah um
and do you i mean it doesn't it doesn't stay with you forever but you know that you're capable of
doing that so if you ever had to pull that up will that come back up if you ever had to have it yes you
know it's there okay so you know you can face bullets and uh world war ii we did so it's kind of like
it's always with you the capacity is there right like for love of your comrades on the ship you're
willing to face death but but when you're when you're ashore
and life is just normal you wouldn't you wouldn't go to such an extreme it's like when the occasion
calls for it you discover you have strength in you that you never knew you had before
that you can face death with the impunity you know like i told that one guy when he said we're
what happens if we blow up i said well then we die big deal so he said yeah you're right so you die
at that moment
so it has nothing to do with failing to keep focused okay thank you very much yeah you don't
need a high state like that all the time you only need it when you're out on the track
running around the track oh you can't go out that way you fall over and um oh okay i'm sorry
i thought there's no stairway off this way and hard fall oh okay oh
not intended all right you clicked that you pressed the uh camera oh you did okay hi i am
wondering if you would be willing to calibrate this teacher that i have and i didn't i didn't
want to say it out loud calibrate what a teacher a teacher living teacher no we won't do a living
teacher okay because it ends up on internet and everything we won't we will not calibrate a living
teacher okay
um could you calibrate whether it's in my highest good to have this teacher
we could do that yes uh this teacher would serve her highest good resist yes
okay be a good teacher for you now thank you and thank you for your teachings and your gift to the
world thank you thank you hello um i'd like to thank you uh for all your teachings and all your
work and
i uh you inspired a poem and here's a poem i wrote um that's uh a appreciative gift for you
uh no i'm too shy to read it but that's for you thank you thank you very much and i also have a
question um um i heard on one of your cds that you um uh had calibrated uh um zen buddhist teachers
in in the united states and there were none that calibrated over 500 and i was wondering if you could
do a calibration of that is that possible i've already said it so what are the what do you want
i just want to confirm that that's what i that's what i heard or if that's what you read what it is
right now or i had heard it on a on one of your cds did you read it i heard it on a cd i thought
i had heard it on a cd oh it was on a cd
i don't remember that cd okay i have permission to answer this that was a correct statement
okay thank you very much appreciate it so they're all at about 500 here in the u.s
i forgot last time we calibrated them all yeah it was disappointing as i remember
okay but you see you don't have to become uh uh enlightened uh to teach spiritual truth
i mean a lot of you know there's thousands of people teaching the life of teaching christianity
that doesn't mean that they have become christ-like i haven't met any christ christ-like
people in weeks so would it would it still be in my highest good um to follow a zen buddhist
teacher who calibrates under 500 we have permission to ask this the answer is yes the answer is yes
okay yeah thank you very much i appreciate it it doesn't mean that he's enlightened but
right you could learn from his teaching exactly right okay yeah that's the reason people go
it's the reason people go to church it doesn't mean that the priest has to become
you know calibrated a thousand the same as jesus christ right that wouldn't be my expectation yeah
okay and but for zen buddhists to follow zen buddhist practice to help me along the path
okay thank you very much appreciate it at one time or another just about everybody's useful along the
path you know what i mean my question is about parents i'm kind of curious if before we incarnate
on this life do we pick our parents or our family for the highest karmic undoing um when we come
before we come back into this life do we pick our parents for the highest karmic learning i don't
know i don't know
Do we pick our parents?
Okay, we have permission to ask this.
We do have a say in picking our parents.
And the spiritual levels are very determining.
Yep.
Thank you.
That undoes a lot.
I have very spiritually committed parents, you know.
Extremely, very intense.
We went to church every Sunday.
Boy, oh boy.
And we didn't eat any meat during Lent.
Much less on Good Friday.
If you ate meat on Good Friday, you'd probably go to hell, I thought.
Yes.
I've had many high experiences in my lifetime.
Lots of miracles.
Wonderful things.
Had abusive parents.
Ironic on that last question.
Physically.
And emotional.
Ended up marrying a woman much like an emotional abusive mother.
Much like what?
The emotional abusive mother that he had.
Oh, uh-huh.
Why is that?
But anyhow, it's not my question.
Emotionally abusive?
You stupid idiot.
Yeah.
What's the deal?
What a dumb guy.
It was familiar.
I guess.
Yeah.
That ended up in divorce.
Oh.
Yay.
Okay, so the propensity is that I got in trouble a lot as a child.
And I always had that feeling of going to the principal's office in the pit of my stomach.
And it seems such a paradox to have really high experiences and a wonderful relationship with divinity.
And then all of a sudden, you just feel in your gut that...
You know, here it comes.
Understanding this is certainly ego attachments.
But I just can't figure out how to unlock it.
How to...
I surrendered it.
But I'm missing something.
I guess that other people have hurt me.
Or I guess it's starting to come clear that am I angry at myself for walking into this situation and allowing...
Things...
It's a mystery still to me.
I don't quite understand it yet.
You don't understand what?
I don't get what the question is.
I'm sorry.
Your life gets screwed up periodically.
That occurred...
That applies to everybody on the planet.
Yep.
Yeah.
For what is it?
For me?
I don't know.
I...
I thought I knew what I was going to ask you when I was over here.
And I'm really confused right now.
I'm sorry.
I think that's part of it.
Always...
Fearful of...
Of getting everybody's approval.
You know, rather than just standing up for the...
I don't know.
I'm...
I'm completely confused.
Yeah.
The minute you bring a third party in, you're adding to the confusion.
Their opinion, their attitude, their approval.
Yeah.
So you have to let go wanting other people's approval in order to get your own.
Isn't that so?
As long as you're wanting everybody...
Everybody's approval, then you haven't achieved your own.
When you become independent of other people's opinions, it doesn't mean to become ignorant
of them.
Sure.
A lot of people become clumsy and stupid, and it'd be better that they stayed in bed
all day.
Yep.
Okay.
Perfect.
Thank you.
Also, you need to forgive.
Yeah.
Because...
They were...
Doing their best.
Well, I don't know that they were even doing their best, but you have to forgive them for
what took place.
Yeah.
Okay.
You're trying to soft-soap it, but it wasn't.
I mean, if they really did...
You really were miserable, then they weren't doing their best.
You don't...
So you need to just forgive them and put it in the past and realize that you're destined
for other things.
Right.
In the future.
But you have to let go of that, because that's holding you down.
Yeah.
Every now and then, there's an occasional zinger.
Just a couple months ago, my mom threw a grenade in my lap, and she's so disappointed at the
way I turned out.
Right.
His mom threw a grenade in his lap, because she was disappointed on the way he turned
out.
A grenade?
Yeah.
I think you need to forgive him and walk away.
Well, I moved.
So...
Yeah.
I would, too.
Fast.
Do you want to get a picture?
Yeah.
Well, it's nice if your mother can be proud of you.
She's so wonderful.
I always worked for my mother's approval.
I always got her approval, because...
I did what she approved of.
It makes it simple.
Okay.
Hello.
Good morning.
Dr. Hawkins, thank you very much for being here with us today.
I have recently been dealing with a sarcoma cancer issue.
You got to speak slowly, and then the mic.
You recently have what?
I have recently been dealing with a sarcoma cancer issue.
A cancer issue.
She what?
It's...
She's been dealing with cancer.
Yes.
so I have accepted that
as my karma
I have accepted that as my karma
I understand from your teachings
that at some level
I may have attracted this to me
I understand from your teachings
that I may have attracted this to me
well attraction is not exactly the right word
created it
occasioned it
so getting any kind of an illness
could have a karmic antecedent
that is true
so if that is true
from now on
how does one not attract illness to them
it is not the right wording attract
you make it sound like a bug flying around
and you attract the bug
and he lands on your arm
how do you avoid the consequences
of having bad karma
is really what she is saying
well what you do is
you try to create as much good
karma for yourself
as you can to counterbalance it
you try to counterbalance it
you try to compensate for it
by as much
spiritual evolution
as you can
accomplish
and the rest is up to God
you know
yes thank you
thank you very much
I would like a picture
and stay out of trouble
I don't have a question
I just want to say thank you
and I also have a gift for you
thank you
I had a desire to meet you
and to be close to you
and I am thankful for God that I
I am thankful for God that I am here
and I have had that opportunity today
and I just ask your blessings on my life
he just wanted to meet you
and ask your blessings
on opening the heart
and your blessings on opening
the heart up
oh God bless you
thank you
kaboom
can I shake your hand?
sure come over here
now he wants my hand
good God what else?
thank you
Thank you guys for your dedication and willingness.
I'm from China.
Right now the government lacks transparency.
Right now what?
The government lacks transparency.
Transparency and-
In China?
Yeah.
Integrity.
And the media is blocked and controlled by the government.
So democracy is a really big issue there, and it's influencing all the people.
So my question is, as a citizen and simply a human being, what can I do to improve the
situation?
Improve the situation where?
In China, because they're blocking all the media and the internet, they only allow certain
things to come into China, and it has to do with the politics.
So as a person-
Has to do with what?
Well, it has to do with the politics.
The politics of the country.
The climate.
Oh.
Uh-huh.
So as an individual, what could he do that would change this situation?
I don't advise trying to change it.
Right.
Not unless you're willing to die soon.
Are you?
No.
Not right now.
If I was the emperor of China and you came to me with that, I would ask them to remove
your head promptly.
It's a disrespect for authority.
Yeah.
See, in a certain culture, authority necessitates respect, and it's not up to you to decide
who deserves it, who deserves respect.
It's not up to you.
The king is the king.
Even if he's a bad king, he's still the king.
So the sovereign is still the sovereign.
So you have to respect the position of the sovereign and ignore the personality.
Yeah.
Many of the great kings of history were terrible people.
But they were still king, whether you liked it or not.
So ...
So we cannot pick or choose.
Do you think that this could be turned around by prayer, or ...
What turned around?
Well, the situation that the government is blocking all outside information ...
No, I don't think so.
So he just has to know that this is the way it is, and that's it?
Yeah.
That's the way it is.
But people will ... democracy will still be insufficient in China, keep being like that?
It might change, but it's going to take a while before China gets caught up with the
rest of the world.
It might change tomorrow.
We don't know.
But ...
Well, you see, all kinds of situations change.
You get idealistic about how a country should behave.
What do you do about overpopulation?
I don't know.
Pass a law.
Give up sex.
No more babies.
China allows you one baby, huh?
Yes.
You're allowed one baby.
But if I marry a single child from the family, I'm allowed to have two.
Okay.
Yeah.
So I read your book, The Truth Versus Falsehood.
In that book, you ... the China ... Chinese government is calibrated in 190, right?
Which is ...
Yeah.
At that time.
Can you calibrate right now the Chinese government?
Right now, Chinese government ... We have permission to do Chinese government
right now.
It's over 190, 195, 200, 199, 198, 195.
Chinese government has come up.
It's coming up?
Yeah.
It is still growing.
But it's still ... Yeah.
So it is looking like it is going towards change.
But it's just gonna take a while.
but it's just going to take a while.
And as a citizen, I can only accept the fact.
That's your opinion. That's your advice, right?
Well, China has been like it has been for many, many, many, many years.
And the world around it has changed, you know,
while China still remains as it was.
So it'll take a while before the change will come up and take over,
but it will eventually come.
Well, you see, in a democracy,
the head of the country changes all the time.
This person's here for four years,
then he goes out and somebody else comes in.
It's constantly changing.
Yeah.
Trying to think what the politics were in China when I was there.
I was in China a couple of times
trying to remember what the politics was at the time.
Right now, you can't have more than one child, yes?
Unless you marry someone that's a single.
A single child, yeah.
Uh-huh, uh-huh.
So, you know, the rulers do what they can with the situation,
and then when the situation changes, they must change, you know?
So as a citizen, I just await the situation change?
Yes.
You can talk about it, but, yeah, you have to wait for it to change.
Okay. Thank you, Doctor. Thank you, Susan.
I loved China when I was there.
I loved the country.
Thank you.
Okay, let's do one more.
Yeah, great food, too.
All the restaurants were great.
I know.
Hi.
I just wanted to thank you and ask for a blessing.
What did he say?
He wants to ask for a blessing.
Yes.
God bless you.
What else?
I have a question.
What?
You have a question?
Yes, I have a question.
Okay.
If you could please expand on fulfilling your potential a little bit,
because I am confused sometimes between working too much as a part of my function here
and wasting time for spiritual progress.
He wants you to talk about one's potential.
He feels like he devotes a lot of time to...
to work, and that, you know, there's...
All of us do that, and there's very little time left over for spiritual work.
Oh.
And so the balance, you know, sometimes we just...
Well, that's the wrong way of looking at it.
Right.
Yeah.
Spiritual is an inner attitude, and nothing can interrupt it.
It has nothing to do with work, because to be in a certain...
attitude or way with life, it doesn't depend on what's going on out there.
To be appreciative of life in all of its expressions,
to be grateful for life in all of its expressions,
does not put any requirements on life.
It puts the requirement on you.
You have to be happy whether it's raining or whether the sun is shining.
You can't say, well, I'm only going to be happy when the sun shines.
No.
You begin to see that all the weather is fun.
If it's a rainy day this morning, you say, well, wow, it's raining today.
If it's sunny, you say, oh, wow, it's a sunny day.
If it's snowing, you say, hey, look, it's snowing.
You see what I'm saying?
Hello?
Is he home?
Yes.
This week, a week ago, we had a very exciting morning.
We got up, and Susan said, it's snowing outside.
Yay!
Man, I jump all over the place.
If you live in Arizona, if it's snowing, it's a big day.
If you live in New York, snowing is not a big day.
So context decides the significance and meaning of things.
Is it just snow?
No, it's snow where and when and under what circumstance.
And if you've had a whole winter of snow,
the fact that it's snowing today is not exactly good news.
So that's what I mean by context.
So the significance of many things in our life,
you know, very dependent on context to whom it's happening and when
and in what kind of a situation.
As a woman will say, to be pregnant at a certain time and month in her life was fantastic.
If it had happened under different circumstances, she'd think of suicide.
You know what I'm saying?
Yeah.
Thank you very much.
Can I have a picture?
Sure.
So circumstances contribute to the meaning, yeah?
Okay, we're going to take a quick break, about 15 minutes,
and then we'll come back and finish questions.
Bum-pa-bum-pum.
Try to get them to say bum-pa-bum-pum.
Our bird says bum-pa-bum-pum.
All the police, I think I'm being kidnapped.
Oh, God bless you all.
God bless you all for being here.
I give thanks for their presence.
Amen.
Oh, hello.
I want to thank you for beautiful work, and you.
I was in Thailand at a monastery for about 150 days, where I want to reach enlightenment.
You've got to speak slower and right into the mic.
You were in Thailand?
In an Indiana Buddhist center, monastery, where I want to reach enlightenment.
But I had difficulties with negative.
I'm not hearing them.
Difficulties with negative energy.
Oh, okay.
What does he mean by negative entities?
Negative thoughts or what?
Yeah, I don't know.
It comes true, and then I couldn't do my thing.
Like, I really want to go to reach enlightenment, but it threw my mind, and I didn't reach.
Yes.
So do you have any?
Is there any, I don't know, answer for it, or?
He really felt like he applied himself to reach enlightenment, but it didn't.
He didn't reach it, so is there any?
What did he think he was going to do?
Get enlightened between Monday and Friday, or what?
You got another 50 years to worry about.
Okay.
No, what you do is you state your intention.
Yeah.
And then you surrender it to God.
Don't keep trying to control it.
Okay.
When you ask God to reach enlightenment, it's now up to God, not up to you.
And if it's slated to happen, then it will happen, and nothing can stop it.
It's not slated to happen.
Nothing will make it happen.
Okay.
Except that you will end up at death as a frustrated devotee.
Well, you have to have some kind of karma in the next lifetime.
So to die in this lifetime, a frustrated devotee.
Probably would have a very good God will feel sorry for you, and you get reborn in Zen Monastery or something.
Okay.
So don't worry about it.
Surrendering it to God means surrendering it to God.
Okay.
And if you're meant to be enlightened, then it will come about no matter what.
It requires several things.
One is karmic propensity, infinite divine mercy, and many other things.
Okay.
And many other factors of which we do not know.
When it comes on, it is very sudden and very unexpected and very profound, profoundly changes
everything.
What everything looks like, what it seems to be, what its reality is, all changes.
Thank you very much.
And once it's changed, so you can see from a changed viewpoint, then you're not being
frustrated.
All right?
Yes.
What about being frustrated?
May I take a picture?
Yes.
Yeah.
Being frustrated means that you're, you know, not surrendering to God's will.
God's will is things happen by karmic propensities, plus God's will, plus many circumstances of
which we have no awareness.
Thank you very much.
I think it's the willingness that counts more than anything.
Yes.
Namaste.
Dr. Hawkins, I'm very blessed to be in your presence.
I was told six months ago that I would meet my teacher that I have studied with in past
lives, and I knew it was you, and I'm very blessed that you are here in my life and in
everyone's life.
I appreciate that.
I have permission to ask what's on my mind.
I am that teacher. Resist.
Oh, what do you know?
You look familiar from a couple thousand years ago.
I remember you from Fum Boo, the year 2012.
Okay, no, I'm glad you've returned.
I have a question.
Yes.
My question is about choiceless awareness.
Choices and awareness.
Choiceless.
Choiceless awareness.
Choiceless awareness. What does that mean?
That means once you're in that state of presence,
when you are so imbued in the presence of presence,
that there's no choiceless.
Everything just flows and just happens.
And you've spoken so beautifully about it many, many times.
When you're in that state...
You're always in that state.
So where does...
I realize it.
Yes.
Yeah.
Everything is flowing perfectly with ultimate beauty,
and perfection right now.
It's obvious, right?
It's obvious.
Yes.
So where does choice fit in then?
Oh, that was a long time ago.
So I go back and forth with just being in that choiceless state,
and then the dualistic choice kicks in.
Well, you see, there's what you're thinking about at the moment.
Then there's what your life is really about.
So we don't think every moment about what our life is really about,
because you'd never get a chance to live it.
You spend all your time thinking about it.
So we make our choice, you know, to visit China, see?
Well, that only takes one second to make the choice.
You don't have to think about it on the plane all the way to China,
you know what I'm saying?
I'm choosing to go to China and say, repeat that over and over again.
So you've already made a choice,
and it's sent your life in this direction rather than this direction, see?
So don't worry about it.
Thank you.
Unless you're overcome by evil, your life is fine.
God bless you.
There'll be a hand on you.
Oh, now it's official.
Look, she could be right and I could be wrong, you know what I'm saying?
Get to heaven, and God says,
how come you didn't put your hand on that lady's head?
Send me back to Chicago for a lifer.
Yeah, go ahead.
Good morning.
Yes.
First of all, I want to give you a copy of my master's thesis in divinity,
where I extensively cited your work.
Yes.
Your brilliant work.
Thank you.
And I would like to ask you if you would please calibrate it.
Calibrate the work?
Calibrate it.
Okay, I have permission to calibrate the thesis.
It's over 450, 470, 480, 490.
500.
It's right at 500.
Wow, that's great.
That's very good.
That's excellent.
Who could ask for more?
Pretty good, yeah.
Hello.
I'm very grateful to be here, and thank you.
I have a question about the value of perseverance.
In my work, I have a company that's developing small airplanes, small jets,
and it appears to be.
I'm financially failing, and I have a dilemma of how to know when to move on to something else,
or what the value of it is.
You have a choice?
Well, you can't be in too bad shape if you've got a choice.
Well, having a choice is a blessing, yes.
What is the choice about?
Well, to persevere with it indefinitely, or to let go and move on.
Oh, I see what you mean, yeah.
Yeah.
Other ventures and other things.
You want me to ask the arm?
I would appreciate that very much, sure.
It would be in his, I have permission to ask this.
It would be in his best interest to persevere with this.
Thank you very much.
Could he resume it at a different date?
Well, it may be the wrong time, the wrong company, the wrong financing.
It could be a thousand factors.
Could maybe at a later date?
Oh, should he be, it might be appropriate to return to the same endeavor at a later date.
Or is this, oh, okay.
I just got that.
Oh, yeah, well, you got it, yeah.
Thank you very much.
I appreciate it very much.
May I take your hands?
Yeah.
Thank you.
Yeah, the timing may be off.
Good luck.
Thank you.
Hello.
I gave up wanting things from God for Lent.
What?
She gave up wanting things from God for Lent.
Wanting things from God?
For Lent.
Oh, for Lent.
Yeah.
Wow.
Gee, what if you got them anyway?
What was that?
Well, instead of, well, I'm praying for God's will instead of praying for what.
I see what you mean, yes.
I want his will for me.
Yeah.
That's fine.
Yeah, and when I pray in the morning, when I pray in the morning, I pray what is thy will,
and how can I?
Can I be your servant today?
Yes.
And most often, I just, it's silence.
And I don't know how to know which way to proceed.
My husband said, if you surrender to every moment,
Yes.
then that's being in God's will.
That's true.
Yeah.
Whatever is, is, and we have to assume,
that divinity is the source.
Without divinity, you and I wouldn't be speaking here at this table,
nor would Susan be sitting here, you understand?
So the whole phenomena is a product of multiple composites.
Uh-huh.
And we add our two cents worth in at the end.
And let it be a blue Cadillac, Lord.
Thank you so much.
Yes.
All I want is a mercer to these bands.
I sat next to her one time in an auditorium.
She was on that day.
Janice Joplin.
That's who it was.
I couldn't think of her name.
I'm so happy to be here.
And I'm going to ask a question for my dear friend from Seattle.
She was wondering, and her name is Pam,
how lower astral entities,
are they actually part of God, too,
with having non-duality?
Are they God, too?
What?
Are lower astral entities God, as well?
Is God in them?
They're godless.
That's why they're lower astral.
Okay.
Thank you.
How does that fit with non-duality?
How does that fit?
I don't know what it's got to do with non-duality.
Okay.
Thanks.
Yeah, the denial of God and divine attributes
is what gets you to the lower astral.
Avoid love, choose hate,
choose revenge instead of forgiveness.
That's how you get to hell.
Yeah.
You can tell something's evil when they think hell is a great place.
I'm stomping.
The stomper is here.
What?
I was just having fun with you.
I want to thank you for your essences
and your wonderful gifts of your books and your being.
And I have a question.
I talked to you about seven years ago,
and you helped me a lot at that time.
And my question now is I had an experience where I was meditating,
and there were two triangles that intersected into my heart
and made the shape of the sign of Solomon.
Or the Star of David.
And I was going to ask you the significance
or the calibration of that.
I don't understand what happened to her.
She was meditating, and she had said
there was two triangles, you know, in her mind.
She put her two triangles intercepting into her heart.
Oh, boy.
And then it said, as above, so below.
That was the words I was given.
Uh-huh.
So she's wondering what the...
Let me just calibrate it.
That was over 550, 600, 590.
Yeah.
590, 580.
It was over 580.
Yeah.
It was very good.
It's a nonverbal way of expressing something.
Now you want me to express it verbally.
If it was verbal, I wouldn't.
It wouldn't have come to you that way.
It would be verbal instead of nonverbal.
So if it's nonverbal, then it's not supposed to be verbal.
Thank you.
Verbal anyways, isn't it?
How do you verbalize
with a nonverbal?
There's the dilemma.
It is.
Yeah, it is.
I think that's why I have so much trouble once in a while.
Yeah.
It's like I understand it, but then for verbalizing it.
Yeah, yeah, that's true.
Uh-huh.
Hi.
Hi, Susan.
Hi, Doc.
Yes.
How are you?
I just wanted to thank you both, and I wanted to thank you, Doc,
for being my teacher.
And I just wanted to know if I could just touch your hand
and ask for a blessing.
What does she want now?
A blessing.
Demanding, demanding, demanding.
God bless you, sweetheart.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Hello.
Hello, Doc.
It's been a long time since I've talked to you,
about seven years since I last talked to you.
I'm very pleased and blessed to be in your presence,
and I want to thank you from the bottom of my heart
for all of us for your work and your service and your love.
And my question is regarding.
Pranayama.
You've repeatedly calibrated Pranayama at or below 200.
But I'm a yoga teacher, and that's
one of the eight limbs of Patanjali's Yoga Sutras,
which you've calibrated, I believe, in the 700, 740.
So I'm confused.
Maybe if you could give me some clarity about why Pranayama,
which is the fourth limb, is so low.
I don't remember what he's referring to.
Pranayama.
OK.
We have permission to calibrate Pranayama.
That's that breathing exercise, you know.
It's a breathing exercise.
OK.
It calibrates over 500, calibrates over 495,
calibrates over 350, 380, 340, 350, 350.
A lot of exercises don't calibrate high.
Yeah.
You know, standing on your head, for instance,
probably doesn't calibrate very high.
I'm sure there's yogas based on standing on your head.
There are, yeah.
Because yoga is based on every physical form, yes, or activity.
Yeah.
So you're saying it's actually 350 around there.
About there.
Yeah.
But that's not bad.
It's about 300.
No, that's the same as most Hatha yoga,
as you've calibrated it.
But, you know, if you're talking about enlightenment,
that isn't going to get you there at 350, right?
But it is.
Why are people attracted to the yogas anyway?
Why?
Yeah.
Of various reasons.
You mean the kind of we practice, like common in the West?
Because of what?
The yogas that are common in the West,
like the physical yoga that most of them.
Oh, I see, those yogas, OK.
Yeah, see, he's doing physical yoga.
Oh, I see.
So that all calibrates at about three.
Uh-huh.
Yeah, 40, 350.
Yeah.
But if you were practicing.
It's in a positive direction.
Right.
You see, what impresses me about it,
about the yogas, is the intention behind it,
not the yoga.
Am I enlightened now?
If you do that 1,000 times, now stop and do it 1,000 times
in the other direction.
Am I enlightened now?
I've done it 1,000 times in both directions.
God feels sorry for you.
His angels say, there's a guy who's really willing down here.
So then God says, well, give him a pat.
OK, boom, boom.
Wow, wow, wow, wow, wow, wow.
It verges into, to my way of thinking, magical.
If I breathe this way and stand that way and eat this
and eat that, to my way of thinking,
it's you're trying to employ the magical.
Resist.
OK.
What I'm saying is correct.
You're employing the magical.
You're employing magic.
So a lot of what goes as yoga is just magical thinking.
Hoo-ha, hoo-ha, boo-hoo, hoo-hoo, yee-hee, ha-ha, hoo-hoo, ha-ha.
Am I any closer to God than I was?
But all action.
God's giggling all the time.
All action dedicated to God then would take on the level 540.
Yeah, yeah.
So if I dedicate.
If you're doing it out of devotion to God, yes.
That's it.
OK.
You got it.
That's it.
So you're doing it out of devotion to God.
And then there's the desire for enlightenment.
And you really have to contemplate
what is the correlation between those two things,
surrender to God and reaching enlightenment.
If you surrender to God, you give up
working towards enlightenment because now it's up to God.
You understand the conflict you get into?
Mm-hmm.
But in resolving the conflict, you find your way.
So you don't need to worry.
So sacrifice is giving it up to God is always the ultimate path.
God feels sorry for you in the end.
Yeah, that's right.
Yeah.
I had another question for my friend.
She's very shy, so she didn't come up here.
But she wanted to know, is it healthy for she raises dogs
to let them sleep with you in your bed?
Is that?
Is it helping to allow dogs to sleep in your bed?
Sure.
If you love the dogs, yes.
If you hate the dogs, no.
I think loving pets gets you closer to God.
Loving pets gets you closer to God, resist.
Yeah.
You love your kitties and your doggies and your bunnies
and birdies and chickens and what else we got?
I don't know.
I don't see the end.
I don't think so.
OK.
What's the bird that talks?
Tucks, what, broccoli?
Broccoli, yeah.
What do you call him?
What is he, he's a?
African grey.
African grey parrot, yes.
She.
She's an African grey parrot.
We have an African grey parrot that is a real knock out.
Yeah.
Says the funniest things unexpectedly.
I think, you know, loving all of God's creations
because I love the elephants, too, and I love the tigers.
I think they're all just stunningly beautiful.
One more thing.
I am with a group, SCA, Self-Centered Anonymous,
that is, you may have heard of them.
We meet, well, anyway, they follow your teachings.
We're all followers of you.
And I told them I was coming today,
and they wanted to know if you might have something to say to the group.
What group?
This group he belongs to.
It's a 12-step group.
It's like a 12-step group.
12-step group.
Based on self-centeredness.
Based on what?
Self-centeredness.
You mean you want to become more self-centered?
No, they're trying not to.
Oh.
You want to stop being self-centered.
Is that right?
That's pretty self-centered, to want to stop being self-centered.
The trouble is you're not being self-centered enough.
If you do it with great intensity, nonstop,
then you'll get relieved of it, because you can't.
I know what you're asking, yes.
It's subtle.
How to let things be without projecting one's own willfulness into it.
How to let the world be as it is.
How to let yourself be as you are.
How to let others be as they are.
So you're really asking how to surrender to God, yes.
Mm-hmm.
And if...
If you're self-centered is where you're at with it,
then you surrender to God that you're self-centered.
So you're self-centered.
Big deal.
Is that a sin?
Huh?
Why are you trying to escape it?
I don't think so.
It's the desire to be selfless.
Right.
Uh-huh.
And what is it that desires to be selfless?
The will, you know?
It's just that you've given it direction.
So you're in a good space.
You're in a good pathway.
Wonderful.
Thank you, Doctor.
Don't be impatient.
Thank you.
It only takes 40, 50 lifetimes.
Here comes the clinking, yeah.
You're fine, but...
However, it can also be accomplished in 30 seconds.
By the time you reach the edge of the stage, you will be enlightened.
You have now just entered the world of evolution.
The end of the world.
Thank you.
The time and moment of his enlightenment is now recorded for all of posterity.
It is said that kinesiology test can only be applied to past or present.
However, if there is no such thing as past, present, or future, why kinesiology cannot
be applied to future, or what we define as future, if there is no such thing as future
exists.
I don't understand what she's saying so far.
It's a riddle.
Riddle, riddles?
I don't know.
It's a riddle to me.
Thank you.
She says that if there's no such thing as past, present, and future, then how can you
call it past, present, and future?
Nobody said there is no such thing.
Right.
Mm-hmm.
Nobody said there is no such thing.
Who said there's no such thing?
I think it's in your books.
I don't know.
I don't think we said there was no such thing.
We just said that.
Okay.
Maybe it's a different verbalization.
It's only a way of looking at things.
Yeah.
Arbitrary way of looking at things.
Right.
So what is the question?
If there's no such thing as past, present, and future, then what?
Well, kinesiology test can only be applied.
Okay.
Right.
That's true.
We cannot, we can look at the past because we test the past all the time.
Right.
But we can't look at the future.
Yeah.
Because the future has no existence.
Right.
That's true.
We cannot, we can look at the past.
Right.
Because we test the past all the time.
But we can't look at the future.
Yeah.
Because the future has no existence.
Because the future does not exist.
Right.
But we can look at the present, and we can look at the past.
Or the past.
Yeah.
But we can't look at the future.
Okay.
I will reread your chapter again.
Yeah.
For clarification.
Thank you very much.
But we can't.
Maybe I just, yeah.
Right.
Because anything that's in the past, you know.
All right.
Well, it's a.
Yeah.
But the, but anything that's in the future, you can't see because it hasn't materialized
yet.
And there's free will in there, and it changes.
So you can't look at the future.
Yeah.
Right.
But we can't look at the past.
Because anything that's in the future, you can't see because it hasn't materialized yet.
And there's free will in there, and it changes.
So you can't predict the future.
No.
Like I can't say, invest in this.
This is going to be a good investment because.
Right.
And I'm going to make X amount of dollars.
I can't do that with it.
Hmm.
Life would be very boring if you could.
I just don't.
You know, control and predict the future.
No.
It's not.
It just.
It would be like reading your own mail all day.
Right.
I.
It just said.
At a certain point.
Like you.
Well, I don't know.
Anyway.
Dr. Hoffman.
Yeah.
I don't know.
Anyway.
Dr. Hawkins.
You.
In your book, Truth Versus Falsehood, you calibrated Ramesh Balsekar at 760.
And I never heard afterwards anything you'd.
Well, we didn't read any books about him, did we?
No.
Why would you hear about him?
It wasn't about him, but.
Because he was involved into kind of scanning.
And he was.
He was.
He was killed in the war.
There were scandals.
There were scandals and lawsuits.
I don't know anything about all that.
I mean, either.
When I wrote, you know, it's like if you wrote an encyclopedia in 1956.
That doesn't mean it's supposed to include things that didn't happen until 1980.
So you're not being rational in the expectation.
May ask question.
If at the end of his life, he passed away a couple of years ago, if he calibrated at
760 as, no.
What is that?
It's an elastic.
It's.
What is that?
Some people fall.
Right, and that's my question.
Spiritual teachers fall all the time.
Right.
Yeah.
Money, fame, sex.
Okay.
That takes care of all of them.
That's what rules the world.
Money, fame, and sex.
And their dream is to have all three at one,
become famous,
and have a rich and powerful, seductive girlfriend
who just jumps in bed with you.
That's going back to kindergarten.
Well, it started from the beginning again.
So, okay.
So, no, he didn't.
We won't calibrate him, but he fell after.
Yeah, that's my...
Yeah, but at the time we calibrated him,
he was at that.
Okay.
Yeah, yeah.
Thank you.
And that's been 10 years ago, you know, or more.
Many, the majority, I would think, grew his fall.
It was very high, 760,
and I kind of attracted to his books.
It's straight and plain.
Well, when he...
Sometimes...
When they're writing books and they're doing the work,
their calibrations are very attractive,
but, you know, the work sometimes is not the man.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, that's true.
Well, thanks for listening.
Yes.
Thank you for your time, Karen.
I don't keep up with the current scandal
of various former teachers.
Right, but that was the one that...
Uh-huh.
Okay, we'll take...
When do we...
Okay.
Oh, my thing's off.
Sorry, you fell from grace.
Okay.
Yeah.
My watch is...
Something's wrong with my watch.
All right.
Hi.
My question has to do with overcoming karma.
I have Renard's.
It's where your hands get really cold
and the fingers will turn white in the cold.
And through kinesiology,
it was identified as a past life expression of ancient karma.
And I'm wondering if the undoing of that
is through prayer,
and also you answered another question about karma
and undoing bad karma with good karma.
And the thought that immediately came to my mind
was for me to volunteer at a hospice because I...
That would be good, yes.
So...
Yes, that would be good.
Okay.
He's talking about what I used to have.
I forget the name of it anymore.
Renard.
Renard syndrome?
Oh, yeah.
Renos.
Yes, Renos disease, yes.
Okay.
No, that would be perfect, yes.
Very good.
Okay.
Thank you.
I'm going to have a picture.
Okay.
Yes.
Yes, I used to have to wear gloves in the...
I had to wear gloves even in the house.
And I related it one time
going to a Chinese restaurant
and eating with chopsticks with my gloves on.
Good morning.
Yes.
You previously stated that you can only go as high
as you have gone low.
Would you speak and say more about that?
Well, it's a saying.
It's not...
It's hypothetically true.
But it can vary from individual to individual.
If a person hits the depths, they despair.
But if you tell them there's a benefit to that,
a benefit,
you've looked at things
that you otherwise couldn't have handled
or couldn't have looked at,
and you've now earned the right to transcend them.
So there's like a karmic benefit
to have looked at the darkest,
been through the worst,
and you've still maintained your allegiance to God
and truth and love and divinity.
Then you've earned the karmic right to transcend it.
So it's sort of a saying.
You can only be as high as...
You once were low.
And it's karmically often true.
It's karmically often true.
Yes.
Okay?
It's an individual matter.
In an individual matter, yeah.
Thank you very much.
I think this will be the last question.
Yes, go ahead.
Thank you.
Hello.
Boo.
You got one last cookie you want to go?
One last quick question or not?
I don't know.
Do we...
I'm going to do a closing.
I'd like to have a prayer sent.
Huh?
I'd like us all to pray for Japan
and the people that are suffering
and have passed away.
Well, let's do that.
Okay.
We can all join together
to try to offset what's going on currently in Japan.
I think you'll have to lead the prayer on this
because it was your thought.
I didn't have the thought.
What does he want me to do?
Where is the mic?
It's on you.
I don't have one.
Well, here.
You take it.
You're welcome.
No flies on me.
Hi.
Am I on?
Oh, there you are.
I want all of us to do a silent prayer
for the people in Japan that are suffering.
We recently had a lovely lady from our group
that has crossed over.
So if everyone could say a prayer
for these people that are now making the transition,
we appreciate it very much.
Thank you.
If we could just do a silent prayer for those people,
it would be very nice.
We pray for thy love and forgiveness
to heal the sorrow and the pain and the suffering
of people who are caught in that catastrophe
and that their suffering may lead to serve thee.
Oh, Lord, amen.
Amen.
And if you want to go ahead and bless everyone that's here.
We're so grateful for all of you to come.
Some of you have come quite a long distance to be with us.
And we appreciate it so much
because without you, the work would be nothing.
And we are so appreciative of all of you
showing up for the events.
It touches both of our hearts very deeply.
We thank thee, O Lord, for thy divine blessing
upon this group of people here assembled this day.
We give thanks for thy presence, O Lord.
Amen.
And now we hug each other and bless each other.
That's the part I always like.
That's the best part of the whole show.
Big hug and God love you.
Look at these beautiful flowers on top of it.
Somebody sent us these gorgeous flowers.
My God, they're beautiful.
Wow.
Thanks, Lidart.
Have I got a mic on now?
Yeah.
Where is the mic?
Oh.
I have a microphone attached to my cheek.
What do you know about that?
I didn't know I had a microphone attached to my cheek.
Go ahead and rush this little microphone.
It's God's microphone.
Thank you, God.
We've had a lovely day.
Lovely day to be here again with you this day.
Your love is a blessing to the world.
When the love of this group is sent
to the people in trouble in Japan,
it actually has,
it actually has an effect.
It actually has a literal,
real effect.
God bless them.
Oh, Lord.
Amen.
Okay.
Let me hear it.
That had a literal,
physical effect.
Wow.
Okay.
Thank you so much.
Is this microphone still on?
Oh, I just love that old doc.
He's also a sweetheart.
Oh, I just love him.
Docky Dock.
Give me a kiss, baby.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.