We discovered that all of the great minds that have ever lived calibrate in the mid-400s.
Spiritual reality starts 500.
So we asked, well, we can see that man has spent thousands of years trying to define truth
and so far has not succeeded.
Despite all the erudition throughout all the centuries,
there's no conclusive definition of what is truth.
Why is that?
Because without understanding consciousness itself, no definition of truth is possible.
First of all, truth, as we commonly think of it, is form.
All duality is form.
So you see, this is what we think is reality.
This is the Newtonian paradigm.
It's measurable.
There's a this causing a that.
We arbitrarily call this an event.
There are no events.
Because?
When would an event start?
Well, it starts when you decide it will start.
When does it end?
It decides when you decide it will end.
So there isn't such a thing out there as event.
That's, again, a mental phenomena.
But this is content.
So this is the content, which is the ego.
It's dualistic.
It's linear and it's form.
Linear form is content.
Definable, statable, arguable.
However, you cannot understand truth
unless you talk about the physical.
You can't understand truth unless you talk about the field.
Because truth is only true under certain circumstances.
The circumstances, then, are the proximate field.
Here's where philosophic and political fallacy abounds.
The failure to state under what conditions such and such a thing is bad.
Yes, it's bad if this was a time of peace.
It's not bad if it's a time of war.
So failure to state whether you're at war or at peace,
in fact, is the basis of the whole argument.
A thing is true, then, defined as its linear content
and its proximate field.
What's true in one circumstance is false in another.
And much political polemics is based on
purposely misstating proximate field.
The proximate field is such and such a law.
Is it just or unjust?
Is it infringing our rights?
Depends on whether you're at war or not, buddy.
Depends on whether you're in the army or not.
Lots of circumstances change what seems good, the bad, and vice versa.
What is the obligation of the government?
Is it just to attack attackers?
Or is it obligated to defend the innocent?
What is its prime obligation?
It's morally deficient.
The failure to protect the innocent is equally morally deficient.
Is it not?
So you see how the proximate field makes what seems moral or immoral
depending on the field.
Under what circumstances?
So we call that, generally, situational ethics.
A thing is true or not true, moral or not moral,
depending on local conditions.
We still don't have the truth.
We have the likelihood of truth,
the content under certain circumstances,
and then we still need the infinite field.
And so beyond the linearity of a statement
is the situation, the time, the era,
what century you're talking about, what's culture.
And then beyond that is the infinite field,
the nonlinear infinite field of consciousness itself.
Therefore, all things are only true to a relative degree,
depending on circumstances and as compared to the absolute.
The narcissistic ego hates the thought of the absolute.
The narcissistic ego rebels against the thought
that there is anything greater than itself.
It hates authority,
it hates whoever's in charge of whatever,
and it hates God.
Therefore, the narcissistic ego is secular, atheistic,
it hates all authority,
and it vilifies whatever authority
happens to be present at the present time.
When it's done vilifying the present authority,
it will move on to the next authority.
Substituting people at the top of the heap doesn't help any.
Because when this one gets fired,
I'll hate the next one.
It's called vilifying the leader, whoever the leader is.
It doesn't make any difference who the leader is.
A certain contingent of society will inevitably hate them.
Why?
Because they're on top.
That's why they hate them.
Once you hate somebody who's on top,
you can find a thousand reasons to hate them,
to rationalize them and justify them,
because they're unfair, unjust, etc., etc.
So you see how then,
truth is only true within a certain context,
time, place, conditions, certain weather,
certain cultural setting, certain generation.
What's true to the generation I grew up in
is not true to this generation.
It's not true to them.
What we all lived by, died for, is not true.
And vice versa.
We consider what they believe in not worth dying for.
I wouldn't die for child pornography,
do a parade about the rights of mankind
to watch child pornography
while the taxpayer pays for it in the nearest library.
Now, some people are willing to die for that.
But generationally, it doesn't make any sense.
You understand?
So in one generation, it sounds idiotic.
In the next generation, it sounds like,
well, that's our rights, isn't it?
That's our rights, yeah.
You see, it depends on the situation.
Okay, so we'll move on to the next one.
So this is just the statement of the content,
the field, and the infinite context.
So we'll move on.
That's just a statement in words.
Anyway, what arises out of this
are the spiritual foundations.
The spiritual foundations.
In the world in which I grew up,
rural Wisconsin, back in the 30s,
we considered that there was only two kinds of people.
There were people like this
that are on the blackboard here,
and then there were criminals.
There's Machine Gun Kelly.
And people like that.
And then everybody else was like we were.
We just assumed this is the way the world was.
Frankly, I never experienced anybody
that wasn't this way.
We read about them, John Dillinger,
Machine Gun Kelly.
There was the criminal,
bank robber weirdo types,
Bonnie and Clyde.
And then there was the normal people.
This is what we thought were normal.
Everybody was friendly.
Does this thing work?
If you look in this thing, you go blind.
So I don't know how you make it work.
Anyway, does this thing work?
No. I pushed the yellow button.
Oh, I just changed the channel. Sorry.
Everybody was friendly, polite.
If you owe people money,
you paid them.
And everybody was moral.
Everybody was helpful, kind.
You could drop into any neighbor,
knock on the door,
and they'd say,
can I help you?
Everybody was calm.
Everybody acted in a respectable
and honorable fashion.
Everybody acted friendly, orderly.
There were no riots anywhere.
Everybody was kind.
Everybody was expected to be sane
and act sane.
And if you weren't sane,
you got quickly told about it.
Everybody tried to be fair,
ethical, and balanced.
You tried to have a sense of humor,
take things lightly.
Everybody was humane.
I don't know anybody that was cruel
or willfully cruel.
If some animal was suffering,
we tried to put it to sleep
so it wouldn't suffer.
Everybody was sort of happy to be alive,
pleasant.
People were relatively modest,
polite.
Life was pretty easy.
Don't think of it.
And then there were the criminals.
See, there were only two kinds of people.
Machine gun Kelly,
and then us, the normal people.
We didn't think there was anything else.
We'll move to the next one.
We call that now
the spiritual foundation.
That's why I like the scouts,
the boy scouts, the girl scouts,
the basic ethics,
because they all take you right over 200.
They all take you right over 200.
It takes you to a moral kind of
moral reality.
Moral and ethical.
We were talking about the fact that the mind
is only
1% of the mind is active.
Everybody thinks your mind is 100% active
except when you're asleep.
Let's reconfirm.
The mind is only 1% active.
2%.
1%.
Are you lying to me?
Y'all know Susan from all the
video tapes and all.
We wouldn't be able to do this work
without Susan.
Thank you very much.
Without Susan, we wouldn't know anything.
The fact is
that only 1% of the mind
is actually active.
So, when you meditate and you say,
I don't know, I can't get my mind to stop.
It just keeps thinking, thinking, thinking.
about the 1%.
To merely know that 99%
of your mind is silent at all times
is already a giant step forward.
Thoughts arise out of nothing.
Each thought arises out of nothingness.
It's sort of non-form.
It takes form.
It arises because of
your fascination with thinkingness.
It takes form.
Then it dies away in the next one.
Each thought is like a tone,
like a note of music.
No sooner does it arise
than it is already fading away.
Therefore,
to rapidly advance in consciousness,
what you do is you stay on the crest of the wave.
Let go of resisting it.
Let go of wanting to change it.
Surrender it as it arises.
Witness it as a phenomena
without any intrinsic
reality.
Realize that it's coming out
of an energy
field that
thrives on the fascination
that you give it
of thinkingness.
As you surrender it, as it arises,
it'd be like surrendering music.
If you cling to the phrase
that just passed by,
you can't hear the music that's playing now.
So you stay on top of the
thinkingness, detach
from it like you do with music.
Yeah?
Surrendering it as it arises,
people who meditate,
the average mind goes
in one of directions.
There are people who are always trying to
anticipate the future.
So they're trying to control the next instant.
Control the next instant.
So they're living on the front of the wave.
They're not paying attention
to the present reality
because they're already anticipating
the next moment.
Then there are people who live on the back of the wave.
I mean, it's happened already
and they won't let it go.
They're still chewing it all over,
chewing it all over.
So the people that are fearful
are always living in the future.
People that are depressed and remorseful
are always clinging and reworking the past.
To transcend the mind,
one has to deny
the temptation,
the seduction of either one.
Anticipation of the future
is a seduction.
Clinging to the past is a seduction.
You have to refuse
the seduction of the mind
and instead live right on
the crest of the moment.
If you live on the crest of the moment
with absolutely, absolutely
no resistance
to that which is being experienced,
you can go through surgery without anesthesia.
I know.
I've done it twice.
The minute you begin to resist the pain,
you experience it.
It's agonizing.
You're being chopped up, fully awake.
So, however,
by staying on the crest of the wave,
you can actually have anesthesia
that can saw off your thumb
and even feel it.
In fact, you're in a beatific state
because as you let go like that,
you begin to transcend the ego altogether
and you're like uplifted by the angelic,
uplifted in the angelic kingdom.
In a state of exquisite peace.
So this is what the mind does
to hang on to you.
The mind then has like a mind of its own.
It has its own motives.
It likes to politicize everything.
You can't mention anything.
I'm trying to finish a book now
and the difficulty is
no matter what you say,
somebody's out there politicizing it.
It's practically impossible
to make a neutral statement in today's world.
Almost impossible.
Somebody has already positionalized it
and politicized it.
Huh?
The mind likes to moralize.
It likes to idealize.
It hypothesizes.
It likes to say what if.
You know, there is no answer to the hypothetical.
The hypothetical itself calibrates it
to 200.
It's a positionality.
It's an attempt to manipulate.
The hypothetical,
which is not the same as the alternative.
There's alternative possibilities.
But the hypothetical
is a way of refuting an argument
that you don't want to believe
by manufacturing intellectual
construction
that would invalidate it.
So the mind hypothesizes.
It likes to romanticize.
How much does
so much that it calibrates
as less than 200
not true, invalid,
in fact, quite invalid,
gain such a hold?
Because we romanticize it.
Romanticize it.
We join the parade,
the revolution,
workmen,
you have nothing to lose but your chains.
Nothing to lose but your chains.
Oh yeah?
You got your life to lose.
That costs 100 million people too.
They died on communism.
They died.
Died by the millions.
Millions.
They died by the millions.
Not such minor little intellectual niceties
but quite a dramatic reality.
Romanticize.
So we romanticize the fallacious
for the Third Reich.
For the Fuhrer.
Romanticize the Fuhrer.
Romanticize Deutschland über alles.
Romanticize the workmen
against the company.
We get out there
behind the barricades,
the guns.
The reason I don't go to peace parades
is they're too dangerous.
All that romanticizing,
emotionalizing.
All right, so we criticize,
we dramatize,
catastrophize, victimize.
The victimology is the biggest
growing industry
in the United States today.
Victimize.
Child Lawyers Association.
Where would it be?
So projecting perpetrator victim
is highly profitable.
It's also
easy to romanticize it.
Get people emotionalized.
Rationalize it.
The mind likes to intellectualize.
Mentalize, glamorize.
It likes to demonize.
Oh, what would you do without demons?
You couldn't write a newspaper
without a demon out there.
Congressman so-and-so is today's demon.
There's always a new demon out there.
And we prize having demons.
And the mind likes to theorize.
So this little 1%
keeps going because
of the energy we give it.
So you're not the victim of your mind.
You're the one that's giving it the energy.
It's only 1%.
All right.
If you look at your mind right now,
you'll find it's silent.
I'm listening to everybody's mind.
I don't hear anything out there.
Nobody's thinking at all.
You find that underneath the surface,
what you think is thinkingness
is an illusion.
You're not thinking at all.
Actually, the mind is silent.
So where do you find the silence?
You don't find the silence
between the billiard balls,
A, B, C.
Try and hold these two billiard balls apart
and see the infinite between them.
No.
They're like flying fish.
Each thought is arising out of nothing.
Out of the sea, this flying fish arises.
Or another flying fish arises.
I was in some...
What was it?
The flying fish are coming up.
They flop on the deck.
Each one is arising of its own.
Nothing's causing them to do that.
The human intellect
res interna.
Sees a fish come up here,
a fish come up here,
and he says, see, they're making triangles.
I think that's funny.
Hundreds of millions of people
die.
They don't see through that.
They don't see through that fallacy.
The fish are not making triangles.
Idiot.
Your stupid mind is making triangles.
The enemy's not out there.
The reason you can't destroy the enemy
is you're looking 180 degrees
out of phase.
It's not out there.
It's the infatuation
with this inner phenomena
and the pleasure we get out of it.
All right.
How do we survive?
Because it's not based in reality,
how does it keep on going?
Because, first of all,
you have the animal illusion
you have to get in order to survive.
Then you have the juice
that the ego gets out of negativity.
You say, oh, my mind doesn't enjoy suffering.
Oh, yeah?
Of course it does.
Everybody loves to feel victim.
They love to feel anger.
Righteous.
Huh?
That's what the animal is.
Those of you out there that are psychotherapists,
you know how hard it is
to get anybody out of victimhood.
Practically impossible.
They hate you for trying to get them out of victimhood
because the payoff is enormous.
You get to be the hero, the heroine.
You get to be righteous.
You get to be wrong.
You get to sue people.
You get to feel sorry for yourself.
Trying to get people out of victimhood
is almost an impossible job.
And I can remember some patients,
and I can see the enormous.
First of all, you're the star of the show.
You're the victim.
You're the star.
So the dualistic perpetrator-victim model
pays off.
And unconsciously,
that's the energy
which keeps the ego going.
People say, what keeps the ego going?
The energy is derived from
the animal energy,
the animal energy
of those energy fuels
below 200.
That's what keeps the ego going.
The payoff of being righteous,
pride,
injustice.
Oh Lord, look what they do to me.
People make God wrong.
Everybody's wrong.
So the ego gets such satisfaction out of it
that it goes on
for millennia.
Okay, so
as we see here,
truth then,
the thoughts are rising out about unity
and appear as
separateness.
So as we're talking now,
as we're talking now,
the mind, there's no mind
that's talking in this
up here right now.
The mind is silent.
This talking is going on of its own.
There's no idea what's going to be said
until I hear it.
How would I know what's going to be said?
It doesn't exist yet.
People say, what are you going to talk about tomorrow?
How would I know what I'm going to talk about tomorrow?
I have the slightest idea.
We make up something
to make them happy.
That's what we do.
You're going to speak and so and so.
What are you going to talk about?
They're not going to be satisfied with the truth.
The truth is having the slightest idea.
Is that right?
Yes, you can make a
generality, but there's no knowing.
Why? Because
once the mind goes silent,
it doesn't speak again.
Speakingness happens of its own.
It's a spontaneous event.
It's the interaction of the
what you would say that aspect
that Jung called the persona,
the interaction-ness
with the social world,
with the beingness inside.
So it serves
a communication function.
But it happens of its own.
It happens of its own.
See what the hand did there?
You see what it did to me?
It did it again.
I mean, who knows what it's going to do?
It can do anything.
Don't subscribe to the mind.
It can say and do anything.
It's totally insane.
Unreliable.
We get by in spite of the mind, not because of it.
You know why you survive?
The mind says, oh, without me
you wouldn't survive.
What keeps you alive
is the spirit.
It's because of the spirit
that you survive
in spite of the ego.
You say, well, I wouldn't remember my vitamins
if it wasn't for the ego.
Without the spirit,
that made your ego remember the vitamins.
which is the energy of life itself,
the mind wouldn't even
think of the vitamins.
So, we survive
because of the spirit
and in spite of the ego.
The ego would like you to think that
without it, you'll die.
So, what?
You know, I practiced for 50 years.
Somebody would say,
well, I'm dying
I'm taking this.
What if it doesn't work?
I'd say, well, then you die.
What's the problem?
What if this area doesn't work?
You know, that sounds awful.
All of us are going to be going.
All of us.
As you'll see later on from some charts,
we swoop in here together,
settle out generally
in sort of the same area,
and then karmically we evolve
and we all swoop back, maybe in a different place
see?
All of us swoop together.
This whole crowd here.
We're all one big swoop.
Like a bunch of herons or something.
All of us here are one big swoop.
We swoop in together all the time.
Resist.
And they're all destined for enlightenment.
That's why you're here.
Everyone is destined for enlightenment here.
Why?
Otherwise you wouldn't be here.
Why would you be at a lecture on enlightenment
if you weren't here?
The end is certain.
Except that is a reality.
Now, we just see how that came about.
So you're rerunning sort of how did I ever get there?
Just like I did with you this morning.
I tried to tell you how it all came about.
What time do we have to stop?
Oh, I hate to stop.
I'm just getting into it now.
12.30 we stop?
Yeah.
Oh, yes, the lower mind and higher mind.
We can stop now?
Huh?
What, are you against me?
You can see how she's against me.
You see that?
Probably against you.
She's probably an enemy of some kind.
We can project anything we want to onto anything.
You understand?
How we want to see it, we can project it.
Then we react to it as though it is that way.
To understand that that which is of the mind
is only of the mind.
That which exists in reality
exists independently of the mind.
Uh-huh.
So, no, I don't want anybody to think about
anything during lunchtime.
What time are we due back?
What time?
We're due back at 2 o'clock.
Well, that's simple.
So you only have an hour and a half
in which you don't have to think of anything.
Now you're going to think that you're thinking about something.
But that's an illusion.
You're not thinking about anything.
It's all happening spontaneously
of its own.
Everything is happening spontaneously
So, identify with the field.
The field in which everything is happening
of its own.
And you move from ego to spirit
because spirit is the ultimate context.
So you're the context,
not the content.
Bravo. Thank you, Lord.
Well, we're wired up for action.
Whoa, boy, look how loud that volume is.
That must be Goethe
speaking.
Oh, great.
Everybody can hear well.
It seems I can hear very well.
I don't know where my mouth is.
Here it is.
Next generation, everybody will be born with these.
You know what I mean? You're born with them.
We were tracking...
We want to recontextualize
the ego
and we're trying
to recontextualize mind.
We got through
the ego, how it evolves
since the beginning of life.
Instead of having a pejorative attitude towards it,
we accept that
its function, its value
is to keep you alive.
The ego feels that
unless it gets things,
you'll die.
So it's serving its function.
And of course, we say you're greedy.
No matter how much you get, you want more.
Right?
That's a good boy.
No matter how much you have, you want more.
Right.
Because
the illusion is
that that's how you stay alive.
Eventually, you surrender to
the field. Not to the content
of the field, which is the ego.
You surrender
to the dominion of
the field, the spirit.
That if you're doing the
course of miracles, it says
you can walk out into the world with no money,
no food, and somehow you will survive.
And so I did.
No money,
no food, no nothing.
I said, yeah, it's spirit's
worry. Why should I worry?
Sure enough, you're wandering through town
and somebody
says, I can't eat my whole lunch.
Could you eat this sandwich?
And everything just happens of its own.
Everything happens of its own.
And of course, it has ever since.
Spontaneously.
So the only thing you have to see
is that everything is happening
automatically, spontaneously
of its own.
Even if you make the decision
to be deliberate,
that decision was spontaneous.
Isn't that irresponsible?
Terrific!
Of course it's irresponsible. I love being irresponsible.
I'm not responsible
for anything I say or do.
It's God's problem.
Everything is occurring spontaneously,
automatically, as a consequence
of that which it is.
Everything is nothing but
potentiality coming into
actuality.
Even the wordingness of a talk,
such as this,
is nothing but potentiality
coming into actuality
as a consequence of the field.
And of course, you're the field.
So what you hear is what you
collectively bring forth.
What you hear is what the field brings forth.
See?
It's happening spontaneously,
automatically, as a consequence
of that which you are.
It's a collective intention.
This speakingness happens of its own.
Yeah.
Now, we were talking about mind,
that mind evolves.
You have this animal,
and then you give him a prefrontal cortex.
In the beginning, he's a rather primitive animal.
He thinks,
but in a sort of rudimentary fashion,
still with
emotionality
dominating the thinkingness.
People arrive at conclusions
that they want to arrive at.
Rather than following the conclusion
based on the dialectic
of reason.
So there are many people in the world
to whom four and four does not create,
you know, a total eight,
because they don't want it to.
They run for office all the time.
Those of you that are into esoteric,
whatever it is,
know that there's two energy fields,
one called higher mind and one lower mind.
So lower mind thinks,
in addition,
it has not heard of
the dialectic
of reason.
So it ignores reason
and it speaks about
what it likes and what it feels like
rather than
what is provable.
So it hasn't quite reached
the calibrated level of the 400.
So we see lower mind,
we have a pointer somewhere,
somebody stole it, give it back.
We see lower mind at 155,
is run by desire.
It still wants control.
It tends to be literal.
It's ego dominated.
It tends to exploit life.
So this is using reason
for sort of
an animal kind of
existence.
Higher mind is more interested
in value
for its own sake.
It tends to be inclusive
instead of exclusive.
It sees
the importance of the survival
of others instead of just
oneself.
It tends to be creative,
cooperative.
It's sophisticated, informed,
it's thoughtful.
It thinks in terms of power,
in terms of balance.
It sees itself as
serving life.
It's more sensitive.
It looks at context instead of content.
It looks at context
instead of content.
So to move forward in consciousness then,
you move to identification
with the field.
The field rather than the content.
If you move to the field,
the content will take care of itself.
The content will take care of itself.
During the break I said,
gosh, there's no chair here.
Next thing you know,
two people came over and dragged over chairs.
I don't know.
I didn't say bring over a chair.
So what you become
then, what you become
is what's important.
Everything is the consequence
of that which you have become.
Everything is the automatic consequence
That which you are,
that which you choose,
that which you value
then determines
what falls into your life.
So there's nothing to blame
if there's no cause
and there's no effect.
What you witness and experience
is a field, an impersonal effect
of the field.
Impersonal effect of the field.
When you choose
goodwill
towards everyone,
when you choose
to support life in all of its expressions,
to see the exquisite
beauty of all of life,
when you choose to see
the sacredness of all of life,
your life automatically changes.
Through that choice
you're walking along
the sidewalk and suddenly
you're struck by the incredible
beauty of a weed.
When you see a weed for what it is,
it's an exquisite
perfection of sculpture.
It's exquisite.
Look at any weed and you'll see
its extreme beauty.
Most people can't see it
unless you chip it out of stone
and put it in a park.
Then they see it.
You have to make it really big
and overwhelming to get it.
And everywhere,
at all times,
under all circumstances,
each thing is exquisitely
the perfect expression
of that which it is,
oh Lord.
In the dance of Shiva,
each thing is exquisitely,
exactly, and perfectly
that which it is.
Therefore,
everything is the perfect expression
of that which it has become.
Out of which arises
the joy,
the realization that
what do I have to do?
You only have to just
be what you are.
That is the fulfillment,
complete and total.
Out of which arises
the experience of the joy
of one's own existence.
The joy of one's own existence.
So we'll move on
to the next evolution
of consciousness.
We see as it moved up to
the prefrontal cortex is growing.
So we saw how it started out
as bacteria,
grew over the millennia,
evolved into brain,
prefrontal cortex.
Then how the mind began to evolve
in higher and higher
evolutionary evolution
from lower mind to higher mind.
We'll move on.
Next one.
The social disparities in our world
have to do really with the predominance
of the voice of lower mind
versus the voice of higher mind.
People bemoan the divisiveness
of current social
discord
and conversation.
It's generally between
lower mind and higher mind.
And if you calibrate it
using kinesiology,
you'll find that the disparate voices
are really the speakingness
of lower mind versus
the speakingness of higher mind.
That's all it is.
It's almost like two societies
together.
This is kinesiologic
response.
As it
is looked at through quantum
mechanics.
The kinesiologic response,
you see the condition of the universe
is calculated
by the Schrodinger equations
which are both
time dependent and time independent.
So the Schrodinger equations
which are mathematical,
and I save you the problem of putting them up there,
then the Heisenberg principle
is so overwhelmingly important
because they introduce
the power of consciousness and intention
that the potentiality
then collapses the wave function
as the actuality
and now you have a new state of the universe
different total state
of potentiality
diagnosable mathematically
through the Dirac equations.
So the Schrodinger equations
and the Heisenberg principle collapses
the wave function, which you have to
calculate now
through the Dirac equations
that's called the von Neumann process
and you now have a new state
of the universe,
a new potentiality
so every decision, every intention
moment to moment
you understand what it's doing.
Heisenberg principle is
the introduction of the freedom of choice.
Freedom of choice.
You're free to choose
the available options.
The options of course are limited
to the level of consciousness.
At this level of consciousness
these are your options,
at this level of consciousness
these are your choices.
The value of quantum mechanics
is we can go from logic and reason,
the Newtonian paradigm,
we can move on to quantum mechanics,
we can move on to non-linear dynamics
and we eventually come
to the level of the 500s
where you enter a new paradigm
of reality determined by
quantum mechanics.
So spiritual reality begins
classically at 500
which is the energy field of love.
Love changes the meaning
and the value of everything,
of existence itself
and all that we value.
Those of you that are interested
in this process
you look up on the internet
Henry Stapp,
professor of advanced theoretical physics
at Berkeley
who explains the von Neumann process
and process one, process two.
And the purpose of all this
is that you can move from reason
and logic, the Newtonian paradigm
without becoming illogical
or unreasonable
as you move into spiritual reality.
A lot of people
doing intellectual pride
don't want to admit they're interested
in spiritual realities
they say all that uh-oh stuff
woo-woo stuff.
There's a guy who used to run a clinic
back in Arizona
and he said
woo-woo,
means you pass beyond
what is reasonable, logical
and comprehensible through the intellect.
So I'm showing you
you don't have to move what is beyond
or incomprehensible through the intellect
you can move right through the intellect
quantum mechanics, non-linear dynamics
and move right into a different dimension.
So at 500 what happens
is the mind makes a paradigm jump.
Eisen, Einstein
and Freud,
in 1999
because there's a paradigm jump
a paradigm jump
if you go to all the conferences
on consciousness
science and consciousness
you'll find they all calibrate around 440, 450
they're hanging onto
the Newtonian paradigm
and looking for God in the Newtonian paradigm
you can't find God in the Newtonian paradigm.
You can spend
millions of dollars in research
on neurologic functioning
as the source of consciousness
that will fail.
Why?
Because if you calibrate that research in advance
you'll find it calibrates at 140
I can tell you what the research is going to show in the end.
So one value of calibrating levels of consciousness
is you can tell whether an experiment
or a research project
is worth
energizing
in advance.
Crick's research
that discovered the double helix
et cetera
calibrated at 440.
He was surprised jointly.
The last research project
before he left
was to set up
to research
neurologic functioning
and find the source of consciousness
within the
neuroanatomy
with neurological functioning
and that calibrated at 140.
Crick's stated purpose was
that after we finish this research
in the future
man will not believe in life after death
or the soul.
And he had great hopes that this project
which calibrated at 140
and cost all of us taxpayers good money
at 140
you can tell it's going to fail.
Well he saved himself the problem.
He left.
Crick died a little while ago
and I've already asked Crick
I have Crick's permission
that he is very very
exquisitely happy
happy to share the wisdom and the news
that he's still very much alive
and that there is no death.
Crick passed over
and is very happy
and excited to find
that he was dead wrong.
I love Crick
because I understand the courage
because I was once an atheist
a dedicated atheist
a deadly atheist boy
anybody who got in conversation with me
because I had a high IQ
and a sharp wit
and I knew all about theology
and epistemology and ontology
anyway I'm a great friend of Crick's
and Watts and both
and I understand exactly how Crick felt
and I can sympathize with him
what a preposterous
fallacy that there is an eternal soul
and I can understand him
so I just get a kick that
he's got a sense of humor
that he's happy to share with the audience
and we always get his permission about this
okay
so we'll move on to the next thing
uh
this is just comparing the two paradigms of reality
the newtonium
and the quantum
in the newtonium
everything is fixed and determined and limited
you see
everything is really a way
it's really force
when you move into quantum mechanics
you see that there's simultaneity
you see there's non predictability
you see that anything can happen anytime
you see what I mean
anything can happen anytime
and you can end up bambling
in a newtonian lecture
no such thing would happen
everything has to be logical reasonable
sequential
we can just go totally mad
and everybody gets it
unruly
disorderly unpredictable
spontaneous
unlimited
so the newtonian
paradigm is provable
and measurable
the closer we get to reality
it's unpredictable
it's subject to imagination
so we'll move to the next
so we're moving from the limitation
of the newtonian paradigm
we're moving to non linear dynamics
quantum mechanics
and you begin to see the opening
of a new paradigm of reality
you don't have to leave reason
you can be scientific
all along the way
so people won't think you're one of those
woo-woos
so the mind thinks dualistically
there's a this causing a that
it divides everything into a duality
we pointed out
the disaster
that's a consequence of the marxian
dualistic perpetrator victim duality
however
the newtonian paradigm
tends to think dualistically
so we can see
let's take two seeming opposites
let's take goodness
and badness
and we see that there are not two
different things at all
there's only one thing
desirability
if desirability is present
we call it good
if desirability is not there
we call it bad
there's not good and evil
there's only desirability
so there's not two variables
in duality
let's take light and darkness
light and darkness are certainly opposites
are they not
no there's only one variable
light
light is either present or not present
the same with truth and falsehood
the importance of seeing this
is truth is either present or not present
there's not an opposite reality
called falseness
light is either present or not present
so you don't have two
conditions light and dark
you only have one
light is either present or not present
so you only have a matter of degrees
of a single variable
single variable
because the mind is dualistic
things in terms of opposites
transcending the duality
of the polarity of the opposites
is one of the barriers
to enlightenment
guarded by the two dragons
classically
the doorways to truth
guarded by two dragons
then we'll move to the next one
you have goodness and badness
light
now we have hot and cold
surely you say hot and cold are opposites
no heat is either present or not
if it's present to a high degree
we call it hot
if it's absent we call it cold
they are not two opposites
there's only one variable
the presence or the absence of heat
hmm
desirability
we say one thing is more valuable than another
we were someplace or other
what was it 205 I think
the hope diamond calibrates it 205
you know what I mean
now if you think it's wonderful
where do we move
oh it's precious it's valuable
it's worthwhile it's marvelous
it's A1
then we say it's not so good
you want to give me the hope diamond
frankly I don't want the hope diamond
would you want the hope diamond
anybody want the hope diamond
good people oh there's the one that's going to descend to the top
I'm going to die
we all know what goes with the hope diamond don't we
so yeah it calibrated 205
I mean it's a nice pretty
a piece of glass
and I wouldn't want it
okay so
some would say it's precious valuable
worthwhile some people would say
neutral oh the hope diamond's
okay if you want to give it to me okay
other people would say no I think it's awful
and other people would say
I think it brings bad luck and
I really don't want the hope diamond so
you see it has no
intrinsic value it only has the value
that we assign to it
most people don't want it wouldn't want to
take a chance for the hope diamond
I wouldn't want it myself
see moving on
these are the progressive fields of consciousness
we were talking about
to glimpse
that which people
misinterpret that the Buddha said
the infinite reality is between
two thoughts it's prior to
two thoughts prior not
between the reason
that nobody's ever succeeded in becoming
enlightened by discerning the
infinite reality between thoughts is because
it's not possible
that's a good explanation isn't it
one ten thousandth of a
second now
the mind cannot move that quickly
the mind cannot move quick enough
what then is able to
discern the reality
prior to
thoughts themselves
not the mind
the mind is too slow
no matter how intently you focus
on the passage of thoughts
you're never going to get to the space
between two thoughts
anybody here ever do that
manage to get to the space between two thoughts
no never has happened
not possible
the mind can't move that quickly
one ten thousandth of a second
what is capable of moving that quickly
the mind is trying to catch
between form
what is faster than one ten thousandth of a second
is back here
the observer witness itself
so you move from identifying
with the content of thought
to realize you're not the thought
you're that which witnesses the thought
how do you know you're thinking
people say I'm thinking
maybe you're lying
how do I know you're thinking
because you're conscious and aware
so instead of
identifying with the content of thinking
you become that which
you realize how do you know what you're thinking
because it registers
how does it register
by recognition
where in the watcher the experiencer
out of awareness itself
so what is faster than
one ten thousandth of a second
is the witness watcher observer
this is what's faster than
one ten thousandth of a second
this you cannot get faster than
become the field
the observer witness field
and then you realize
how does the witness watcher
experiencer arise
and you realize
that it's the presence of the light of consciousness
itself
so you move back from identifying
with the content of thought
to the witness of thought
to the experiencer of thought
the observer the watcher
the observer the witness
you realize that you are
the light of consciousness
consciousness then is
the expression of divinity
as awareness
as awareness consciousness
you realize
that you are not the content
you're not the content
because the content is always changing
you're not even the witness the watcher
you're something more primary than that
you become
the field
you will say how should I
how shall I meditate
well I say don't
contemplate
why because when you meditate
you have to take yourself outside of the world
you're going to go in the corner
and sit cross legged
and maybe
I was going to say smoke incense
light incense
play gongs
beautiful music
get into a woo woo mood
except when you get up from the woo woo mood
you're right back to the fact that the car won't start
you know what I'm saying
alright so meditation is alright
if you take yourself out of the world
and meditate day in and day out
non-stop how long
forever
when are you going to stop meditating
never
if you're willing to do that
you have no trouble with becoming enlightened
through meditation
in the meantime
what's real
what's real is contemplation
why because to contemplate
is a way of being in the world
meditation you have to take yourself
out of the world
many people reach states of samadhi
think they're enlightened
except when you get up and walk around
then the state leaves
that is satori
those are preliminary glimpses
but that is not enlightenment
enlightenment condition stays the same
when you open your eyes and walk around
so contemplation
is something you can do all the time
anytime anywhere
and it's a way of being in the world
contemplation is
a way of being in the world
it is simultaneously
a prayer
in the form of a mudra
it's a way of being in the world
the trouble with meditation
is it tends to be too yang
realization enlightenment
comes about as the absolute
expression
of yin
so as you reach for enlightenment
it eludes you
i'll meditate harder and harder
and harder
your legs are going to sleep
your back is itching
you're living on brown rice
you've got berry berry
and all kinds of crap
and you're still not enlightened
you all know
we've all tried it
many a lifetime
we wouldn't be here today
if we hadn't all tried it
rice and no vitamins
ended up cramped legs
didn't get us there
it's too yang it's too determined
i think i'll be enlightened
so i'll sit down cross-legged
and breathe real funny
and i'll
i'll do all these things
i'll eat weird food
crap i'm not enlightened yet
what is it
i'll turn up more
that's too hard
no
no it's because it's easy
it's because it's letting go
it's because it's surrendering
because it's allowing
because as it
as the experiential
crests you don't try to cling to it
you don't try to out guess it
and reach ahead of it
you don't try to suck the energy out of it
by holding on to it
hmm
how do you pray
you become that
you are the prayer
to thee oh god
do i surrender my life
my beingness
and i open myself
to the revelation
of the divinity of thy presence
as the source of my existence
huh
your life becomes
the position
the prayer
the supplication
because you are the field
and not the content of the field
you become one
with the field
which cannot resist
the mudra of the question
because that which is being
asked is the very source
of your existence
and therefore
cannot refuse
so you understand spiritual work
as an expression of
being
so i want to
to
When you're at the level of the spiritual knight, which I spoke of earlier, both of
us were dangerous because we were the spiritual knight that would stop at nothing, forget
about death, deadly.
That's the spiritual knight who's dangerous, dangerous when he gets misled, as we can see
in the world today.
The spiritual knight, when let loose, very dangerous animal, very dangerous animal when
he observes the wrong field.
We'll move on.
So there you see, starting from meditation then, you can go back to the realization that
one is the field.
So you identify with the field and not the content of the field.
How does this affect brain physiology?
You see that a person who is spiritually...
Evolved, has a different brain physiology.
What time do we stop again?
3.15.
Okay.
The minute you go over 200, the brain physiology changes.
Below 200, we're talking now in the average, in the right-handed person.
Below 200 then, we are primarily left brain animal.
What's interesting, you see, is in the animal, the input, the sensory input.
It goes via the thalamus, a fast track, to the amygdala, which is the emotional center.
And then the experience is stored in the memory, which is the hippocampus, right south of Cincinnati
there someplace.
The left brain then, below consciousness level 200, is primarily animal.
The fast track is to the emotional center.
And the slow track is to the prefrontal cortex.
All right.
The animal brain has dominated for millions and millions of years.
Now you plaster on a prefrontal cortex, but it's still in the habit of responding emotionally.
Jane, you see him?
He looks very dangerous to me.
Yes, let's call the police.
Let's call the police.
So the cortex gets its input, but you see that it's slow.
So in the left brain, person reacts.
It reacts primarily emotionally, what I want, what I don't want, what I like.
Reason only comes in belatedly, belatedly.
So the left brain dominance then, below consciousness level 200, is linear.
It's prone to stress, release of adrenaline, cannons, fight or flight, Selye's stress syndrome.
Because it's constantly in a state of stress, it suppresses the thalamus.
Thalamus output of killer cells.
There is a greater proneness to disease.
It blows out the acupuncture system.
Every time you go into fight or flight, the acupuncture system goes weak.
That blows the energy flow to whatever meridian you're blowing.
So if it's hatred, you're constantly blowing the heart meridian.
Eventually, you get a heart attack.
So the left brain then is thymic stress.
Negative.
Negative kinesiologic response.
It releases neurotransmitters and eventually depletes your serotonin.
Track to the emotions is twice as fast as through the prefrontal cortex.
Therefore, less than 200 responds first on the animal level.
I like it.
I don't like it.
I hate it.
I fear it.
I have to be on guard against it.
Over 200 now, the brain physiology changes.
It shifts more to right brain.
The difference is above 200, the fast track is to the cerebral cortex.
And at 200, we have an amazing development for the first time in evolution.
That's the development of spiritual energy, so-called kundalini energy.
At 200, you get the production of kundalini energy, spiritual energy.
The most important thing is it creates an etheric brain.
Less than 200.
There's no etheric brain.
Consciousness level 200 and up, there's the development of the etheric brain.
The etheric brain.
Huh.
Now, over 200 then, now things are processed differently.
The fast track is through the etheric brain and the prefrontal cortex.
Very fast to the emotional center.
So you have right brain dominance, which is nonlinear.
What you read is the field.
You begin to read the field.
The person is at peace because you're released from the field.
You're releasing endorphins instead of adrenaline.
Emotions are positive instead of negative.
The thymus gland is supported.
Therefore, that increases the availability of killer cells, which destroy bacteria,
increased immunity, more rapid healing.
You get a balanced acupuncture system and a positive kinesiologic response.
That which is false then makes the body go weak.
Blows out the acupuncture system.
That's why it goes weak.
That which is true is recognized by consciousness as pro-life and true, aligned with divinity,
might say.
And it makes the acupuncture system go strong.
So all you see in the kinesiologic response then is the presence of truth or falsehood
and the response of the absolute field of consciousness itself.
So we have the next one.
So we can tie everything together.
Evolution, animal kingdom, the evolution of human consciousness, brain physiology.
And as we demonstrated before, we tend to come in together.
A group like this, we tend to come in.
We're like, you see, migratory flight or something.
We're like a bunch of swans or something.
And we all swoop onto the planet together.
We tend to settle out in various parts of the world.
And then we all leave.
And then we swoop back.
And then we swoop back in again.
And people tend to congregate like swans, whistling swans, ducks or whatever, in various
parts of the world.
So if we ask, if we calibrate the levels of consciousness throughout human life, which
is the formidable task, which I'm just concluding, an encyclopedia of truth, calibrate the level
of truth of everything in history.
Everything that exists, all the famous people, movies, television, advertising, companies,
corporations, leaders, entertainers.
If you go through the whole world and calibrate the level of consciousness, you better leave
town.
Because not everything, essence is not appearance.
All right.
So if you just say, what's the distribution of the level of consciousness on the planet,
you begin to understand history.
And.
You start to think about it.
We're talking about 20, 30, 40 years ago.
And because it's a part of history, it's not about time.
It's not about history.
And you start to think about it.
And I mean, that's the way history is.
But there are some people that have more experience in the world, which are the ones that do it
the hardest, because they don't know how to do it.
And if you have more experience in the world, that's why we start to think about history.
Because history starts to be a part of history.
And the history has many parts.
It's a part of history.
You see, if you look at, once a century, the Pacific Ocean used to be a part of history.
You see, the millennium, US.
Here, we have a lot of history.
Central America, 400, the Caribbean Islands in 300s.
You see South America generally overall, high 200s to 300.
And only one peculiarity in this entire hemisphere,
and that's Haiti, which calibrates at 55,
the home of voodoo and devil worship
and blood sacrifice, et cetera.
So they have their own karmic inheritance
and calibrate at 55.
So you could say 55 can't cause the world much trouble.
It's too crippled by its own pathology.
You could say this hemisphere looks...
So if you came from another universe and you said,
what does this universe look like?
And you come with this map, you'd say,
well, I don't see much trouble here.
Maybe a few arguments, but I don't see any big trouble.
Let's go to the next map.
All right, now we look at another hemisphere.
No, this is still North America.
Then we look at another hemisphere.
This is not too good.
Let's go to the next one.
This is more general.
If you want to know what is the condition of the world,
you see, well, here's Australia at 410.
Then you see various parts of the world,
and you see China and India in the 300s.
You see Mongolia at 175.
And you see that the difficulty is going to be in North Africa.
And you can see that Central Africa,
calibrating at 40, is probably going to be destitution.
Destitution, poverty, and the helplessness of life at 40.
So this begins to tell you what it is you're dealing with.
So let's move to the next one.
This is just an explanation of the same thing,
but specific countries which you can read about in the Daily News.
All right, so just leave that for a second.
If things are not happening by causality,
then what is the explanation?
The explanation is most of what you witness and read about in the paper
is a field effect.
It's a consequence of the field.
We all know the broken window principle.
Everybody know the broken window principle?
Anybody not?
It has to do with the fact that it's a sociologic observation
of why neighborhoods become what they become.
If you allow one single broken window,
to exist in a neighborhood,
it will attract the next one.
The first broken window, the next thing that happens is trash.
Then kids say, oh, let's throw rocks.
Then cockroaches, then crime, prostitution, drugs,
and gang dominance.
The field begins to attract that which it is.
You know that unrepaired, broken factory windows
result in cockroaches.
How can that be?
Soon after the broken windows appear the rats,
appear the drugs, appears the crime,
appears the prostitution, the drug dealing,
then the murders, then the arson.
And when you drive through the South Bronx or Brownsville,
you see the blackened windows
because they've all been torched by rival gangs.
Who's going to dominate that block, et cetera?
What you see is a field effect.
If things are not within the Newtonian paradigm,
causality, then what society does
is use the perpetrator, victim model,
and begin to look for who to accuse.
When we were in England, I got, we read in the newspaper,
the insulation effect on the,
what was that thing that goes out?
The spacecraft shuttle, yes.
Everybody was looking for the bad guy,
who to blame for the insulation defect
in the space shuttle crash, see?
You see how the mind thinks dualistically.
This is bad. There must be a bad person.
We should find this bad person.
We should blame and vilify this bad person
because he's responsible for this.
I mean, that's sort of simplistic third grade, isn't it?
Then I was thrilled to see the headline.
It says that the problem was due to the overall climate.
Aha!
It was the climate of NASA
that accounted for the carelessness,
the fault, et cetera, the climate.
It is like Pearl Harbor.
It was the climate preceding it.
Secretary of State Stinson didn't bother to read
the intelligence reports.
He said, gentlemen don't read gentlemen's mail.
They turned off reading the Japanese secret code.
And we got, then, Pearl Harbor.
Consequence of the field.
So we could say 9-11 is nothing but
a consequence of the field.
If you watch it on TV,
all of the government was unprepared.
All of it.
FBI, CIA, military, Pentagon,
the city of New York.
The totality of our civilization
was totally unprepared.
Who's the bad guy? There ain't any.
It's the overall field.
The field of negligence and denial
is the same as it was right prior to World War II.
Same thing. Denial.
OK, so things are then a field effect.
They're not due to cause and effect.
Newtonian paradigm.
If they were, they'd be incorruptible.
Be hopeless.
So if we look at the distribution of AIDS,
HIV and AIDS,
we'll see that it follows exactly the same pattern
as the levels of consciousness
in the previous map.
Exactly the same distribution.
So you see, certain things are then
the consequence of the overall field.
That tells us then where to put our effort.
To lift the field.
If we lift the level of the ocean,
all the ships afloat are simultaneously lifted.
One way to lift it is by
stop looking for the cause
in a Newtonian kind of a manner.
If we look at the climate,
then we see the climate has to be changed.
Climate.
There was a book on excellence.
Excellence in business
is what it was specifically about.
Now with the value of excellence,
who remembers the name of the book?
It's a very famous book.
Huh?
OK, In Search of Excellence.
So what they found was a field.
Within that field,
excellence begins to get esteemed for its own sake.
For its own sake, excellence.
So what we need is government
that seeks excellence for its own sake.
For its own sake, yeah.
As a physician, you're obligated.
The only one I was ever concerned about
is pleasing my own standards.
You couldn't sleep if you had not served
the quality of excellence within yourself.
If you'd done the best job you could.
You'd actually get out of bed
that you left a stone unturned
to help a specific patient with a specific problem.
Call the hospital.
Jesus Christ, Alan.
Did you get the iodine on him, you know?
Did you get the iodine uptake?
All right, so how do I think that?
Jesus.
Can't sleep.
So the obligation is to yourself
to excellence, to excellence.
I don't care what anybody out there thinks of me.
Good doctor, bad doctor, immaterial.
I am concerned with what I think of myself as a physician.
So, all right, so the calibrated levels of consciousness
then mean that pride in oneself,
self-esteem,
the things that Bill Cosby spoke about.
I agree with him.
To value yourself, to value life,
to value environment.
To pick up the newspaper.
Why?
Because, you see, when you value life,
you create a field in which everybody else values life.
When you go into the great beautiful buildings of the world,
you don't see graffiti.
Why is that?
How come?
You see graffiti in the subways in New York City,
all over everything.
Even in England, we're going along on the train,
graffiti everywhere.
You get to certain places, no graffiti.
Why?
Because the energy of it is different.
You just wouldn't even think of graffiti there.
So here we see the field effect.
Let's move on.
If we're going to improve the world,
we have to need to know what to address.
If the world doesn't operate on cause and effect,
and we're seeing nothing but coalescence of field effect,
then it tells us where we have to put our energy
is in the field, the field.
If I want to improve an area,
I move into the field.
This is just localities in the United States just for fun.
We said, you know, if we go around willy-nilly,
what does the world look like?
And so we just did some places in New York City.
We were in Chicago at the time.
The United States calibrates at 421.
Chicago calibrates at 455, right?
What is it, 455?
What is Chicago?
Eh?
No, 445, yeah.
Chicago calibrates at 445.
Now, I was looking at Chicago.
I said, man, there's one stunning, beautiful buildings,
beautiful architect, beautiful museums.
You know, who was the poet that wrote about Chicago?
Huh?
Carl Sandburg, yeah.
So I saw the Chicago of Carl Sandburg.
Anyway, it calibrated at 445.
So I'm thinking of lost Americans
who wander to foreign countries,
and the excuse their family gives is he's trying to find himself.
If you can't find yourself, I suggest you go to Chicago.
At 445.
You'll do better than wandering around civilizations
to calibrate about 145.
Okay, so we'll move to the next one.
These are just sort of fun things.
What are all these things here?
These are just the current dialogue, social dialogue.
What's the next one?
You can't read these things.
Yeah, well, the emergence, the okayness of relativism, you see,
when you move away from any kind of an absolute.
When you move from the absolute, you move to relativism.
In relativism, then, you have no right or wrong,
nothing valued, nothing nonvalued, anything goes.
We find the number of hate violence websites.
There's a company called Surf Control.
From 2000 to 2004, jumped from around 2,700 to 11,000.
11,000 websites.
We say, well, freedom of speech,
that's the most touted advantage of democracy, right?
Freedom of speech.
And yet Socrates and Aristotle said it'll also be its downfall.
Because freedom of speech
is a two-edged sword.
You know, the Course in Miracles says
that forgiveness is the only one-edged sword.
Freedom of speech means you give freedom to the lie
equally with the truth.
And pretty soon, the mind cannot tell the difference.
And as Freud pointed out in 1900,
the unconscious very often turns things into their opposite.
Turns things into their opposite.
Doesn't want to refer to it directly,
refers to it as opposite.
So we see the downside of freedom of speech
is the abuse of the freedom of speech
instead of the respecting of it.
And you see 11,000 websites devoted to nothing but hate.
Okay, let's move on to the next one.
We just wanted to see what happened to freedom of speech.
What is this one?
Oh, this is movies.
So we said, what the heck?
How does the Calibrations of Truth,
how is it reflected in our world, in society?
We did all the famous books.
We did the famous websites.
I mean, sites, pyramids.
The Chartres Cathedral went across Europe,
did all the great cathedrals.
Let's move on to the next one.
These are all movies.
So we did 200 movies.
What does that movie reflect?
What level of truth does that movie reflect?
So we did 200 movies.
Show us what the effect was, Susie.
We did 200 movies.
We did the great books of the Western world.
We did hundreds of places on the planet, et cetera.
And that's more movies. Okay.
And finally she said,
I don't think I can do any more movies.
Any more slides?
Eh? What is that?
No, we'll move on from that.
I just want to show the coalescence
this is sort of the field effect
of the levels of consciousness.
You see, we take perpetrator-victim
projected into the world.
Now we look for the bad guys.
We're going to correct the bad guys.
We change all kinds of social programs,
only things don't improve.
That's because that's fallacious causality.
Here, let's correlate level of consciousness
with rate of unemployment,
rate of poverty, happiness,
and rate of criminality.
You see, 600 and over.
Unemployment, zero.
Poverty, zero.
Happiness, 100%.
Criminality, zero.
500 to 600.
Unemployment, zero.
Poverty, zero.
Happiness rate, 98%.
Two of them are loonies.
Criminality, 0.5%.
We'll have to figure that one out.
Okay, 400 to 500.
Unemployment now drops to 2%.
Poverty, 0.5%.
Happiness, 70%.
Criminality, 2%.
Calibration level, 300 to 400.
Unemployment, 7%.
Poverty, 1%.
Happiness, 50%.
The other 50% need to attend these lectures.
Criminality, 5%.
I guess that must be stealing from the pews or something, huh?
5%.
And now what you see is the tremendous change
at consciousness level 200.
At consciousness level 200,
the unemployment rate goes,
it's from 8% to 50%.
The minute you cross below 200,
unemployment suddenly instead of 8 is 50%, huh?
You see poverty jumps from 1.5% to 22%.
Happiness drops to 15%.
And 50% of people below consciousness level 200
will engage in criminality of one type or another,
even if it's just stealing from the company.
By the time consciousness level gets down to 100 or less,
you see unemployment is almost 100%,
poverty is extremely high,
life is okay is down to practically 0%,
and criminality becomes almost universal as a lifestyle.
So then to affect the quality of life,
we begin to see it's not cause and effect,
it's a field effect,
the consequence of that which we have become.
That which we have become is that which we value
and hold in high esteem.
That which we value and hold in high esteem.
Is that the last of the slides?
Yeah?
Ah, yes.
All right, this is the last of the one.
What time do we stop, 3.15, I forget?
Okay, all right.
I just want to show the practical application
and calibrating levels of consciousness.
In the history of mankind,
peace has prevailed 7% of the history of civilization.
Seven percent.
War has prevailed 93% of the history of civilization.
Huh?
Fierce statistics to deal with.
If we calibrate levels of consciousness now,
what I'm proposing is,
this sounds like megalomania,
and it is probably, it's okay,
a new science of diplomacy based on
calibrated levels of consciousness.
You can't succeed unless you know who you're dealing with.
So here I have a comparison of,
first I had a raw scale without any countries in here.
You can use the raw scale here.
This is called us, or me,
and this is called them.
Over here you have the levels of consciousness.
Here you have just the raw numbers.
Here's us, and here's them.
This can be your company, your country,
your state, your program,
anti-poverty program,
literacy program, whatever you want.
This is the calibrated level of your program
or who you are.
Here's America overall at 421.
Where's U.S.? 421.
Okay, this is us, 421.
All right, now we calibrate the level of consciousness
of what country we're dealing with.
We have to know three things.
We have to know the calibrated level of the leader,
the people, and the government.
You have to know all three.
Very often there's a big disparity.
One country I'm holding in mind right now,
the leader is extremely high,
the government is completely rotten and dissolute,
and the people are loving, wonderful.
You've got to pay off for everything.
The government's rotten.
The guy at the head calibrates over 500.
You're really high.
And the people are adorable,
but just the government is rotten through and through.
So you've got to know the difference
between who you're dealing with,
diplomatically, yeah?
So here's us.
Now here's the calibrated level
of who you're dealing with.
Let's say, let's take a country
like the Middle East, huh?
Here you are at 421.
You're dealing with somebody at 190.
Here you're dealing with Afghanistan
and various militant countries.
You can't talk any kind of sense
when you're talking your language
because you're speaking a different language.
So in the office, there's a psychoanalyst,
there's a psychiatrist, there's a physician.
I don't expect the patient to be where I am.
I go where they are.
It's my job to understand them,
not for them to understand me.
So I want to understand who I'm dealing with.
So I go into Afghanistan and I say,
young man, please give me your gun.
We would like you to have the freedom of the vote.
Democracy.
Freedom of speech, right?
Except the gun's the only thing he's got.
He lives in a culture in which,
without a gun, he's nobody.
With a gun, he's employable.
He can live, make a living.
He gains respect, has self-esteem.
Without a gun, he's nobody.
He's a joke.
Can't read or write. Pathetic. Stone age.
Worthless.
Consequently, if we know where the other people are,
then we can talk to them at their level.
Why would democracy appeal to people like that?
What a joke, democracy.
We have an inflated ego about democracy,
how wonderful it is.
How wonderful it is for who?
For these people here?
What would democracy do for these people?
They can't spell it to begin with.
Self-interest.
How would democracy improve your life?
There, now that would start to make sense.
What is the gain?
Below consciousness level 200,
people are only interested in gain.
What's in it for me?
Foreign aid, where does it go?
It goes to enrich the people at the top
who have siphoned it all off,
and the poorest are just as poor as ever.
So what's real?
Utilizing calibrating levels of truth,
we could make our efforts in the world
far more beneficial
by understanding a different paradigm of reality.
Happy things come about as a consequence of the field,
not as a consequence of causality.
You can pour millions and millions
of dollars into this anti-poverty program
and you haven't changed the incidence of poverty at all.
You haven't even addressed where it's coming from.
Where it's coming from.
So this would be a science of international diplomacy
based on the calibrated levels of consciousness.
I've watched embarrassing interviews
in which an American commentator
is talking to the head of the biggest nation in the world
and insulting him.
What about your civil rights violations in your country?
Happily, he was a very cool guy.
Calibrate's quite high, frankly.
And he said, well, you do have a few problems
in your own country.
Crime, divorce, drugs, et cetera.
Yes, America does have a few guys.
50% divorce rate, et cetera.
Drugs, crime.
Highest rate of imprisonment of any country.
You do have a few problems of your own.
So he took it very gently.
But I thought it was very disrespectful.
The person he was talking to
calibrated around 460.
Brilliant man.
You're not the head of the biggest nation in the world
for nothing.
And here's this interviewer,
cocky, adolescent, typically American,
challenging him, you know.
I thought, how disrespectful.
So that's how America gets its reputation.
Disrespect for the reality
in which other people are living.
So calibrating the level of consciousness
should give us humility.
Get real.
Get to see what people,
what their level of consciousness is.
Who they really are.
Which is their leader?
Which is their government?
And which is the people?
Which is the people, you know?
Which is the government?
To bring about a greater likelihood of peace.
In the history of the world, then,
falsehood has been,
the consequence of falsehood has been war.
And peace only comes about as a consequence of truth.
Falsehood is always the consequence of falsehood.
It is never the consequence of truth.
So an indirect truth instead of falsehood
is to increase the likelihood
that peace will prevail.
By our combined intention, then,
if we value peace,
we have to value truth.
Truth above positionality.
The pathway to God through truth.
Devotional non-duality means
the pathway to God through devotion
to the presence of God
as it is revealed by truth itself.
Devotional non-duality.
Is that the last?
Okay, so,
then the summation of
going through the world and all of its expressions
since the beginning of time,
calibrating the levels of consciousness,
we see the evolution of consciousness
on up through the animal kingdom,
the progression of the ego,
transcending the ego into spiritual reality,
and, hmm,
we see the ongoingness of calibrations
of levels of consciousness
all the way up to 1,000.
The Bhagavad Gita at 900.
The great gurus of Aryan culture.
The sages of old already knew
truth at levels of 900 to 1,000.
900 to 1,000.
Before present-day religions were born.
Long before the birth of Jesus or Buddha
or Muhammad,
the great sages calibrated at 900 to 1,000.
Krishna at 1,000.
Hmm.
So, O Lord, we do pray to Thee
that Thy truth prevail
in mankind
for the sake of peace,
for the sake of peace.
Amen.