Well, we're glad to be here.
Well, we're glad to be here. This is a arodite audience.
This is a arodite audience.
This is a arodite audience. Areite.
Areite.
Areite. That's the trouble.
That's their trouble.
That's their trouble. So the intellect which informs us of
So the intellect which informs us of
So the intellect which informs us of spiritual reality
spiritual reality
spiritual reality first of all we for eons were the animal
first of all we for eons were the animal
first of all we for eons were the animal then we learn how to think
then we learn how to think
then we learn how to think then through thinking we learn that
then through thinking we learn that
then through thinking we learn that there is a higher awareness
there is a higher awareness
there is a higher awareness and then we decide we are interested in
and then we decide we are interested in
and then we decide we are interested in that higher awareness. We become
that higher awareness. We become
that higher awareness. We become spiritually involved
spiritually involved
spiritually involved and then the intellect which was
and then the intellect which was
and then the intellect which was a friend to us to inform us about it,
a friend to us to inform us about it,
a friend to us to inform us about it, bring us here
bring us here
bring us here uh becomes the the trap.
uh becomes the the trap.
uh becomes the the trap. It becomes uh that which attracted us
It becomes uh that which attracted us
It becomes uh that which attracted us now becomes what we become mired in.
now becomes what we become mired in.
now becomes what we become mired in. So
So
So the central to the intellect
the central to the intellect
the central to the intellect and reason and logic
and reason and logic
and reason and logic is the Newtonian paradigm of reality
is the Newtonian paradigm of reality
is the Newtonian paradigm of reality which is the obstacle to a group like
which is the obstacle to a group like
which is the obstacle to a group like this.
Love is not an obstacle.
Love is not an obstacle. Willingness to love
Willingness to love
Willingness to love motivation.
So it become the intellect then becomes
So it become the intellect then becomes the trap
the trap
the trap how to transcend the dualistic structure
how to transcend the dualistic structure
how to transcend the dualistic structure of the ego
of the ego
of the ego essential to the ego's de dominion
essential to the ego's de dominion
essential to the ego's de dominion is the Newtonian belief in causality
is the Newtonian belief in causality
is the Newtonian belief in causality and therefore
and therefore
and therefore we'll start out with the end of the
we'll start out with the end of the
we'll start out with the end of the lecture and move back to the Hey,
there's only one thing you need to learn
there's only one thing you need to learn from the whole lecture today.
from the whole lecture today.
from the whole lecture today. The reasons for it we will go over.
The reasons for it we will go over.
The reasons for it we will go over. There is nothing causing anything.
There is nothing causing anything.
There is nothing causing anything. That's the good news.
If nothing is causing anything,
If nothing is causing anything, then how do things come to be?
then how do things come to be?
then how do things come to be? It's very simple.
It's very simple.
It's very simple. Potentiality
Potentiality
Potentiality blossoms forth as actuality
blossoms forth as actuality
blossoms forth as actuality when conditions permit
when conditions permit
when conditions permit because of the infinite power of the
because of the infinite power of the
because of the infinite power of the field.
field.
field. The field is so powerful
becomes transformed into its actuality
becomes transformed into its actuality because the power of the field is so
because the power of the field is so
because the power of the field is so infinite
infinite
infinite far beyond causality.
far beyond causality.
far beyond causality. The Newtonian paradigm of reality
The Newtonian paradigm of reality
The Newtonian paradigm of reality calibrates around 450 on the scale of
calibrates around 450 on the scale of
calibrates around 450 on the scale of consciousness. 450 is hardly sufficient
consciousness. 450 is hardly sufficient
consciousness. 450 is hardly sufficient to explanate to explain the existence of
to explanate to explain the existence of
to explanate to explain the existence of the universe.
the universe.
the universe. 450 will
450 will
450 will uh get you a long way. Get you to the
uh get you a long way. Get you to the
uh get you a long way. Get you to the moon. That's as far as it'll get you.
moon. That's as far as it'll get you.
moon. That's as far as it'll get you. And then it strands you there.
Hey God, I'm caught in the universe
Hey God, I'm caught in the universe here. How do I get out of here? It's one
here. How do I get out of here? It's one
here. How do I get out of here? It's one planetary system after another.
planetary system after another.
planetary system after another. your mic. I'm sorry.
your mic. I'm sorry.
your mic. I'm sorry. >> Did you say shut your mouth or shut your
>> Did you say shut your mouth or shut your
>> Did you say shut your mouth or shut your mic? Oh,
>> I am willing to be cut off anytime. You
>> I am willing to be cut off anytime. You know,
things come into manifestation
things come into manifestation because karmically everything that
because karmically everything that
because karmically everything that exists is the consequence of a karmic
exists is the consequence of a karmic
exists is the consequence of a karmic evolution over great eons of time.
evolution over great eons of time.
evolution over great eons of time. And now at any moment anything and
And now at any moment anything and
And now at any moment anything and everything and everyone represents the
everything and everyone represents the
everything and everyone represents the karmic inheritance of the past
karmic inheritance of the past
karmic inheritance of the past presenting to the potentiality
presenting to the potentiality
presenting to the potentiality of the present.
of the present.
of the present. When conditions are favorable that
When conditions are favorable that
When conditions are favorable that potentiality becomes an actuality.
potentiality becomes an actuality.
potentiality becomes an actuality. Nothing forces it to. Nothing causes it
Nothing forces it to. Nothing causes it
Nothing forces it to. Nothing causes it to.
to.
to. Nothing has the power to do that.
The infinite field of consciousness
The infinite field of consciousness is like a giant electromagnetic field of
is like a giant electromagnetic field of
is like a giant electromagnetic field of infinite power. Infinite power
infinite power. Infinite power
infinite power. Infinite power everywhere present
everywhere present
everywhere present beyond time and space with no beginning
beyond time and space with no beginning
beyond time and space with no beginning and no ending.
and no ending.
and no ending. So it's not necessary to originate a
So it's not necessary to originate a
So it's not necessary to originate a philosophy of the beginning of God
philosophy of the beginning of God
philosophy of the beginning of God because there is no beginning to God.
because there is no beginning to God.
because there is no beginning to God. That takes care of prime cause.
That which is beyond time has no
That which is beyond time has no beginning and no ending. It has no
beginning and no ending. It has no
beginning and no ending. It has no future and it has no past. So there's
future and it has no past. So there's
future and it has no past. So there's nothing to be explained.
That's the end of the lecture for today.
That's the end of the lecture for today. Bye.
Out of the infinite power of the
Out of the infinite power of the manifest
manifest
manifest arises the manifest.
It's an actualization out of potential.
It's an actualization out of potential. The flower unfolds. Nothing is forcing
The flower unfolds. Nothing is forcing
The flower unfolds. Nothing is forcing it to unfold.
A little seed along the highway in
A little seed along the highway in Arizona.
Arizona.
Arizona. We looked at this incredible century
We looked at this incredible century
We looked at this incredible century plant. Stunning.
plant. Stunning.
plant. Stunning. Early spring, it wasn't there.
Early spring, it wasn't there.
Early spring, it wasn't there. By the end of June, it's 12 feet high.
By the end of June, it's 12 feet high.
By the end of June, it's 12 feet high. Incredible.
We found that the seed out of which it
We found that the seed out of which it had had risen had been lying in the dirt
had had risen had been lying in the dirt
had had risen had been lying in the dirt for 150 years.
for 150 years.
for 150 years. 150 years. The potential lay there
150 years. The potential lay there
150 years. The potential lay there waiting for the exact conditions.
waiting for the exact conditions.
waiting for the exact conditions. Sequence of barometric pressures,
Sequence of barometric pressures,
Sequence of barometric pressures, sequence of moisture,
sequence of moisture,
sequence of moisture, chemical constituents, a thousand
chemical constituents, a thousand
chemical constituents, a thousand variables
variables
variables and then uh out of potential
and then uh out of potential
and then uh out of potential potentiality
potentiality
potentiality arose the actuality
arose the actuality
arose the actuality not because it was caused to but because
not because it was caused to but because
not because it was caused to but because everything then is the manifestation of
everything then is the manifestation of
everything then is the manifestation of a field.
a field.
a field. What you see is the action of a field.
What you see is the action of a field.
What you see is the action of a field. But you see, you don't see the action of
But you see, you don't see the action of
But you see, you don't see the action of the field. You see
the field. You see
the field. You see the manifestation of the field.
the manifestation of the field.
the manifestation of the field. Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. This is very simple.
Therefore,
Therefore, all that you think you are the cause of
all that you think you are the cause of
all that you think you are the cause of is actually happening of its own as a
is actually happening of its own as a
is actually happening of its own as a consequence of the field
what should we say configuration
what should we say configuration is part of the field.
There is no personal self causing
There is no personal self causing anything.
anything.
anything. Everything is happening of of its own.
Everything is happening of of its own.
Everything is happening of of its own. The ego jumps in and says I did that.
The ego jumps in and says I did that.
The ego jumps in and says I did that. No, it did it of its own. And then the
No, it did it of its own. And then the
No, it did it of its own. And then the ego jumps in in one 10,000th of a second
ego jumps in in one 10,000th of a second
ego jumps in in one 10,000th of a second to claim authorship.
110,000th of a second.
110,000th of a second. It happens within 1/10,000th of a
It happens within 1/10,000th of a
It happens within 1/10,000th of a second. The ego claims ownership and
second. The ego claims ownership and
second. The ego claims ownership and authorship.
authorship.
authorship. And this is the way it keeps itself
And this is the way it keeps itself
And this is the way it keeps itself going lifetime after lifetime
going lifetime after lifetime
going lifetime after lifetime until one day you catch it.
uh red-handed I caught it.
uh red-handed I caught it. I think I was in college and driving a
I think I was in college and driving a
I think I was in college and driving a cab
cab
cab and
and
and a rabbit crossed the road and the brakes
a rabbit crossed the road and the brakes
a rabbit crossed the road and the brakes went on and then I caught eye claiming
went on and then I caught eye claiming
went on and then I caught eye claiming credit but it had already happened. The
credit but it had already happened. The
credit but it had already happened. The break had already gone on to save the
break had already gone on to save the
break had already gone on to save the rabbit's life
rabbit's life
rabbit's life in one 10,000th of a second.
a mistrans misunderstanding of what the
a mistrans misunderstanding of what the Buddha taught. I've spoken to the Buddha
Buddha taught. I've spoken to the Buddha
Buddha taught. I've spoken to the Buddha about it. He agrees.
One of my jobs here is to correct that
One of my jobs here is to correct that misquote.
Eternity is glimpsed between two
Eternity is glimpsed between two thoughts.
Hundreds of thousands of people have
Hundreds of thousands of people have meditated for probably collectively
meditated for probably collectively
meditated for probably collectively centuries looking for the space between
centuries looking for the space between
centuries looking for the space between two thoughts
two thoughts
two thoughts to get a glimpse of the eternal.
to get a glimpse of the eternal.
to get a glimpse of the eternal. How many here have succeeded?
How many here have succeeded?
How many here have succeeded? No one in history has succeeded. That's
No one in history has succeeded. That's
No one in history has succeeded. That's a mistransation.
a mistransation.
a mistransation. Now
the nothingness just prior to the
the nothingness just prior to the thought.
thought.
thought. So the thought arises out of the sea
So the thought arises out of the sea
So the thought arises out of the sea like a flying fish out of the
like a flying fish out of the
like a flying fish out of the nothingness
out of nothingness. Each thing arises
out of nothingness. Each thing arises out of nothingness as an actualization
out of nothingness as an actualization
out of nothingness as an actualization of its potential.
The mind cannot catch a space between
The mind cannot catch a space between two thoughts. The mind thinks that the
two thoughts. The mind thinks that the
two thoughts. The mind thinks that the thoughts work like billiard balls A B
thoughts work like billiard balls A B
thoughts work like billiard balls A B CDE E etc.
CDE E etc.
CDE E etc. And it looks between the billiard balls
And it looks between the billiard balls
And it looks between the billiard balls to find that space. Well, there isn't
to find that space. Well, there isn't
to find that space. Well, there isn't any because it's not a sequence that
any because it's not a sequence that
any because it's not a sequence that goes from A to Z at all.
goes from A to Z at all.
goes from A to Z at all. Each one arises independently
Each one arises independently
Each one arises independently out of nothing.
The space you're looking for is just
The space you're looking for is just prior to the thought.
prior to the thought.
prior to the thought. You're looking for the nothingness
You're looking for the nothingness
You're looking for the nothingness out of which the thought begins to
out of which the thought begins to
out of which the thought begins to arise, take form, pull energy to it.
Out of nothing arises like the
Out of nothing arises like the feelingness of caniness and then
feelingness of caniness and then
feelingness of caniness and then dogness.
dogness.
dogness. Then the image of dogness, then Rover,
Then the image of dogness, then Rover,
Then the image of dogness, then Rover, then Rover got run over. And then how we
then Rover got run over. And then how we
then Rover got run over. And then how we all cried and then we got Beaver and he
all cried and then we got Beaver and he
all cried and then we got Beaver and he got hit by a car, too. And then the
got hit by a car, too. And then the
got hit by a car, too. And then the whole tragic story. And here you're
whole tragic story. And here you're
whole tragic story. And here you're trying to find God. Instead, you're
trying to find God. Instead, you're
trying to find God. Instead, you're rerunning an old story.
Caught in the drama.
Caught in the drama. Caught in the emotionality, caught in
Caught in the emotionality, caught in
Caught in the emotionality, caught in the past, far from reality. Okay.
the past, far from reality. Okay.
the past, far from reality. Okay. The only thing to know then is that
The only thing to know then is that
The only thing to know then is that everything is arriving arising every
everything is arriving arising every
everything is arriving arising every instant as a consequence of the field
instant as a consequence of the field
instant as a consequence of the field acting on potentiality.
acting on potentiality.
acting on potentiality. Your potentiality is called karma.
The unmanifest becomes manifest by
The unmanifest becomes manifest by divine ordinance.
divine ordinance.
divine ordinance. The field then has the power
The field then has the power
The field then has the power to actualize potentiality.
You go over to an apple tree
You go over to an apple tree and you snip the stem
and you snip the stem
and you snip the stem and the apple falls to the ground.
The apple fell to the ground
The apple fell to the ground due to gravity, not due to you.
It was the infinite power of gravity,
It was the infinite power of gravity, not you, that caused the apple to hit
not you, that caused the apple to hit
not you, that caused the apple to hit the ground. You understand? You release
the ground. You understand? You release
the ground. You understand? You release the potential, but the field is what
the potential, but the field is what
the potential, but the field is what brought forth what you witness. Yeah.
That's all you need to know.
That's all you need to know. That's all you need to know. And then
That's all you need to know. And then
That's all you need to know. And then from knowing it, you realize it. You
from knowing it, you realize it. You
from knowing it, you realize it. You realize it by first of all, you take my
realize it by first of all, you take my
realize it by first of all, you take my word for it.
I have no profit to lie to you. There's
I have no profit to lie to you. There's no profit in that.
The mind cannot catch it that rapidly.
The mind cannot catch it that rapidly. How can it be caught?
How can it be caught?
How can it be caught? The the field of the witness observer is
The the field of the witness observer is
The the field of the witness observer is faster than the mind. So the mind will
faster than the mind. So the mind will
faster than the mind. So the mind will run along the billiard balls looking for
run along the billiard balls looking for
run along the billiard balls looking for the space between the billiard balls. It
the space between the billiard balls. It
the space between the billiard balls. It won't find it.
Out of the infinite space then arises
Out of the infinite space then arises the actualization of potentiality.
the actualization of potentiality.
the actualization of potentiality. out of nothingness.
out of nothingness.
out of nothingness. The nine the mind is 99% silent.
The nine the mind is 99% silent.
The nine the mind is 99% silent. What happens is we become hypnotized and
What happens is we become hypnotized and
What happens is we become hypnotized and fascinated by the 1%.
fascinated by the 1%.
fascinated by the 1%. 1% is like having the TV set on in the
1% is like having the TV set on in the
1% is like having the TV set on in the corner.
corner.
corner. The whole room is empty. The
The whole room is empty. The
The whole room is empty. The amphitheater is empty. You're in the
amphitheater is empty. You're in the
amphitheater is empty. You're in the Roman coliseum. There's nobody there.
Roman coliseum. There's nobody there.
Roman coliseum. There's nobody there. There little 4-in TV set in the corner
There little 4-in TV set in the corner
There little 4-in TV set in the corner and you're focused on it.
Why don't you go away from the little
Why don't you go away from the little 4-in television set and experience the
4-in television set and experience the
4-in television set and experience the grand jur and the stillness, the
grand jur and the stillness, the
grand jur and the stillness, the coliseum at midnight in a full moon,
coliseum at midnight in a full moon,
coliseum at midnight in a full moon, nobody there but yourself.
nobody there but yourself.
nobody there but yourself. It's because you've become hypnotized.
to realize that the mind is a
to realize that the mind is a nothingness, an emptiness.
nothingness, an emptiness.
nothingness, an emptiness. There's a program going on
There's a program going on
There's a program going on and you have become hypnotized by the
and you have become hypnotized by the
and you have become hypnotized by the program. You're hypnotized, brainwashed
program. You're hypnotized, brainwashed
program. You're hypnotized, brainwashed to believe that that's you and that's
to believe that that's you and that's
to believe that that's you and that's your mind.
So, we start out with those grim words
So, we start out with those grim words and it gets better.
So, we'll
So, we'll go through. How many people have never
go through. How many people have never
go through. How many people have never read Power Versus Force?
read Power Versus Force?
read Power Versus Force? Oh my God. Please, Lord.
How have I failed thee, Lord?
How have I failed thee, Lord? I haven't because you're here today.
I haven't because you're here today.
I haven't because you're here today. Okay. So, for the sake of those who
Okay. So, for the sake of those who
Okay. So, for the sake of those who misfortunates,
misfortunates,
misfortunates, we will uh put the map of consciousness
we will uh put the map of consciousness
we will uh put the map of consciousness up there.
up there.
up there. The MEP consciousness has evolved over
The MEP consciousness has evolved over
The MEP consciousness has evolved over the centuries. You know, evolved over
the centuries. You know, evolved over
the centuries. You know, evolved over the centuries. It's collectively man's
the centuries. It's collectively man's
the centuries. It's collectively man's wisdom.
wisdom.
wisdom. Um, this is a modification from Columbia
Um, this is a modification from Columbia
Um, this is a modification from Columbia Psychoanalytic Institute.
Psychoanalytic Institute.
Psychoanalytic Institute. Below below the level of 200, they're
Below below the level of 200, they're
Below below the level of 200, they're called the emergency emotions. Over 200,
called the emergency emotions. Over 200,
called the emergency emotions. Over 200, they're called the welfare emotions.
they're called the welfare emotions.
they're called the welfare emotions. It it's throughout the it's the
It it's throughout the it's the
It it's throughout the it's the perennial philosophy. It's the wisdom of
perennial philosophy. It's the wisdom of
perennial philosophy. It's the wisdom of the ages. revisited. The only difference
the ages. revisited. The only difference
the ages. revisited. The only difference is it's stratified on a calibrated scale
is it's stratified on a calibrated scale
is it's stratified on a calibrated scale logarithmic scale of 1 to a thousand.
This particular lifetime
This particular lifetime to be understood have to
to be understood have to
to be understood have to uh this particular lifetime was unusual
uh this particular lifetime was unusual
uh this particular lifetime was unusual in this entity speaking here. Well,
in this entity speaking here. Well,
in this entity speaking here. Well, it began at age three with rather
it began at age three with rather
it began at age three with rather stunning, quite advanced, what the role
stunning, quite advanced, what the role
stunning, quite advanced, what the role calls advanced spiritual experiences.
calls advanced spiritual experiences.
calls advanced spiritual experiences. At age three, out of nothingness,
At age three, out of nothingness,
At age three, out of nothingness, out of nothingness, out of complete and
out of nothingness, out of complete and
out of nothingness, out of complete and total oblivion,
total oblivion,
total oblivion, out of nothingness, suddenly,
out of nothingness, suddenly,
out of nothingness, suddenly, stunningly,
stunningly,
stunningly, there was a shocking awareness of
there was a shocking awareness of
there was a shocking awareness of existence. existence as existence
existence. existence as existence
existence. existence as existence without any thought with no words. A
without any thought with no words. A
without any thought with no words. A three-year-old doesn't know the word
three-year-old doesn't know the word
three-year-old doesn't know the word word existence.
word existence.
word existence. There wasn't any thinkingness involved,
There wasn't any thinkingness involved,
There wasn't any thinkingness involved, just the confrontation out of
just the confrontation out of
just the confrontation out of nothingness with existence,
which was not pleasing.
which was not pleasing. Oblivion was fine.
Oblivion was fine.
Oblivion was fine. Existence brought up immediate problems.
Existence brought up immediate problems.
Existence brought up immediate problems. The first one being if you exist it
The first one being if you exist it
The first one being if you exist it could have come about that you would not
could have come about that you would not
could have come about that you would not have existed. So the first thing that
have existed. So the first thing that
have existed. So the first thing that happens when you identify reality's
happens when you identify reality's
happens when you identify reality's existence is the fear of non-existence
existence is the fear of non-existence
existence is the fear of non-existence was the ultimate reality
was the ultimate reality
was the ultimate reality existence or non-existence
as a hinana Buddhist
as a hinana Buddhist negating everything I had arrived in the
negating everything I had arrived in the
negating everything I had arrived in the void.
void.
void. If the void was real, you'd stay there.
If the void was real, you'd stay there.
If the void was real, you'd stay there. The void is almost real, but not quite.
Out of nothingness then arose the
Out of nothingness then arose the stunning confrontation of existence and
stunning confrontation of existence and
stunning confrontation of existence and immediately arose uh out of existence
immediately arose uh out of existence
immediately arose uh out of existence the fear of non-existence
the fear of non-existence
the fear of non-existence was the ultimate reality. Nothingness or
was the ultimate reality. Nothingness or
was the ultimate reality. Nothingness or allness. That was the dilemma
allness. That was the dilemma
allness. That was the dilemma which you resolve at consciousness level
which you resolve at consciousness level
which you resolve at consciousness level 850
850 whether the ultimate reality is
whether the ultimate reality is
whether the ultimate reality is nothingness or allness.
nothingness or allness.
nothingness or allness. So out of that mistransation
So out of that mistransation
So out of that mistransation misunderstanding of the Buddha's work
misunderstanding of the Buddha's work
misunderstanding of the Buddha's work that the ultimate reality is void
that the ultimate reality is void
that the ultimate reality is void nothingness it's no thingness it's
nothingness it's no thingness it's
nothingness it's no thingness it's beyond form in as much as it's beyond
beyond form in as much as it's beyond
beyond form in as much as it's beyond form is allness. Nothing
form is allness. Nothing
form is allness. Nothing could exist or be known to exist
could exist or be known to exist
could exist or be known to exist except for the infinite reality of
except for the infinite reality of
except for the infinite reality of allness.
allness.
allness. Was the ultimate reality nothingness or
Was the ultimate reality nothingness or
Was the ultimate reality nothingness or allness? Existence or non-existence
at age three.
at age three. I said it was a weird a weird life.
And such experiences then had to do with
And such experiences then had to do with what's real. And I would sit in class
what's real. And I would sit in class
what's real. And I would sit in class trying to the sense of self would
trying to the sense of self would
trying to the sense of self would disappear into sort of an infinite field
disappear into sort of an infinite field
disappear into sort of an infinite field and I would get scared and I would try
and I would get scared and I would try
and I would get scared and I would try to bring myself together to give my name
to bring myself together to give my name
to bring myself together to give my name that I'm sitting in this chair etc.
that I'm sitting in this chair etc.
that I'm sitting in this chair etc. And then um oh in um adolescence
And then um oh in um adolescence
And then um oh in um adolescence it was another ex exquisite experience
it was another ex exquisite experience
it was another ex exquisite experience of uh in a blizzard one time to get out
of uh in a blizzard one time to get out
of uh in a blizzard one time to get out of the wind. I got into a snowbank. I
of the wind. I got into a snowbank. I
of the wind. I got into a snowbank. I was not in bad condition or anything.
was not in bad condition or anything.
was not in bad condition or anything. It's just I wanted to get away from the
It's just I wanted to get away from the
It's just I wanted to get away from the cold. Uh it was a blizzard. It was pitch
cold. Uh it was a blizzard. It was pitch
cold. Uh it was a blizzard. It was pitch black. No electricity on the highway
black. No electricity on the highway
black. No electricity on the highway where I lived.
where I lived.
where I lived. And no sooner did I make a hole than and
And no sooner did I make a hole than and
And no sooner did I make a hole than and I got out of the wind and an infinite
I got out of the wind and an infinite
I got out of the wind and an infinite presence of such exquisite magnificence.
The mind melted in into its presence.
The mind melted in into its presence. The infinite sense of love was
The infinite sense of love was
The infinite sense of love was exquisite, exquisite beyond description.
exquisite, exquisite beyond description.
exquisite, exquisite beyond description. The mind, what was the mind melts and
The mind, what was the mind melts and
The mind, what was the mind melts and becomes silent. And there was the
becomes silent. And there was the
becomes silent. And there was the awareness that that which I am existed
awareness that that which I am existed
awareness that that which I am existed before all universes and will be in
before all universes and will be in
before all universes and will be in existence after all universes have ended
existence after all universes have ended
existence after all universes have ended beyond all time.
That was true. The revelation of the
That was true. The revelation of the presence then
the only change in life after that was
the only change in life after that was uh as I told the story before my father
uh as I told the story before my father
uh as I told the story before my father found me in the snowbank
found me in the snowbank
found me in the snowbank and I was in this exquisite state. No
and I was in this exquisite state. No
and I was in this exquisite state. No need to breathe. No need to resume the
need to breathe. No need to resume the
need to breathe. No need to resume the body.
He thought if I didn't believe he he
He thought if I didn't believe he he thought if I didn't breathe again that I
thought if I didn't breathe again that I
thought if I didn't breathe again that I was dead. My father
was dead. My father
was dead. My father uh God. So if I didn't breathe and
uh God. So if I didn't breathe and
uh God. So if I didn't breathe and didn't reactivate the body, he would go
didn't reactivate the body, he would go
didn't reactivate the body, he would go through a lifetime feeling guilty that
through a lifetime feeling guilty that
through a lifetime feeling guilty that his son had died in a snowbank
his son had died in a snowbank
his son had died in a snowbank in a blizzard and it was his fault. So
in a blizzard and it was his fault. So
in a blizzard and it was his fault. So he would have been saddled with guilt
he would have been saddled with guilt
he would have been saddled with guilt for the rest of his days. No doubt
for the rest of his days. No doubt
for the rest of his days. No doubt I love my father a great deal. So for
I love my father a great deal. So for
I love my father a great deal. So for the sake of love
the sake of love
the sake of love I like reown the body.
I like reown the body.
I like reown the body. grave error but nevertheless
grave error but nevertheless
grave error but nevertheless never heard of codependency
Same thing happened several times in his
Same thing happened several times in his lifetime when for the sake of love one
lifetime when for the sake of love one
lifetime when for the sake of love one decides to reactivate the body.
decides to reactivate the body.
decides to reactivate the body. Then
Then
Then um I'll finish this story of the author
um I'll finish this story of the author
um I'll finish this story of the author here so that we don't have to go back
here so that we don't have to go back
here so that we don't have to go back into it later. So I forget the sequence
into it later. So I forget the sequence
into it later. So I forget the sequence of events but uh I was brought up
of events but uh I was brought up
of events but uh I was brought up extremely religious high episcopal. I
extremely religious high episcopal. I
extremely religious high episcopal. I was a older boy. I was an acolyte to the
was a older boy. I was an acolyte to the
was a older boy. I was an acolyte to the bishop. I was a boy soprano
bishop. I was a boy soprano
bishop. I was a boy soprano and um very religious scrupulous.
and um very religious scrupulous.
and um very religious scrupulous. I went to confession late Saturday
I went to confession late Saturday
I went to confession late Saturday afternoon and went to the earliest
afternoon and went to the earliest
afternoon and went to the earliest communion on Sunday morning possible to
communion on Sunday morning possible to
communion on Sunday morning possible to leave as short a possible time in which
leave as short a possible time in which
leave as short a possible time in which a sin could occur.
a sin could occur.
a sin could occur. A sin was a black spot on your soul
A sin was a black spot on your soul
A sin was a black spot on your soul which God could see and I lived in dread
which God could see and I lived in dread
which God could see and I lived in dread of it.
Carefully you had to live when you got
Carefully you had to live when you got through confession, said about 10 Hail
through confession, said about 10 Hail
through confession, said about 10 Hail Marys and did the rosary carefully.
Marys and did the rosary carefully.
Marys and did the rosary carefully. carefully. You guarded your thoughts and
carefully. You guarded your thoughts and
carefully. You guarded your thoughts and you lived in fear that a sin might
you lived in fear that a sin might
you lived in fear that a sin might happen.
happen.
happen. And you could finally get into 7:00
And you could finally get into 7:00
And you could finally get into 7:00 mass, have communion, and now you could
mass, have communion, and now you could
mass, have communion, and now you could relax.
Scrupulosity. Yeah.
Scrupulosity. Yeah. And I was tell the tale I was on the way
And I was tell the tale I was on the way
And I was tell the tale I was on the way to communion and uh in the 29 Model A
to communion and uh in the 29 Model A
to communion and uh in the 29 Model A Ford with the top down and we passed a
Ford with the top down and we passed a
Ford with the top down and we passed a 30foot billboard, a Jansen swimming suit
30foot billboard, a Jansen swimming suit
30foot billboard, a Jansen swimming suit sign, a 30-foot blonde curvishly laid
sign, a 30-foot blonde curvishly laid
sign, a 30-foot blonde curvishly laid out like this and then I saw a black
out like this and then I saw a black
out like this and then I saw a black spot.
spot.
spot. At 14, there's nothing but pure
At 14, there's nothing but pure
At 14, there's nothing but pure testosterone running through your veins.
testosterone running through your veins.
testosterone running through your veins. I thought, "Oh god, I've sinned."
I thought, "Oh god, I've sinned."
I thought, "Oh god, I've sinned." So now I didn't want my folks to know
So now I didn't want my folks to know
So now I didn't want my folks to know what I had sinned. So here I'm at the
what I had sinned. So here I'm at the
what I had sinned. So here I'm at the communion rail and I thought if I take
communion rail and I thought if I take
communion rail and I thought if I take the communion with this spot on my soul,
the communion with this spot on my soul,
the communion with this spot on my soul, I expected lightning to come down and be
I expected lightning to come down and be
I expected lightning to come down and be struck dead.
struck dead.
struck dead. So I was terrified. So I sipped from the
So I was terrified. So I sipped from the
So I was terrified. So I sipped from the cup and no lightning. Boy,
you can see why I later I became an
you can see why I later I became an atheist.
That's looking for God to the downside.
That's looking for God to the downside. Guilt, fear,
Guilt, fear,
Guilt, fear, etc. Downside of the scale of
etc. Downside of the scale of
etc. Downside of the scale of consciousness.
consciousness.
consciousness. Guilt, sackcloth, and ashes, penance,
Guilt, sackcloth, and ashes, penance,
Guilt, sackcloth, and ashes, penance, saying the rosary.
Yeah.
Yeah. Later on one day I was walking through
Later on one day I was walking through
Later on one day I was walking through the woods. October stunningly beautiful.
the woods. October stunningly beautiful.
the woods. October stunningly beautiful. Out of nothingness I wasn't thinking
Out of nothingness I wasn't thinking
Out of nothingness I wasn't thinking about anything.
about anything.
about anything. Out of nothingness
Out of nothingness
Out of nothingness came the realization
came the realization
came the realization of the totality of man's suffering
of the totality of man's suffering
of the totality of man's suffering throughout all of time.
throughout all of time.
throughout all of time. All of a sudden, it was like a
All of a sudden, it was like a
All of a sudden, it was like a presentation
presentation
presentation in which I witnessed and comprehended
in which I witnessed and comprehended
in which I witnessed and comprehended the totality of all of mankind's
the totality of all of mankind's
the totality of all of mankind's suffering throughout all of time.
It was staggering,
It was staggering, staggering, shocking.
staggering, shocking.
staggering, shocking. The totality of it is incomprehensible,
The totality of it is incomprehensible,
The totality of it is incomprehensible, not explicable,
not explicable,
not explicable, cannot be
cannot be
cannot be defined in linear terminology.
defined in linear terminology.
defined in linear terminology. Its totality is staggering.
Its totality is staggering.
Its totality is staggering. Instantly I thought any god who would
Instantly I thought any god who would
Instantly I thought any god who would create this or allow this I couldn't
create this or allow this I couldn't
create this or allow this I couldn't believe in. In an instant I became an
believe in. In an instant I became an
believe in. In an instant I became an atheist.
atheist.
atheist. Very intense atheist too.
Very intense atheist too.
Very intense atheist too. Very learned atheist. I could out
Very learned atheist. I could out
Very learned atheist. I could out maneuver all the Catholic theo
maneuver all the Catholic theo
maneuver all the Catholic theo theologians. I got straight A in
theologians. I got straight A in
theologians. I got straight A in theology and ethics and everything in
theology and ethics and everything in
theology and ethics and everything in the Jesuit university. Didn't believe
the Jesuit university. Didn't believe
the Jesuit university. Didn't believe any of it,
any of it,
any of it, but I was an expert at it because if
but I was an expert at it because if
but I was an expert at it because if you're going to disagree with something,
you're going to disagree with something,
you're going to disagree with something, you better be an expert at it.
So then I was an atheist for many years.
So then I was an atheist for many years. Atheist for many years.
Atheist for many years.
Atheist for many years. But still dedicated to ascertaining what
But still dedicated to ascertaining what
But still dedicated to ascertaining what is truth? How can truth be identified?
is truth? How can truth be identified?
is truth? How can truth be identified? As a youth, while other normal children
As a youth, while other normal children
As a youth, while other normal children were out playing stickball and and jacks
were out playing stickball and and jacks
were out playing stickball and and jacks and wrestling, doing other disgusting
and wrestling, doing other disgusting
and wrestling, doing other disgusting things.
things.
things. I think they're disgusting. Dirty
I think they're disgusting. Dirty
I think they're disgusting. Dirty fingernails and they're sticking them in
fingernails and they're sticking them in
fingernails and they're sticking them in your face and oh, yuck.
your face and oh, yuck.
your face and oh, yuck. So I was reading Plato and the apherisms
So I was reading Plato and the apherisms
So I was reading Plato and the apherisms of
arguing Plato and Aristotle and
arguing Plato and Aristotle and Socrates. Socrates was my hero. Uh
Socrates. Socrates was my hero. Uh
Socrates. Socrates was my hero. Uh Socrates is still my hero in worldly
Socrates is still my hero in worldly
Socrates is still my hero in worldly hero. Socrates calibrates at 540.
hero. Socrates calibrates at 540.
hero. Socrates calibrates at 540. Socrates, I don't know how he had such a
Socrates, I don't know how he had such a
Socrates, I don't know how he had such a profound faith and knowledge of God
profound faith and knowledge of God
profound faith and knowledge of God because uh
because uh
because uh the religions that we know about today
the religions that we know about today
the religions that we know about today didn't even exist in those days. But
didn't even exist in those days. But
didn't even exist in those days. But through the elect then anyway, however
through the elect then anyway, however
through the elect then anyway, however Socrates got there,
Socrates got there,
Socrates got there, uh Socrates actually willingly gave up
uh Socrates actually willingly gave up
uh Socrates actually willingly gave up his life for the sake of truth rather
his life for the sake of truth rather
his life for the sake of truth rather than violate his belief system to thine
than violate his belief system to thine
than violate his belief system to thine own self be true.
own self be true.
own self be true. So, my heroes were Socrates and
So, my heroes were Socrates and
So, my heroes were Socrates and Aristotle and Plato and um
Aristotle and Plato and um
Aristotle and Plato and um uh I had to forget what that's got to do
uh I had to forget what that's got to do
uh I had to forget what that's got to do with what I was talking about.
with what I was talking about.
with what I was talking about. Anyway, I was Oh yes, I was an atheist.
Anyway, I was Oh yes, I was an atheist.
Anyway, I was Oh yes, I was an atheist. So, oh yes, the Pure with truth. So,
So, oh yes, the Pure with truth. So,
So, oh yes, the Pure with truth. So, then I went into psychoanalysis,
then I went into psychoanalysis,
then I went into psychoanalysis, classical psychoanalysis every day of
classical psychoanalysis every day of
classical psychoanalysis every day of the week for four years.
the week for four years.
the week for four years. training analyst from Columbia
training analyst from Columbia
training analyst from Columbia Psychoanalytic and Lovacy by name whose
Psychoanalytic and Lovacy by name whose
Psychoanalytic and Lovacy by name whose analyst was Carder and Cardner's analyst
analyst was Carder and Cardner's analyst
analyst was Carder and Cardner's analyst was Freud.
was Freud.
was Freud. So Freud was my great-grandfather.
And if you think you don't have an
And if you think you don't have an edible complex, let me tell you,
edible complex, let me tell you,
edible complex, let me tell you, you just lay down on an analyst couch an
you just lay down on an analyst couch an
you just lay down on an analyst couch an hour a day every day of the week and see
hour a day every day of the week and see
hour a day every day of the week and see what comes up. You didn't have to say
what comes up. You didn't have to say
what comes up. You didn't have to say anything. You recreate the whole thing.
anything. You recreate the whole thing.
anything. You recreate the whole thing. Uh so then I looked through
Uh so then I looked through
Uh so then I looked through psychoanalysis and the post and Carl
psychoanalysis and the post and Carl
psychoanalysis and the post and Carl Young and through with great psycho so I
Young and through with great psycho so I
Young and through with great psycho so I looked to psychoanalysis and science and
looked to psychoanalysis and science and
looked to psychoanalysis and science and medicine uh logic the great books of the
medicine uh logic the great books of the
medicine uh logic the great books of the western world which we'll calibrate uh
western world which we'll calibrate uh
western world which we'll calibrate uh later today looked to the intellect for
later today looked to the intellect for
later today looked to the intellect for truth looked into the unconscious
truth looked into the unconscious
truth looked into the unconscious and became ill due to excessive stresses
and became ill due to excessive stresses
and became ill due to excessive stresses of one kind and another
of one kind and another
of one kind and another and one day I decided I was going to go
and one day I decided I was going to go
and one day I decided I was going to go deep into the unconscy
deep into the unconscy
deep into the unconscy unconscious. I was going to go wherever
unconscious. I was going to go wherever
unconscious. I was going to go wherever it took to find the truth.
it took to find the truth.
it took to find the truth. And so I went on a relentless,
And so I went on a relentless,
And so I went on a relentless, I mean absolutely relentless crash
I mean absolutely relentless crash
I mean absolutely relentless crash through every belief system,
through every belief system,
through every belief system, everything that could be held by the
everything that could be held by the
everything that could be held by the mind, every feeling state,
mind, every feeling state,
mind, every feeling state, every intellectual position.
every intellectual position.
every intellectual position. And I drove right to the core of truth
And I drove right to the core of truth
And I drove right to the core of truth with an absolute determination
Wow. I wasn't going to let hell stop me.
Wow. I wasn't going to let hell stop me. So I went through the upper layer, what
So I went through the upper layer, what
So I went through the upper layer, what people call hell are the upper layers. I
people call hell are the upper layers. I
people call hell are the upper layers. I mean that's jacks for openers. torture,
mean that's jacks for openers. torture,
mean that's jacks for openers. torture, the part body parts being torn off, you
the part body parts being torn off, you
the part body parts being torn off, you know, burning sticks through your
know, burning sticks through your
know, burning sticks through your eyeball. That's all child's play.
eyeball. That's all child's play.
eyeball. That's all child's play. That's the top surface, the scary to
That's the top surface, the scary to
That's the top surface, the scary to people. But that's not where it's bad.
people. But that's not where it's bad.
people. But that's not where it's bad. It's beyond beyond that. One gets into
It's beyond beyond that. One gets into
It's beyond beyond that. One gets into the very core of dread.
the very core of dread.
the very core of dread. One gets to the core of hopelessness.
One gets to the core of hopelessness.
One gets to the core of hopelessness. One gets to the core of despair.
One gets to the core of despair.
One gets to the core of despair. And then it gets bad
And then it gets bad
And then it gets bad and you go past it's almost like a sign.
and you go past it's almost like a sign.
and you go past it's almost like a sign. How Dante knew that? I don't know. Cal
How Dante knew that? I don't know. Cal
How Dante knew that? I don't know. Cal Dante calibrates quite high.
Dante calibrates quite high.
Dante calibrates quite high. How did Dante know that? Because that
How did Dante know that? Because that
How did Dante know that? Because that there's a certain level you in which you
there's a certain level you in which you
there's a certain level you in which you realize what hell really is.
realize what hell really is.
realize what hell really is. Far worse than you could imagine. And
Far worse than you could imagine. And
Far worse than you could imagine. And there it says abandon all hope ye who
there it says abandon all hope ye who
there it says abandon all hope ye who enter here. There's the knowingness of
enter here. There's the knowingness of
enter here. There's the knowingness of that.
that.
that. And beyond that then it gets bad. The
And beyond that then it gets bad. The
And beyond that then it gets bad. The hopelessness is eternal.
hopelessness is eternal.
hopelessness is eternal. Hopelessness is forever.
Hopelessness is forever.
Hopelessness is forever. There is nothing and no one to be called
There is nothing and no one to be called
There is nothing and no one to be called upon. Nor is there any recourse.
upon. Nor is there any recourse.
upon. Nor is there any recourse. One is in an agony of despair and
One is in an agony of despair and
One is in an agony of despair and hopelessness forever.
hopelessness forever.
hopelessness forever. And the hell of it is you understand
And the hell of it is you understand
And the hell of it is you understand what forever means.
what forever means.
what forever means. And then the eons go by.
And then the eons go by.
And then the eons go by. Hell forever.
Hell forever.
Hell forever. In the depths of that black blackness,
In the depths of that black blackness,
In the depths of that black blackness, a voice arose within and said,
a voice arose within and said,
a voice arose within and said, "If there is a God, I ask him to help me
"If there is a God, I ask him to help me
"If there is a God, I ask him to help me now."
now."
now." Stupid thing.
Stupid thing.
Stupid thing. when you're hopeless and no appeal is
when you're hopeless and no appeal is
when you're hopeless and no appeal is possible to be answered. And yet a voice
possible to be answered. And yet a voice
possible to be answered. And yet a voice said that. Huh?
And then came oblivion.
And then came oblivion. Complete and total oblivion
Complete and total oblivion
Complete and total oblivion which lasted I don't know how long in
which lasted I don't know how long in
which lasted I don't know how long in earthly time.
earthly time.
earthly time. And then the oblivion cleared. And this
And then the oblivion cleared. And this
And then the oblivion cleared. And this time
time
time the stunning magnificence of the
the stunning magnificence of the
the stunning magnificence of the presence of divinity is all that exists
presence of divinity is all that exists
presence of divinity is all that exists shown forth. The divinity of all
shown forth. The divinity of all
shown forth. The divinity of all existence. The mind
existence. The mind
existence. The mind it disappeared.
There's only infinite field.
There's only infinite field. It's exquisite beauty
is paralyzing.
is paralyzing. can't function in that state and so I
can't function in that state and so I
can't function in that state and so I then did leave the world for some many
then did leave the world for some many
then did leave the world for some many years and actually I had at the time of
years and actually I had at the time of
years and actually I had at the time of all of that the largest psychiatric
all of that the largest psychiatric
all of that the largest psychiatric practice in the United States I had 50
practice in the United States I had 50
practice in the United States I had 50 50 employees half a dozen psychiatrists
50 employees half a dozen psychiatrists
50 employees half a dozen psychiatrists and
and
and we had advanced research laboratory one
we had advanced research laboratory one
we had advanced research laboratory one of the first computers in the country
of the first computers in the country
of the first computers in the country and I walked away from it
packed up my tools in my old truck and
packed up my tools in my old truck and drove away.
And the mind never did return to
And the mind never did return to thinking.
manifests forth in this world as the
manifests forth in this world as the speakingness.
speakingness.
speakingness. The speakingness is a consequence of the
The speakingness is a consequence of the
The speakingness is a consequence of the presence. Yeah.
presence. Yeah.
presence. Yeah. Because everything is happening of its
Because everything is happening of its
Because everything is happening of its own.
own.
own. As you see, the body moves about by
As you see, the body moves about by
As you see, the body moves about by itself.
itself.
itself. You see that it's walking by itself. You
You see that it's walking by itself. You
You see that it's walking by itself. You see anybody making it walk?
see anybody making it walk?
see anybody making it walk? I don't know what it's going to do. What
I don't know what it's going to do. What
I don't know what it's going to do. What are you doing?
are you doing?
are you doing? How should I know?
How should I know?
How should I know? It does whatever it does by itself.
It's always doing that.
It's always doing that. Consequently,
Consequently,
Consequently, no longer having the heavy burden of
no longer having the heavy burden of
no longer having the heavy burden of being the cause of things,
being the cause of things,
being the cause of things, your life can be one of infinite joy and
your life can be one of infinite joy and
your life can be one of infinite joy and ecstasy.
ecstasy.
ecstasy. And then it's hard to stay serious.
Oh god.
Oh god. Um, plumb out from all that. However,
Um, plumb out from all that. However,
Um, plumb out from all that. However, people do ask, "What is it like? what
people do ask, "What is it like? what
people do ask, "What is it like? what what are the experiences? How does it
what are the experiences? How does it
what are the experiences? How does it come about? And so I've told you
come about? And so I've told you
come about? And so I've told you having done my duty, we will go on with
having done my duty, we will go on with
having done my duty, we will go on with the lecture.
the lecture.
the lecture. Uh
one time I went to a lecture by
one time I went to a lecture by um
um
um Dr. Diamond, John Diamond,
Dr. Diamond, John Diamond,
Dr. Diamond, John Diamond, having to do with kinesiology. And uh so
having to do with kinesiology. And uh so
having to do with kinesiology. And uh so he's an excellent teacher
he's an excellent teacher
he's an excellent teacher and he uh gave a course on kinesiology
and he uh gave a course on kinesiology
and he uh gave a course on kinesiology applied kinesiology
applied kinesiology
applied kinesiology and his two books the body doesn't lie
and his two books the body doesn't lie
and his two books the body doesn't lie and behavioral kinesiology are classics
and behavioral kinesiology are classics
and behavioral kinesiology are classics in the field and when I watched the
in the field and when I watched the
in the field and when I watched the phenomenon of kinesiology because of the
phenomenon of kinesiology because of the
phenomenon of kinesiology because of the experiences I'd had I understood it in a
experiences I'd had I understood it in a
experiences I'd had I understood it in a different context
different context
different context everybody was in
everybody was in
everybody was in their life is in the Newtonian
their life is in the Newtonian
their life is in the Newtonian causality. So they saw this causing of
causality. So they saw this causing of
causality. So they saw this causing of that. So they saw kinesiology as a local
that. So they saw kinesiology as a local
that. So they saw kinesiology as a local phenomena.
phenomena.
phenomena. You put a fig here and if you're
You put a fig here and if you're
You put a fig here and if you're allergic to figs your arm goes weak. So
allergic to figs your arm goes weak. So
allergic to figs your arm goes weak. So they looked at it like fig arm cause
they looked at it like fig arm cause
they looked at it like fig arm cause effect. See so they were seeing it as a
effect. See so they were seeing it as a
effect. See so they were seeing it as a local phenomena. I thought that's
local phenomena. I thought that's
local phenomena. I thought that's ridiculous you know. So what I could see
ridiculous you know. So what I could see
ridiculous you know. So what I could see what I saw was there's an infinite
what I saw was there's an infinite
what I saw was there's an infinite field.
field.
field. When you present to the field that which
When you present to the field that which
When you present to the field that which is concordant with truth or life
is concordant with truth or life
is concordant with truth or life because of the field the life energy
because of the field the life energy
because of the field the life energy flows and you go strong.
flows and you go strong.
flows and you go strong. In the absence of truth the body goes
In the absence of truth the body goes
In the absence of truth the body goes weak. The absence of truth is what the
weak. The absence of truth is what the
weak. The absence of truth is what the world calls false because the world
world calls false because the world
world calls false because the world thinks as dualistic opposites.
thinks as dualistic opposites.
thinks as dualistic opposites. H
H
H that which is supportive of life. That
that which is supportive of life. That
that which is supportive of life. That which is aligned with truth
which is aligned with truth
which is aligned with truth energizes the body. The b the body goes
energizes the body. The b the body goes
energizes the body. The b the body goes strong. It's a quick response.
strong. It's a quick response.
strong. It's a quick response. Quick response. You can feel the energy
Quick response. You can feel the energy
Quick response. You can feel the energy flow down the arm and then you press
flow down the arm and then you press
flow down the arm and then you press down with two fingers.
down with two fingers.
down with two fingers. So you say, "Elephants calibrate over
So you say, "Elephants calibrate over
So you say, "Elephants calibrate over 120. Resist." If they're over 120, the
120. Resist." If they're over 120, the
120. Resist." If they're over 120, the arm will go strong.
arm will go strong.
arm will go strong. You see, elephants calibrate over 600.
You see, elephants calibrate over 600.
You see, elephants calibrate over 600. Weak. Okay.
It's not yes and no. It's yes or not
It's not yes and no. It's yes or not yes. There is no opposite.
Truth is either present or not present.
Truth is either present or not present. There isn't an opposite to truth called
There isn't an opposite to truth called
There isn't an opposite to truth called falsehood.
falsehood.
falsehood. It is not an o opposite. It's an
It is not an o opposite. It's an
It is not an o opposite. It's an absence.
absence.
absence. Just as electricity
Just as electricity
Just as electricity flows down a wire, it's either on or
flows down a wire, it's either on or
flows down a wire, it's either on or it's not on. There is not an opposite of
it's not on. There is not an opposite of
it's not on. There is not an opposite of electricity called offness.
electricity called offness.
electricity called offness. You say there's onness going down the
You say there's onness going down the
You say there's onness going down the wire. Now there's offness going down the
wire. Now there's offness going down the
wire. Now there's offness going down the wire. You see the fallacy? So there you
wire. You see the fallacy? So there you
wire. You see the fallacy? So there you begin to catch what the Newtonian
begin to catch what the Newtonian
begin to catch what the Newtonian duality is about.
duality is about.
duality is about. Truth is either present or not present.
Truth is either present or not present.
Truth is either present or not present. Reality is not a duality. It's a
Reality is not a duality. It's a
Reality is not a duality. It's a singularity expressed in a matter of
singularity expressed in a matter of
singularity expressed in a matter of degrees which will explain.
Truth is either present or not present.
Truth is either present or not present. Then what we discovered is that truth
Then what we discovered is that truth
Then what we discovered is that truth could be calibrated on a scale of 1 to a
could be calibrated on a scale of 1 to a
could be calibrated on a scale of 1 to a thousand
thousand
thousand a logarithmic scale.
a logarithmic scale.
a logarithmic scale. What's the smallest energy of living
What's the smallest energy of living
What's the smallest energy of living things we consciousness conscious things
things we consciousness conscious things
things we consciousness conscious things and we got it was bacteria.
and we got it was bacteria.
and we got it was bacteria. Bacteria then became number one.
Bacteria then became number one.
Bacteria then became number one. What's the highest consciousness that's
What's the highest consciousness that's
What's the highest consciousness that's ever walked the planet?
ever walked the planet?
ever walked the planet? We got the great avatars. Jesus Christ,
We got the great avatars. Jesus Christ,
We got the great avatars. Jesus Christ, Krishna, Buddha at 1000. Between
Krishna, Buddha at 1000. Between
Krishna, Buddha at 1000. Between bacteria
bacteria
bacteria and the great avatars,
and the great avatars,
and the great avatars, all of life, all expressions of life can
all of life, all expressions of life can
all of life, all expressions of life can be calibrated from one to a thousand.
be calibrated from one to a thousand.
be calibrated from one to a thousand. This gives us a new way of looking at
This gives us a new way of looking at
This gives us a new way of looking at the world,
a new way of looking at the world
a new way of looking at the world to see the relative truth of everything
to see the relative truth of everything
to see the relative truth of everything within the world.
All right. So, let's go to the
All right. So, let's go to the calibrated levels. Can you see see that
calibrated levels. Can you see see that
calibrated levels. Can you see see that from back there? Golly, I can't see it
from back there? Golly, I can't see it
from back there? Golly, I can't see it at all.
at all.
at all. Well, I don't see much anyway. So,
Well, I don't see much anyway. So,
Well, I don't see much anyway. So, anyway, we got a thingy here that makes
anyway, we got a thingy here that makes
anyway, we got a thingy here that makes this light up or else it turns on the
this light up or else it turns on the
this light up or else it turns on the television. One of the other iss going
television. One of the other iss going
television. One of the other iss going to happen. Wow. Can you see that?
to happen. Wow. Can you see that?
to happen. Wow. Can you see that? >> My golly.
>> My golly.
>> My golly. All right. So, we calibrated then a
All right. So, we calibrated then a
All right. So, we calibrated then a scale of consciousness from one to a
scale of consciousness from one to a
scale of consciousness from one to a thousand. We said on a hypothetical
thousand. We said on a hypothetical
thousand. We said on a hypothetical scale one to a thousand all that exists
scale one to a thousand all that exists
scale one to a thousand all that exists can be calibrated.
can be calibrated.
can be calibrated. Also, it extend extends beyond time.
We found that everything that cal that
We found that everything that cal that was true or supportive of life
was true or supportive of life
was true or supportive of life calibrated over 200.
calibrated over 200.
calibrated over 200. Everything that was false nonsup
Everything that was false nonsup
Everything that was false nonsup supportive of life. The absence of truth
supportive of life. The absence of truth
supportive of life. The absence of truth calibrated below 200. So we have then a
calibrated below 200. So we have then a
calibrated below 200. So we have then a line.
line.
line. Everything above 200 is relative degrees
Everything above 200 is relative degrees
Everything above 200 is relative degrees of truth. Below 200 is falsehood.
And we discovered you could calibrate
And we discovered you could calibrate anything and everything that exists or
anything and everything that exists or
anything and everything that exists or ever did exist.
ever did exist.
ever did exist. The infinite field of consciousness then
The infinite field of consciousness then
The infinite field of consciousness then the substrate of all existence and all
the substrate of all existence and all
the substrate of all existence and all of life
without which nothing could be known.
without which nothing could be known. The infinite field beyond all time,
The infinite field beyond all time,
The infinite field beyond all time, beyond all dimension, beyond all measure
beyond all dimension, beyond all measure
beyond all dimension, beyond all measure is like a giant field which records
is like a giant field which records
is like a giant field which records everything that ever existed.
everything that ever existed.
everything that ever existed. Every thought, every passing feeling,
Every thought, every passing feeling,
Every thought, every passing feeling, no matter how seemingly trivial, is
no matter how seemingly trivial, is
no matter how seemingly trivial, is recorded in this infinite field forever.
recorded in this infinite field forever.
recorded in this infinite field forever. Forever beyond time.
Forever beyond time.
Forever beyond time. Consequently, anything that has ever
Consequently, anything that has ever
Consequently, anything that has ever existed, done, or been happened,
existed, done, or been happened,
existed, done, or been happened, everything that ever happened anywhere
everything that ever happened anywhere
everything that ever happened anywhere in time or location or space can be
in time or location or space can be
in time or location or space can be retrieved and calibrated right now.
retrieved and calibrated right now.
retrieved and calibrated right now. There is no past. There is no time
There is no past. There is no time
There is no past. There is no time dimension.
dimension.
dimension. That which has no beginning, has no
That which has no beginning, has no
That which has no beginning, has no ending. Therefore, it is outside of
ending. Therefore, it is outside of
ending. Therefore, it is outside of time. Therefore, every hair on your head
time. Therefore, every hair on your head
time. Therefore, every hair on your head should be counted is true.
The very essence of karma. Everything
The very essence of karma. Everything that one does, every intention
that one does, every intention
that one does, every intention most important of all is intention then
most important of all is intention then
most important of all is intention then is recorded
is recorded
is recorded like on a disc forever.
It's fantastic. It's also scary. Huh?
It's fantastic. It's also scary. Huh? Why is it scary? Because people say,
Why is it scary? Because people say,
Why is it scary? Because people say, "Yeah, but think of all the bad thoughts
"Yeah, but think of all the bad thoughts
"Yeah, but think of all the bad thoughts I've had and all. All the people I've
I've had and all. All the people I've
I've had and all. All the people I've probably killed over the lifetimes."
probably killed over the lifetimes."
probably killed over the lifetimes." Good thing you did. I remember killing
Good thing you did. I remember killing
Good thing you did. I remember killing people.
people.
people. Good. Good thing too.
One lifetime. or
One lifetime. or in a certain level of consciousness, you
in a certain level of consciousness, you
in a certain level of consciousness, you remember these lifetimes, you know, and
remember these lifetimes, you know, and
remember these lifetimes, you know, and it was during the Crusades. And uh this
it was during the Crusades. And uh this
it was during the Crusades. And uh this guy's recurred throughout a number of
guy's recurred throughout a number of
guy's recurred throughout a number of lifetimes and he's a he's a pal of mine
lifetimes and he's a he's a pal of mine
lifetimes and he's a he's a pal of mine forever. Anyway, we're both warriors and
forever. Anyway, we're both warriors and
forever. Anyway, we're both warriors and we were both really good at what we do.
we were both really good at what we do.
we were both really good at what we do. I mean, if it's your turn to be killed,
I mean, if it's your turn to be killed,
I mean, if it's your turn to be killed, you'd better elect me because I am good
you'd better elect me because I am good
you'd better elect me because I am good at it. Perfected it many a lifetime. You
at it. Perfected it many a lifetime. You
at it. Perfected it many a lifetime. You can't trans transcend it till you master
can't trans transcend it till you master
can't trans transcend it till you master it. Anyway, in this lifetime,
it. Anyway, in this lifetime,
it. Anyway, in this lifetime, uh it was during the Crusades, I get to
uh it was during the Crusades, I get to
uh it was during the Crusades, I get to the year 1099 or whatever it was, and he
the year 1099 or whatever it was, and he
the year 1099 or whatever it was, and he was
was
was a warrior for Allah and I was a warrior
a warrior for Allah and I was a warrior
a warrior for Allah and I was a warrior for Christ. So, here we are in the Holy
for Christ. So, here we are in the Holy
for Christ. So, here we are in the Holy Lands and I was good and he was
Lands and I was good and he was
Lands and I was good and he was excellent. He was super
excellent. He was super
excellent. He was super right through that I got him and he got
right through that I got him and he got
right through that I got him and he got me through at the same time. Both went
me through at the same time. Both went
me through at the same time. Both went on a body. I looked at him. He looked at
on a body. I looked at him. He looked at
on a body. I looked at him. He looked at me. We both break out laughing.
me. We both break out laughing.
me. We both break out laughing. I did it for Jesus. I did it for all
I did it for Jesus. I did it for all
I did it for Jesus. I did it for all buddy. We love each other.
buddy. We love each other.
buddy. We love each other. No. We love each other like two
No. We love each other like two
No. We love each other like two warriors, you know, after the war.
warriors, you know, after the war.
warriors, you know, after the war. Oh god. So you both shoot over 200.
Oh god. So you both shoot over 200.
Oh god. So you both shoot over 200. willingness to sacrifice your life for
willingness to sacrifice your life for
willingness to sacrifice your life for something higher than yourself. So one
something higher than yourself. So one
something higher than yourself. So one of the side effects of war is it's the
of the side effects of war is it's the
of the side effects of war is it's the only way many people can walk into the
only way many people can walk into the
only way many people can walk into the bullet
bullet
bullet face even death themselves for a higher
face even death themselves for a higher
face even death themselves for a higher principle God, country, wife, family,
principle God, country, wife, family,
principle God, country, wife, family, religion, whatever. And
religion, whatever. And
religion, whatever. And the willingness to sacrifice your life
the willingness to sacrifice your life
the willingness to sacrifice your life itself for a higher principle takes you
itself for a higher principle takes you
itself for a higher principle takes you above 200 forever. So you got out of
above 200 forever. So you got out of
above 200 forever. So you got out of cowardice, fear
and you jumped over 200.
and you jumped over 200. So the levels below 200 then we're going
So the levels below 200 then we're going
So the levels below 200 then we're going to see how they evolved because I want
to see how they evolved because I want
to see how they evolved because I want to recontextualize the ego and how it
to recontextualize the ego and how it
to recontextualize the ego and how it arose
arose
arose because the ego seems to be from a
because the ego seems to be from a
because the ego seems to be from a spiritual viewpoint uh man's traditional
spiritual viewpoint uh man's traditional
spiritual viewpoint uh man's traditional enigma
guilt and anger and fear and pride and
guilt and anger and fear and pride and desire and greed and possessiveness
desire and greed and possessiveness
desire and greed and possessiveness in a audience such as this. Those are
in a audience such as this. Those are
in a audience such as this. Those are not the prime problems. Yes, we get
not the prime problems. Yes, we get
not the prime problems. Yes, we get trouble in the desiring and guilt and
trouble in the desiring and guilt and
trouble in the desiring and guilt and angry thoughts and all, but a crowd like
angry thoughts and all, but a crowd like
angry thoughts and all, but a crowd like this, your real problem is you're caught
this, your real problem is you're caught
this, your real problem is you're caught in
in
in the duality of cause and effect. So,
the duality of cause and effect. So,
the duality of cause and effect. So, we'll concentrate more on that today
we'll concentrate more on that today
we'll concentrate more on that today than we usually do on guilt and sin.
than we usually do on guilt and sin.
than we usually do on guilt and sin. There's a lot of preachers on guilt and
There's a lot of preachers on guilt and
There's a lot of preachers on guilt and sin. I don't want to compete with them.
sin. I don't want to compete with them.
sin. I don't want to compete with them. They're experts.
The sackcloth and ashes crowd has been
The sackcloth and ashes crowd has been around for centuries, thousands of
around for centuries, thousands of
around for centuries, thousands of years. So you can go on your knees uh
years. So you can go on your knees uh
years. So you can go on your knees uh around Sat Cathedral and circle it seven
around Sat Cathedral and circle it seven
around Sat Cathedral and circle it seven times this way, seven times this way.
times this way, seven times this way.
times this way, seven times this way. And uh
And uh
And uh good luck.
good luck.
good luck. They sell padded knee things for
They sell padded knee things for
They sell padded knee things for crawling around the cathedral. I don't
crawling around the cathedral. I don't
crawling around the cathedral. I don't know. And sackcloth and ashes for sale.
know. And sackcloth and ashes for sale.
know. And sackcloth and ashes for sale. They never miss a book either around all
They never miss a book either around all
They never miss a book either around all the Greek cathedrals. Sackloth, ashes,
the Greek cathedrals. Sackloth, ashes,
the Greek cathedrals. Sackloth, ashes, crucifixes, coffins, holy metals.
crucifixes, coffins, holy metals.
crucifixes, coffins, holy metals. All right.
So, the calibrated scale of
So, the calibrated scale of consciousness then using kinesiology
consciousness then using kinesiology
consciousness then using kinesiology such as we did and we'll just say a
such as we did and we'll just say a
such as we did and we'll just say a brief note about kinesiology and then
brief note about kinesiology and then
brief note about kinesiology and then we'll go on uh to cover the lecture
we'll go on uh to cover the lecture
we'll go on uh to cover the lecture today.
today.
today. It's a very quick response. Very quick.
It's a very quick response. Very quick.
It's a very quick response. Very quick. You hold something in mind. You don't
You hold something in mind. You don't
You hold something in mind. You don't have to verbalize it. You don't have to
have to verbalize it. You don't have to
have to verbalize it. You don't have to verbalize it. You don't have to
verbalize it. You don't have to
verbalize it. You don't have to verbalize it. I can say to her, "What
verbalize it. I can say to her, "What
verbalize it. I can say to her, "What I'm
I'm
I'm what I'm holding in mind calibrates over
what I'm holding in mind calibrates over
what I'm holding in mind calibrates over 600, 650,
600, 650,
600, 650, 680.
680.
680. What I'm holding in mind calibrates over
What I'm holding in mind calibrates over
What I'm holding in mind calibrates over 670, 680. Thank you. She doesn't know
670, 680. Thank you. She doesn't know
670, 680. Thank you. She doesn't know what I'm holding. See, people say,
what I'm holding. See, people say,
what I'm holding. See, people say, "Well, you're suggesting it." I'm not
"Well, you're suggesting it." I'm not
"Well, you're suggesting it." I'm not suggesting it. She doesn't even know
suggesting it. She doesn't even know
suggesting it. She doesn't even know what I'm holding in mind. It's a
what I'm holding in mind. It's a
what I'm holding in mind. It's a specific cathedral in Europe uh that we
specific cathedral in Europe uh that we
specific cathedral in Europe uh that we were there last year. So, she doesn't
were there last year. So, she doesn't
were there last year. So, she doesn't know what I was holding in mind,
know what I was holding in mind,
know what I was holding in mind, but obviously it calibrates close to
but obviously it calibrates close to
but obviously it calibrates close to 700. The great cathedrals, uh, great
700. The great cathedrals, uh, great
700. The great cathedrals, uh, great Gothic cathedrals all calibrated around
Gothic cathedrals all calibrated around
Gothic cathedrals all calibrated around 700.
700.
700. Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. All right. So you see the calibrated
All right. So you see the calibrated
All right. So you see the calibrated levels
levels
levels are really the animal world. Below 200
are really the animal world. Below 200
are really the animal world. Below 200 you're going to the animal world and the
you're going to the animal world and the
you're going to the animal world and the human world you might say to some degree
human world you might say to some degree
human world you might say to some degree is from 200 on up. All right let's go to
is from 200 on up. All right let's go to
is from 200 on up. All right let's go to the next slide. What time do we have to
the next slide. What time do we have to
the next slide. What time do we have to break for lunch? It's breakfast. Okay we
break for lunch? It's breakfast. Okay we
break for lunch? It's breakfast. Okay we got enough to cover the world here.
those states ordinary consciousness.
those states ordinary consciousness. Then the intellect is in the 400s. Truth
Then the intellect is in the 400s. Truth
Then the intellect is in the 400s. Truth is 200 and up. Uh the 300s are great.
is 200 and up. Uh the 300s are great.
is 200 and up. Uh the 300s are great. The 300s are great. Um the great
The 300s are great. Um the great
The 300s are great. Um the great corporations, the great accomplishments,
corporations, the great accomplishments,
corporations, the great accomplishments, inventions, the steam engine,
inventions, the steam engine,
inventions, the steam engine, uh engineering in the 300s, 400s is
uh engineering in the 300s, 400s is
uh engineering in the 300s, 400s is intellect. We said 450 is
intellect. We said 450 is
intellect. We said 450 is Newton Newton and uh evol theories of
Newton Newton and uh evol theories of
Newton Newton and uh evol theories of evolution theory of evolution see is at
evolution theory of evolution see is at
evolution theory of evolution see is at 450.
450.
450. Now the theory of evolution is at 450
Now the theory of evolution is at 450
Now the theory of evolution is at 450 and you see evolution then from
and you see evolution then from
and you see evolution then from Darwinian viewpoint is cast within a
Darwinian viewpoint is cast within a
Darwinian viewpoint is cast within a Newtonian paradigm of reality. You know
Newtonian paradigm of reality. You know
Newtonian paradigm of reality. You know actually evolution doesn't happen that
actually evolution doesn't happen that
actually evolution doesn't happen that way at all. No, because evolution and
way at all. No, because evolution and
way at all. No, because evolution and creation are one in the same thing.
What you see, what the world calls
What you see, what the world calls evolution
evolution
evolution is the way creation unfolds.
is the way creation unfolds.
is the way creation unfolds. Creation unfolds
Creation unfolds
Creation unfolds thusly.
Creation is continuous, always
Creation is continuous, always ongoing,
progressive in nature. And as we see it
progressive in nature. And as we see it unfolding,
unfolding,
unfolding, we realize
evolution is the way creation manifests
evolution is the way creation manifests itself
itself
itself to witnessing. Because what's sequential
to witnessing. Because what's sequential
to witnessing. Because what's sequential is not evolution. What's sequential is
is not evolution. What's sequential is
is not evolution. What's sequential is you're witnessing.
you're witnessing.
you're witnessing. The only thing that's sequential is
The only thing that's sequential is
The only thing that's sequential is first I see it, see it, see it, see it,
first I see it, see it, see it, see it,
first I see it, see it, see it, see it, see it, see it. That's the only sequence
see it, see it. That's the only sequence
see it, see it. That's the only sequence going on.
going on.
going on. The infinite reality is not sequential.
The infinite reality is not sequential.
The infinite reality is not sequential. Your witnessing of it is sequential.
Your witnessing of it is sequential.
Your witnessing of it is sequential. It unfolds. You say that sequence.
It unfolds. You say that sequence.
It unfolds. You say that sequence. Sequence is a thought in your head. Like
Sequence is a thought in your head. Like
Sequence is a thought in your head. Like causality.
causality.
causality. Causality is a belief system.
So the core of the ego then is the
So the core of the ego then is the Newtonian paradigm of causality. of this
Newtonian paradigm of causality. of this
Newtonian paradigm of causality. of this causing of that.
There is no this causing of that because
There is no this causing of that because causality is a tautology.
causality is a tautology.
causality is a tautology. So the second
So the second
So the second difficulty
difficulty
difficulty is what Decart pointed out long ago. The
is what Decart pointed out long ago. The
is what Decart pointed out long ago. The mind confuses rest internal rest
mind confuses rest internal rest
mind confuses rest internal rest kajutans
kajutans
kajutans with rest externa
with rest externa
with rest externa rest extensza
rest extensza
rest extensza thinkingness is one thing
thinkingness is one thing
thinkingness is one thing the objective reality is something else.
the objective reality is something else.
the objective reality is something else. The mind thinks
The mind thinks
The mind thinks that how it thinks is how it is out
that how it thinks is how it is out
that how it thinks is how it is out there. Confuses risk internal with risk
there. Confuses risk internal with risk
there. Confuses risk internal with risk external.
external.
external. Catastrophic catastrophic catastrophic
Catastrophic catastrophic catastrophic
Catastrophic catastrophic catastrophic limitation.
It cripples you to about level 450.
It cripples you to about level 450. You have to understand what you think is
You have to understand what you think is
You have to understand what you think is not what is.
not what is.
not what is. What you think is what you think.
What you think is what you think.
What you think is what you think. What is has nothing to do with what you
What is has nothing to do with what you
What is has nothing to do with what you think.
think.
think. Causality then is like helotropism.
Causality then is like helotropism.
Causality then is like helotropism. The child comes home or goes to school
The child comes home or goes to school
The child comes home or goes to school and says to the teacher, why is it that
and says to the teacher, why is it that
and says to the teacher, why is it that the sun flower sun follows the sun? She
the sun flower sun follows the sun? She
the sun flower sun follows the sun? She says heliotropism.
says heliotropism.
says heliotropism. Oh ho. The child goes home.
Oh ho. The child goes home.
Oh ho. The child goes home. The mother says, "Why did did you ask
The mother says, "Why did did you ask
The mother says, "Why did did you ask the teacher?" Yes. She said, "It's
the teacher?" Yes. She said, "It's
the teacher?" Yes. She said, "It's helotropism." Oh. Mother says,
"Either one of them still know why the
"Either one of them still know why the sunflower follows the sun, do they?"
So to catch to be to people here are
So to catch to be to people here are reaching for enlightenment advanced
reaching for enlightenment advanced
reaching for enlightenment advanced states of consciousness
states of consciousness
states of consciousness you must get beyond the confusion of
you must get beyond the confusion of
you must get beyond the confusion of rest internal with rest externa.
rest internal with rest externa.
rest internal with rest externa. You must jump that Newtonian paradigm of
You must jump that Newtonian paradigm of
You must jump that Newtonian paradigm of duality
duality
duality and see clearly that thinkingness is
and see clearly that thinkingness is
and see clearly that thinkingness is internally consistent.
internally consistent.
internally consistent. It uses stuff from out there to feed
It uses stuff from out there to feed
It uses stuff from out there to feed itself.
itself.
itself. And that which is exists independently
And that which is exists independently
And that which is exists independently of any thoughts you have about it
of any thoughts you have about it
of any thoughts you have about it because the mind says it's true has no
because the mind says it's true has no
because the mind says it's true has no bearing on reality whatsoever. Yeah.
bearing on reality whatsoever. Yeah.
bearing on reality whatsoever. Yeah. To confuse rest internal with rest
To confuse rest internal with rest
To confuse rest internal with rest external. Rest kajans
external. Rest kajans
external. Rest kajans with rest extensza.
with rest extensza.
with rest extensza. It can be kajatans or kajetans.
It can be kajatans or kajetans.
It can be kajatans or kajetans. Can be rest externa.
Can be rest externa.
Can be rest externa. I looked it up in a Latin dictionary
I looked it up in a Latin dictionary
I looked it up in a Latin dictionary just to make sure I was right. Should it
just to make sure I was right. Should it
just to make sure I was right. Should it be coatans or cognitans?
be coatans or cognitans?
be coatans or cognitans? Said either way. That didn't help at
Said either way. That didn't help at
Said either way. That didn't help at all.
Ordinary consciousness then
Ordinary consciousness then the number of people
the number of people
the number of people uh
uh
uh reaching it highest high states is very
reaching it highest high states is very
reaching it highest high states is very limited. So the scale of consciousness
limited. So the scale of consciousness
limited. So the scale of consciousness goes up to 600 and then at 600 there's
goes up to 600 and then at 600 there's
goes up to 600 and then at 600 there's only a few individuals but for spiritual
only a few individuals but for spiritual
only a few individuals but for spiritual research we put it there. Enlightenment
research we put it there. Enlightenment
research we put it there. Enlightenment occurs at level 600.
occurs at level 600.
occurs at level 600. uh
uh
uh the great sages uh Ramana Maharshi,
the great sages uh Ramana Maharshi,
the great sages uh Ramana Maharshi, Nisar Gadana Maharaj, Meister Eckhert
Nisar Gadana Maharaj, Meister Eckhert
Nisar Gadana Maharaj, Meister Eckhert uh 700 the great Christian saints uh
uh 700 the great Christian saints uh
uh 700 the great Christian saints uh fable Christian saints back at 700 and
fable Christian saints back at 700 and
fable Christian saints back at 700 and then rarely does life rarely does it
then rarely does life rarely does it
then rarely does life rarely does it ever go beyond that hardly ever on the
ever go beyond that hardly ever on the
ever go beyond that hardly ever on the planet now there's maybe six people 600
planet now there's maybe six people 600
planet now there's maybe six people 600 and up extremely rare and then at the
and up extremely rare and then at the
and up extremely rare and then at the very top is 1,00 000
very top is 1,00 000
very top is 1,00 000 and at 1,00 you've hit the limitation of
and at 1,00 you've hit the limitation of
and at 1,00 you've hit the limitation of the human nervous system.
the human nervous system.
the human nervous system. Doesn't mean that there are no realities
Doesn't mean that there are no realities
Doesn't mean that there are no realities that calibrate beyond 1,00. It's just
that calibrate beyond 1,00. It's just
that calibrate beyond 1,00. It's just that it's not possible to exist in human
that it's not possible to exist in human
that it's not possible to exist in human form. In fact, from 750 on up, it is
form. In fact, from 750 on up, it is
form. In fact, from 750 on up, it is extremely painful to the nervous system.
extremely painful to the nervous system.
extremely painful to the nervous system. The frequency and the intensity, the
The frequency and the intensity, the
The frequency and the intensity, the frequencies of energies that high are
frequencies of energies that high are
frequencies of energies that high are very taxing. And so the Buddha felt like
very taxing. And so the Buddha felt like
very taxing. And so the Buddha felt like his bones were cracked, Jesus Christ
his bones were cracked, Jesus Christ
his bones were cracked, Jesus Christ sweat blood, etc. So it's advisable to
sweat blood, etc. So it's advisable to
sweat blood, etc. So it's advisable to go to higher realms if you're going to
go to higher realms if you're going to
go to higher realms if you're going to keep on advancing in consciousness. And
keep on advancing in consciousness. And
keep on advancing in consciousness. And I advise people to do that. When you get
I advise people to do that. When you get
I advise people to do that. When you get 750 or 800, leave
750 or 800, leave
750 or 800, leave other realms where you're not stuck with
other realms where you're not stuck with
other realms where you're not stuck with protoplasm because protoplasm doesn't
protoplasm because protoplasm doesn't
protoplasm because protoplasm doesn't handle those energies too well. Uh
handle those energies too well. Uh
handle those energies too well. Uh so let's go on to the next slide. So
so let's go on to the next slide. So
so let's go on to the next slide. So those are the higher levels. Uh if we
those are the higher levels. Uh if we
those are the higher levels. Uh if we calibrate the field of consciousness,
calibrate the field of consciousness,
calibrate the field of consciousness, you see it's logarithmic.
you see it's logarithmic.
you see it's logarithmic. In power versus force, we estimated it
In power versus force, we estimated it
In power versus force, we estimated it using kinesiology
using kinesiology
using kinesiology in microwatts. Microwatts. And as
in microwatts. Microwatts. And as
in microwatts. Microwatts. And as consciousness goes up, you see a frec
consciousness goes up, you see a frec
consciousness goes up, you see a frec increase in frequency.
increase in frequency.
increase in frequency. the this frequency is
the this frequency is
the this frequency is uh as you get to the higher levels uh
uh as you get to the higher levels uh
uh as you get to the higher levels uh handled really through the atheric brain
handled really through the atheric brain
handled really through the atheric brain not through the protoplasmic physical
not through the protoplasmic physical
not through the protoplasmic physical brain. Anyway, this was done by u
brain. Anyway, this was done by u
brain. Anyway, this was done by u an engineer mathematician calibrated in
an engineer mathematician calibrated in
an engineer mathematician calibrated in microwatts. So this is the relative
microwatts. So this is the relative
microwatts. So this is the relative increase in strength in microwatts in
increase in strength in microwatts in
increase in strength in microwatts in power and microwatts as consciousness
power and microwatts as consciousness
power and microwatts as consciousness advances. Okay, move on.
advances. Okay, move on.
advances. Okay, move on. just the people on the planet. This is
just the people on the planet. This is
just the people on the planet. This is not correct. I don't know. We didn't
not correct. I don't know. We didn't
not correct. I don't know. We didn't correct that yet. That's 78 supposed to
correct that yet. That's 78 supposed to
correct that yet. That's 78 supposed to be 85. I think
be 85. I think
be 85. I think uh 85% of the world calibrates below
uh 85% of the world calibrates below
uh 85% of the world calibrates below 200.
200.
200. 85%. So because of evolution then only
85%. So because of evolution then only
85%. So because of evolution then only 15% of the people on the planet
15% of the people on the planet
15% of the people on the planet calibrate over level 200 over the level
calibrate over level 200 over the level
calibrate over level 200 over the level of integrity and truth. 85% live below
of integrity and truth. 85% live below
of integrity and truth. 85% live below 200.
200.
200. So you see in the 200s then from 200 up
So you see in the 200s then from 200 up
So you see in the 200s then from 200 up where's 200
there we are. So the great mass of
there we are. So the great mass of mankind then fills this is the huge mass
mankind then fills this is the huge mass
mankind then fills this is the huge mass of mankind and a small number even get
of mankind and a small number even get
of mankind and a small number even get to the 400s you see a a group like this
to the 400s you see a a group like this
to the 400s you see a a group like this here today is around in here. You see
here today is around in here. You see
here today is around in here. You see how few of you there are. There's hardly
how few of you there are. There's hardly
how few of you there are. There's hardly any of you out there.
However, enough to support spiritual
However, enough to support spiritual bookstores and all.
We'll move on to the next. Yeah. Move on
We'll move on to the next. Yeah. Move on to the next slide. Who's doing the
to the next slide. Who's doing the
to the next slide. Who's doing the slides? Who's running the slides? Oh,
slides? Who's running the slides? Oh,
slides? Who's running the slides? Oh, okay. There's the mastermind. So, you
okay. There's the mastermind. So, you
okay. There's the mastermind. So, you see 15 these are relative power. the 15%
see 15 these are relative power. the 15%
see 15 these are relative power. the 15% why don't why don't the 85% then destroy
why don't why don't the 85% then destroy
why don't why don't the 85% then destroy life it's because the 15% have so much
life it's because the 15% have so much
life it's because the 15% have so much power you saw from that graph power goes
power you saw from that graph power goes
power you saw from that graph power goes up 15% of the people calibrate over 200
up 15% of the people calibrate over 200
up 15% of the people calibrate over 200 on this planet of the total worldwide
on this planet of the total worldwide
on this planet of the total worldwide population that 15% has so much power
population that 15% has so much power
population that 15% has so much power that they calibrate they counterbalance
that they calibrate they counterbalance
that they calibrate they counterbalance the destructiveness of the other 85%
the destructiveness of the other 85%
the destructiveness of the other 85% without that 15%
without that 15%
without that 15% mankind kind would have self-destructed
mankind kind would have self-destructed
mankind kind would have self-destructed exterminated itself long ago.
exterminated itself long ago.
exterminated itself long ago. It would have exterminated itself.
The Russians, in fact, remember the end
The Russians, in fact, remember the end of during the Cold War, if they lost the
of during the Cold War, if they lost the
of during the Cold War, if they lost the war, they had the the infinite bomb and
war, they had the the infinite bomb and
war, they had the the infinite bomb and they would destroy all of life forever
they would destroy all of life forever
they would destroy all of life forever on this planet. Swell people.
Nice thought, eh? Right. Well, how come
Nice thought, eh? Right. Well, how come it didn't come to pass? If you look
it didn't come to pass? If you look
it didn't come to pass? If you look within the Newtonian paradigm, you can
within the Newtonian paradigm, you can
within the Newtonian paradigm, you can come up with an explanation. Actually,
come up with an explanation. Actually,
come up with an explanation. Actually, it's because of this the sheer weight of
it's because of this the sheer weight of
it's because of this the sheer weight of the 15%. Uh, it never came to pass.
the 15%. Uh, it never came to pass.
the 15%. Uh, it never came to pass. Okay, so this 15% then counterbalances
Okay, so this 15% then counterbalances
Okay, so this 15% then counterbalances the negativity of the rest of mankind.
the negativity of the rest of mankind.
the negativity of the rest of mankind. Okay, let's move on.
They didn't tell me it was going to be
They didn't tell me it was going to be way back there. It was supposed to be
way back there. It was supposed to be
way back there. It was supposed to be right here. They put it where I can't
right here. They put it where I can't
right here. They put it where I can't reach it.
Oh. This is the evolution of life on the
Oh. This is the evolution of life on the planet.
planet.
planet. In order to transcend the ego, it's best
In order to transcend the ego, it's best
In order to transcend the ego, it's best to understand what the ego is, how it
to understand what the ego is, how it
to understand what the ego is, how it arose, and then having recontextualized
arose, and then having recontextualized
arose, and then having recontextualized it, uh you'll see that it's easy to
it, uh you'll see that it's easy to
it, uh you'll see that it's easy to dissolve it. Whereas it's formidable to
dissolve it. Whereas it's formidable to
dissolve it. Whereas it's formidable to set it up as an enemy, become
set it up as an enemy, become
set it up as an enemy, become dualistically opposed to it and try to
dualistically opposed to it and try to
dualistically opposed to it and try to conquer the ego. The more you try to
conquer the ego. The more you try to
conquer the ego. The more you try to conquer or destroy the ego, oh, the
conquer or destroy the ego, oh, the
conquer or destroy the ego, oh, the greater the power you give it. So, let's
greater the power you give it. So, let's
greater the power you give it. So, let's see how life evolved. life evolved.
see how life evolved. life evolved.
see how life evolved. life evolved. There's this
There's this
There's this galactic explosion supposedly.
galactic explosion supposedly.
galactic explosion supposedly. All this energy is whirling around in
All this energy is whirling around in
All this energy is whirling around in the infinite universe. It finally
the infinite universe. It finally
the infinite universe. It finally coaleses into
coaleses into
coaleses into a lavaike hot stuff flying around there.
a lavaike hot stuff flying around there.
a lavaike hot stuff flying around there. And this hot mass coaleses.
And this hot mass coaleses.
And this hot mass coaleses. It spins around for some more billions
It spins around for some more billions
It spins around for some more billions and trillions of years. It gradually
and trillions of years. It gradually
and trillions of years. It gradually cools down. eventually gets a crust on
cools down. eventually gets a crust on
cools down. eventually gets a crust on the surface. A crust on the surface. The
the surface. A crust on the surface. The
the surface. A crust on the surface. The center of the Earth is still molten. Go
center of the Earth is still molten. Go
center of the Earth is still molten. Go down that way. It's thousands of degrees
down that way. It's thousands of degrees
down that way. It's thousands of degrees inside there. Do you know that you're
inside there. Do you know that you're
inside there. Do you know that you're sitting over 10,000 degrees of molten
sitting over 10,000 degrees of molten
sitting over 10,000 degrees of molten lava?
lava?
lava? And you realize that
And you realize that
And you realize that you realize that
that's the past has not disappeared.
that's the past has not disappeared. It's still very active waiting for you
It's still very active waiting for you
It's still very active waiting for you down there, folks. Occasionally, it
down there, folks. Occasionally, it
down there, folks. Occasionally, it comes up
comes up
comes up and destroys whole colonies of people.
and destroys whole colonies of people.
and destroys whole colonies of people. Anyway, this molten on the surface cools
Anyway, this molten on the surface cools
Anyway, this molten on the surface cools down enough you can get a crust and the
down enough you can get a crust and the
down enough you can get a crust and the material of life then chemically
material of life then chemically
material of life then chemically reaches a certain stage.
reaches a certain stage.
reaches a certain stage. Local conditions become favorable.
Local conditions become favorable.
Local conditions become favorable. The energy field of consciousness
The energy field of consciousness
The energy field of consciousness in its interaction with matter
in its interaction with matter
in its interaction with matter is the potential for life. The
is the potential for life. The
is the potential for life. The unmanifest becomes manifest.
unmanifest becomes manifest.
unmanifest becomes manifest. Out of the light of God arose creation.
Out of the light of God arose creation.
Out of the light of God arose creation. The light of God then is consciousness
The light of God then is consciousness
The light of God then is consciousness is the light of God.
is the light of God.
is the light of God. Its power is so infinite that the
Its power is so infinite that the
Its power is so infinite that the interaction of consciousness and matter
interaction of consciousness and matter
interaction of consciousness and matter spawns life.
spawns life.
spawns life. Life then arises out of life. A life
Life then arises out of life. A life
Life then arises out of life. A life cannot arise out of non-life.
cannot arise out of non-life.
cannot arise out of non-life. That is so obvious and clear. You see
That is so obvious and clear. You see
That is so obvious and clear. You see how you jump categories. If you say that
how you jump categories. If you say that
how you jump categories. If you say that life arose mechanically as a chemical
life arose mechanically as a chemical
life arose mechanically as a chemical accident out of non-life, you've just
accident out of non-life, you've just
accident out of non-life, you've just violated
violated
violated All the laws of logic, you've jumped
All the laws of logic, you've jumped
All the laws of logic, you've jumped from one level of abstraction to
from one level of abstraction to
from one level of abstraction to another. This level of abstraction does
another. This level of abstraction does
another. This level of abstraction does not apply to this level abstraction. The
not apply to this level abstraction. The
not apply to this level abstraction. The laws of life.
Life cannot arise out of non-life. Life
Life cannot arise out of non-life. Life can only arise out of life.
can only arise out of life.
can only arise out of life. That's clear once I tell it to you. You
That's clear once I tell it to you. You
That's clear once I tell it to you. You see, it's not possible for life to arise
see, it's not possible for life to arise
see, it's not possible for life to arise out of non-life.
out of non-life.
out of non-life. It even violates
It even violates
It even violates categories of abstraction.
categories of abstraction.
categories of abstraction. No, life can only arise out of life.
No, life can only arise out of life.
No, life can only arise out of life. Also, because of the quality and the
Also, because of the quality and the
Also, because of the quality and the nature of life, the essence of life,
nature of life, the essence of life,
nature of life, the essence of life, life cannot be destroyed.
life cannot be destroyed.
life cannot be destroyed. It is impossible to destroy life.
It is impossible to destroy life.
It is impossible to destroy life. When you think you've killed something,
When you think you've killed something,
When you think you've killed something, you've just gone into a delusion.
you've just gone into a delusion.
you've just gone into a delusion. You cannot kill anything.
Life is infinite and indestructible.
Life is infinite and indestructible. Resist. The law. The conservation of
Resist. The law. The conservation of
Resist. The law. The conservation of life is absolute. Resist.
life is absolute. Resist.
life is absolute. Resist. It's impossible. How could mankind have
It's impossible. How could mankind have
It's impossible. How could mankind have existed this long? They know about the
existed this long? They know about the
existed this long? They know about the law of matter,
law of matter,
law of matter, energy, light, matter, and energy cannot
energy, light, matter, and energy cannot
energy, light, matter, and energy cannot be destroyed. Equ= MC².
be destroyed. Equ= MC².
be destroyed. Equ= MC². Man has yet to discover that the law of
Man has yet to discover that the law of
Man has yet to discover that the law of the invincibility of life.
the invincibility of life.
the invincibility of life. You cannot destroy life. Not possible.
You cannot destroy life. Not possible.
You cannot destroy life. Not possible. You swat the fly. Isn't he goes off in
You swat the fly. Isn't he goes off in
You swat the fly. Isn't he goes off in his atheric body? Do you know the fly
his atheric body? Do you know the fly
his atheric body? Do you know the fly doesn't even notice it?
doesn't even notice it?
doesn't even notice it? You're weeping. Oh god, I've killed
You're weeping. Oh god, I've killed
You're weeping. Oh god, I've killed another being.
The fly goes on flying in his atheric
The fly goes on flying in his atheric body and doesn't even notice it. Resist.
body and doesn't even notice it. Resist.
body and doesn't even notice it. Resist. doesn't even notice it. Folks, you're
doesn't even notice it. Folks, you're
doesn't even notice it. Folks, you're wailing with guilt. Oh, I've killed the
wailing with guilt. Oh, I've killed the
wailing with guilt. Oh, I've killed the living thing.
living thing.
living thing. The fly doesn't even notice it. Foams
The fly doesn't even notice it. Foams
The fly doesn't even notice it. Foams along his little energy comes back
along his little energy comes back
along his little energy comes back karmmically. Another egg and goes on
karmmically. Another egg and goes on
karmmically. Another egg and goes on flying.
You know, an animal doesn't
You know, an animal doesn't to an animal, the dream world has the
to an animal, the dream world has the
to an animal, the dream world has the same reality as this world.
same reality as this world.
same reality as this world. That's why you wake your cat up, you go
That's why you wake your cat up, you go
That's why you wake your cat up, you go over to pet her and she's annoyed. Why?
over to pet her and she's annoyed. Why?
over to pet her and she's annoyed. Why? Because she's having a ball and you just
see if that's so
see if that's so the animal the dream life has the same
the animal the dream life has the same
the animal the dream life has the same reality as physical life. Resist same
reality as physical life. Resist same
reality as physical life. Resist same life.
life.
life. Ah why why is that so? Because the
Ah why why is that so? Because the
Ah why why is that so? Because the experience of life is 100% subjective.
experience of life is 100% subjective.
experience of life is 100% subjective. All experience is subjective.
All experience is subjective.
All experience is subjective. The core of the infinite eye is
The core of the infinite eye is
The core of the infinite eye is subjectivity. Reality is radical
subjectivity. Reality is radical
subjectivity. Reality is radical subjectivity. Enlightenment is nothing
subjectivity. Enlightenment is nothing
subjectivity. Enlightenment is nothing but radical subjectivity. There is
but radical subjectivity. There is
but radical subjectivity. There is nothing else.
Without the subjective,
Without the subjective, you could not say that only the
you could not say that only the
you could not say that only the objective is real.
Radical
Radical reductionism,
reductionism,
reductionism, mechanistic reductionism.
mechanistic reductionism.
mechanistic reductionism. Nothing is real unless you can measure
Nothing is real unless you can measure
Nothing is real unless you can measure it and weigh it, locate it in time and
it and weigh it, locate it in time and
it and weigh it, locate it in time and place.
place.
place. Yeah,
Yeah,
Yeah, that is a radically subjective
that is a radically subjective
that is a radically subjective statement.
statement.
statement. Subjectively, it seems that that is
Subjectively, it seems that that is
Subjectively, it seems that that is truth.
It's meaningless,
It's meaningless, meaningless verbiage unless subjectively
meaningless verbiage unless subjectively
meaningless verbiage unless subjectively you conclude that's truth. Now, the fact
you conclude that's truth. Now, the fact
you conclude that's truth. Now, the fact that you conclude it is truth doesn't
that you conclude it is truth doesn't
that you conclude it is truth doesn't make it truth. It just means that to you
make it truth. It just means that to you
make it truth. It just means that to you it's truth.
it's truth.
it's truth. Mechanistic reductionism then relies
Mechanistic reductionism then relies
Mechanistic reductionism then relies completely on subjectivity for its
completely on subjectivity for its
completely on subjectivity for its reality and it thereby negates its
reality and it thereby negates its
reality and it thereby negates its premise.
premise.
premise. If the only thing that's real is what is
If the only thing that's real is what is
If the only thing that's real is what is measurable in time and space, there
measurable in time and space, there
measurable in time and space, there would be no way of knowing that. You
would be no way of knowing that. You
would be no way of knowing that. You wouldn't know it except for
wouldn't know it except for
wouldn't know it except for subjectivity. Okay.
subjectivity. Okay.
subjectivity. Okay. Well, the protozoa doesn't worry about
Well, the protozoa doesn't worry about
Well, the protozoa doesn't worry about such things.
The first life is lychans. And I've
The first life is lychans. And I've always wondered, I've never heard
always wondered, I've never heard
always wondered, I've never heard anybody speak the word l i c hen. Is
anybody speak the word l i c hen. Is
anybody speak the word l i c hen. Is that lichens or lychans?
that lichens or lychans?
that lichens or lychans? Hey,
Hey,
Hey, >> lychans.
>> Well,
>> Well, I've always called them lichen liychans.
I've always called them lichen liychans.
I've always called them lichen liychans. That way I'm correct one way or the
That way I'm correct one way or the
That way I'm correct one way or the other.
other.
other. Those are the first things. You see,
Those are the first things. You see,
Those are the first things. You see, chlorophyll appears as a source of
chlorophyll appears as a source of
chlorophyll appears as a source of energy.
energy.
energy. And that the misfortune of humans is
And that the misfortune of humans is
And that the misfortune of humans is that we're not green.
that we're not green.
that we're not green. If we were green, we just walk around
If we were green, we just walk around
If we were green, we just walk around and automatically recharge our energy
and automatically recharge our energy
and automatically recharge our energy source.
source.
source. And life appeared then in animal form,
And life appeared then in animal form,
And life appeared then in animal form, the prozzoa.
the prozzoa.
the prozzoa. And this is the crucial point.
And this is the crucial point.
And this is the crucial point. It doesn't have within itself the source
It doesn't have within itself the source
It doesn't have within itself the source of energy and therefore it has not
of energy and therefore it has not
of energy and therefore it has not within itself the source of survival. It
within itself the source of survival. It
within itself the source of survival. It must get
must get
must get got to get
got to get
got to get To survive the animals got to get right
To survive the animals got to get right
To survive the animals got to get right from the proozoa the amoeba the amieba
from the proozoa the amoeba the amieba
from the proozoa the amoeba the amieba has to get.
has to get.
has to get. The basic law of the ego is get. Get. It
The basic law of the ego is get. Get. It
The basic law of the ego is get. Get. It becomes more and more clever how to get
becomes more and more clever how to get
becomes more and more clever how to get in order to survive. It joins with other
in order to survive. It joins with other
in order to survive. It joins with other getters, forms tribes, clubs,
getters, forms tribes, clubs,
getters, forms tribes, clubs, organizations, armies. Hm. Anyway, it
organizations, armies. Hm. Anyway, it
organizations, armies. Hm. Anyway, it starts out the bacteria at calibrated
starts out the bacteria at calibrated
starts out the bacteria at calibrated level one.
Viruses do are not conscious. Viruses
Viruses do are not conscious. Viruses only reduplicate their own DNA, but they
only reduplicate their own DNA, but they
only reduplicate their own DNA, but they are not conscious. They're not aware
are not conscious. They're not aware
are not conscious. They're not aware that they exist. They don't experience
that they exist. They don't experience
that they exist. They don't experience that they exist.
that they exist.
that they exist. All right. The first conscious organism
All right. The first conscious organism
All right. The first conscious organism is bacteria at one.
is bacteria at one.
is bacteria at one. Then life evolves. This is so far back
Then life evolves. This is so far back
Then life evolves. This is so far back in time in archaeologic time that I
in time in archaeologic time that I
in time in archaeologic time that I can't pronounce the words.
can't pronounce the words.
can't pronounce the words. Precolia
was killing trillions of years ago. By
was killing trillions of years ago. By the time bacteria which only calibrated
the time bacteria which only calibrated
the time bacteria which only calibrated one appeared,
one appeared,
one appeared, 70% of Earth time had already evolved.
70% of Earth time had already evolved.
70% of Earth time had already evolved. 70% of rock archaeologic time had
70% of rock archaeologic time had
70% of rock archaeologic time had already evolved. After 70% of time of
already evolved. After 70% of time of
already evolved. After 70% of time of our universe had evolved, only then did
our universe had evolved, only then did
our universe had evolved, only then did appear consciousness level one
appear consciousness level one
appear consciousness level one in the form of bacteria.
Then the first marine invertebrates
Then the first marine invertebrates at consciousness level three. The first
at consciousness level three. The first
at consciousness level three. The first fish.
fish.
fish. Then
Then
Then land life. Then scorpions. Sc scor
land life. Then scorpions. Sc scor
land life. Then scorpions. Sc scor scorpions crawled out of the sea 400
scorpions crawled out of the sea 400
scorpions crawled out of the sea 400 million years ago.
million years ago.
million years ago. Then primitive brachopods. Shellcrushing
Then primitive brachopods. Shellcrushing
Then primitive brachopods. Shellcrushing sharks, reptiles,
sharks, reptiles,
sharks, reptiles, dinosaurs.
dinosaurs.
dinosaurs. You see in only in the last and you see
You see in only in the last and you see
You see in only in the last and you see consciousness level slowly evolving here
consciousness level slowly evolving here
consciousness level slowly evolving here and only in the last 2% of time would be
and only in the last 2% of time would be
and only in the last 2% of time would be anything really meaningful to modern
anything really meaningful to modern
anything really meaningful to modern man.
man.
man. So move on to the next one. You see
So move on to the next one. You see
So move on to the next one. You see the interesting thing is is that the
the interesting thing is is that the
the interesting thing is is that the core then of survival which is the ego.
core then of survival which is the ego.
core then of survival which is the ego. The ego is your human brain is your
The ego is your human brain is your
The ego is your human brain is your brain
brain
brain over the evolution of time. Then you see
over the evolution of time. Then you see
over the evolution of time. Then you see how consciousness evolved from a
how consciousness evolved from a
how consciousness evolved from a bacteria at one. But you see the law of
bacteria at one. But you see the law of
bacteria at one. But you see the law of life here up to consciousness level 200
life here up to consciousness level 200
life here up to consciousness level 200 is to get.
is to get.
is to get. Now it doesn't kill anything.
When a lion eats a rabbit, it does not
When a lion eats a rabbit, it does not kill the rabbit. Killing is in your
kill the rabbit. Killing is in your
kill the rabbit. Killing is in your mind.
mind.
mind. rest intern.
Rabbitness
Rabbitness goes back into its etheric
goes back into its etheric
goes back into its etheric representation in a collective attractor
representation in a collective attractor
representation in a collective attractor field and remmanifests as rabbitness.
field and remmanifests as rabbitness.
field and remmanifests as rabbitness. But rabbit consciousness is not
But rabbit consciousness is not
But rabbit consciousness is not destroyed
destroyed
destroyed up to level 200. Then you see the main
up to level 200. Then you see the main
up to level 200. Then you see the main characteristic from human viewpoint
characteristic from human viewpoint
characteristic from human viewpoint is that it looks it looks cruel and
is that it looks it looks cruel and
is that it looks it looks cruel and horrible. It always has to get
horrible. It always has to get
horrible. It always has to get something. So here you have uh
something. So here you have uh
something. So here you have uh crustaceians,
crustaceians,
crustaceians, insects, arachnids at seven, fish at 20.
insects, arachnids at seven, fish at 20.
insects, arachnids at seven, fish at 20. Where's the octopus? Octopus is at 20.
Where's the octopus? Octopus is at 20.
Where's the octopus? Octopus is at 20. Sharks at 24.
Sharks at 24.
Sharks at 24. Komodo dragon at 40. Reptiles, snakes,
Komodo dragon at 40. Reptiles, snakes,
Komodo dragon at 40. Reptiles, snakes, dinosaurs, oils, dolphins, birds of
dinosaurs, oils, dolphins, birds of
dinosaurs, oils, dolphins, birds of prey, rhinoceros,
prey, rhinoceros,
prey, rhinoceros, polar bears, grizzly bears, jackals and
polar bears, grizzly bears, jackals and
polar bears, grizzly bears, jackals and foxes,
foxes,
foxes, wolves,
wolves,
wolves, havalina, hippopotamus.
havalina, hippopotamus.
havalina, hippopotamus. And then suddenly at 200 you see a
And then suddenly at 200 you see a
And then suddenly at 200 you see a shift. At 200 you suddenly see the
shift. At 200 you suddenly see the
shift. At 200 you suddenly see the emergence of the herbivores.
emergence of the herbivores.
emergence of the herbivores. On the human levels of consciousness 200
On the human levels of consciousness 200
On the human levels of consciousness 200 was a critical level between truth and
was a critical level between truth and
was a critical level between truth and falsehood between that which is
falsehood between that which is
falsehood between that which is supportive of life etc. And in the
supportive of life etc. And in the
supportive of life etc. And in the animal world you see exactly the same
animal world you see exactly the same
animal world you see exactly the same thing. At level 200 suddenly
thing. At level 200 suddenly
thing. At level 200 suddenly instead of killing others you become a
instead of killing others you become a
instead of killing others you become a herbivore peacefully munching the grass.
herbivore peacefully munching the grass.
herbivore peacefully munching the grass. And so you see the elk at 210, sheep,
And so you see the elk at 210, sheep,
And so you see the elk at 210, sheep, elephants,
elephants,
elephants, farm horses, cats, raceh horses, family
farm horses, cats, raceh horses, family
farm horses, cats, raceh horses, family dog, gorilla, monkeys.
dog, gorilla, monkeys.
dog, gorilla, monkeys. Ah, so the evolution of consciousness
Ah, so the evolution of consciousness
Ah, so the evolution of consciousness then is not just a human affair. It's an
then is not just a human affair. It's an
then is not just a human affair. It's an it's an the evolution of life. Life
it's an the evolution of life. Life
it's an the evolution of life. Life itself. Life itself
itself. Life itself
itself. Life itself up to 200. It is only interested in me.
up to 200. It is only interested in me.
up to 200. It is only interested in me. From 200 on now, it becomes less and
From 200 on now, it becomes less and
From 200 on now, it becomes less and less destructive to others. The
less destructive to others. The
less destructive to others. The herbivore eats the grass, fertilizes the
herbivore eats the grass, fertilizes the
herbivore eats the grass, fertilizes the grass, and doesn't kill anything or
grass, and doesn't kill anything or
grass, and doesn't kill anything or anybody.
anybody.
anybody. Now, you get up to some interesting
Now, you get up to some interesting
Now, you get up to some interesting things here. You see cats and dogs. Cats
things here. You see cats and dogs. Cats
things here. You see cats and dogs. Cats and dogs at 240.
You remember the scale of of
You remember the scale of of consciousness? You realize that cats and
consciousness? You realize that cats and
consciousness? You realize that cats and dogs calibrate higher than but large
dogs calibrate higher than but large
dogs calibrate higher than but large percentage of the population of the
percentage of the population of the
percentage of the population of the people on the planet
when we were in Toronto. You know, we
when we were in Toronto. You know, we were talking about dogs. See, a dog and
were talking about dogs. See, a dog and
were talking about dogs. See, a dog and a dog's wagging tail calibrates at 500.
a dog's wagging tail calibrates at 500.
a dog's wagging tail calibrates at 500. The cat's purr calibrates at 500. That's
The cat's purr calibrates at 500. That's
The cat's purr calibrates at 500. That's why we love them so much. People worship
why we love them so much. People worship
why we love them so much. People worship their cats and their dogs and don't like
their cats and their dogs and don't like
their cats and their dogs and don't like people. I used to think they were weird.
people. I used to think they were weird.
people. I used to think they were weird. No, they make sense.
If you came from her family, you you'd
If you came from her family, you you'd rather be with a dog or a cat, too. You
rather be with a dog or a cat, too. You
rather be with a dog or a cat, too. You know, you're all backbiting, vicious,
know, you're all backbiting, vicious,
know, you're all backbiting, vicious, and uh really
and uh really
and uh really once you adopt an animal, the
once you adopt an animal, the
once you adopt an animal, the consciousness animal of the animal jumps
consciousness animal of the animal jumps
consciousness animal of the animal jumps five or 10 points.
Strangely enough, the dog's wagging tail
Strangely enough, the dog's wagging tail is 500 and the cat's purr is 500. And
is 500 and the cat's purr is 500. And
is 500 and the cat's purr is 500. And when we were in Toronto, the front page
when we were in Toronto, the front page
when we were in Toronto, the front page of the paper, we were up there to give a
of the paper, we were up there to give a
of the paper, we were up there to give a lecture, there was a dog named uh Elvis.
lecture, there was a dog named uh Elvis.
lecture, there was a dog named uh Elvis. And out in a park, out in a park, there
And out in a park, out in a park, there
And out in a park, out in a park, there was a a a slightly um mentally
was a a a slightly um mentally
was a a a slightly um mentally imbalanced uh man. He had a whole bunch
imbalanced uh man. He had a whole bunch
imbalanced uh man. He had a whole bunch of u high-powered uh rifles, 6,000
of u high-powered uh rifles, 6,000
of u high-powered uh rifles, 6,000 rounds of ammunition.
rounds of ammunition.
rounds of ammunition. He was a mass killer, and he was just
He was a mass killer, and he was just
He was a mass killer, and he was just going to mow down people and then commit
going to mow down people and then commit
going to mow down people and then commit suicide.
suicide.
suicide. Nobody could deter him, and he, you
Nobody could deter him, and he, you
Nobody could deter him, and he, you know, he's fully armed. He's got all
know, he's fully armed. He's got all
know, he's fully armed. He's got all kinds of weapons. He's a walking walking
kinds of weapons. He's a walking walking
kinds of weapons. He's a walking walking army all by himself. Nobody could talk
army all by himself. Nobody could talk
army all by himself. Nobody could talk to him or get near him. And all of a
to him or get near him. And all of a
to him or get near him. And all of a sudden, this dog with a Frisbee in his
sudden, this dog with a Frisbee in his
sudden, this dog with a Frisbee in his mouth runs over to this guy and wants to
mouth runs over to this guy and wants to
mouth runs over to this guy and wants to play with him. Jumps up with his
play with him. Jumps up with his
play with him. Jumps up with his Frisbee. And this dog's name is Elvis.
Frisbee. And this dog's name is Elvis.
Frisbee. And this dog's name is Elvis. He's on the front page of the paper. And
He's on the front page of the paper. And
He's on the front page of the paper. And when Elvis approached this mad killer
when Elvis approached this mad killer
when Elvis approached this mad killer who was about to mow everybody down and
who was about to mow everybody down and
who was about to mow everybody down and commit suicide, this guy changed his
commit suicide, this guy changed his
commit suicide, this guy changed his mind. The dogs love at 500, over 500.
mind. The dogs love at 500, over 500.
mind. The dogs love at 500, over 500. Uh, the heart chakra. Then the guy said,
Uh, the heart chakra. Then the guy said,
Uh, the heart chakra. Then the guy said, "What the hell am I doing? It must be
"What the hell am I doing? It must be
"What the hell am I doing? It must be crazy. And he put down his weapons and
crazy. And he put down his weapons and
crazy. And he put down his weapons and went for help. That was on the front
went for help. That was on the front
went for help. That was on the front page of the paper the very day we gave
page of the paper the very day we gave
page of the paper the very day we gave the lecture on it. Very funny. Okay. So,
the lecture on it. Very funny. Okay. So,
the lecture on it. Very funny. Okay. So, the cat's purr, the dog's wagging tail.
the cat's purr, the dog's wagging tail.
the cat's purr, the dog's wagging tail. And uh I'm interested in
And uh I'm interested in
And uh I'm interested in talking parrots. You know, there's a
talking parrots. You know, there's a
talking parrots. You know, there's a famous one, Alex. You've probably seen
famous one, Alex. You've probably seen
famous one, Alex. You've probably seen on the History Channel or Discovery
on the History Channel or Discovery
on the History Channel or Discovery Channel. Alex is a trained uh African
Channel. Alex is a trained uh African
Channel. Alex is a trained uh African gray calibrates at 401. Coco the trained
gray calibrates at 401. Coco the trained
gray calibrates at 401. Coco the trained gorilla calibrates at 405. The question
gorilla calibrates at 405. The question
gorilla calibrates at 405. The question is, can animals think? Well, you watch a
is, can animals think? Well, you watch a
is, can animals think? Well, you watch a crow figure out. You got to pick this
crow figure out. You got to pick this
crow figure out. You got to pick this up, use it as a tool, use it as a lever,
up, use it as a tool, use it as a lever,
up, use it as a tool, use it as a lever, and of course they can think. I mean,
and of course they can think. I mean,
and of course they can think. I mean, what do you think he's doing there? He's
what do you think he's doing there? He's
what do you think he's doing there? He's obviously thinking the obvious. Over
obviously thinking the obvious. Over
obviously thinking the obvious. Over 200, then you're in a different
200, then you're in a different
200, then you're in a different dimension. At 400, you're capable of
dimension. At 400, you're capable of
dimension. At 400, you're capable of thinking. And uh we have the good
thinking. And uh we have the good
thinking. And uh we have the good fortune now. A friend of us, friend of
fortune now. A friend of us, friend of
fortune now. A friend of us, friend of ours gave us an African gray parrot.
ours gave us an African gray parrot.
ours gave us an African gray parrot. And so we're finding out whether this is
And so we're finding out whether this is
And so we're finding out whether this is all true or or not. Let's see where
all true or or not. Let's see where
all true or or not. Let's see where she's at this morning.
she's at this morning.
she's at this morning. Broccoli. Broccoli. When we got her 8
Broccoli. Broccoli. When we got her 8
Broccoli. Broccoli. When we got her 8 weeks ago, calibrated over uh let's see,
weeks ago, calibrated over uh let's see,
weeks ago, calibrated over uh let's see, 325,
325,
325, 340,
340,
340, 335,
335,
335, 340. Broccoli calibrated at 335. Okay,
340. Broccoli calibrated at 335. Okay,
340. Broccoli calibrated at 335. Okay, broccoli now we've had for a couple
broccoli now we've had for a couple
broccoli now we've had for a couple months. Calibrates over at 335, 340,
months. Calibrates over at 335, 340,
months. Calibrates over at 335, 340, 345,
345,
345, 342, 343,
342, 343,
342, 343, 342. All right. So Bradley's
342. All right. So Bradley's
342. All right. So Bradley's consciousness has gone ahead seven
consciousness has gone ahead seven
consciousness has gone ahead seven points just in a couple of months due to
points just in a couple of months due to
points just in a couple of months due to human interaction and love and
human interaction and love and
human interaction and love and caringness. So you see how we affect the
caringness. So you see how we affect the
caringness. So you see how we affect the field, how the field affects others.
field, how the field affects others.
field, how the field affects others. People say, "What can I do to help this
People say, "What can I do to help this
People say, "What can I do to help this planet?"
planet?"
planet?" I tell them, "Keep off the streets.
Approach everything lovingly with
Approach everything lovingly with goodwill.
goodwill.
goodwill. Uh see the sacredness and the beauty of
Uh see the sacredness and the beauty of
Uh see the sacredness and the beauty of all of life. To be kind to all that
all of life. To be kind to all that
all of life. To be kind to all that exists.
exists.
exists. To be loving and kind towards all that
To be loving and kind towards all that
To be loving and kind towards all that exists. See the beauty of all that
exists. See the beauty of all that
exists. See the beauty of all that exists. You're already doing all you can
exists. You're already doing all you can
exists. You're already doing all you can do. You're already raising the level of
do. You're already raising the level of
do. You're already raising the level of consciousness of the world.
consciousness of the world.
consciousness of the world. Because the level of consciousness of
Because the level of consciousness of
Because the level of consciousness of mankind is like the sea. And as we by
mankind is like the sea. And as we by
mankind is like the sea. And as we by combined intention then raise the
combined intention then raise the
combined intention then raise the overall level of consciousness, we lift
overall level of consciousness, we lift
overall level of consciousness, we lift all the ships in the sea. Little
all the ships in the sea. Little
all the ships in the sea. Little organizations that try to lift this ship
organizations that try to lift this ship
organizations that try to lift this ship have quite a job because it slips back
have quite a job because it slips back
have quite a job because it slips back as fast as you can lift it. It's by
as fast as you can lift it. It's by
as fast as you can lift it. It's by lifting the the sea effortlessly,
lifting the the sea effortlessly,
lifting the the sea effortlessly, all that float in the sea are lifted
all that float in the sea are lifted
all that float in the sea are lifted equally. and to which it has no
equally. and to which it has no
equally. and to which it has no resistance. If you use force, they will
resistance. If you use force, they will
resistance. If you use force, they will resist you. But if you lift the sea,
resist you. But if you lift the sea,
resist you. But if you lift the sea, they cannot resist it.
they cannot resist it.
they cannot resist it. And so we'll take a break and we'll see
And so we'll take a break and we'll see
And so we'll take a break and we'll see you right after.
>> Well, I just explained the secret of the
>> Well, I just explained the secret of the universe while you folks were talking.
universe while you folks were talking.
universe while you folks were talking. The dilemma of few of mankind.
The dilemma of few of mankind.
The dilemma of few of mankind. Once you understand the structure of
Once you understand the structure of
Once you understand the structure of mankind, compassion is an automatic
mankind, compassion is an automatic
mankind, compassion is an automatic consequence of the understanding.
consequence of the understanding.
consequence of the understanding. Certain information is in and of itself
Certain information is in and of itself
Certain information is in and of itself transformational.
You see the evolution of consciousness
You see the evolution of consciousness throughout the animal kingdom which is
throughout the animal kingdom which is
throughout the animal kingdom which is represented in the human brain today.
represented in the human brain today.
represented in the human brain today. And then the difficulty was when humans
And then the difficulty was when humans
And then the difficulty was when humans evolved
evolved
evolved the prefrontal cortex was plastered onto
the prefrontal cortex was plastered onto
the prefrontal cortex was plastered onto the old animal brain.
the old animal brain.
the old animal brain. Oh dear.
So the old animal brain wasn't silenced
So the old animal brain wasn't silenced and substituted by an advanced
and substituted by an advanced
and substituted by an advanced consciousness.
consciousness.
consciousness. No, advanced consciousness was now
No, advanced consciousness was now
No, advanced consciousness was now plastered on to the old animal brain.
Here you walk around with a spiritual
Here you walk around with a spiritual conscience and the emotions of an
conscience and the emotions of an
conscience and the emotions of an animal.
If you want to super fix, be a human
If you want to super fix, be a human being.
being.
being. We all get extra credit for having done
We all get extra credit for having done
We all get extra credit for having done it.
If I was St. Peter, I'd say, "Where were
If I was St. Peter, I'd say, "Where were you?" I was on
you?" I was on
you?" I was on planet Earth. Okay. Enter.
That doesn't undo all kinds of karma. I
That doesn't undo all kinds of karma. I don't know what does.
don't know what does.
don't know what does. So now you're
So now you're
So now you're now you're in the squash between animal
now you're in the squash between animal
now you're in the squash between animal drive and intelligence and spiritual
drive and intelligence and spiritual
drive and intelligence and spiritual awareness.
awareness.
awareness. So self-hatred then becomes endemic
So self-hatred then becomes endemic
So self-hatred then becomes endemic because it's intolerable. It now becomes
because it's intolerable. It now becomes
because it's intolerable. It now becomes projected onto the world and hatred then
projected onto the world and hatred then
projected onto the world and hatred then tends to run the social world, political
tends to run the social world, political
tends to run the social world, political world, world of war.
world, world of war.
world, world of war. the projection of that self-hatred.
the projection of that self-hatred.
the projection of that self-hatred. Once you understand that the animal
Once you understand that the animal
Once you understand that the animal animal in you
animal in you
animal in you instead of your enemy should be adopted
instead of your enemy should be adopted
instead of your enemy should be adopted and here's my ego, his name is ego.
So we adopt the pet within us
So we adopt the pet within us and I say,
and I say,
and I say, "We hate people who cut in front of us
"We hate people who cut in front of us
"We hate people who cut in front of us in traffic, don't we, ego?" Yes, we hate
in traffic, don't we, ego?" Yes, we hate
in traffic, don't we, ego?" Yes, we hate them. They should die. They should die.
them. They should die. They should die.
them. They should die. They should die. They deserve death.
They deserve death.
They deserve death. They should be killed, tortured, and
They should be killed, tortured, and
They should be killed, tortured, and blown away. Right.
Good boy.
Good boy. Good boy.
Good boy, ego. So
Good boy, ego. So instead of guilt pen and sackcloth and
instead of guilt pen and sackcloth and
instead of guilt pen and sackcloth and ashes which hasn't really worked
ashes which hasn't really worked
ashes which hasn't really worked as you can tell by today's headlines
compassion for the animal evolution of
compassion for the animal evolution of the ego seeing that the ego's primordial
the ego seeing that the ego's primordial
the ego seeing that the ego's primordial drive is is to continue existence and it
drive is is to continue existence and it
drive is is to continue existence and it thinks it's only the only way it can
thinks it's only the only way it can
thinks it's only the only way it can continue to exist is by getting. So you
continue to exist is by getting. So you
continue to exist is by getting. So you see the human drive to constantly get
see the human drive to constantly get
see the human drive to constantly get more more
more more
more more money, more prestige, more power, more
money, more prestige, more power, more
money, more prestige, more power, more windows in your office, a bigger,
windows in your office, a bigger,
windows in your office, a bigger, longer, better car,
longer, better car,
longer, better car, etc. And therefore, until the late
etc. And therefore, until the late
etc. And therefore, until the late 1980s,
the um paradigm
the um paradigm consciousness of mankind was uh 90 at
consciousness of mankind was uh 90 at
consciousness of mankind was uh 90 at the time of the birth of Buddha.
the time of the birth of Buddha.
the time of the birth of Buddha. At the time of the birth of Jesus
At the time of the birth of Jesus
At the time of the birth of Jesus Christ, the collective consciousness of
Christ, the collective consciousness of
Christ, the collective consciousness of mankind overall was 100.
mankind overall was 100.
mankind overall was 100. Throughout the Middle Ages,
Throughout the Middle Ages,
Throughout the Middle Ages, uh, the Inquisition all all up until
uh, the Inquisition all all up until
uh, the Inquisition all all up until actually the late 1980s,
actually the late 1980s,
actually the late 1980s, the overall level of consciousness of
the overall level of consciousness of
the overall level of consciousness of mankind was 190.
mankind was 190.
mankind was 190. As you see, integrity and truth is at
As you see, integrity and truth is at
As you see, integrity and truth is at 200. when 90 is pride gain.
200. when 90 is pride gain.
200. when 90 is pride gain. Then in the late 1980s at at about the
Then in the late 1980s at at about the
Then in the late 1980s at at about the time of the harmonic concordance the
time of the harmonic concordance the
time of the harmonic concordance the consciousness level of mankind jumped
consciousness level of mankind jumped
consciousness level of mankind jumped from
from
from 190 to 205.
190 to 205.
190 to 205. Many of us remember that people around
Many of us remember that people around
Many of us remember that people around the world prayed at the same time.
the world prayed at the same time.
the world prayed at the same time. Consciousness double jumped to 205.
Consciousness double jumped to 205.
Consciousness double jumped to 205. It stayed at 205 until October of last
It stayed at 205 until October of last
It stayed at 205 until October of last year when it suddenly went from 205 to
year when it suddenly went from 205 to
year when it suddenly went from 205 to 207
207 again at the time of the harmonic
again at the time of the harmonic
again at the time of the harmonic concordance.
Life at 190 is different than life at
Life at 190 is different than life at 205 and certainly different than 207
because you're talking about a
because you're talking about a logarithmic logarithmic scale not math
logarithmic logarithmic scale not math
logarithmic logarithmic scale not math arithmetic.
arithmetic.
arithmetic. 207 is a lot more powerful than 190.
207 is a lot more powerful than 190.
207 is a lot more powerful than 190. It's changed the paradigm. The world in
It's changed the paradigm. The world in
It's changed the paradigm. The world in which I grew up, traditional America. I
which I grew up, traditional America. I
which I grew up, traditional America. I was born right after World War I. went
was born right after World War I. went
was born right after World War I. went through World War II, etc.
through World War II, etc.
through World War II, etc. At 190, success was
At 190, success was
At 190, success was um status, money, house, car, title,
um status, money, house, car, title,
um status, money, house, car, title, position.
position.
position. At 190, then what counts is
success in a worldly term.
success in a worldly term. Therefore, the the ethics of successful
Therefore, the the ethics of successful
Therefore, the the ethics of successful business was oh, a few things could be
business was oh, a few things could be
business was oh, a few things could be swept under the carpet. The old boy
swept under the carpet. The old boy
swept under the carpet. The old boy network worked, you know, 190. Then we
network worked, you know, 190. Then we
network worked, you know, 190. Then we saw the collapse
saw the collapse
saw the collapse of the u Enron and Worldcom and all
of the u Enron and Worldcom and all
of the u Enron and Worldcom and all those things. Why did they collapse? Not
those things. Why did they collapse? Not
those things. Why did they collapse? Not because they were not integrous. Because
because they were not integrous. Because
because they were not integrous. Because the consciousness of mankind had moved
the consciousness of mankind had moved
the consciousness of mankind had moved to 205. At 190, they would still be
to 205. At 190, they would still be
to 205. At 190, they would still be successful corporations.
successful corporations.
successful corporations. You see, but you can get away with at
You see, but you can get away with at
You see, but you can get away with at 190. You can't get away with at 205. So
190. You can't get away with at 205. So
190. You can't get away with at 205. So now the new paradigm of success is
now the new paradigm of success is
now the new paradigm of success is integrity. Integrity. What's Martha
integrity. Integrity. What's Martha
integrity. Integrity. What's Martha Stewart on the carpet for? Not money.
Stewart on the carpet for? Not money.
Stewart on the carpet for? Not money. Integrity.
Integrity.
Integrity. Not for taking a stock tip, but for
Not for taking a stock tip, but for
Not for taking a stock tip, but for lying to the government. She's in jail
lying to the government. She's in jail
lying to the government. She's in jail for lying, not for
for lying, not for
for lying, not for whatever the financial thing was. That
whatever the financial thing was. That
whatever the financial thing was. That was just the incident. Right? Nowadays,
was just the incident. Right? Nowadays,
was just the incident. Right? Nowadays, we're interested in integrity. So, it's
we're interested in integrity. So, it's
we're interested in integrity. So, it's integrity that counts now. And all we
integrity that counts now. And all we
integrity that counts now. And all we look for in others and in employees and
look for in others and in employees and
look for in others and in employees and in companies. If we invest in a stock,
in companies. If we invest in a stock,
in companies. If we invest in a stock, we want to know what is this level of
we want to know what is this level of
we want to know what is this level of integrity? What's the integrity of this
integrity? What's the integrity of this
integrity? What's the integrity of this corporation?
That's the new measure of success is
That's the new measure of success is integrity.
integrity.
integrity. Anybody can make money. It's simple. I
Anybody can make money. It's simple. I
Anybody can make money. It's simple. I can tell anybody how to double your
can tell anybody how to double your
can tell anybody how to double your income in no time.
income in no time.
income in no time. I can double everybody's income in no
I can double everybody's income in no
I can double everybody's income in no time. I did it. I did it.
time. I did it. I did it.
time. I did it. I did it. Instead of working 40 hours of work
Instead of working 40 hours of work
Instead of working 40 hours of work week, you work 80. Simple.
week, you work 80. Simple.
week, you work 80. Simple. As an intern, I worked a 100 hours a
As an intern, I worked a 100 hours a
As an intern, I worked a 100 hours a week. As a resident, I worked 100 hours
week. As a resident, I worked 100 hours
week. As a resident, I worked 100 hours a week. When I started in practice, I
a week. When I started in practice, I
a week. When I started in practice, I worked 100 hours a week. It's simple.
worked 100 hours a week. It's simple.
worked 100 hours a week. It's simple. You double your income, idiot.
You double your income, idiot.
You double your income, idiot. You can't make money sitting home
You can't make money sitting home
You can't make money sitting home watching TV, eating popcorn.
watching TV, eating popcorn.
watching TV, eating popcorn. No, you need a second job. Simple. Okay.
All right. So, the new paradigm now is
All right. So, the new paradigm now is integrity because the consciousness
integrity because the consciousness
integrity because the consciousness level of mankind is 207.
level of mankind is 207.
level of mankind is 207. You see that women executives, the
You see that women executives, the
You see that women executives, the corporations run by women executives,
corporations run by women executives,
corporations run by women executives, according to Fortune magazine, outdid
according to Fortune magazine, outdid
according to Fortune magazine, outdid those run by men executives in 2003.
those run by men executives in 2003.
those run by men executives in 2003. Huh? Why is that? Women executives try
Huh? Why is that? Women executives try
Huh? Why is that? Women executives try harder.
But another thing is they don't belong
But another thing is they don't belong to the old boy network.
to the old boy network.
to the old boy network. In the old boy network, a few little
In the old boy network, a few little
In the old boy network, a few little I'll pay you off for this, you pay me
I'll pay you off for this, you pay me
I'll pay you off for this, you pay me off for that is understood.
off for that is understood.
off for that is understood. What do they call it? Mida, the payoff.
What do they call it? Mida, the payoff.
What do they call it? Mida, the payoff. You know,
the women weren't engaged in that. Women
the women weren't engaged in that. Women are scrupulously honest. It's a pain in
are scrupulously honest. It's a pain in
are scrupulously honest. It's a pain in the neck.
This form is supposed to be filed with
This form is supposed to be filed with this and so you think, "Oh, Jesus, we
this and so you think, "Oh, Jesus, we
this and so you think, "Oh, Jesus, we haven't filed it in 20 years." is what
haven't filed it in 20 years." is what
haven't filed it in 20 years." is what do you mean? Well, it says right here,
do you mean? Well, it says right here,
do you mean? Well, it says right here, this is supposed to be filed by the post
this is supposed to be filed by the post
this is supposed to be filed by the post office. And you'll say, "Oh, God, help
office. And you'll say, "Oh, God, help
office. And you'll say, "Oh, God, help us."
So, more women are more integrous, you
So, more women are more integrous, you might say, in business because they're
might say, in business because they're
might say, in business because they're newer at the game. They're on trial
newer at the game. They're on trial
newer at the game. They're on trial and
and
and they're art performing men in the
they're art performing men in the
they're art performing men in the corporate world for now.
corporate world for now.
corporate world for now. In due time, they'll be the old girl
In due time, they'll be the old girl
In due time, they'll be the old girl network.
Mildred, I'll lend you. Thanks, Dorothy.
Mildred, I'll lend you. Thanks, Dorothy. But they haven't been at it long enough
But they haven't been at it long enough
But they haven't been at it long enough to get the old girl network going yet.
to get the old girl network going yet.
to get the old girl network going yet. Maybe they won't because in a world at
Maybe they won't because in a world at
Maybe they won't because in a world at 207,
207,
207, maybe that a few bucks under the counter
maybe that a few bucks under the counter
maybe that a few bucks under the counter will not happen.
will not happen.
will not happen. But the women right now were leading are
But the women right now were leading are
But the women right now were leading are leading the pack. Okay, let's go back to
leading the pack. Okay, let's go back to
leading the pack. Okay, let's go back to where we were.
where we were.
where we were. the evolution of consciousness then
the evolution of consciousness then
the evolution of consciousness then through
through
through the advancement of the levels of
the advancement of the levels of
the advancement of the levels of consciousness. You see, the great books
consciousness. You see, the great books
consciousness. You see, the great books of the Western world, the great books of
of the Western world, the great books of
of the Western world, the great books of the Western world are important because
the Western world are important because
the Western world are important because they're the intellectual
they're the intellectual
they're the intellectual um the jewels of man's thinking
um the jewels of man's thinking
um the jewels of man's thinking throughout all of time from 350 BC,
throughout all of time from 350 BC,
throughout all of time from 350 BC, Aristotle, Socrates,
Plato
Plato on down to the modern time. The great
on down to the modern time. The great
on down to the modern time. The great books of the western world was put
books of the western world was put
books of the western world was put together by Mortimer Adler at the
together by Mortimer Adler at the
together by Mortimer Adler at the University of Chicago, I think back in
University of Chicago, I think back in
University of Chicago, I think back in the 50s. I had the good luck to come
the 50s. I had the good luck to come
the 50s. I had the good luck to come upon a whole set.
upon a whole set.
upon a whole set. And this is how they calibrate.
And this is how they calibrate.
And this is how they calibrate. Extremely interesting. You see, they're
Extremely interesting. You see, they're
Extremely interesting. You see, they're all in the 400s. You see, I keep
all in the 400s. You see, I keep
all in the 400s. You see, I keep thinking this is a TV controller. It's a
thinking this is a TV controller. It's a
thinking this is a TV controller. It's a spotlight. Okay. Uh
spotlight. Okay. Uh
spotlight. Okay. Uh you see they all calibrate in the mid to
you see they all calibrate in the mid to
you see they all calibrate in the mid to high 400s. One or two go as far as 500.
high 400s. One or two go as far as 500.
high 400s. One or two go as far as 500. The great names of all all time,
the great inventors, the great geniuses,
the great inventors, the great geniuses, uh, Uklid, Hypocrates, the great names
uh, Uklid, Hypocrates, the great names
uh, Uklid, Hypocrates, the great names throughout all of time. uh can't
throughout all of time. uh can't
throughout all of time. uh can't categories of John Lockach,
Shakespeare, Plato,
Shakespeare, Plato, Socrates is not on there because
Socrates is not on there because
Socrates is not on there because Socrates didn't write any books, but
Socrates didn't write any books, but
Socrates didn't write any books, but Socrates calibrates at 540.
Socrates calibrates at 540.
Socrates calibrates at 540. So these are the great thinkers of all
So these are the great thinkers of all
So these are the great thinkers of all of life and it ends with Freud. Freud
of life and it ends with Freud. Freud
of life and it ends with Freud. Freud and Einstein are both at 499.
and Einstein are both at 499.
and Einstein are both at 499. Einstein was couldn't shift paradigms.
Einstein was couldn't shift paradigms.
Einstein was couldn't shift paradigms. You see at 499 at 500 you shift
You see at 499 at 500 you shift
You see at 499 at 500 you shift paradigms. The 400s is the intellect.
paradigms. The 400s is the intellect.
paradigms. The 400s is the intellect. 500 is the level of love. Now the
500 is the level of love. Now the
500 is the level of love. Now the primordial reality is not whether a
primordial reality is not whether a
primordial reality is not whether a thing is logical but whether it's
thing is logical but whether it's
thing is logical but whether it's loving. So lovingness
loving. So lovingness
loving. So lovingness the spiritual realm really shows up from
the spiritual realm really shows up from
the spiritual realm really shows up from 500 and up. 500 and up is the level of
500 and up. 500 and up is the level of
500 and up. 500 and up is the level of love. So there you move from
love. So there you move from
love. So there you move from describable scientific objectivity to
describable scientific objectivity to
describable scientific objectivity to subjectivity. Spiritual reality is all
subjectivity. Spiritual reality is all
subjectivity. Spiritual reality is all subject subjective.
subject subjective.
subject subjective. That which is a spiritual reality cannot
That which is a spiritual reality cannot
That which is a spiritual reality cannot be proven.
be proven.
be proven. That which is provable belongs within
That which is provable belongs within
That which is provable belongs within the intellectual domain.
the intellectual domain.
the intellectual domain. Therefore you cannot
Therefore you cannot
Therefore you cannot uh demand or expect any kind of
uh demand or expect any kind of
uh demand or expect any kind of spiritual reality to be provable. If it
spiritual reality to be provable. If it
spiritual reality to be provable. If it were provable, it wouldn't be a
were provable, it wouldn't be a
were provable, it wouldn't be a spiritual reality.
It would be an intellectualization.
It would be an intellectualization. Okay. The interesting thing for our our
Okay. The interesting thing for our our
Okay. The interesting thing for our our world, our world,
world, our world,
world, our world, uh Freud Freud of course discovered the
uh Freud Freud of course discovered the
uh Freud Freud of course discovered the unconscious, he calibrates at 499.
unconscious, he calibrates at 499.
unconscious, he calibrates at 499. When science moved into quantum
When science moved into quantum
When science moved into quantum quantum science, the Heisenberg
quantum science, the Heisenberg
quantum science, the Heisenberg principle was the the big advance. The
principle was the the big advance. The
principle was the the big advance. The discovery that the mere act of
discovery that the mere act of
discovery that the mere act of observation already changes
observation already changes
observation already changes the
the
the changes.
You can't do the same experiment twice
You can't do the same experiment twice because having observed it the first
because having observed it the first
because having observed it the first time, you've already collapsed the wave
time, you've already collapsed the wave
time, you've already collapsed the wave function. Yeah. And you've collapsed it
function. Yeah. And you've collapsed it
function. Yeah. And you've collapsed it to the new to a new paradigm. So the
to the new to a new paradigm. So the
to the new to a new paradigm. So the Heisenberg principle was the stunning
Heisenberg principle was the stunning
Heisenberg principle was the stunning philosophic metaphysical confrontation
philosophic metaphysical confrontation
philosophic metaphysical confrontation coming out of quantum mechanics.
coming out of quantum mechanics.
coming out of quantum mechanics. Even Einstein bucked at it. Einstein
Even Einstein bucked at it. Einstein
Even Einstein bucked at it. Einstein calibrates it the same as Freud at 499.
calibrates it the same as Freud at 499.
calibrates it the same as Freud at 499. And Einstein said, "I prefer to believe
And Einstein said, "I prefer to believe
And Einstein said, "I prefer to believe that there is an independent objective
that there is an independent objective
that there is an independent objective reality out there that exists
reality out there that exists
reality out there that exists independent of consciousness." and he
independent of consciousness." and he
independent of consciousness." and he refused to walk through the door and
refused to walk through the door and
refused to walk through the door and therefore he stayed at 499. Just as
therefore he stayed at 499. Just as
therefore he stayed at 499. Just as Freud refused to accept spiritual
Freud refused to accept spiritual
Freud refused to accept spiritual reality, Carl Young who calibrates at
reality, Carl Young who calibrates at
reality, Carl Young who calibrates at 520 included the human spirit as part of
520 included the human spirit as part of
520 included the human spirit as part of the experiential reality. He calibrates
the experiential reality. He calibrates
the experiential reality. He calibrates at 520.
at 520.
at 520. David Bow calibrates at 505 and he was
David Bow calibrates at 505 and he was
David Bow calibrates at 505 and he was able to include uh the extension of he
able to include uh the extension of he
able to include uh the extension of he was able to make the jump that Einstein
was able to make the jump that Einstein
was able to make the jump that Einstein couldn't make. So we see the this is the
couldn't make. So we see the this is the
couldn't make. So we see the this is the historic anticcedence of our culture,
historic anticcedence of our culture,
historic anticcedence of our culture, our culture, our academic culture. This
our culture, our academic culture. This
our culture, our academic culture. This is the paradigm of truth that has stood
is the paradigm of truth that has stood
is the paradigm of truth that has stood the test of time since 350 BC at least.
the test of time since 350 BC at least.
the test of time since 350 BC at least. And then we see unfortunately there's a
And then we see unfortunately there's a
And then we see unfortunately there's a couple errants in here. Um the whole
couple errants in here. Um the whole
couple errants in here. Um the whole thing calibrates at 450 and if you
thing calibrates at 450 and if you
thing calibrates at 450 and if you remove Karl Marx it calibrates at 465.
What was Marx's error? Marx's error
What was Marx's error? Marx's error don't forget I was a psychiatrist for 50
don't forget I was a psychiatrist for 50
don't forget I was a psychiatrist for 50 years psychoanalyst.
years psychoanalyst.
years psychoanalyst. At the time in the early first part of
At the time in the early first part of
At the time in the early first part of the 1800s
the 1800s
the 1800s um Hegel was the predominant professor
um Hegel was the predominant professor
um Hegel was the predominant professor of philosophy
of philosophy
of philosophy and uh Karl Marx uh had an unresolved
and uh Karl Marx uh had an unresolved
and uh Karl Marx uh had an unresolved edible complex
edible complex
edible complex resented his authority and threw it out.
resented his authority and threw it out.
resented his authority and threw it out. Says specifically he didn't like Hegel's
Says specifically he didn't like Hegel's
Says specifically he didn't like Hegel's principle of the absolute.
principle of the absolute.
principle of the absolute. The principle of the absolute is the
The principle of the absolute is the
The principle of the absolute is the whole basis for the calibrated levels of
whole basis for the calibrated levels of
whole basis for the calibrated levels of consciousness. All these calibrated are
consciousness. All these calibrated are
consciousness. All these calibrated are in comparison to the absolute.
in comparison to the absolute.
in comparison to the absolute. The absolute of course is divinity and
The absolute of course is divinity and
The absolute of course is divinity and god. Uh so
god. Uh so
god. Uh so mark substituted then a dualistic
mark substituted then a dualistic
mark substituted then a dualistic perception of reality which has been
perception of reality which has been
perception of reality which has been fatal to mankind and that is the
fatal to mankind and that is the
fatal to mankind and that is the perpetrator victim model.
perpetrator victim model.
perpetrator victim model. The perpetrator victim model of reality
The perpetrator victim model of reality
The perpetrator victim model of reality calibrates about 135
calibrates about 135
calibrates about 135 and it's caused no marks at 130.
and it's caused no marks at 130.
and it's caused no marks at 130. It's cost to mankind has been in my
It's cost to mankind has been in my
It's cost to mankind has been in my lifetime 100 million people dying.
lifetime 100 million people dying.
lifetime 100 million people dying. You think philosophy is an academic
You think philosophy is an academic
You think philosophy is an academic practice?
practice?
practice? Hardly.
The dualistic conception which sees
The dualistic conception which sees everything in terms their perpetrator
everything in terms their perpetrator
everything in terms their perpetrator and victim is a rejection from rest
and victim is a rejection from rest
and victim is a rejection from rest intern.
So philosophy is hardly an intellectual
So philosophy is hardly an intellectual dry academic study. the very basis upon
dry academic study. the very basis upon
dry academic study. the very basis upon which mankind makes his decisions. Yeah.
which mankind makes his decisions. Yeah.
which mankind makes his decisions. Yeah. You can see perpetrator victim as a
You can see perpetrator victim as a
You can see perpetrator victim as a duality. You can project it into
duality. You can project it into
duality. You can project it into anything and everything.
anything and everything.
anything and everything. Then you believe that it's out there.
Then you believe that it's out there.
Then you believe that it's out there. It's all in your head.
It's all in your head.
It's all in your head. There are no perpetrators and there are
There are no perpetrators and there are
There are no perpetrators and there are no victims out there. Why? Because
no victims out there. Why? Because
no victims out there. Why? Because everything is manifesting its own innate
everything is manifesting its own innate
everything is manifesting its own innate potential. Huh?
potential. Huh?
potential. Huh? A company goes to town. Comes to town.
A company goes to town. Comes to town.
A company goes to town. Comes to town. All I saw it in Theville, Wisconsin. You
All I saw it in Theville, Wisconsin. You
All I saw it in Theville, Wisconsin. You company comes to town. The town people
company comes to town. The town people
company comes to town. The town people are very rural. Hardly have any money.
are very rural. Hardly have any money.
are very rural. Hardly have any money. Now this big canning company comes in
Now this big canning company comes in
Now this big canning company comes in there. Suddenly the whole town thrives.
there. Suddenly the whole town thrives.
there. Suddenly the whole town thrives. People got new cars.
People got new cars.
People got new cars. People can buy books, clothes, etc.
People can buy books, clothes, etc.
People can buy books, clothes, etc. The company makes money. Stock people
The company makes money. Stock people
The company makes money. Stock people own the stock are happy. Everybody's
own the stock are happy. Everybody's
own the stock are happy. Everybody's happy until somebody comes in and says
happy until somebody comes in and says
happy until somebody comes in and says perpetrator victim.
perpetrator victim.
perpetrator victim. Now you've destroyed the community.
Now you've destroyed the community.
Now you've destroyed the community. They're all happy and thriving.
They're all happy and thriving.
They're all happy and thriving. Is the company
living off the worker
living off the worker or are the workers living off the
or are the workers living off the
or are the workers living off the company?
company?
company? The company was poor before it got to
The company was poor before it got to
The company was poor before it got to Theesville
Theesville
Theesville and the people in Theville were poor
and the people in Theville were poor
and the people in Theville were poor before the company got there.
before the company got there.
before the company got there. Why not see that as a mutuality
Why not see that as a mutuality
Why not see that as a mutuality instead of a duality?
The people are good for the company. The
The people are good for the company. The company is good for the town. Why not
company is good for the town. Why not
company is good for the town. Why not see it as a mutuality?
Because as mutuality, you can't sell
Because as mutuality, you can't sell hatred. That's it. You can't sell
hatred. That's it. You can't sell
hatred. That's it. You can't sell hatred. If I can stir you all up and see
hatred. If I can stir you all up and see
hatred. If I can stir you all up and see that the employees are screwing the
that the employees are screwing the
that the employees are screwing the company or the other way around, the
company or the other way around, the
company or the other way around, the company is screwing the employees. Now
company is screwing the employees. Now
company is screwing the employees. Now with my leverage of hate, I can make a
with my leverage of hate, I can make a
with my leverage of hate, I can make a vocation for myself
vocation for myself
vocation for myself and profit off the conflict. So that's
and profit off the conflict. So that's
and profit off the conflict. So that's what happens with the that dualistic
what happens with the that dualistic
what happens with the that dualistic error of perpetrator victim which now
error of perpetrator victim which now
error of perpetrator victim which now pervades our society and shreds it. It
pervades our society and shreds it. It
pervades our society and shreds it. It sees everything as perpetrator and
sees everything as perpetrator and
sees everything as perpetrator and victim. You can't mention anything
victim. You can't mention anything
victim. You can't mention anything but somebody doesn't have a parade about
but somebody doesn't have a parade about
but somebody doesn't have a parade about it.
Is it right we should have men's and
Is it right we should have men's and bathroom women's bathrooms separately? I
bathroom women's bathrooms separately? I
bathroom women's bathrooms separately? I don't know. you can make. You see what
don't know. you can make. You see what
don't know. you can make. You see what I'm saying?
I'm saying?
I'm saying? You go to France, they don't Oh, well,
You go to France, they don't Oh, well,
You go to France, they don't Oh, well, we could have a men's and women's
we could have a men's and women's
we could have a men's and women's bathroom rights. You know what I mean?
bathroom rights. You know what I mean?
bathroom rights. You know what I mean? You go to France, there's just one place
You go to France, there's just one place
You go to France, there's just one place and you go in men and women, you know.
and you go in men and women, you know.
and you go in men and women, you know. See? So, anyway, so divisiveness then
See? So, anyway, so divisiveness then
See? So, anyway, so divisiveness then divisiveness and conflict originates
divisiveness and conflict originates
divisiveness and conflict originates within the mind and then gets projected
within the mind and then gets projected
within the mind and then gets projected into the world. But the consequences are
into the world. But the consequences are
into the world. But the consequences are grave.
grave.
grave. 100 million people have died due to that
100 million people have died due to that
100 million people have died due to that falsity, that duality projected from the
falsity, that duality projected from the
falsity, that duality projected from the mind of Karl Marx.
mind of Karl Marx.
mind of Karl Marx. 135 is far from truth. Okay, so let's
135 is far from truth. Okay, so let's
135 is far from truth. Okay, so let's move to the next one.
move to the next one.
move to the next one. I just want people to see that
I just want people to see that
I just want people to see that philosophy is not some academic thing,
philosophy is not some academic thing,
philosophy is not some academic thing, you know.