I'm going to make the announcements, so if you want to sit down while I make the announcements.
Sit here.
Good morning.
For headquarters.
Hi.
It's so nice to see all of you here today.
I know for Arizona it's been cold weather.
For the rest of the country it's been nice, but anyway, there's a few little things that
we have to follow.
Number one, please turn off your cell phones, and there's no filming or recording of the
event.
Line up for questions over here to my left, your right, whatever.
And anyone can ask questions.
We've asked that from our students that they would allow.
They're the ones to have an opportunity to ask, but this year we're going to have anyone
can ask a question that wants to.
The bookstore will close after the last break, so if you want anything at the bookstore,
if you'll get it at the break or now, it's about the only opportunity that you can, the
bookstore will be open.
We have...
We're going to be producing these Q&As.
Okay.
The Q&As that we're doing this year, they're going to be produced in DVDs as well as CDs,
so we're asking everyone to sign a release form when they're in line, because the images
will be shown now on DVDs, so they'll be available in DVDs.
Okay.
With that, we have Dr. Moon is here from Korea again.
Please stand up, would you please, yeah.
So she's visiting.
And she presented us with these lovely flowers, and now I'd like to introduce Dr. Hawkins.
Thank you.
Glory and excelsis to you.
Thank you, Lord, for this magnificent day.
Amen.
Want a Pepsi?
No, God don't want a Pepsi.
Oh.
Hello.
She would like you to give her a silent transmission.
She already got it.
That'll be a dollar.
.
Yeah.
Okay.
Well.
Yeah.
And she would like to have the grace of being, I don't know what that is, silent transmission.
In the grace of the teacher.
In the grace of the teacher is what she said.
Yes, that's automatic.
Even though you don't deserve it, of course.
Now, I looked up her Good Karma account.
She gets one.
Yes.
God bless you, sweetheart.
What exactly is involved in a silence transmission?
It's an energy field.
And it comes on down through time.
And it's transmitted back out to the world through the teacher.
Yes.
It's called the...
It's called the silent transmission.
The Buddha, when he passed the flower to Ananda,
it symbolized the passing on of that energy field.
It's silent and visible.
And it also, surprisingly, carries through the voice.
It also carries through the voice.
Because we do interviews on the telephone.
And I was concerned.
And it said, yes, it transmits through the voice.
Which I didn't know.
But it's nice to know.
Let's see if that's true.
It transmits through the voice.
Yeah, it transmits through the voice as well as the presence.
That's fine.
That makes me happy.
Because how many places can you be?
But your voice, recorded voice, can be many places.
Even though your physical body can only be in one place.
So is that why when you're listening to music, such as Andrea Bocelli,
and you go to that really high space when he's singing,
is that part of it?
Because you're listening to it when he's in his voice?
Oh, I don't know if he has it in his voice.
Well, but...
Well, all I can ask.
Okay.
Does Bocelli have that energy in his voice?
Yeah.
Okay.
That's the voice.
It's a beauty.
Beauty.
Beauty and really grace.
Divine grace.
Okay.
Thank you.
Yes.
he's asking
could you please meditate with us
for one minute
could you do a meditation
for everybody for a minute
well I don't know
if I want to do that or not
a whole minute
oh my god
well we will
do that
I have an announcement
we have a pair of lost keys in the
bookstore if you could
if you've lost your keys please check there
we are all meditating
for one minute
there will be an extra charge
if it runs over
do you want to
do an own
for a minute
no an own is something different
no he didn't ask for an own
he asked for a meditation
how long is a minute
he asked for an hour
but I don't know
how long it will take
if I don't know
he's talking about
if it runs out
I'm not going to
check it
uh
I'm going to check
for what's in there
for a minute
so you just
you're going to
check what's in there
and I'm going
to help you
I'm not going to
do anything
you just
just
let me know
something
Zip it
just
zip it
and there it is
I've found
you
yeah
and I don't know
if this is
I don't know
but I don't know
if it's
like
Ah, thank you.
It's the longest minute on record.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
Yes.
Thank you for being here.
And I also want to thank you for showing up in my dreams periodically.
You've, uh...
Here's an extra charge for that.
I'll pay them at the bookstore.
About two months ago, I had an intense spiritual state arise,
and it lasted for about a day.
And afterwards, I felt quite devastated and...
Devastated?
Why do you call it a spiritual state?
I'm sorry?
What kind of a state was it?
I had sat down to contemplate because I had a lot of mental chaos going on.
Yes.
And the minute I sat down,
it instantly became an awareness of the duality.
And I heard a voice or a thought came that said,
forget about yourself.
And the small self fell back,
and, um...
Everything just, uh, lit up.
And I just...
Okay, beautiful.
I knew the self as that.
And what?
And I just, I just knew my self as that.
Yes.
Was it a light?
Just everything.
The essence of existence and your own existence is divinity, and that's what you affirmed.
Is that correct?
Yes.
That's a great experience.
I was just curious if it would be of any use to you.
Yes.
Thank you.
Okay.
See you in the next dream.
What do you got?
Okay.
I can't see you.
I can't see that world to see what he was doing.
Hello.
Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
Thank you.
And my husband dragged me here the first time a while back.
Oh, I'm not hearing her very well.
Yeah, sit back just a little bit.
Okay.
My husband dragged me here about a year ago.
Her husband what?
Dragged her here about a year ago.
Dragged her.
Oh, yes.
Uh-huh.
And I'm very glad he did.
And I just wanted to ask for a blessing.
Well, you're here.
That's the blessing.
The presence of the teacher is itself the blessing and the good karma to bring that experience within your own life, yes.
Thank you.
He can't see.
Go ahead.
May I touch your hand?
Right.
Okay.
Thank you.
Hi.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
I come from Croatia.
He comes from where?
Croatia.
Where is that?
Next to Italy.
Next to Italy?
Yeah.
Oh, oh, oh.
I thought it was south of Phoenix.
But I don't know.
I don't know.
I don't know where you are.
I just wanted to thank you and ask for a blessing.
Ah.
Yes.
It is so.
Thank you.
This is a longer thank you.
Okay.
Thank you so much.
He can't see.
I've never been to Croatia.
Croatia is very beautiful.
I've been to Cottonwood.
Cottonwood?
Okay.
Yeah.
Is that in your career, is she?
Sometimes I think so.
Yes.
Hi, my question is in regards to the energy in your CDs and your DVDs.
I understand there's energy in them, and I listen to your CDs all the time,
and I have them playing, and I'm not listening to it, but it's on.
Yes.
Am I still getting the energy?
The answer, we can ask this.
We have permission to ask this.
The answer is yes.
The answer is no.
Yeah, so he has to have it on, actually.
It has to be in my ear and hearing it.
Yeah.
Oh, uh-huh.
Okay.
In the similar vein, I have the DVDs playing, the volume is off, and I'm reading a book.
So am I getting the energy then?
That's a bizarre question.
I'm a bizarre person, so.
Is there one?
Can you tell me what you're getting, actually?
Yes.
The answer is no.
Okay.
Yeah.
Thank you.
You've got to watch it.
Yeah.
Yeah, you have to.
I see.
They want to have the radio on the car while they're driving.
I understand without actually listening to it, because that would be a distraction from
the driving.
Good morning, Dr. Hawkins.
Yes.
I actually have no questions.
I wanted to just come here and thank you.
I'm a fairly new student.
I'm a very good student.
I'm the first student here, so I'm very happy about that.
I'm very excited.
I'm a very good student.
I'm very good at talking, so I'm very, very excited.
I'm very excited.
I'm a fairly new student.
My son stumbled on Power vs. Force and talked about it for three months while he was digesting
the book.
And, of course, I pooh-poohed it, thinking where it was coming from.
And after he finished the book, he gave me his copy, and it was obviously a life-changing
experience for me, and I just wanted to take this opportunity to thank you and tell you
how impressed I am with the devotional nature of your followers and the people that follow
your work.
So thank you very much.
Yes, thank you for coming here and affirming it.
Thank you so much.
And you have a good son.
Hello.
Hi.
I've only been studying your work for about three months, but I'm very excited to see
your work.
But my question is, my son and his wife have been heroin addicts for three years, and they're
clean right now.
She's got to sit closer.
Okay.
Sit just a little closer.
A little closer to the mic.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Tell me again.
What?
My son and his wife.
Your son.
And who else?
His wife.
And his wife.
Have they...
Your son and your daughter-in-law.
Yes.
Yes?
We don't get along very well, though.
But they have...
I didn't ask you that, did I?
No.
Are you the typical mother-in-law?
I try to be good, but...
You try to be good.
It's hard to do.
It's really hard to be good, isn't it?
But, yes.
Yeah.
Go ahead.
Tell me which one.
Well, they're not using right now.
They're not what?
They're not using any heroin.
They're heroin addicts, and they're not using.
They're off drugs at the moment.
Okay.
Yes.
I do know.
OK.
Thanks.
But I believe that they're...
Because they're actions, and they're always hollering and screaming and fighting, and they
have an eight-year-old, and we all live together right now for a couple of months.
And I wonder how I can best help them.
By remaining serene and loving.
To be serene and loving.
Yeah.
It's to be loving towards all of life and all of its expressions, including the one that you just described.
It's easy to be nice to life when life is nice.
It's more a greater discipline to be agreeable to life, no matter what its conditions are.
So to be consistent, then, you be as loving as you can be as a way of being in the world.
If lovingness is your way of being in the world, then it's not affected by what's going on out there.
Everybody, your purpose here is to be loving as a way of being in the world.
And it's irrelevant.
It's irrelevant what the world thinks of it or does about it.
That's irrelevant.
Okay?
Okay.
Thank you.
Anybody can be cheerful on a sunny day.
To be cheerful on a rainy day is something different.
Yeah.
It's easy to get dragged into arguments, so that's what I'm trying to follow.
Just refuse and smile benignly at them like they're idiots, you know?
That's good to hit each other.
It gets rid of all that.
It gets rid of all that extra energy, yeah.
Thank you.
May I have a picture?
Is that okay?
Sure.
So that way, remain as loving towards life as you can be at all times.
It's very difficult to stand by and watch your children make mistakes, too.
It's one of the hardest things a mother has to do.
Yeah.
I'm glad I'm not a mother.
Thank you.
Can we have a look?
Yeah.
Thank you.
Hi, Ц klein ли, Hi.
Hi.
How much of seventh act just here.
how much how much of When I'm setting in front of you we'll transfer to my children.
How much of the energy will transfer to them.
How much of the energy when you're sitting, he's sitting in front of you would transfer
would transfer to his children.
Hayley, how much.
children. Why would it transfer to his children? Well, that's what he's asking.
Will it transfer to his children? Oh, in other words, if he picks up my energy, can he then
transmit it? Okay. Yes. I understand what you're asking. Okay. Does it, it does transmit.
It does not transmit. Okay. Okay. They got to find it on their own. I see. All right.
That's all right. My next question was. Uh-huh. Okay. Thank you.
I wonder how, why that is. I'm not satisfied with it. If he picks up my energy. Right. Then.
If he picks up my energy, he can then transmit it to someone else. Resist. No.
I don't know why. That's disappointing.
We'll have to do research on it. I don't have the answer right now.
Could you recall the final doorway for us?
No. No.
Could you tell me what I need to know if I ever get there?
Yeah. I, I think.
It's on DVDs and in books, isn't it?
I've heard it many times, actually. But I want to know, like.
If you've heard it many times, why are you asking me to repeat it?
Because I want to have, like, conviction. It takes a lot of.
Because he wants what?
You want to have what?
Conviction.
He feels that you could push him through.
Oh, push him through. No push, no push, no push, no.
You don't push?
Yes.
It happens of its own, automatically, when the time is right.
What about fear?
Hmm?
Fear. What about fear?
What about fear?
How do you handle that?
You don't handle it. You turn it over to God.
You surrender the fear to God. You surrender your life to God.
And as you do that, terror comes up.
And you surrender your terror to God.
That's it. Just surrender.
Yes.
That's, that's the, what carries you through all of it.
The willingness to surrender everything to God, including your own life.
So if you feel like you're dying, you say, all right, so I'm dying.
And you surrender your life to God.
And then you either die or you don't.
Seeing as you're here, I guess.
But the experience is that of dying.
Yes.
Thank you.
Thank you, Susan.
And then you lose your fear of dying.
You lose your fear of dying.
When I was in World War II, I lost my fear of dying.
I said, you're going to explode.
And this mind's going to explode and kill you.
Any second.
I said, so?
So?
So if we go, we go.
And the other guy said, yeah, you're right.
I don't really have a question.
I just wanted to come up.
I just wanted to come up here and thank you for all that you've done in my life over the last few years that I've known you.
I'm having trouble hearing her.
She just wanted to come up and thank you for what you've done for her the last few years.
Oh, yes.
Okay.
She's been following us for quite some time.
Oh, I see.
Uh-huh.
And I thank you for being my teacher.
You've been following this?
As much as I can, Doc.
In my rearview mirror, I see you all the time, huh?
There's that lady again, by golly.
I'm glad you're keeping an eye on me.
Call the police.
All right.
My goodness sakes.
What is this here?
That's your...
That's dialogues.
Just sign it.
Okay.
May I shake your hand?
Thank you.
Hello.
I want to thank you for your body of work on disease and recovery.
I mean, it's huge.
And I wanted to know if you could comment at all on the cause of diseases like dementia and Alzheimer's.
Alzheimer's.
And how would you treat these types of diseases at your clinic?
What is your question?
Why is there mental illness?
She wants you to comment on dementia.
Dementia.
Right.
And how would you look at it and how would you treat it?
I would look at it as premature aging and the mind is aged.
And, you know, usually chronic.
It occurs, you know, old age, and it's just a natural wearing out of the brain.
It's the only way I look at it, the natural wearing out of the brain.
Brain fag.
That's what I used to tell patients.
They say, what's wrong with me, doc?
I can't seem to remember anything.
I said, well, it's just brain fag.
Everybody was happy with that.
I have a little case of it myself.
Brain fag.
I don't know.
Brain fag sometimes.
Accepted as normal evolution in the human domain.
Do you remember the story you told about when you went to the rest homes and the little
old lady, you know, would be sitting there and they say, what did you have for dinner
tonight?
Oh, I don't know.
Remember that story that you tell?
That she'd already crossed over, you know, to the other side.
You're not close enough to the mic.
Okay.
Do you, do you remember the story about the little old lady that you would go see when
you would visit the rest homes and you would ask her, well, what'd you eat today?
And she couldn't answer you.
Oh, yeah.
And you said she was perfectly happy.
It's the people around them.
Oh, yes.
It's the people around her that are disturbed by dementia.
The person who has dementia has already forgotten that he's forgotten.
Yeah.
So you say, how are you today?
I'm fine.
Do you know what day it is today?
No.
Does that worry you?
Nope.
It worries the family.
Oh, grandpa doesn't remember what, what day it is anymore.
Why should he remember what day it is?
I mean, who needs to know what day it is?
I don't know what day it is today.
Doesn't really worry me.
Do you know what day it is today?
No.
As long as somebody knows what day it is, yeah, you don't have to worry.
They might pawn off yesterday's newspaper on you and you didn't know it, you know what
I mean?
That's true.
That's the way I tell what day it is.
I go and I look at the newspaper and it says right up there, the Arizona Republic, I think
it is.
You can't find out what day it is on Fox News, you know.
They don't tell you what day it is.
Yeah.
Here we are.
Hi, teacher.
What?
Yes, sit back, just a hair.
Okay.
What did she say?
I said, hi, teacher.
Oh, hi.
Salute.
Souto's amigo, Hachikamana.
Thank you.
First, I just want to thank you for everything.
My question is, Buddhas said transcend your six sense into wisdom.
I just wondered if you can give me a practical examples about how you can transcend the taste,
sense of taste, into wisdom.
Which you're saying?
How to transcend, just a minute.
taste. Sixth sense.
Into wisdom.
Into wisdom. Yeah.
And the sixth sense is? Like just give an
example of like you said
one sense which is taste.
In what way you can transcend
like eating a chocolate.
Oh.
What is your question?
I can't hear
very well. I know Dave. I'm trying to think
how to put it to you so you don't understand it.
What she wants to know
is the Buddha
said to transcend
your sixth sense.
Yeah.
And that into wisdom.
Yeah. So what she's
asking you is
such as taste
how would you. Such as what?
Taste. Taste.
The senses. The physical senses.
Taste. Yeah. How would you
transform that into wisdom?
Oh. You can't
do that.
You can't really
That's why not many people are enlightened.
Sort of a bum direction isn't it?
Totally.
Transform your taste into
enlightenment?
I mean that's nonsensical.
Okay. Well the sixth sense.
The senses. Yes. All the senses.
All the senses. And he says take those
senses and change it into
wisdom. The sixth sense. Yes.
Change it into wisdom.
You just keep surrendering your will
to God all the time and forget all
those cookbooks.
Transfer your senses into wisdom. I mean that sounds
idiotic.
That's why the Buddha's not around
anymore.
Laughter.
You come back talk. Talk. Sense
talk.
Laughter. So what
does he really mean when he said
that? Yeah. When he said that.
What's your interpretation of it when he
said that? To surrender
all
as it occurs.
Yeah.
To be in a
permanent state of surrenderingness.
So
so it's a continuous
process with
no beginning and no end.
And
you allow that state
to
you might say flow of its own.
You allow the state to flow of its own.
I don't know what you're going to
say next. You understand what I'm saying?
I don't have to
demand that you tell me what you're
going to say next.
Whatever you say next is
whatever you say next. And I have no
position about it.
So it's
non-positionality.
Non-positionality.
So I remember you said
that just be the best of who you are.
Is that
pretty much it?
She remembers you saying
be the best of
you know
try and do your best.
That's it.
That's all you can do.
Be the best doggy you can be.
Yes.
Give me your paw.
That's what I do.
I give God my paw.
There you go.
Now it's up to God
what he does with my paw.
Oink.
That is so cute.
Thank you so much.
Be a happy dog. Be a happy doggy.
People say how do you reach enlightenment?
Oink.
Just be a happy dog.
Just keep wagging your tail.
Stop complaining and carrying on
and fussing.
I just try to keep my tail wagging.
Okay.
That's all.
My dog wags her tail at me
in the morning and I wag my tail back
and we're all happy.
Everybody's happy.
Thank you so much.
Love all of life unconditionally
in all of its expressions.
Sometimes the doggy's tail wags.
Sometimes it doesn't.
And
you love everything
continuously no matter what.
Oh, wait.
This is hers.
Yeah.
Uh-huh.
What daily prayers
and practices would be useful
for a spiritual student
seeking enlightenment?
What daily practices
would be suitable
for a student in daily practices?
Well, that's written extensively
in the world of literature.
Are you really asking me the question?
Did you ever hear meditation?
Hello?
Okay. Yes.
What's he asking me?
Sorry?
What is your question again?
What daily prayers and practices
would be useful for a spiritual student?
Daily?
What daily prayers and practices?
Okay.
So meditation is the practice.
And prayers are
prayers of thanks,
requests,
divine requests of God.
Dear God, please help me
put my socks on the right feet.
Ha, ha, ha.
What are you looking for?
The big payoff, you know?
The magic prayer that,
oh, instantly you're enlightened.
You know what happens
when you're enlightened?
You don't care about being enlightened.
The only people who care about being enlightened
are people who are not enlightened.
Once you're enlightened,
you couldn't care less.
The world would call it
whatever it calls it.
If you're not careful,
they'll put you in a, you know,
funny house.
Ha, ha, ha.
Can we get a picture?
Sure.
Ha, ha, ha.
They put you in the funny farm.
Yeah.
Wait, let's picture.
I just wanted to thank you
for the difference
you've made in my life,
as well as my brother's
and my mom.
So thank you.
Thank you for thanking me.
Thank you.
Thanks.
The question is,
is somebody enlightened
or are they retarded?
Ha, ha, ha.
We're politically correct today.
Good morning.
Yeah.
Love you, Dr. Hawkins.
Love you, Susan.
Thank you.
I have a question
from the book I.
Oh, okay.
I wanted to read
two sentences
and then ask
a question.
One can view
the spiritual ego
as the current manifestation of one's karma
so that undoing the ego is the same
as resolving one's karma
because they are operationally one and the same.
If the term karma is not acceptable,
one can use the term unconscious instead.
So my question is,
how is undoing the ego and karma operationally the same?
The ego is karma.
The ego is a karmic creation.
And then one's inner attitude towards that ego
is one's spiritual state.
Are you going to take it seriously?
Are you going to throw yourself down a well
because your ego is condemning you?
So the inner attitude is one of humility
and surrender without identifying with it.
The human condition is, you see, what it is.
And the human brain operates
in its own way.
Because that's our karmic inheritance as human beings.
So I always respect,
if God's will is for me to have a brain that functions that way,
who am I to tell God that he's wrong?
Right?
So you accept with humility the human condition.
The human condition.
You don't have to personalize it.
You can just accept it's the human condition.
You have two legs.
You have two arms.
How come you don't have five?
How come you don't have one?
You know what I'm saying?
So it's dumb to keep asking questions
about why is everything the way it is.
It's obvious that it's God's will that it be that way.
Yes?
So you just surrender it to the creator.
Thank you.
God was bored, so he created human beings.
He's regretted it ever since.
Never got a good night's rest anymore since I created humankind.
There's always some prayer bouncing off the floor of heaven.
Thank you.
Pay attention to me.
Oh, yes.
Hello.
Yes.
I'd just like to, I'm just here to thank you for your time.
Thank you.
Thank you, for taking a machete to my ego.
Ah, ha, ha, ha.
Thank you both.
Thank you.
Sometimes we drowned it, too, sometimes.
Yes.
Sometimes we drowned it.
Sometimes we used a machete.
Other times, we just drowned it.
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
You can drown it in pea soup.
Thank you.
Yes.
Good morning.
I wanted to come
actually offering, bringing something to you
to both of you to thank you
and I was praying and asked God to show me
and nothing came
and I just wanted to offer my heart
and just
we'll cut it out
that's the old Aztec technique
cut your heart right out of it
hold it up for the crowd
while it's still beating
I would really
I'm in 12 step recovery
been for a few years
in 12 step recovery
I just wanted to, my first sponsor said
that AA can open the gates of hell
and let you out
and last night as I was
falling asleep, I had this vision of you
and it was you at the gates of heaven
pushing them wide open
and with your arms open
saying
you know
it's safe to surrender
come on in
you know
it's your home too
and I just wanted to thank you
yeah
it is God's gift
the wretched
that's me
my question is
I've done what you said to do
and dedicate my life to serve
you know
God, self and others
and recently I've got an opportunity
an invitation
to go stay at Ramana Maharishi's ashram
for an indefinite period
and I'm going to go
and also an invitation to come serve
with the missionaries of charity
yes
and I wanted to see if you could ask the
ask the arm if that's in the highest good
yes that's in the highest good
it's a pretty safe bet right
laughter
okay
um
laughter
I guess there are some dumb questions right
no no it's fine
that is a dumb question yes
laughter
um
it was mentioned earlier
I'll make this real quick
um
in
as you advance
and you get to those doorways
um
that
those who have been there
will
the awareness of them
having been there
and who went through
and who didn't
yes
will be there
in the meditation
I've had some very
very
seen to be high states
glimpses of that
ultimate
exactly like you described
is it possible
I brought a couple dollars
if it takes that
for you to do it
but would you
could I look in your eyes
and um
if you could reflect
the reality of what I am
so that I know it's safe
to surrender
what is he requesting
I don't know
he just wants
you to look at him
and
transmit to him
that it's okay
uh
to surrender
and
because that terror comes up
because the terror comes up
every time he tries to do it
oh
well then you won't be able to make it
laughter
you need to surrender
to the terror
and stop trying to avoid it
or you don't
when you let go of the self
as you understand it
you feel you're letting go of life
and you feel a terror
like for you
or perhaps dying
to get through there
you just keep surrendering
to that
and eventually it dies
away
and you know
and you're either alive
or dead
you may live through it
and maybe not
maybe not
laughter
since this is the last
maybe the last
I don't know
you know
time I'll be this close to you
in the physicality
I'm trying to let go
of the attachment to you
I'm in the process
could I get a picture
to take with me to India
laughter
please
I've got
like I said
I've got a couple dollars
laughter
what does he want
a picture
to take with him
where to heaven
to India
India
yeah
that's where I'm going
seems like
I'm going to the ashram
Ramana ashram
oh yeah
you're going to India
yeah
like this is a huge deal
you know
it's a huge deal
so
it feels safe
I just wanted
to
you know
no that sounds exciting
yeah
just watch
drinking the water
there
laughter
get all your shots
oh I'm
yeah
somebody
gave me a little bottle
of the water
from the Ganges
recently
it came back
from India
and we calibrated it
it was 700
right
yeah
so
be sure
and have a swim
laughter
while you're there
okay
thank you
yes
we don't need that
laughter
the water of the Ganges
is a
miraculous
ouch
look what you did to my thumb
for Christ's sake
laughter
give me back my thumb
oh thank you
oh god
there we are
laughter
thank you
yes
I just wanted to
thank you
for your teachings
and receive a blessing
yes
God bless you
thank you
and a picture
yeah
ah
now he brings in the picture
laughter
ouch
his thumb's in there
laughter
smile
there you go
thank you
ouch
hello doc
I've said in the audience in the audience lots of times
and ah
I feel like for probably like a few weeks after
a real subtle energy
that feels like
it can be very subtle
but I think that the fact is
that I feel alive
and that I can this
one day
you know
it's that
That feels really nice.
But last time I actually came up on stage
and for about a month after that I could barely function.
I can't.
But I could feel an energy from my feet
right up through my spine at all times.
And it felt wonderful.
So I was wondering how much proximity has to do
with maybe the transmission we get from the teacher.
He came up on stage and asked a question last time
and he wants to know how much.
Yeah, physical proximity is necessary, unfortunately.
Otherwise I could retire.
Well, I'm glad you're here.
And thank you very much.
Thank you, Susan.
Thank you.
Yes, unfortunately, physical proximity.
Although it does go through the voice.
The energy does go through the voice.
Yeah, the energy does go through the voice
without the physical proximity.
So I was pleased to learn that.
Yes.
In contemplation, it's like I'm in a field of love.
And wherever attention goes, the love is there.
But when I close my eyes in meditation,
the love rapidly falls away until it's unnoticeable.
When he closes his eyes in meditation, what?
The love falls away and it's unnoticeable.
In other words, it changes.
It shifts and the love no longer is there.
Oh, the love is not there.
Yeah.
I don't even know if that's a problem.
But if it is a problem, I'd like to know
if there's a different approach to meditation
that would prevent the love falling away.
The feeling of the presence of love
depends on whether you have your eyes open or closed.
Is that what you're saying?
Yes, yes.
That's exactly it.
All right.
Usually it is that you feel the presence
when you close your eyes.
And it disappears when you open them.
Is that the way it is with you?
No, it's the opposite.
I don't know.
I've never heard of it.
Oh.
Okay.
Maybe you got your clothes on backwards.
So, what is he...
All right, if it was the reverse,
what would be your suggestion?
Well, he's experiencing the world.
He's experiencing the world as divine.
Right.
Then when he shuts his eyes,
he shuts out the world,
but he doesn't keep including himself.
If he included himself,
which is also divine,
then it wouldn't go away.
Okay.
He's saying God is only out there,
but not just in me.
Not in me, you know.
So, don't exclude God
as the source of your consciousness.
Don't exclude God
I mean, what is telling you
all these things that you're reporting
except the presence of divinity
as your consciousness, right?
So, you can hardly refute it
when that's the very thing
that you're reporting, yeah?
Right.
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
Yes.
Thank you.
Hi.
I've had several spiritual experiences
that I can verbalize,
but I had one that I can't.
And I was wondering
if you could calibrate that
and also if you would
maybe
I don't know.
She's had a couple
of spiritual experiences.
What?
Well, I've had one
that I can't verbalize at all.
And I've had others
that I can.
I can't hear what she's saying.
Just a minute.
She's had one experience
that she can't verbalize.
Yes?
Well, don't verbalize it then.
And the others, you know,
she could,
but this is one experience
she had that she can't verbalize.
No.
The more the advanced
the experience,
the more the experience
the experience
the less it's capable
of being verbalized.
To be in the presence
of divinity
is overwhelming
and it cannot be described
because you realize
the essence of all that exists
and you're experiencing
the essence
rather than the appearance.
And there's no way
to explain that to anybody.
That's like seeing beauty.
Uh-huh.
Is there any beauty?
Is there any beauty
out there in the world?
No.
Where is beauty?
It's in your mind.
Why is it in your mind?
Because it's everywhere
in the world.
It's everywhere in the world.
You see the beauty
of all that exists.
So where is that beauty?
Is it in the world
or is it in your mind?
Or is it in your mind?
Or is it in the mind of God?
You can puzzle that
for a couple decades
and report back.
Do we have permission
to calibrate that experience?
Calibrate what experience?
I can't get what experience
you're talking about.
If I hold it in mind.
I can't calibrate something
you don't even know what it is.
If I hold it in mind?
Yeah.
Okay.
What she's holding in mind.
We have to ask permission.
Okay.
We have permission to calibrate
what she's holding in mind.
No, I don't think so.
Okay.
No, because we can't identify
what it is.
Okay.
Yeah, it's too confusing.
All right.
Thank you.
Okay.
Somebody asked us
something simple.
Like when I walk down
the sidewalk,
I see little green men
running down.
Nobody asked me
something simple like that.
Anybody here see
the little green men
running around?
Hey, volunteers,
there's the little green men people.
I knew they'd be here today.
The reason you can't see them
is because they're invisible.
I don't have a question.
I just wanted to
come up on stage
and look into your eyes.
Yes.
And I wanted to thank you
for being my teacher.
Thank you for the privilege
of being your teacher, yes.
Okay, we have about
five minutes
before we have to take a break.
All right.
Yes.
It was said
that there's individual karma
over 200.
And also,
there is no personal you.
And is there any way
to explain
the seeming difference
between those?
What's he asking?
Repeat it one more time
because the microphone
was...
First, make one sentence.
It was said
there was individual karma
over 200.
We have individual karma
when we're over 200.
You said that
there was individual karma
over 200.
Yes.
And it's also been said
that there is no personal you.
There's no personal person.
There's no personal you
or personal...
Yeah, you're mixing
levels of awareness.
Okay.
You're mixing levels.
You can't...
What's true at this level
is not explicable
in the same language
at this level.
So what was the second part
of your question you wanted?
Well, just to...
If it was explainable
why they seem to be different.
They don't seem to be able
to coexist.
I don't get what the question is.
I don't either.
Okay.
You have to know
what you're asking.
Well, that's my confusion about it
is the question.
It's because if there's...
It seems like personal
and individual
would be the same thing.
Personal.
And individual
would be the same thing.
If you have individual karma,
if I'm choosing...
If I choose and do something,
I'm going to have...
the karma of that
individually.
And that's going to make
my level of consciousness
go up or down
based on my intention
and choice.
And that's going to be
personal to me.
Or it may have no effect.
Yeah.
Or it may not have no effect,
but that would be personal
to me, correct?
Yeah.
Uh-huh.
So...
The infinite self
is uninfluenced
by what the small self
is up to.
Okay.
Yeah.
The infinite self,
the infinite self,
it doesn't even register
what the small self
is up to.
Like the sun shines
on all equally,
no matter what's going on.
Whether it's mayhem
or a peace march,
it's all the same
to the sun.
Yeah?
Yes.
Thank goodness.
All right?
All right, thank you.
Yes.
So this...
The small self
is the ego.
Yes.
And the large self...
Or the large S...
Yeah, is the self...
Is the...
With a capital S.
Like the soul.
Yes.
All right.
And that part is eternal.
The self with a capital S
is eternal.
Right.
Uh-huh.
And the self with the small S
is your ego.
Yeah.
Right.
That comes and goes.
Okay.
Does that explain it a little better?
Yes.
Okay.
It's 11.
Do you want to take a break?
Yeah, we're going to...
Yeah, it's...
We're going to take
about a 10-minute break
and then we'll resume.
Please remember
your place in line.
And we'll be right back.
Thank you.