Heat.
Are we here?
Well, I'm glad we're here
because if we weren't here, we wouldn't
be here.
So I feel blessed by your presence
and I ask God to bless thee in the name
of the Lord. Amen.
Thank you.
I need this cane to beat off the women.
They're all after my little body.
What can you do
now? What happens this morning,
sweetheart?
>> We're going to start with our first
question.
>> What do we do this morning?
>> Come right over here. This is
>> somebody comes over and speaks to us.
>> Oh,
who is going to speak?
>> Do you have a um a thing to sign books
if we have to. A pen. Do you have a pen?
>> Ah,
here. Let me look.
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
>> I think I have two of them here.
>> Thank you.
>> All right. What is it?
That's my friendly voice.
Well, everyone wants to see see you know
everybody.
>> Yes. Good morning.
>> Did somebody come here for a question?
>> Yeah.
>> Who came for a question?
>> They brought you a present. So, I'm
trying to get it out.
>> Good god.
A live giraffe. No.
>> Oh boy. Oh boy. Look at that.
>> Upside down.
Hey, isn't that gorgeous?
>> This is this is from our Korean uh
followers.
>> Are these Korean people here?
Oh, God bless you Korean people.
We haven't been in Korea since we were
in Korea.
How many We were there, I guess, a
couple times. Yes.
and uh helped settle a dangerous
situation
using the arm and it came out well.
Yeah.
Okay. What is the h happens next?
>> My question
in relationship with others I always
initute their shortcomings and attack
them.
They know their own shortcomings and
feel inferior about them. So when I
point out they get severe emotional
damage. I had to recognize my offensive
attitude about 10 years ago.
But I couldn't control that.
After then I've adopted an alternative
attitude of just shutting my mouth
and this made me isolated and remain a a
spectator. Although I want to join the
conversation and promote friendly
relations with others but I actually
judge others with
>> this is a long speech. I have to know
what his question is. He he's uh what it
is is that he feels that he is
overcritical of others.
>> Yes.
>> And um so he tries not to be but then it
makes him feel like he's not um
friendly or not.
>> So
>> he does he mean critical think the way
he thinks or the way he talks or
behaves?
critical thinking or critical behavior.
What does he mean?
>> Both.
>> So when he sees
>> all right crit being critical means you
consider yourself superior to others.
>> Yes.
>> That you are perfect and they are dumb
and stupid.
So what you need is some humility.
Everybody is being
everybody is doing the best they can at
any time. That's a good rule to
remember.
Everybody is already doing the best they
can at that moment. If they could be
doing better, they would be.
If people could could be smarter, they
would be. We are created as God created
us with limitation.
So you begin the way to heal this is to
see that other people are God's
creatures, God's creatures.
And that there's somewhere along the
path of evolution.
And it's not up to you to judge them.
Judge not, said the Lord. Judge not,
said the Lord. Yes, lest ye be judged.
Consequently,
humility is the answer to the whole
thing.
Everybody's is doing the best they could
be the best they can do or they would be
doing better.
Do you understand that
>> he though in his thought
can't
>> Yeah. He's he's thinking that you know
up here he's thinking that but
>> he's thinking critically. He's not
really being critical verbally.
>> Oh, well that's a big improvement. That
I I I
thought he was going around being an
idiot. No,
>> I'm trying not to think judgmentally,
but
>> trying not to think critically. Yes.
>> I can't control.
>> Well, you you just stay in acceptance.
You move from acceptance to acceptance
to acceptance
and everybody is the way they are. So
you don't have to change your opinion
about anybody if you stay in acceptance.
Some people are loud and noisy. Some
people are quiet and mousy. Some people
are forgetful. Some people are getting
old and falling over.
I got so old I forgot that I was old.
I thought I was just getting
The ultimate solution to all of it is
love. By being loving towards all
creatures,
large and small, all creatures be to be
loving towards all that exists solves
the whole problem. To be loving, because
once you're loving, that guides you in
what you do and say and think.
Be loving towards all creatures at all
times and that will take care of it for
you and you don't have to worry anymore.
All right.
Yes, I will do.
>> What did he say?
>> Yes, he said thank you.
>> Yes.
>> Well,
>> now she has a question.
>> Oh,
>> speak.
>> Yeah.
I have been meditating almost every
morning and evening for about seven
years. Recently, my meditation state is
not so good because of distracting
thoughts.
I can't enter the silent and deep state
beyond thinkingness. Sometimes I have
been in silent state unexpectedly
and unintentionally
but instantly distracting thoughts break
into that state.
Sorry.
>> In in one sentence in one sentence,
>> she's having trouble getting into a very
deep meditated state. You know, she's
been meditating a number of years and
Yes. And so all of a sudden she has all
Maybe it's because you you have a lot
more pressure.
>> Yeah. And so, you know, you think, "Oh,
I should be doing the dishes. I should
be doing this instead of sitting here
meditating."
>> In order to meditate, you know, you need
to know how to compartmentalize your
world, your life. Compartmentalize.
>> When you're going to the bathroom,
you're in one state of consciousness.
When you're playing in the backyard with
the dog, that's another one. When you're
meditating, that's a totally different
one.
You have to compartmentalize your life
into areas where you're automatically
uh attuned to what's in that department
in your life. When you run into the
bathroom, you're not worrying about
these things, are you?
>> Oh, I try to.
>> So, you learn how to compartmentalize
your life.
Don't expect to be cheerful and happy
and skipping around
and also in a meditative state. Don't
you see the two don't blend?
>> Is that simple?
>> No, not simple.
>> Yes.
>> Well, she still a little confused.
>> What you confused about? I just
explained it to you. Don't ask me a
question and then tell me you don't
understand.
>> When mentally
mentally when you go into meditate. What
you need to do is block out all the
outside world.
>> Oh yeah.
>> Just block it out
>> and say this is my 20 minutes or 15
minutes for just myself and try and
block out everything and only
concentrate on your inner spiritual
being at that point for that length of
time.
>> Turn off the television set.
>> Oh yes.
>> It goes on in your mind.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. And but if you do that then
eventually you will get back into that
very deep meditative state.
>> I don't understand.
>> Yeah. Um if you can turn off that TV,
you know, while you're meditating,
you'll go into that deep state like
where you want to be.
>> It's difficult.
>> Yeah, it's hard. Yeah,
>> it's not hard.
>> I think it's hard.
>> Oh, okay.
>> Cuz sometimes you just can't get to that
spot.
>> I think it's easy because I go I go
there all the time and I have to pull
myself back to watch television.
On television, they only have one story.
They play it round the clock, week after
week after week.
Some killer lady right now, isn't he?
>> Casey Anthony.
>> Yeah. That plays 20 24/7, week after
week after week. Same story.
Uh what else do you want to know?
>> Uh please help me progress in my
meditation. Yeah, just she about the
meditation was what she wanted to know.
>> Oh, thank you sweetheart.
Goodbye.
>> Goodbye.
They want a
>> They want what?
>> They want a picture.
>> A picture.
>> They're not sensitive to social cues.
You got to perfectly throw them off the
stage for them to get to their time is
over.
God bless you, sweetheart.
>> They have to they have to, you know,
translate all this. They
>> Yeah. Oh, yeah. I'm sorry about that,
honey. You I'm glad you reminded me of
that.
>> Um myself, sorry.
>> Yes. Uh myself and some other students
of your work have started reading the
great books of the western world and
we're doing the 10-year reading plan.
>> Oh.
>> This month is Adam Smith.
>> Smith.
>> The following month is Karl Marx.
>> Oh yeah. And in power versus force, you
have a quote which I typed out in size
30 font.
>> What this is? This is the I'm going to
read what that states.
>> Read what this says.
>> If Doc wants to read it and can't hear
me. Um, the extreme negativity of many
popular works of pseudo philosophy, for
example, is obvious if one tests these
books. But even being forewarned cannot
defend us against unwitting entrainment
by negative energy fields which activate
when these works are read. One may think
he can maintain his psychic independence
by refuting the work intellectually. But
mere exposure to the material has
profound negative effects that continues
even after the material is
intellectually rejected.
>> Like what material?
>> This is what
>> Karl Marx.
>> Like Karl Mars because you're going to
be
>> Oh, I see what you're saying. Okay. Um,
it is as though uh there is within these
negative influences a hidden virus whose
invasion of our psyche goes unnoticed.
Do you suggest we skip Karl Marx this
month?
>> What?
>> He wants to know if you suggest that
they skip over Karl Marx in the books of
the great Western world.
>> No, you should know what the world
believes and you can see why the world
believes what it believes.
Karl Marx had a big impact on the
uh
on the political philosophy of the world
all of Russia for instance
that's sort of part right
>> okay great thank you
>> no you should read them all
>> and if you end up a Marxist well
you can Both to Russia.
>> What? Honey,
>> I got it
>> here. I'll take it.
>> I'll put it on my mic so you can grab
it.
>> No, I need this here to defend myself
against Marxists.
>> Yes. Go ahead.
I wanted to start by saying thank you
for staying around so long, for being
here.
>> It's not up to me, you know.
>> I know.
>> It's God's idea, mine.
>> Yeah. Go ahead, honey.
>> Yes. I was um just thought by just being
up here in your presence that I could
better come to know how to view all
peoples and all creation.
>> I cannot hear what she's saying.
>> And if it's in God's will, I would also
like to have your blessing.
>> What is she saying? I can't hear her.
>> She would like you to give her a
blessing. She said that um coming up
here she thought that she had a better
understanding of the world around her
and the spiritual aspects of it.
>> Oh.
>> So she could you uh give her a blessing?
>> Oh yes.
Uh I bless you in the name of the Lord
and I thank you for your presence and
your contribution to the to this meeting
for coming up here that takes courage.
Thank you.
>> Thank you. Takes courage to come up on
stage.
Yes.
I'm scared to death every time I come
up.
>> Is that a bag of goodies for me?
>> No.
>> I was hoping for fresh shrimp. Oh well.
Just chocolate.
>> It's chocolate.
>> Oh, just kidding.
>> All right.
>> Um, thank you guys for being my
teachers. And um, I have a question
about an energy
in my navl, which I would uh consider to
be emotional insecurity and uh,
emotional overwhelm that I experience as
emotional overwhelm. And I have for
maybe 20 years of my life. And uh
>> is it about everything or what?
Selective.
>> Um
>> does it happen once a day, twice a day,
all day? What
>> it comes?
It can be an exterior event or an
interior event and then it's like I go
from high functioning to like um
emotional overwhelm where uh um I don't
>> How often does this happen? I'm trying
to get an answer out here. Every day or
all day? Um
>> it when it comes in waves sometimes it
lasts several weeks. I've had one
>> several weeks.
>> Several weeks like crying.
>> Is he saying several weeks?
>> Weeks.
>> Weeks like crying. crying every day. Um,
>> oh,
>> and I so I I assume that's a stack
>> and I guess
>> Yes, it is.
>> I guess I I feel stuck because I know I
if I look at the last 20 years, I go
that same experience occurs of
powerlessness, emotional insecurity.
Um, and I've I've I've done
surrendering um surrendering it to God,
asking for more.
And I
>> Uhhuh.
>> I still feel like like I'm stuck. And I
guess I'm wondering if there's a deeper
subconscious
um guilt or sometimes I feel when the
state comes on like it pulls negative
energy like it's both from within and
and about me like
um
uh
it's
so what my question is if is I'm having
trouble discerning is this a deeper
subconscious guilt. Um, is it simply
an an emotional attachment like it's the
center of my emotional body that I I'm
unwilling I get attached to people,
places, and things and then can't
release them. I guess I'm looking for
like the critical point because you
speak often of critical points that will
this is due to his attachments.
Yes,
due to your attachments to everything.
This is a very nice cane. It was
handmade as a personal present.
And if I lost it, I would feel a sense
of loss. Yeah.
but it's not the end of my life. So
that's the way you have to be with your
thoughts and your feelings
that you value them for what what they
serve at the moment and then your
willingness to let them go that they
have served their purpose.
There's a time to be very pious and
withdraw to the woods and pray on your
knees for weeks until they get raggedy.
But then that time goes. So
when when a when the purpose of a period
of your life has been served then walk
away from it with gratitude. I thank
thee oh Lord for what was learned in
that state of consciousness and now I
must move on. Yeah. You still have to
earn a living. You still have to
survive in the world in the worldly
world.
You don't have to worry about heaven for
a while.
You got a ways to go.
>> Thank you.
>> But you're in a good space. You're in a
good space.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah. Don't worry about it.
>> Can I get a picture?
>> Yeah. Life is transitional.
Well,
all right. Good God almighty. What's
going on? Oh my Jesus. Oh my god.
Cut it out.
No cuddling.
This is my cuddle bunny here. Everybody
else, keep your hand off
or or she'll kill you.
>> Hello.
>> Hi. Thank you, Doc, for all your
teachings. I'm I'm very grateful for all
the years that I've been with you. in uh
2004 December I read your book for the
first time power versus force
and um when I read your book I had a
experience of a condalini awakening from
my spine to my head the energy just went
up and I also saw a vision of a monk uh
a Buddhist monk I was wondering if that
experience was myself going over 200 at
that point
>> I don't get the question
>> um he had a an experience after reading
power versus force of the of the condi
energy his spine.
>> Yeah.
>> And he said he had a vision of a monk.
>> A monk. Yes.
>> Yes. Could that be um when he went over
200? Was that what was it was or was it
a past life or what was that?
>> A vision. Where did this vision of a
monk come from?
>> Yeah.
>> Right. Just just just as I had the
awakening the the the experience right
then I saw a monk standing uh
>> oh yes
>> yeah it's because it's part of that
whole energy field and all the
associations that go with it you could
have seen church bells too
>> right
>> you know what I mean
what whatever holiness means to a person
so a person has a whole energy field
called holiness
and includes all kinds of symbols
experiences, places, historic events
and uh
becomes quite sizable in mankind.
So you can summon up portions of it.
>> Mhm.
>> And recently uh while meditating I um
came up with this field of white noise.
Should I stay in that field of a white
noise? Is that like
>> of what
>> white noise? It's kind of like, you
know, like static. It blocks everything
else out.
>> I don't know what what noises.
>> Okay.
>> Does it
>> while while meditating?
>> By meditating, but does it keep you in
that meditative state?
>> Yes. Yes. It actually takes me away from
my mind to the white noise so I can
focus on that white noise. So, is that a
good thing? Should I continue?
>> I would say so if it works for you.
>> Yeah. If it works.
>> Yeah. Whatever works. You got to be
pragmatic in spiritual events as well as
worldly events.
>> This man did a great um
what little documentary on Doc and put
it up on YouTube.
>> That was a devotional video.
>> Yeah, a devotional video. And put it up
on what? YouTube. Yeah. Yeah. So, he
sent it to us and it's very nice. So, if
you get a chance to go and look it up,
do
>> look it up where?
>> On online. It's on YouTube.
>> I never heard of YouTube. What is that?
It's a It's a site online that they can
post something.
>> What does online mean?
>> I'm of a different generation.
Online meant on the clothes line.
>> My mother would say, "Hang these online.
That's true.
Hang me online. She say
your white pajamas swinging in the wind.
>> Yes. Okay.
>> That'll never mean the same to me.
>> May I have your blessing, please?
>> Yes. He'd like your blessing, please.
>> God bless you with God's love. Amen.
>> Thank you.
God's love. Amen.
>> Yeah.
>> He wants to touch your feet.
>> Oh,
come on.
>> That's a message from you know who.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you, madam.
Hello. Have I seen you here before?
>> A couple times. Yeah.
>> Yes. They look familiar.
>> Thank Thank you. I'm a little out of
breath. I ran here. Um, hi. My name is
Jonathan.
It's an honor to meet you, sir.
>> What?
>> What is he saying?
>> Oh, can you hear me? Okay. Okay. Um,
>> yeah, this is a little different.
>> Okay. I just wanted to thank you both
from the bottom of my heart. You know,
your work has changed my life.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah. And I was wondering if we could
say the Lord's Prayer together.
>> You wanted to say the Lord's Prayer
together,
>> please.
Well, if you know how it goes, lead it.
>> Okay.
Lead it.
>> Our Father,
>> yes.
>> Who art in heaven. Hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done on
earth as it is in heaven. Give us this
day our daily bread. and forgive us our
trespasses as we forgive those who
trespass against us. And lead us not
into temptation, but deliver us from
evil. For thine is the kingdom and the
power and the glory forever and ever.
Amen.
>> Thank you. Thank you, David. Thank you,
Susan.
Love is transformative.
We try to at all times,
you know, move into a field of
compassion and love for all that exists.
Compassion and love for all that exists.
We see this lion kill the baby rabbit
and the mind says, "Oh, bad lion. Bad
lion."
But the lion has to eat.
And
if lions didn't eat rabbits, there
wouldn't be any rabbits
because rabbits come here so lions have
something to eat.
People are born in order to pay taxes,
right?
>> The government's against birth control,
>> Go ahead. What's on your mind?
>> I want to thank you for your work. It's
been Your books have been very helpful
to me. Yes.
>> And I've to use your own term. I've been
in the midst of a final run and find
myself impatient
and would just ask for some word of
encouragement. It's a
>> What makes you think you're in the final
run?
>> Because I've dedicated every moment um
to that.
Oh, I see
you're serious about your spiritual
commitment.
>> Yes.
All right. So, you
you can't really lay out a period of
time and say this is when the final run
starts and this is when the final run
ends.
You know this this lifetime you're born
at a certain level of consciousness
and with karmic factors involved you may
choose to move on or you may choose to
skip it this lifetime and move on some
later time. Yeah.
So I would not be self-critical about
it.
I would just ask God to reveal to me the
purpose of the primary purpose of this
time and this lifetime.
>> Yes.
>> Very good. Thank you.
>> Hi.
>> Hello.
Um uh my question is related to an
experience I had. Um I was on a extended
meditation retreat and I had taken vows
and surrendered my life to God. And
during that retreat uh we
were to learn a special technique and
out of pride as well as uh just not
being open to
um stop getting the technique. I
received the technique before
>> understanding him. You was on a retreat
which was devoted to what?
>> To God.
>> Speak slowly please.
>> Yeah.
>> Devoted to of course I was it was
essentially a meditation retreat.
>> A meditation retreat. Okay.
>> And I to receive a special meditation
technique.
>> Oh.
>> And I received it.
I was told that if you receive it too
early that you can actually totally mess
up
um your ability to be have a continuous
experience of the silence.
So
>> wait a minute
>> I'll I'll try and paraphrase.
>> Don't run on it.
>> Yeah.
>> What he's saying uh the teaching is
false.
>> Okay. Thank you.
So I essentially I've been doing the 12
steps and there's just I've I'd released
this
um and I've spoke about it. Um so
essentially that belief is incorrect is
what you're saying.
>> Correct.
>> That's what the arm says. Don't quote
me.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Um because the essentially my
question is the belief is around the
fact that
um in that experience I had forsaken my
relationship with God in this life.
Um
>> where did you get that message from?
>> From from what happened during the
experience. It was more an internal
thing not so much from others. But
essentially since that point I've been
meditating a lot, doing spiritual work
and my experience continues to evolve.
But I have a belief that
or I believe I have a block
to experiencing the silence continually
all the time,
which is what I'd like to is to
experience the presence of God
at all times. And I have I feel that I
have a block to that.
So, I just wondered if you have any
advice for that.
>> You want to experience the presence of
God at all times, correct?
>> Yes.
>> Uh-huh.
Well, why don't you just do that?
>> That is a good question.
Pay no attention to the passing street
cars and the passing women
and people dangling money in front of
your nose for one thing or another.
Keep in mind that God it prevails at all
times and in all places and in all
situations.
The presence of God is continuous.
It's like the weather. You can stop now
and notice the sunshine is sh sh sh sh
sh sh sh sh sh sh sh sh sh sh sh sh sh
sh sh sh sh sh sh sh sh sh sh shining or
not not notice it.
But whether you notice it or not doesn't
affect the fact that the sun is shining.
You understand? It's just a matter of
what you want to focus on, what you want
to look at.
I can look at the quietude in this room
or I can look at the sun coming in the
windows. Yes.
So that's not God coming up and then
disappearing again.
You're just noticing what you notice.
So you accept life as you experience it
unfolding.
Right at this moment you are here
talking to me and within a few seconds
you'll be out in the room going that
way. And uh that's the way it's supposed
to be. continuous change and movement
etc.
And uh you tell yourself that's normal.
That's what's desirable. If God wanted
it to be different, it would be okay.
If God wanted it to be different, it
would be
simple enough.
>> Thank you.
>> Could I shake your hand and get a
picture?
Thank you.
>> Yeah. Thank you.
If God wanted things to be different,
they would be.
We came here to become enlightened.
We're enlightened, we wouldn't be here.
So, we don't have to feel ashamed that
we're not enlightened.
We come here to become so to move us
along the pathway.
>> Hi. Yes.
>> Will you own for us?
>> What?
>> That'll be a dollar.
>> You want a big M or a little M?
>> Big one. Let's do a big
>> Oh, a big M. Oh, golly Wizard.
Wow.
That was good.
>> May I also shake your hand and yours
too?
>> What?
>> She wants to touch your hand.
Please.
>> Yes.
>> The last time I was up here, I was a
little too nervous to look into the
doc's eyes. I was wondering if I could
look into his eyes.
I can't hear what he's saying. What is
he saying?
>> Just look at him.
>> Right. Thank you very much.
>> The eyes have the window to the soul.
>> Oh.
Dr. Hawkins.
>> Yes.
>> I came here to offer my prostrations and
receive your blessings. Please allow me
to do that.
>> He wants to
>> He's a monk.
>> Yes.
>> From where?
>> I don't know.
>> From India.
>> Oh. Oh. Oh.
Better call when they're from India.
Yeah.
God bless you.
It's harder to be a monk in the world
than out of the world.
Yes.
>> First, I would like to thank you for all
your teachings.
I have a question about uh the
connection between selfless service and
uh the inner work
>> they're both the same.
So then the question is when I see
something happens in the world and I
there's a response coming from inside my
mind do I have to recontextualize
and or recontextualize and do something
about it
>> when he sees something happening in the
world does he have to recontextualize it
or and induce act on it or Oh, it
depends on where he is in the evolution
of his spirit. Uh, I think it's God's
problem. See, you may figure you got to
help the street car get back on the
track. And I figure it's God's problem.
>> So, where is the selfless service? Uh,
where does the service come into
picture? If I
>> contextually contextualize it as a God's
problem,
>> where do I act?
>> When you give Yeah. selfless service and
inner work and you said it's one and the
same. So when does he
>> do the selfless service
>> uh
and um
>> be of service to the world at all times.
There isn't any separation of the two.
>> If I don't see a problem where where do
I serve?
>> If Yeah. So he's looking for a problem
to solve so he can't search. So
>> no that's that's defective
that's
>> looking for problems is not the way to
find out anything about anything.
>> So Southwest service should be done with
without a heavy heart. It should be done
with an open heart.
>> Yes. Mhm.
And uh it's artificial to like look for
a problem.
I mean what do you think is a problem is
in your head?
There aren't any problems in the world.
>> So we just sit and meditate or
>> what?
>> Well, you know, in ashrams there's
always things that need to be done.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, so that's selfless service.
But
>> oh
>> but so that's what he's saying is he
says do you just sit and meditate and
just ask or is there when do you uh
respond?
>> So he has a conflict between
uh striving for enlightenment
>> right
>> and service to the world. That's an
artificial dichotomy. There is no
difference between the two. You know,
you can be sweeping the street and uh or
sitting cross-legged and meditating.
They're both the same.
Sweeping the street is the same.
>> So, in other words, he can be service
whether he's sweeping the street or
whether he's meditating, he's still
service to the world.
>> Well, he's defining service in what he
calls service,
>> right?
>> So then he it's just the definition he
makes up. If he thinks this is a service
to the world, then that's service to the
world.
But if I say it's irrelevant to the
world, then it's not service anymore.
Right?
So service to the world is whatever you
define as service to the world. Keeping
out of the way and staying silent is the
best way.
>> One more question. Uh I when I witness
the thoughts
>> what
>> when he witnesses the thoughts.
>> Yes.
>> How do I take the next step from
witnessing to the next deeper
state?
>> What is the next deeper state?
>> You're in a deeper state. Witnessing is
what's happening all the time.
The mind is doing witnessing all the
time. It doesn't need you to tell it to
go ahead and witness.
The lights go on. You notice that the
lights go on. You didn't say to your
mind, "Mind, please watch and notice
whether the lights go on." It's
happening spontaneously. So you don't
have to
um
do anything about it because that's what
the mind is is doing automatically
because of its quality.
So just let the mind do what it does. It
just notices
things spontaneously
and autonomously.
So we allow the mind to just be
autonomously that which it is already
and it doesn't need your help to be told
what to do.
You don't have to tell your mind notice
everything going on around here. That's
what it's doing.
>> Yeah.
>> And and that's the step. Is there
anything else needs to be done or it's
>> No, you keep pushing for something to
do. Let go of D do D do D do D do D do D
do D do D do D do D do D O
say just B
okay
>> I would seek uh blessings from you on my
spiritual journey.
>> God bless you on your spiritual journey.
Amen.
Call the police.
God bless you.
Yeah. Uh-huh.
I'm going to have something in my mind.
Give me your arm.
Resist. Thank you.
>> Hi,
>> Dr. Hawkins. Yes,
>> I'm from India.
>> She's from India.
>> Yes.
>> I've been in this country for last about
30 years. And yesterday was a very
significant day in our lives which is
called Guru Purima that's called in
India.
>> Terrible time here.
>> Guru is master Purima is yesterday was a
full
>> full moon day where we have tribute to
Guru Parara. I I'm just here to seek
your blessings since this was only
yesterday. And I love you, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Yes.
>> God bless you, sweetheart.
God bless India.
How many times have we lived in India
already? I hate to think of it.
Rotate through India.
India is like spiritual headquarters.
>> We've all probably lived 20 30 lives in
India.
>> Yeah.
>> He said he was afraid to go back to
India because he because he's
>> he said the same thing when I was here
last time.
>> That's right. Because Shiva he's going
to kiss Shiva or something.
>> Thank you.
>> It's a great country.
>> I love you. I love you. God bless you.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Um uh 11:30.
>> I wanted to say thanks for the work. Um
on step 11, are there any techniques we
can do to help us discern
uh God's will versus the ego's will?
Well, the ego is always looking for gain
and uh God looks to isness.
The ego is always looking for what it
can get
and that helps differentiate.
So
spiritual states are a way of being and
uh they're not concerned with getting.
What is the 11th step again?
uh sought through prayer and meditation
improve our conscious contact with God,
praying for the knowledge of his will
and the power to carry that out.
>> That's right.
>> That's easy enough.
>> Dear God, we pray for the conscious
awareness and knowledge of your will for
us and then the the capacity
to fulfill that. That's simple and
self-explanatory.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Namaste, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Namaste.
>> I love you.
>> Uhoh. I'm in trouble.
Oh, help.
called the police.
>> Yes.
>> When I finally met you, there was
annoyingness that came about
that my search is complete.
>> Yes.
>> Then why would you recommend we do
course of miracle Gita?
You know,
>> did I recommend it for you?
>> For her?
>> Mhm. last time.
>> Oh,
>> another Q&A.
>> Oh, well, what was the question?
>> Well, the question is, if your
teachings, which I feel
are the ultimate
and I feel so complete,
having found your teachings.
>> Yeah.
>> Then why
do I need to study anybody else?
>> You don't.
>> Then why do you recommend course of
miracle? Oh, Ramana or Gita.
>> Well, there's alternate ways to go. You
know, I'm not the only source of truth
in the history of this universe.
>> I I feel that you are
>> no because various spiritual pathways
are appropriate for different times in
our spiritual evolution.
There's a period of searching and
becoming familiar with the field and
trying to find what fits for you and um
each one adds another layer of
comprehension and depth of
understanding.
So there are things that are unique to a
course of miracles. There's things that
are unique to Christianity. There's
things that are unique to Judaism.
uh each of them have a contribution to
make because the totality of spiritual
knowledge and understanding is pretty
voluminous is it not
otherwise you would think you the
Vatican's library is useless you
no man has been studying this subject
and meditating on it and
uh fasting and sacrificing and doing all
kinds of things to increase his
conscious awareness ness of the presence
of God.
And I suppose when we reach a certain
degree of understanding, we don't
reincarnate.
That's true.
>> Thank you.
>> That's the bodhic sata.
>> Yes.
God bless you. God bless you,
sweetheart.
Hello.
>> Hi. Thank you for your teachings, Dr.
Hawkins, and I love you very much.
Uh my question is
uh
in case of when we are getting older and
in case of illnesses,
we have many
um uh medications on the market. But
also uh going back where you say on your
books that we one could do
many things uh it from home remedies or
anything to get us well.
But my question is there is some
medications that uh do more harm than
than good. Uh there is um osteoporosis
medications
that uh have many side effects
and my question is what's your advice on
that particular subject to take it or
not to take it?
>> What did she saying? Um she said there's
several for her there is osteoporosis
medication and she was wondering what
your advice would be to her for it which
is you know everything's mental,
spiritual and physical.
>> I don't get the question. She has
osteoporosis.
>> Yes.
>> And they have medications that they're
asking her to take which
>> medications. Yes.
>> That have side effects. Like what does
she mean by a side effect?
>> Bleeding um uh bone uh pain uh muscle
pain swollen
tongue.
>> You have osteoporosis?
>> Yes.
Do you have a calcium deficiency?
>> Uh yes, I think so.
>> Huh?
>> Yes, she does.
So if you take calcium that cures it,
right?
>> My question is uh to if you should you
could take if you should take the
medications where where they said the
medication is good. It reverses the
osteoporosis but they the the side
effects do a lot of harm.
>> What's the question?
>> And what's his advice? question is
>> should she take medication for um
osteoporosis or not
>> because medication
>> she has osteoporosis and she they are
suggesting that she takes this
medication that has a lot of side
effects and she's afraid of the side
effects of it.
>> Okay. Oh, stop there. Stop there. Okay.
>> Okay. It's safe for you to take that.
All right.
>> So, it's safe for you to take the
medication.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay.
>> Could I shake your hand? Yes. Dr.
Hatkins.
>> Thank you.
>> He's joking around.
>> Osteoporosis.
>> We'll take one more question and then
we'll take a break.
>> Osteoporosis.
Sounds impressive. Osteoporosis
holes in the bones.
>> Oh, there's two with one. Uh oh. All
right. You got uh
>> Oh.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Big trouble.
>> Big five.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> Actually, she has a one question about
her dream.
>> Her dream.
>> Yes.
>> What? What?
>> She had a dream. She ask a question
about her dream.
>> Oh, dream.
>> Yeah. Actually I mean 17 years ago she
has a kind of four years treatment about
psychosocial I mean psychoanalysis
treatment for psychoanalysis
>> psychoanalysis sorry
>> yeah psychoanalysis treatment for her
psychological problem
>> and then she learned that kind of
procedure as well and then several years
later she has another kind of big big
kind of event for her life and then she
suffer that kind of experience And then
later on and then she learned about Dr.
Hopkins and then his book and then he
learned a lot and then later on in her
dream physical dream he show up and
kind of try to resolve some issue and
then one of them and then after that she
tried to meet him but she can't because
there's a several issue in South Korea
and then she cannot get a visa to come
USA
>> and then later on suddenly he coming out
coming in in her dream again and then
ask
her to meet that radish namashi
>> namashi
>> in India
>> and then so she go there I mean it was
very hard but she got some I mean
resolution for her psychological problem
but she still had some problem and then
probably in this recently in her dream
she saw for some kind of two huge big
gold rock
>> rocks.
>> Yeah, rocks. It it is rocks. L rocks.
So, and then she want to find some keys.
I mean she based on her experience for
the psychoanalysis treatment, she
thought that kind of some big big huddle
to recover from her psychological
disorder. It's like depression. She has
some depression and then she cannot
sleep at all in the night and then
anxiety disorder. So I mean she has a
lot of the psychological disorder and
then she want to have some kind of
solution or what and then she want to
find some key. I mean that kind of in
dream she think the big two gold rock
mean some kind of huddle and then she
want to find some keys and that
>> she thinks that the these two rocks she
saw in her dream were a hurdle that she
needs to go over. Yeah.
>> Well it could represent other things
too.
>> Yeah. But that's why she wondering I
mean that's why she get some other
advice or any comment. the question.
>> Okay. Um she has she's been going to uh
psychoanalyst about
>> um depression and um certain uh issues.
Yes.
>> Anyway, in a in a dream you came to her.
>> Yes.
>> And it was very difficult for her to
come and see you because she had to get
a visa and different things.
>> Oh, I see.
>> Okay. So, anyway, um she's been having
these dreams and you are in them.
>> Yes. and she wants to know um she saw
these two big gold rocks that and she
doesn't know if that's a hurdle that she
has to overcome or whether that
represents something.
>> Two rocks. Yes, there's two rocks in the
stream.
>> And she wants to know if this is a
hurdle to overcome or is this a
representation of, you know, the problem
she has with um
>> Okay.
>> Right.
>> The rocks are representative
of the hurdles that she has to overcome.
>> No.
>> Could it be um
It could be the rocks represent truth.
>> There's some truth she has to understand
and those will relieve her. Yes.
>> Yeah.
There's some kind of truth she has to
understand.
>> Yeah.
>> Whether it's um
>> it's a spiritual truth.
>> Oh,
>> spiritual truth. Yeah.
>> Oh, okay. It's a spiritual truth that
those represent that she needs to
understand.
Yeah,
>> it is not the huddle.
>> It's not the
>> No. Okay.
>> So, it's a So, they represent that she
needs to uh there's some kind of block
or
large like moving mountains kind of, but
it's a large it represents a large
barrier that she has to understand about
spirituality.
Thank you.
>> So maybe I mean I kind maybe maybe I'm
not sure about I kind of I mean
pronounced it the cor I mean correctly.
What I'm saying is L is L O C K R O C K.
Is that
rough?
>> Yeah. Rough.
>> What?
What's the question?
>> Rock.
>> Yeah.
>> R O C.
>> No, no, not the R. Abra
or
>> Okay, let me let me write it down for
you. I'm sorry.
>> Oh, lock.
>> Yeah, I know.
>> It's my fault. Sorry.
>> Okay,
>> that was funny.
>> There's these two large locks.
Not rock.
>> Maybe a walk.
>> How about a squawk? A dock, a pock.
>> You mispronounced it. Anyway, there's
two locks. So, anyway, it would still
apply. I mean, either way.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> What we got would probably even though I
misunderstood it.
>> Yeah. No, it's correct. Yes. Okay.
>> So, it's still, you know, could be still
that it's would still apply that it was
the spiritual
truth that she needs to.
>> Yes.
Okay. What's What? Come on.
I'm sorry. I think I explained him
the question, but I think he
>> mis understood my question.
>> Okay. So, what she wondering is in her
dream. I mean he I mean he Dr. Dawkins
was there and then talk to her. I mean
he may be able to kind of the treat her
very well and then she can recover the
kind of the psychological disorder.
So and then after that dream and then
she saw that that block or rock whatever
it is. I mean we he she saw that and
then she believe I mean he may some
answer how can kind of overcome or some
she thought is still kind of harder but
you said it's not a hot it's kind of
spirituality truth
>> okay yeah it's a sub type of spiritual
truth that she needs to come to an
understanding about
>> just come to understand that
>> yes
okay
Okay. Okay. Thank you.
>> Okay. Um if you can always email us if
you have
>> Okay.
You don't feel satisfied with so
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
>> Give you a better explanation.
>> Okay. That sounds
>> Yeah. You know. Yeah.
>> Okay. Great. Thank you very much.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay. We're going to take a quick break
and we will meet back here in about 10
minutes.
>> Thank you, honey.
Okay, let's get down to business here.
Enough frivvality.
What's happening next?
>> Hello.
>> Um, doc, you've pretty much answered
every question I've ever had. Um, so I
don't have any questions to ask. Um, but
I've I've experienced um the power of
group healings and um I was just
wondering, you've done so much for us.
if we could just take a minute to
collectively
send you our love.
>> Oh wow. I don't know if I can handle
that or not.
Thank you. That would be a great gift.
And I need to turn that spotlight off
over there.
>> Yeah. Feel that stuff.
>> So, if we could all just close our eyes
for a minute and direct our love to Doc.
Thank you.
I thank God for the gift.
>> Oh boy, they cut that spot. Okay,
>> it's too dark.
>> All right, I'm afraid they're going to
have to have it on.
>> I can't I can't see you.
>> He can't He can't film you unless the
spot's on.
>> Oh, okay. So, we'll be uh blinded. It
doesn't work. I don't have to see
anything.
>> Hello.
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins philosis. My question
is um I feel in this point in my life
it's time for me to start
focusing on taking direction and
guidance from within and I would like
any advice or direction that you would
have in doing that.
>> Well, you pray uh you pray and then uh
what comes up you have to assume that's
somehow related to your prayer.
fuel prayer and then they ignore it and
they go pray some more and then they
pray some more.
They to go to the cathedral 32 times the
first time they got the answer. I don't
know. I guess they like the trip.
Be kind and loving towards all all all
of life and all of creation. Be kind and
loving towards all of creation. You
don't need anything more after that.
That's submission.
You don't have to buy wampom.
I love that word wampom.
>> Thank you. I have another question also.
Uh I would like to find out if this is
who I was in my last life.
>> He wants to know what
>> if a person on this book was who he was
in a past life.
>> Well, we have permission to ask that.
The answer is no.
Oh,
>> that saves you all kinds of guilt.
>> Yes.
>> Okay,
thank you very much.
>> Yes.
>> Hello. Hello, Sen. Hello, Doc. Um, I
would like to hold in mind a family
member and to be calibrated if that's
possible.
>> No, I don't want to do that.
>> No.
>> Okay.
May I have a handshake?
>> Huh?
>> What's handshake?
>> Yep.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you.
>> Probably had his mother-in-law in mind.
>> Pretty close. Pretty close.
Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
>> What a pleasure to be here with you.
Yeah,
>> you'd say that you've been such an
incredible inspiration to me and and I'm
a 12steper
and your work has meant so much to me.
>> Good
>> in that in that venue. My question is
about Robert Monroe's last work.
>> I believe it's called
>> who?
>> Robert Monroe and his last work it's
called the ultimate journey.
>> I don't recall it.
>> Uh the out of body experiences
Robert Monroe.
>> I don't recall it.
>> No, he doesn't. Is it a new book?
>> No, it's it's his last book.
>> I don't recall it.
>> Well, okay. Well, in it he he talks
about
the physical universe and he also talks
about the non-physical universe.
>> Yeah. And he says it that in the
physical universe in their explorations
of the physical universe they've run
into no intelligent alien species.
Whereas in the non-physical universe
>> I can't answer your question.
>> You can't answer my question.
>> I don't really understand either what
you're asking. What are you asking?
>> This is about the uh
>> Robert Monroe wrote a book. What was the
name of the book?
>> He wrote uh
>> Journeys Out of the Body. Journeys out
of body. You wrote three.
>> Yeah.
>> And I'm do the third book.
>> What What do you mean by three?
>> Three books.
>> I only know Journeys Out of the Body.
>> The last one is called Ultimate Journey.
>> Well, he doesn't know that.
>> Okay. Well, in it, he talks about
intelligent species that are within the
non-physical universe and their
significance
in in terms of your own or my own I
would suppose uh pursuit of of those
kinds of things.
>> You don't need to know the answer to
that one.
>> Don't need to know the answer to that.
>> Okay.
>> Well, thank you so much.
>> Yes.
>> My answer to him was correct. Resist.
Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> You don't have to know everything that
was written since the beginning of time.
You know,
I used to know everything that was ever
written since the beginning of time.
Then I gave it up as a as a hopeless
addiction.
I was a very I learned speed reading as
a kid. I always read a book a day. I
read 400 books a year
for decades. 400 books a year for
decades. So for one decade that's 4,000
books. For two decades that's 8,000
books.
And I sneaked in a couple thousand on
the side for amusement.
So my intellect has been
uh fortified by the intellectual content
of 10,000 books.
resist
time trying to quit reading.
>> Um, I'd like to thank you both for your
dedication to the work. Um, it's touched
all of our lives significantly and I
would like a blessing and hold your hand
>> if possible.
>> Cold wet hands.
>> Yeah.
>> Boy oh boy, you have cold wet hands. You
better hold him in a tub of warm water.
>> Thank you.
>> Try friction.
>> Friction. Yes. There you go.
>> Friction. Keep going. Oh, don't go away.
Let's go.
Let's go. Let's go. Okay. Now, let's
feel him. Okay. Let's feel them. That's
better. Thank you.
>> Still chilly, but
okay, honey. Thank you very much.
Yeah.
>> Um he's from Korea and there are people
in the Hawkins study group that were not
able to come today and they're asking
you to send them a special blessing.
>> I will do so right now.
>> Dear God. Amen. I hold this mine. I send
a special blessing these thy children
and my brothers. Amen. Yes.
>> Thank you. We thought we'd be going back
to Korea when they got supersonic jets,
but they never developed the supersonic
jets.
>> Hi.
>> Hi, Susan. Hi, doctor.
>> Yes.
My my question is how how does one get
over approval seeking?
>> How does one get over what?
>> Approval seeking. Seeking the approvals
of others.
>> Oh. Oh. Oh. Oh.
>> Is that a type of ego thing or
>> Oh, it sure is ego. Yeah. It's nothing
but ego.
>> Well,
love is the answer to just about
everything.
And uh
you don't need other people's approval
when you love yourself and when you love
everything and everyone around you
because love is its own reality.
Whether people love me while I give this
uh talk here in front of the group is
irrelevant.
uh my service is to God and uh
I serve God by serving my fellow man and
all that lives and therefore I don't
step on the bug on the sidewalk because
it has life and I respect life and life
to me is is the expression of divinity.
So I don't want to step on God. That's
why I walk around the bug
out of devotion to God and
realizing that love is God that that
solves all problems.
>> And if you're less than perfect, uh uh
it's not permissible to beat up on
yourself. That is not permissible.
No beating on yourself for not being
perfect.
Uhhuh.
To not be perfect is perfect. If you
were perfect, you wouldn't be a human
being. You'd stay in heaven. Wouldn't
have made a trip here.
So I say, "Thank you, God, for whatever
lessons have been learned. No matter
what happens, everything is a gift from
God." Everything is a gift from God.
Thank you, Lord. Amen. Get lost. Bye.
Thank you.
>> That was a good question. Thank you very
much.
That was a good question.
Something I haven't made clear
apparently the lectures.
Everything that exists is God.
Nothing can exist except God.
Existence is solely the realm of
divinity.
Okay.
So, I don't really have a question
today. Um, I'm just here to
um ask your ask your blessing and
um guidance on the path.
>> What?
>> He wants to ask your blessing.
>> God bless you.
>> And guidance on his path.
>> And what?
>> And guidance on the path.
>> I can't give him guidance on the path.
I'd have to be your spiritual counselor.
I don't know where the hell you are.
>> I believe I believe you are my spiritual
counselor though.
>> Are you in chapter one? No, he's here.
If if you're here at a le one of these
lectures, that's pretty advanced already
because our lectures don't appeal to the
uh the average person in the world. I
don't think
that's true. They're too arerodiodite,
you might say. And they wouldn't
understand them.
>> Well, it's a total joy and
just unspeakable love to be here.
>> What?
>> It's a total joy, he said.
>> Oh, good for you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Yes. Thank indeed. Indeed.
Hi.
>> Hello.
>> Hi, Doc.
Um, I want to go to grad school to be a
therapist.
And my question is, is that an
appropriate path for me?
>> Of course.
>> You chose it, didn't you?
>> Yeah.
>> What more do you want?
>> Well, is is the school that I'm choosing
in the highest good? I have that
question. If it's in a line,
>> you're going to fuss jump me now. what
she's doing is correct and the school is
fine.
>> Yeah. No, thank you for the question. I
understand what you meant.
>> Everybody wants to know, am I doing the
right thing?
>> Thank you so much.
>> Every thinking person really wonders
that. Am I doing the right thing? You
know, should I be doing something else?
Should I give up booze and women or not?
You know,
>> gave up booze and women for God. Yeah.
>> I just want to thank you, doctor, and
Susan. Uh, when I first read your book,
Power Versus Force,
my actual proof was that I actually went
out, I'm a jazz composer, and I went out
and wrote three of the best tunes that
I've ever written. So,
>> you wrote a nice tune.
>> Three,
>> three tunes.
>> Three tunes. They just came out.
>> Good.
>> Yeah. So, um, my question actually
concerns my son.
uh about a year and a half ago he came
to you and um my son's name is Brian and
he
was embarrassed about living with his
folks still at 25 or something
>> 25 and he's still living with the folks
at home right yeah right okay
>> and you told him in no uncertain terms
to get his act together and go get a job
uh for all of you who
remember this uh
and uh you know said you know pretty
cushy there huh you know
so uh but what's happened since hasn't
hasn't been so fortunate uh he uh always
had respiratory problems severe
respiratory problems then after he
talked to you he went through a year
where he was in three different
mental uh psychiatric wards for
uh diagnosis of schizophrenic.
>> Oh, I see. Huh.
>> And uh since then he's gotten out and is
doing uh his respiratory the psych um
the schizophrenic
>> mixing two problems respiratory and
schizophrenia.
>> Well, they may be connected. I don't
know.
>> They're not connected.
>> Okay. So, he's he's he's gone now from
his schizophrenia to
>> respiratory back to respiratory
problems. He and he's still not working.
He does a lot of 12step work. I'm just
wondering how I can best
>> assist him in a
recovery that's real.
>> Okay. Recovery from what?
>> Recovery.
>> Respiratory.
>> Respiratory. That's a strictly physical
problem. Correct. Medicine.
Um,
I don't know.
>> Well, he doesn't do yoga for it, does
he?
>> No.
>> So, what does he do for his respiratory
problem? Are you his father?
>> Yes, I'm his father.
>> And he lives with you?
>> Yes. And he lives with me and he still
>> You must know what does he do for his
respiratory problem? Does he take
medicine?
>> Yes, he takes uh
>> Yes.
>> And he also takes uh Well, he's taking
uh Lexapro for his mental problems.
>> I'm asked you one thing. I asked you
about his respiratory problem. Why do
you answer me about his mental problem?
>> I asked you about his lung problem.
Yeah.
>> Can you focus on that?
>> I don't know what he takes.
>> Oh, okay.
>> Okay.
>> For his mental problem, he takes an
anti-s schizophrenia drug.
>> He takes Lexapro, which is an
anti-depressant.
>> Oh, an anti-depressant. Oh, okay.
>> So, how is he doing on that?
>> He's stabilized.
>> Oh, good.
>> He has stabilized.
>> He's improved. You mean he's improved?
same
>> and he does a lot of 12step. He leaves a
lot of 12step.
>> Oh, great. Okay.
>> So, what's your question now? uh just
how can I assist him into getting you
know work get getting him into the real
world
or is it this is something I just have
to lay hands off and you know pray and
>> okay hands off resist
he'll do whatever he's going to do
spontaneously
>> yeah okay thank you very much really
>> when a rabbit needs a better hole. He
goes and gets a better hole, you know.
Run, run, run. Okay.
>> Bless you both.
>> Thank you.
>> Bless you. Bless you, doc.
>> Yeah. God bless you.
>> That's hard though.
>> Well, we all love We love rabbits.
I love rabbits. Some people shoot them
and eat them, but I love them.
>> Yes. Go ahead.
>> Well, I had this dream.
>> Hello.
>> She had She's talking.
>> No, I'm kidding.
>> I'm kidding.
>> She had this dream.
>> No, no, I'm kidding.
>> A dream.
>> Oh, no.
>> You said she was kidding. I don't know.
>> I'm having a bad day.
OKAY.
>> When you get here, let me know.
>> Bring your mind with you when you come
up here. Please.
>> I was trying to make a joke.
>> Go ahead. Go ahead.
>> I was wondering if I could get you to
>> Go ahead.
>> Will you sign this, please?
>> You can sign the picture if you would.
It's one of us. I can't got a pen or
what do you think I am
>> here?
>> You sign it, please. Please, please,
please.
>> Your signature means more than mine.
>> All right. Here's this handsome looking
man.
>> And this beautiful woman. Oh, dear. Oh,
dear.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> Handsome is as handsome does. My mother
used to say, my grandmother used to
>> pretty is is pretty.
>> Yeah. Well, handsome, too.
>> Do you happen to have any ideas about
how acupuncture works?
>> You're asking me about acupuncture?
>> Yes.
>> How does it work? Is it good?
>> How does it work? It works fine.
Human
experience and ingenuity uh is developed
over the centuries. Some parts of the
world is very advanced. I've had a lot
of things cured by acupuncture.
Acupuncture has cured uh a lot of things
of me. Right.
>> He had an ulcer, a bleeding ulcer and
>> cured that
>> when it first came to the US he had it
treated with acupuncture
>> and diverticulitis. I had it treated.
Yeah.
and other diseases. I forgot. Migraine,
headaches, all kinds of things.
>> Yeah, acupuncture. I'm a big enthusiast
about it.
>> It's not totally
uh it's dis it can be discomfort.
A little bit of discomfort when you do
acupuncture.
>> Yeah.
>> It's not like you, you know, oh, that's
nothing. It's there is if they hit the
right point, you'll know it.
>> I Yes. I studied acupuncture and I'm
familiar with it, its use and I've seen
it useful for people. I just never had
um an explanation of the mechanism of
how does it work and I wondered if you
had any ideas but
>> she's asking me how does it work?
>> Yes.
>> I don't know. I don't know how it works.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> How does the nervous system work? It's
it's the analogous to the nervous system
through the energy energy fields, energy
points, energy parameters.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Right. Okay. Thank you.
>> It works through the energy meridians is
what it works through. Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah. I've had very good experience with
acupuncture. Cured a lot of things.
>> Yes.
>> For you.
>> Who did this?
>> I did.
>> You did?
>> Yes. For you.
>> Oh, this is great. This is a a drawing.
A pencil drawing. A dot.
>> Very good.
Thank you very much.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Special.
>> Yeah, it is lovely.
>> I'm from Korea to see you. So, thank you
for everything. So, my question is like
that.
Um, she says, "May I have your blessing
for using my creative art to advance my
spiritual growth?"
>> Yes, you have my blessing to do so.
>> Amen.
>> Everything subserves our spiritual
growth when we reach a certain level.
>> I like you like
>> Yes.
Yes.
Here we go.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thank you so much.
>> That's very pretty.
>> It is.
>> I call a picture of myself pretty.
>> That's because everything looks pretty.
Hi.
>> Hi.
>> Hi, Doc. Hi, Susan.
>> Um, I'm here to clean up my side of the
street.
>> Here to what?
>> Clean up my side of the street with the
the organization and and you, Doc, and
and the spiritual community. Um, I had
some inner emails with with you and Don
and I was calling Doc by his first name
and you said that that was disrespectful
and it wasn't my intention and I'm
sorry. It was uh
>> the man it was the adolescent in you.
>> Yes.
>> I was hanging around with Randy and and
I figured if I
>> if I'm what if
>> I'm with him
>> Randy you know Randy
>> are Randy.
>> Yeah, you're Randy.
>> Oh. And so he calls you that all the
time and I figured I would be closer by
doing it.
>> Before he was
>> Yeah.
>> He knew R. He knew I mean he knew him
before he was
>> before he was what?
>> Doc.
>> Oh.
>> Oh, right. Yeah.
>> So I'm sorry.
>> Okay. Uhhuh.
>> Um,
>> it's easy to do.
>> Yeah. Go ahead.
>> I can't date.
Well, it kind of put me in a like a a
prideful than everybody else, you know,
because I could do that. And so that was
wrong.
>> He doesn't even like me calling you D.
Like, so I'm not calling you doc.
>> I draw the line.
>> What's going on?
>> And so I had a question about um
Um, he's into human design and he's kind
of teaching me that. I was wondering if
if you would calibrate that to see
>> human design.
>> I don't know what he's talking about.
>> I don't even know what human design is.
How can I calibrate something I don't
even know what it is?
>> Um,
>> I guess I can, but
>> Yeah. Well, I just I want to know if
it's good to you know
>> what
>> human design.
>> I don't know what it is.
>> I don't either.
>> It's just an abstraction. Intellectual
obstruction. There's no reality.
You don't need to know it in the first
place.
>> Okay.
>> Should I let it go?
>> Yes.
Forget you even thought of it.
>> I mean, if this occurred, I mean, it's
like it's like learning, you know, about
what crystals do or whatever. It's it's
an intellectual
uh
>> it's like 400 type.
>> Well, no.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. But I mean it's just like
something that you learn about but I
don't know that it has any power.
>> Okay.
>> It's a natural curiosity.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> Do you remember the story you tell about
the engine going down the track and
there's only one thing? There's only
what?
>> One thing you need to know about the
buttons that you get at Denver.
>> Yeah.
>> Hi Doc.
>> Hello.
>> Uh, I had my question. It's gone.
>> I had my question and it's gone. I um in
my meditation
have fallen into a deep pit of despair.
>> Stop meditating.
>> Really?
>> Yeah. Cool.
>> So, what should you do instead? Pray.
>> Yeah.
>> Meditation doesn't work for everybody.
And uh I I if it doesn't work for you,
then pray. There's many other things you
can do. You can walk the uh what is it?
>> Labyrinth.
>> You can walk the labyrinth. Okay. So, so
for him, it's better to walk the
labyrinth. Yeah.
So there's other things you can do that
are spiritual.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Uhhuh. Mhm.
>> Yeah. Many other things you can do. You
can dedicate everything you do to God.
>> Oh, so you can here. He wants to touch
my hand. Um, you can you what what did
you say you could do? You can dedicate
anything everything you do to God.
>> Yes, you can. You know, if you're
digging in the garden, you say, "Dear
God, I do this in thanks for my
humanness and my life, and I do it for
the good of the garden. I do it for the
good of the people who get fed by the
food. I do it out of love for my
surroundings.
I love our bunnies.
We got wild bunnies. I love them."
>> Wild bunnies.
>> And I love my wild bunnies. Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> My dog likes them, too.
She loves chasing him. Susan, take off
the rabbit.
>> Hi, Susan and Dr. Hawkins.
>> Um, I I talked to you last in I think 99
when you came to Seattle.
>> What does he say?
>> Yeah, we were in Seattle in 99.
>> We were what?
>> We were in Seattle, Washington in 99.
>> Remember that?
>> If you must say, if you say so.
I I would I would like to um thank God
for Dr. Hawkins and the work that's come
through him
>> and um I had a question but I think it
has been answered and can I ask
permission? Should I ask it anyway or
for the highest good of everybody?
>> Yeah.
>> Um okay. So what's been on my heart
lately is um um you know I have a deep
love for my country and I don't like the
way it's going. it seems to be uh
so I I've been doing the the um
reflection on on the work that you put
out and trying to elevate my
consciousness as as much as I can. Um,
and I and I pray for those in power um
at night and uh say the Lord's Prayer.
And I I'm just wondering if um it seems
like there's being and then as long as
I'm here, should I be doing something to
to help? And what could we do
>> to help
>> to to help?
>> He's going to help the United States of
America. Thanks a lot.
>> You're going to help it? If I can, if
it's God's will, I I would like to know
what his will is in my life. A clearer
connection and and
>> um
awareness of his will and the capacity
to carry out his will.
>> So, how are you going to help your
country?
>> I would surrender at your feet and ask
for his help in my
>> How are you going to help your country?
I asked you.
>> Well, I have I have some ideas that come
to me. Um and I feel maybe I should act
on them and and um
>> so should we say ask the question
whether or not he should act on some of
the ideas that he has.
>> Yes, of course.
>> Yes, of course. In what way do you want
to help your country? Please stop being
vague and general.
>> You want to be a good guy and help the
world. Thank you. In what way? Sweep the
walk or invent a new buzz buzz or what?
So invention and ideas um are are
something that come easy to me and I've
had an experience with some fellows u
building a robot for a contest and
>> building a robot.
>> Yes sir.
>> For what? For what?
>> Forest a NASA contest. A
>> robot for what?
>> A NASA contest. In other words, it would
you know it's a they're using robotics
now.
>> Oh, I see. Robotics. Yeah. Yeah. Okay.
And in in doing that, it was uh it was a
a great experience with my fellows uh
and camaraderie. And um I would like to
reinitiate that spirit of
entrepreneurship in in our country and
do that by leading by example and maybe
have a group of guys like that that
might have a live in a community with
like a central shop where you know
there's tools that we can use that none
of us could fine. Good idea.
>> I think that's an excellent
>> Yep. Okay.
>> I think it sounds great.
>> Yep.
>> Thank you, sir.
>> Yeah, I got what he's asking. That's
true. Yep.
>> Yeah, that's the best way to do it.
>> Yeah.
Have your creativities observe the
common good.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Thank you.
Hi.
>> Hello there.
Hi. I just um I wanted to say thank you
very much for
all that you've done for me.
I'm very grateful and um
thank you. That's all.
There's nothing I can do about that
life. So, I have to film you without it.
>> Yeah, that Okay, I'll live with it.
Okay. Mhm.
>> I got to live with it.
>> Got to live with it. Like taxes.
>> The government.
>> Thank you. Um,
>> yeah. My son Jimmy and thousands of
other people in the world suffer from
stuttering and there's
>> suffer from stuttering. Yes. Yes.
>> There's no known cause of it and there's
no known cure. And
>> well, have you tried hypnosis?
>> No.
>> Yes. That's very effective.
>> Okay. Thanks very much.
>> Hypnosis helps it a lot.
>> Great. Thank you. Thank you.
>> Try it.
Yeah.
>> Yeah. Hypnosis has been pretty good with
it.
Okay, we have about five minutes left.
So, uh, let's try and keep the questions
short so we can maybe get more in.
>> Okay, cool.
>> I was wondering if you could uh verify
some suspicions I've had about my past
lives.
I don't want to get into your past
>> Um, my first one was Plato.
>> What?
>> Plato.
>> What's this question?
>> If you could test if I was Plato.
>> No, you weren't Plato.
>> Could you just
He was not Plato.
If you were Plato, you wouldn't be
asking, "Were you Plato?
Uh,
>> who told you you were Plato?
>> Some idiot.
>> I've had some very deep cries about it.
>> Huh?
>> What?
>> I've had some very deep cries about it.
>> Yeah, just
uh
>> cries.
What is he talking about? Please speak
English. Speak up.
>> You were not Plato in a previous life.
No. Okay.
Um, could you do some other past lives?
The Leonardo da Vinci.
>> He was Leonardo da Vinci in a past life.
Is this
>> Huh?
>> You weren't Jesus Christ either. That'll
save you asking.
>> That's interesting.
>> A lot of grandiosity with you, boy. Give
up the grandiosity.
>> I
>> give up the grandiosity. I said,
>> "Yeah,
>> you're not the world's great genius.
The world doesn't need another genius.
It's suffering from all past geniuses.
Give the world a break and be ordinary.
Be loving, kind, gentle, do it.
Look after your own responsibilities.
Pick up your own messes.
That's what you can do for the world.
The world's full of people that want to
be great. You know that's stupid.
>> Okay.
>> Uh would you calibrate me? Please
>> calibrate you. Do we calibrate people?
No, we don't calibrate people.
>> We won't do it in a public setting.
>> It's too much stuff.
>> Yeah. It's not accurate.
>> Do it in a private setting.
>> No.
>> We don't like calibrating people.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Um mine my request was a similar one uh
but to Carl Yung and that's all I want.
He thought he was Carl Young. Jung
He thought he was Carl Young.
>> Oh god. There's no end to grandiosity.
Just
>> Carl Young. Yeah.
Anyway, it wouldn't do you any good if
it was in your past life anyway.
Even if these things were true in your
past life, it wouldn't do you one iota
of good. It would just make you
grandiose and arrogant. Oh, I was
Aristotle.
>> If you could
>> I was Plato.
>> Humiliation.
>> Give me a break. I don't want to meet
Joe Blow who goes to work every day. It
was real and genuine.
Now, it won't do you any good.
Past lives don't mean anything as far as
your current reality. Your current
reality of what you are now. See?
Uhhuh.
>> Please do that.
>> What?
>> He wants you to calibrate to tell me it
wasn't Carl Young.
>> That's all.
>> He wants to know if he was Carl Young.
He was not Carl Young.
>> He wants you to test with the arm.
>> Oh. Oh, he was not Carl Young. Resist.
Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. Thank God.
Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Move along. Move along.
>> Okay. One more and then that's it.
>> I'm sorry. It's 12:30.
>> Yep.
>> Yeah. Hello.
>> Hello. Um, I had a question, but it
seems like it's already been answered.
>> Good. So,
so I would just like to thank you both
very much uh for in your inspiration and
I would like to shake your hand as well.
>> Thank you. Yeah. Mhm.
>> Thank you.
>> Right.
>> Oh,
>> if you want to say a few words or
>> Okay.
God's love is the law of the universe.
It is by his love that we live and
breathe.
Nothing exists except divinity.
It is the only reality.
So we have to ex accept the divinity of
our own creation.
I thank thee Lord God
for my life
>> and I ask how may I serve thee
and my fellow men.
And we give thanks for our Lord Jesus
Christ
>> and for all the saints.
>> I give thanks for this life and I
dedicate it to thy service, oh Lord.
with gratitude
>> and I accept thy blessing
which was my creation.
It is out of God's blessing that I exist
and came into creation
and came to be.
And I'm grateful that we have all come
to be here together.
This is a very wonderful group of
people.
So they represent God's blessing.
By serving each other we serve God
and by serving God we serve each other.
Therefore
we are fulfilled by gratitude.
Grateful for thee oh Lord. Grateful for
the love of my brother and my sister
and for all of life.
So we give thanks to thee, oh Lord, for
our life.
>> Amen.
>> That's it.
I squeezed them all at once, honey.
I squeezed everybody all at once.
Boy, I'm pooped.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu
Hallelu.
We're blessed by the presence of each
other.
>> Each one of us here
>> is thereby blessing everybody else here
>> because we dedicate ourselves to God.
We have a capacity that does not occur
otherwise.
>> So we are grateful for that gift from
the old Lord.
We are grateful for thy love and thy
presence
and thy gift of being able to bless
others through thy love and divine
presence.
>> Amen.
>> Let's all say amen together.
>> Amen. That's it.
Okay folks, thank you so much.
I am grateful for your presence today.
Everything's divine,
>> especially Susie.
I'm so
grateful for the gift of her love,
>> for the love of all beings, but
especially for her
cuz uh she came into my life to be with
me.
>> She was the only one willing to put up
with me.
They asked for volunteers in Evan and
she raised her hand
thereby undoing all her past negative
karma.
But when do we go this time? Where do I
go?
Hallelujah.
Hallelu.
Halleluah.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu.