Well, Dr. Hawkins, I sure want to thank you for just allowing me the time to sit with you today
and be in your presence. That's a great one for me. And I guess my first question is,
I know that you live out there under the foot of beautiful Cathedral Rock.
And so I'm wondering, it's one of those well-known so-called vortex sites. Do you
ever notice any energies or vibrations while you live out there? No. I thought you might say that.
Let me ask you about the nature of your teachings, devotional non-duality. Oh, yes.
I guess, you know, my question is, I can comprehend devotion, but non-dual to me is
neither subject nor object. It's neither here nor there. Can you just give us a little explanation?
Well, it was a little chancy to use that in the title, except, you know, in religious spiritual
literature, non-duality is a very specific,
specific area. And therefore, I thought I'd make it non-duality to make it so they know
what area we're speaking of. You know, the closest thing classically would be Advaita
and that entire orientation. What was the question? Oh, just from a naive perspective,
how does one surrender to? Oh, yes. Something that's, you know, not subject, not object.
Well, okay. The research technique,
we use, differentiates between the linear domain and the non-linear. The linear is perception
and definition and logic and reason, et cetera. The non-linear is context. Out of context arises
the significance and the meaning of it all, you see. You know, all the great teachers over time,
the great sages said, let go attachment to the linear.
Let go your attachment to the linear. And as you do that, you begin to experience the
non-linear aspects of, don't be attached to the linear, the definition. And as you do,
the non-linear becomes the greater reality. And your own consciousness advances as a consequence.
So, what's linear?
The linear is that linear is.
loaded to this world and if you're nothing but linear then that would make you think there's
nothing once the physical collapses which is how most people view things um what would be the best
way to let go of the linear to um is surrender is acceptance the same as surrender are they
similar and is that one way to let go of the linear they're similar so the attachment is
because the ego seems to see some gain in it and uh perception perception is really a projection
of the ego you know descartes made the famous statement that differentiating rest internal
that is how a thing looks and rest external meaning how things actually are in reality
so to differentiate perception from essence is what spiritual work is all about
in our particular research is very specifically focused on differentiating essence from appearance
so for instance when we calibrate um the the consciousness level or energy of something
what we're looking for is the essence and not the perception we're looking uh what the world
looks at is the sheep's clothing and what we see is the wolf inside or vice versa some people
pretend to be a wolf
and they're actually a sheep i've seen some of those well they sound fierce and all uh
intrinsically they're they're safe to be with you know yeah i've seen both so the calibrated level
of uh something in a way it tells you really how safe it is in a way you know how safe it is
is there um this is a funny question but is there any kind of fast track or accelerated technique
to actually accept um
to accept what that which you don't want to accept i mean let's face it the ego has a hard time
accepting things it doesn't like so i wonder is there any quick way technique that you can share
with me to accept well there are certain spiritual rules and disciplines which are applied almost any
spiritual pathway um to let go of attachments to let go aversions and attachments um to accept
everything uh being as it is
uh to focus on the perfection of all things um to let go attractions and aversions is is a fast track
could i let go of being angry etc could i let go hating that and of course the course of miracles
emphasizes a transformation of the way you see things once you let go your judgmentalism you
it's recontextualized you know when it's recontextualized you can see that it's just
whatever you're doing it's just what you're doing it's just what you're doing it's just what you're doing
whatever it is being what it is and uh is neither good nor bad
so the only way to do that quickly would be to do that right in the moment where it's
a right arising in you is that right that's that's more advanced technique more advanced technique
is mindfulness where you're aware of what's arising within yourself
and you're willing to let it go early in the game before it gains gets hold
um you feel the energy of it being irritated arising you don't wait until you're in a full
temper tantrum you you let go of it so in more advanced spiritual awareness you're on the you're
you're constantly aware of the leading edge of what's arising within your consciousness
and you're constantly surrendering that to god as it arises
oh yeah constantly and and you stop trying to control it i resisted or i used to say it's writing
the crest of the wave right i just was thinking that right in other words you're not clinging
to the past that's over already and you're not anticipating the future because the future has
no reality until it gets here there was a good example from uh in aa in 12-step program this
guy goes to a meeting and he looks a little bedraggled and unhappy and so people say what's
the matter with you he says well my wife was killed and run over the house burned down i lost
my job went bankrupt and so the other guy says well yeah but that was yesterday
that's a good friend to have isn't it it's a basic in the 12-step program yeah is to live
be in the present live one day at a time if it happened yesterday forget it exactly yeah
so you transcend all that because if you don't keep letting it go and releasing it and surrendering it
that accumulates and you find that you're becoming the prisoner of it you know we've got so many
reasons why we don't let it go we don't let it go we don't let it go we don't let it go we don't let
it go we don't let it go we don't let it go we don't let it go we don't let it go we don't let it go
resentments and griefs and you don't even know yourself you're immobilized you'll say
isn't that a funny story that was yesterday oh i love that i'll try to remember that
i'm curious um i noticed that over the years you've definitely acquired quite an exponential
following of people and i just wonder if there's any concern on your part of your teachings
becoming misinterpreted or distorted or warped just due to the sheer volume of
listeners out there well i i have been uh concerned that that not happened because that's
happened to the teaching great teachings over time you know even the new testament you see
right in the middle of the new testament which calibrates in the 800s you suddenly
have the book of revelations which calibrates at 70 you know and every religion it seems like
that which is negative or evil has managed to sneak in the door and put in their two cents for
it uh contaminated it so one reason i bullworked i bullworked everything i've said experientially
i've been the witness to it i've testified to it i've calibrated it then i've cited the references
in history and they confirm it and all the books i i write have an extensive extensive references
in the back so i've tried to um and then i've tried to show the student how to how to go about
confirm or not confirm a statement so i felt it was it's more safeguarded than any teachings i
know in history i would think so too i like to surf the web though you know and i take a look
out there and there are websites that reference your name and your map of consciousness and um
one i found recently was calibrating things into the fifth and sixth dimensions you know two and
three thousand and i thought how can this be i i have to grow there
there you know there are people that don't understand the work yeah these are people
that are seeking to profit that's what they'll tell you how to i can raise your consciousness
100 points in an hour and it's only 350. i found him too there's one guy that will calibrate you
every hour on the hour and you'll become enlightened within two weeks and he only wants
five thousand dollars yeah or they'll take you to the 50th dimension so so it doesn't really concern
you because it more entertains you
because um you people would need to rely on their own use of kinesiology to legitimize something
they find on the internet well i tell people you know go back go back to what's written and look at
the lectures and first understand it before you start trying to use it and manipulate it you
understand but but that's way with with everything uh there are people that look uh to uh exploit
everything right
people that are out to exploit everything
and of course the most exploitable product or aspect of life is man's intrinsic innocence
you think so the real charlatan knows that within the person there is that vulnerability of
innocence and all they have to do is figure out how to get to it entities on the other side so
called and on the other side people are always getting readings from entities on the other side
so their minds are crammed into a web of questions and they're going through things to get to it
and so that's why it's really important to get rid of the
but in many cases we can have a calibrative mind we can harvest an idea of where the mind is and
use it in society right and so by struggling to do that by first trying to get the right answer to
it and so then we begin to learn and we go back to the Braille method anyway and then when we are
going to man democracy and we are forced to get to it then we start to get stuck out there as we're
and sometimes under 200 so i did wonder if that correlates with your findings yeah because uh
why would a person exploit it they would be exploiting something for personal gain
you know that's different than sharing your enthusiasm about something yeah you know let's
say the 12-step groups of course of miracles or a really lovely church you know they they don't
proselytize they they share with you gee it was wonderful but they're not gaining anything out
of getting you to go there you know right and uh so integrity means you're not out to proselytize
control people and uh people are trying to put me in a position of trying to convince people
i have no interest in convincing people whatsoever
i'm not interested in selling it to people i'm not interested in persuading them
i just give them the evidence because their own karmic proclivity will lead them to the truth
if they're actually if they're truly interested
in the truth they'll be drawn to it and if they are not they will find some way to
to negate it so well let me ask you about um the child within at one of these recent
satsangs you refer to the child within a number of times and i was wondering the child within the
inner child oh yeah the inner child and i was wondering is that are you um speaking of the
ego or the innocence of consciousness oh no it is psychologically you might say the archetype of the
child within you know the i forget what author it is popularized the inner child the adult and the
parent i forget too right now but i've read it i forget who i forget it was but anyway it became
very popular for a while okay and it's uh it's useful pragmatically psychologically
you know that the child you can see all the protesters out there you can see the infant
infant child in them you know uh and then the parent is like the conscious i mean the
conscience you know so the parent is like and the parent yeah and then there's the adult has to
balance the child in you against the parent you know and i would say people who have an
eating problem it's because the minute they sit down to eat the the adult says i'm gonna
you know wash my calories but the minute they sit down the child comes up in them the archetype
of the child comes up you know i remember seeing that in the cafeteria here's this elderly gentleman
you know he's probably watching his cholesterol and he sits down with his tray at the table
and then he takes his napkin and put it under his and instantly he transformed right into a child
the child was just i see that every day when i sit down to eat the child instantly comes up
so i say to people um make sure your adult put a sign in your refrigerator that says adults only
because the minute the refrigerator door is open the child archetype unconsciously
okay so then you overeat all that ice cream and do whatever you said you weren't going to
do and then the adult comes in and says how could you have done that stupid how do you
know so much about me the adult comes in then and the parent comes in and says look it's stupid
you've eaten all that ice cream again you know so now you get hit with guilt so the first the
child gets you into trouble then the adult parrots you so you have to consciously recall
your adult take you know to be reasonable you see and all that goes on inside us the parent the
child yeah so the three you can see that you can see it you can watch it in a restaurant it's
hysterical yeah and especially when people put a napkin on somehow that just brings up the kid you
know from when you're a kid your mom would you know i never forget this guy he looked like the
president of a giant university or something you know dignified and susie with the bib on
the kid just
came up and couldn't wait to get permission to make a mess spaghetti a big bowl of spaghetti
well i'm wondering i mean do we want to is there a way to get back to that innocence would we want
to do we want to that innocence um that is this child archetype is that of a benefit to us
that's using the term innocence a little differently than i use it in consciousness
research in consciousness research i use it more or less to explain the
intrinsic innocence of the ego the ego doesn't realize it's ignorant it thinks that appearance
is reality so all the great teachers you know jesus christ the buddha as well they say there's
man only has one limitation one sin one defect and that is ignorance and of course that ignorance is
what leads them to follow false leaders and and think that adolf hitler is a hero and because
people are intrinsically innocent and lived an entire life that takes a long time to reach more people még forgiven them the insence of the ego give up the ego the ego non- sinful is ignorance it thinks that appearance is reality so all the great teachers you know jesus christ the buddhas when they put on you see onlyamus flying around in the electronics
so the danger is that innocence that's that's the fall of man isn't it we were living in a
non-duality and then the serpent came along and what the serpent did was seduce the child within
her he knew that inside there's an innocent child trust me trust me so it you know it's
moralistically looked at that the fallen man is due to disobedience a sin of defying God I see I
don't see it that way I see it was the innocence of the child man fell because of the innocence
he didn't know enough to guard himself and he trusted so the child the woman what was it Eve
anyway the guile of the serpent was to the innocent child within her she didn't do it out
of defiance I don't think she did it out of defiance she didn't do it out of defiance I don't
believe so at all you know that the man's projecting his own unconscious guilt onto the
story so I don't believe that story in Genesis it's symbolic that man fell out of his innocence
when he bought the linear domain but he did it out of innocence so that snake is like the wolf
and sheep's clothing that you referred to so it's out of innocence look at all the pilots and World
War two kamikaze pilots so we were scared to death of them because they had no fear of death
you
know out of their innocence they were sacrificing their life for the Sun God the Emperor glory of
Japan so we respected them after the war you know I respected any kamikaze pilot the same so after
the war the both sides we looked at each other equally I had no resentment against the Nazis or
the Japs or anybody they were I could see their innocence they were doing for their country but
they were called upon so we all were scared to death of them because they had no fear of death
all their all respected each other world today if everyone felt that way well I you know the same
with the islamics now if the terrorist thinks that this is his dirty to God I can see how
he's easily seduced into it you know he's practically mesmerized into it other childhood
I mean what else could he think has no alternative view one and any in me within
there very naive and childlike not even educated actually so what else could he think except to the
serve God is to blow yourself up and then that's why they're dangerous they're extremely dangerous
because the same as the kamikaze pilot because the ignorance with no yeah with no sense of
self-preservation a person will do anything to kill you including killing himself that is pretty
scary so the only thing I was ever scared in World War II I wasn't I wasn't afraid of dying
I wasn't afraid of being blown up but the kamikaze pilots would make you it would scare you because
anti-aircraft didn't scare them away you know 20 millimeter we'd be going like this and just
chasing what's going on that is scary so that's the downside of extremism in our world today.
So man's Achilles heel?
Yes.
Achilles heel.
intrinsic innocence and what I do in all the books is try to get people to go
beyond that innocence to realize to realize that that innocence is what the
your Achilles heel is the thought that you know something is an illusion so to
know be always aware that your inner self you know is really childish and and
without some kind of education or assistance or knowing kinesiology or
something how do you know well let me ask you a question I'm wondering
speaking of children and innocence you state that 4% of the current overall
population of the world calibrates above 500 which is the state of love over 500
is that correct over 500 4% let's see 4% calibrates over 500 0.4% calibrates over
540 mm-hmm but what I'm wondering
is because I'm always looking around for that one in 25 people but I notice
I'm usually looking for people that I would recognize I'm starting to wonder
could it be that a large percent of that 4% is the very young children that their
innocence hasn't been programmed by the world yet is that possible no I don't
think so it's not due to the effect of the world because the child's level of
consciousness is present already at birth I don't think it changes until
they have
the responsibility of moral decision and choice okay so the 4% would be
comprised of karmically the innocence of the child is not really changing it it's
only when when you choose an option well he's already choosing when he decides to
mind his parents rather than defy them yes so by age two you see the beginning
you can either be defined when it comes to toilet training or you want to please
your mother's
so whether you would you love them enough to forego the plight pleasures of
impulsivity is already showing up at age two and a good part of the population in
fact they they form a good part of the protest movement never got beyond the
defiance stage of age two they hate authority you look at the large amount
of the population hates the president why because he's the president that
make a difference who the president is they hate authority you know I said if you put an ad in the next week's
paper protest demonstration Saturday morning and then give so-and-so parking lot a lot of people will show up just a protest
in fact the videos that the FBI takes a protest groups you know the same faces just show up all the time it doesn't make any
difference what protests about they just love the riot and throwing rocks at the police so they they would be that that child that never wanted to listen to the parent that's the anally defiant very zanily defiant
defiant very zanily defiant
so none of the protesters and the
Misfits and they're always grumbling and complaining and they hate authority in any form whatsoever
oppositional defiance
Means discipline authority means this one
So it's not possible that that 4% would be children because children come into the world at the same level
Well, this leads me to another question
You talk about well recently, I know that the overall level of consciousness dropped a few points
Yes, and it's a logarithmic scale. So this is substantial and I'm wondering if that affects the
level the five-point
Ability, let's see a person rises five points in any given lifetime. That's your statistical average
Yeah, might it affected if the world is dropping points a person's ability to rise
those five points
In any given lifetime might that be different? I haven't researched that
whether that capacity to advance is independent of
The overall level or not. Can we do it find that out?
the
Capacity to rise in consciousness is independent of the prevailing
Level of consciousness of mankind in general is it is it? Yes. I thought so. Yeah. No, it's an individual matter
So you're not controlled by the consciousness
though
So we are of the world we are part of that hole, but we also have our individual karmic
Right, so it's over not at the effect of the world. No
We're at the effect of our own
Experience in the world but not we're not at the effect of the world oh very good
I mean kamikaze pilots can't make you hate them right? You know, it's up to you
You know
You see they're doing their duty to their Emperor so you respect them, but that's an option
I did see somebody on TV the other day, a veteran of World War II,
and he still hasn't forgiven him.
He still hasn't forgiven him.
I'm thinking, why not?
He's got a permanent resentment.
And there's not much you can do about that.
Not in this lifetime.
No, not in this lifetime.
But some lifetime.
Well, if we do reference your map of consciousness,
we can see that things fluctuate.
And I wonder if you've ever experienced any fluctuations
in your own level of consciousness
that you're aware of these days, currently.
These days, it's more, let's just say, a choice of where to be at.
And one sacrifices a certain inner state of bliss,
I guess bliss would be the closest to it,
in order to function.
So I look at it.
I look at it as temporary.
In other words, it's a temporary, in other words,
in order to finish what I'm doing,
you have to forego being in a higher place.
Because in a higher place, function is out of the question.
There's no interest in the linear world.
And at a certain level of a linear world,
doesn't really have any intrinsic reality.
So there's no point to sacrifice for that which has no intrinsic reality.
Right.
But it's more than that.
It's more the obligation of realizing one has valuable information
to share with the world,
and feeling the obligation to finish that
before one withdraws from it again,
which I intend to do.
And I'm finishing some books,
and I'm looking forward to the fact that
I'm tired of processing the linear domain.
It's very tedious.
I can only imagine.
Do you notice the fluctuations physically?
Is it a physical sense when you notice that happening at a level,
and you make a choice to come to a certain level?
No, it's not physical.
It's an awareness.
It would be like walking through the woods,
the degree of the background light, let's say.
It can become very intense or diminish.
So it's more of a shift in the field of context, you see.
And then you reach a certain point where
you feel you've pretty much said what you want to say in this lifetime.
And you look forward to not having to function on that level again anymore.
It takes energy
to not be really what you are, you know?
Doesn't it?
It's so hard to be not myself.
It is, it is.
Once you experience just being the self with the capital S,
it takes energy to be the small, small self.
with a small s again you know for me at this point in my life it takes energy i guess to be
the capital s because it's not my it's not what the world has taught me but well it's more like
you you buy somebody gives you something you buy something it's a nice little gadget and then
you open it up and then the instructions are always printed in china and very small print
and faint and you got to unwrap this whole thing and here's all these diagrams telling you how to
use this gizmo and you say i don't think it's worth a lot so it's sort of like that well we
should come with on your owner's manuals like that that would be nice you said i'd rather do
without the gizmo than than read all that and figure it out you know you just listen well i
have friends that know how to figure things out like that that's always helpful so i call him in
and he looks at it and he tells me here you just turn it on this way and again
thank you that's it you're reading all these pages fine print i think it's hard for some
people to find the voice inside to listen and then once they hear it even through kinesiology
to actually actually follow through with it um i think that that can be hard for some people
do you have any advice for folks that are trying to find or listen to that voice
oh it's not so much a voice as an inclination there is that inclination to
you
expand the depth of the field and one follows that inclination especially when people begin
to practice spiritual concepts and feel an immediate result you know you're very very
angry and then suddenly you remembered it so you ask for a miracle you just want to see it
differently you remember the intrinsic innocence of people that they don't know any better or they
would you know they couldn't have done any differently or they would have instantly you
feel released from that guilt
so when you experience that benefit that increases your desire to see that things that way in
the future you know negative things become less and less tolerable and people below 200
enjoy being angry and hating things and having protests for aids and all that and above 200
it's uh it becomes progressively unpleasant you're very very unhappy if you get irritated
with something whereas people below i'd love to indulge in it yeah you're you're very very
unhappy if you get irritated with something whereas people below i'd love to indulge in it
talk about it for days you know somebody screwed them years later they're still into it you know
so they're pulling juice they're getting juice and I call it the ego juices negative feelings
you say why would you have negative feelings because ego gets so much juice out of that
it just loves being angry it just loves being the victim it just loves all that
and the first way to get off it is to recognize that your ego loves it
your ego loves feeling sorry for itself being jealous and being angry and feeling victimized
and it loves to wallow in guilt and uh unbelievable but it does yeah it's a secret payoff all right so
the key to getting off it is to discern that secret payoff so you don't have to give up being
angry resentful all these things you only have to give up one thing one thing only the willingness
to let go of the juice that you're getting out of that
the negativity being the victim being wronged whatever the juice that the ego
gets out of that is all you got to give up I'm gonna remember that one so it
isn't fame it's the juice you get out of fame would you be willing to let go of
the juice that you get out of fame I mean fame is boring if there's no juice
you know one more one more is a star show one more yeah a big deal right so
what else you know right once you've juiced it you're not willing to kill for
it or die for it or sacrifice your whole life or sell your soul for it you know
so that juice that you get from the ego that's why people sell their soul hmm
that's what Faustus got at the end the opera Faust you know the great opera
and then at the end the whole audience
gets to its end and they're just like hey we got to come back into the theater
and then they're just like hey we got to come back into the theater
holds their breath when they realize that satan is now calling for his soul you know
the moment has arisen now it's payback time and then everybody in the u.s goes oh god
you get the dread of it the spiritual terror you know having sold your soul now is the payoff
was it worth it i helped you be rich and famous and all this and now now and we have a lot of
people in the world that you know take that choice you can see that and now it's now you
belong to me it's sort of dreadful and i can remember that from childhood no no you know as
a child as a child i had a obsessive fear and guilt of sin you know and in fact i had to go
for counseling about it scrupulosity they call it but i remember seeing you know dr faustus you
know the opera and that added to my dread
but added to my drug sure if you sin at the moment of death satan's gonna come for you
oh boy so i was scared to death of it yeah the death of sin yeah um and you grew up catholic
was that right episcopal that's right episcopalian um i'd like to ask you a question about you had
spiritual breakthrough in 1965 that you've shared with us before and i am curious speaking of you
what was it like moving the fluctuations the way consciousness moves as we can tell that it does
and choices what was it like for you for that 15 years from 65 to 80 when you moved to sedona
um did it feel like you were as my friend refers to it the roller coaster of the path
did you feel like you were moving forward moving back two steps forward one step back
or was it just a smooth transition no it it it moves in phases it moves in phases
can you tell us a little bit about any memories well you could say in general you know through
good karma and inner spiritual work you transcend the various levels then when you get to the next
higher level let's say one of i can remember being being in a state of ecstasy um i mean
ecstasy is beyond what people even imagine ecstasy is it is beyond this world and it's paralyzing you
can't do anything in ecstasy
and uh but each level each level uh is preparatory and opens the way to the next level
so joy i remember going through these various stages you go through a state of universal
lovingness in which you break into tears all the time and uh you go into a state of joy as i say an
ecstasy and in those states you can't function you can't function in a state of ecstasy
you can't function so in those years uh that when when that was going on it wasn't functioning and
then and what levels are those at well ecstasy on and on the scales i forget where it is it's about
590 yeah 595 excuse me it's beyond 570 570 is like sainthood and yeah joyfulness and then comes
ecstasy yeah ecstasy is about 590.
it's exquisite beyond all description and uh it's been described by uh the great saints over time and
i was trying to think of the more recent one um and it in in ecstasy then
i saw that this too had to be surrendered to god so each thing as it arises you surrender to god
and i surrendered the ecstasy to god and then even thinking about it brings it back
again now. Once the ecstasy resides, the divinity of the present shines forth at
the level of 600 of infinite timeless peace. Sat Chit Ananda is 600. In that state
you need nothing from the world nor does life need to go on or not go on. It makes
no difference. So as I talk about it right now, the state returns. Whether we continue
to talk or don't continue to talk is irrelevant. Whether it's interesting to people is irrelevant.
If I keep reading long enough to walk out the door when it's over is irrelevant. That
which I am at this moment is complete and total, all satisfying, forever. Amen. O Lord,
so be it. Now let's see if that's the truth.
What was just spoken was the truth. Resist. Yes. So the state is in the background as
we speak now. If I don't stop, we won't stop speaking because to speak further would be
irrelevant. But then comes love and the love then says, yes, but you would then be short
circuiting the purpose of her being here. And so then love returns and continues the
conversation.
That love it would stop. So would that itself be a fluctuation and a choice? No, it's always
there. Okay. You see, it's like your consciousness is like a full pipe organ. And when you stop
playing this note, it doesn't go away. It's just, you know, all this panorama. So at a
high level of consciousness, you can really be at any level you want. So for purposes
of the functioning, you know, you go into what I call the persona that interacts with
the world, such as I'm doing now, you see, because you have to converse and talk to the
world. You have to talk, gesticulate, etc. So that's one thing in the organ, but it's
not what the organ is. The organ is also this, being in a state of bliss and absolute silence.
Then the organ is also ecstasy. And then there's a point which is beyond all of that. Anyway,
all these phenomena are happening autonomously. Our conversation, all this being here, the
whole phenomena as it unrolls, is all happening autonomously. You see?
And it really comes that there is no personal I doing this, or initiating it, or deciding
it. That that's an illusion. The autonomous emergence of potentiality into actuality manifests
in our conversation as what goes on as we speak. There's no personal self deciding that
this is the way it's going to go. No personal self in you decided to interview me. That's
the autonomous phenomena because creation is ongoing and eternal.
And the interaction of these energies amount for all the people in this room right now
and all the equipment and the phenomena. It's all happening autonomously. Everybody thinks,
well, it's because I decided to do that or I. There's no personal I deciding to do that.
So you're just an impersonal agent of creation, autonomously functioning, fulfilling one's
potential. So the butterfly flies because that's what butterfly does. He doesn't sing
a song, see?
Mmm.
He doesn't decide he's going to fly. The butterfly doesn't say, gee, I think I'll fly
and look beautiful in the nature today. It just is being what it is. So conversation
is our being what we are this morning, talking this, or using Susan's arm. She's so attuned
to essence of things. The people that put the equipment, all this is happening spontaneously.
We're all the witness of it.
Well, let me ask you a question about consciousness.
Consciousness bleeding, you've mentioned that when a higher level of consciousness
communicates to a lower level, so that lower level can comprehend what is being said, that
you experience a consciousness bleeding. Do you experience that?
That I experience what?
The bleeding of consciousness, it lowering to communicate, say, to me or when you're
in lectures?
No, it doesn't lower.
Oh, okay.
No, consciousness, you say, don't forget the consciousness.
The whole of consciousness.
The whole organ.
It's really the witnessing of all this. I witness what's being said. I'm aware of what's
being said, but what's being said is happening of its own. I have nothing to do with it.
That which I am has nothing to do with it whatsoever except the awareness of what the
problem is. I don't decide. I think I'll say this and I think I'll say that. I don't know
what's being said until I hear it.
Is that hard to see?
No.
I can see that.
All right. So the question is, do you see it?
I can just ...
Because you're asking are already happening of their own, you see, and then you become
aware of them. Oh, I just asked that. Yes. That's one ten-thousandth of a second after
the phenomena. The awareness is one ten-thousandth. Now, what happens in full enlightenment is
that one ten-thousandth of a second disappears, and suddenly you're transformed into a different
dimension of existence. That delay between that and me disappears, and that which you
are is all that is. So all you're listening to is an expression of that which you are,
which is all that is.
And I could sit there ...
In its linear form.
... forever. But I'll ask you a few more questions just for the viewers and the listeners.
I wonder, too, about entrainment, because quite clearly now as you're speaking, I feel
entirely different. There's something that's taking place physically in my heart, and I'm
going to ask you a question.
Okay.
So I'm in entrainment to, you know, there's something going on that I'm experiencing,
as we probably all are. Are there consequences to my leaving the room and going back to my
little ordinary life?
No, because you carry the frequency and the vibration in the imprint. It's like your aura
imprints it.
So it's not like I come down?
No.
Good.
Now it's an availability. So those vibrations, those frequencies, and the knowingness that
each one then becomes a part of the aura as an energy field of potentiality. And then
it comes forth when it's needed.
Do we all have that?
Everybody who's experienced an energy field anywhere in their lifetime of a higher frequency
can pick it up. I don't know. I've never researched that specifically.
Would they have to be ...
Whether you can refuse it or agree to it, I don't know.
Would they have to be over 200?
Would they have to be over 200 to have a relationship with a higher frequency, or could that happen
at any level?
In other words, despite oneself, one picks it up. Okay, let me just ask that one. It's
possible that despite oneself, people below 200 pick up on a higher energy field, resist.
Yes, I thought so. See, otherwise there'd be no point. There was a savior, a Buddha,
an avatar.
So that frequency is picked up within human consciousness, generally, and it comes down
through the centuries. And then you don't realize it's within yourself until you reach
by agreement. In other words, spirituality doesn't force itself. Nobody's forced through,
see? But then when you're ready for it, it's there because it's in your aura. Yeah.
Very good.
And we even checked one time that the energy field is there because it's in your aura.
The energy field of a great teacher can last you through 25 lifetimes, 25 reincarnations.
People don't believe in karma, and they don't have to, and I don't insist that they do.
But it will last down through the lifetimes.
25 lifetimes.
Yeah, at least 25. I didn't ask you if it was more. 25 should do you.
Well, I've heard you say that no one calibratable level is better than another, just different
from each other.
But, you know, in speaking about some of the levels that are under 200, it seems like
wouldn't you have to agree some levels are preferable to others?
Oh, God, yes.
Okay. Not necessarily better than.
Well, we're talking about judgmentalism, you see.
I know.
Is it better to be a chameleon or a crane? Is it better to be a heron or a hippopotamus?
You know, it's not really better than. You know, being a hippo is a hippo, and being
a whistling crane is something else. You can't really say one is better than the other,
projecting preference. It isn't that it's better than. It's that it is what it is. What
everything means is what it is. What it is is what it means. What it means is what it
is.
Clear.
Identity and meaning are identical. So if you live in the world of essence, then, you
see and experience the world differently. And you see that everything is just being
that which it is at that point in its evolution. So what eventually dawns on you is the
perfection of all things. Each thing is only being what it can be at that moment of its
being that. So it's an adolescence who's been brainwashed into violence as holiness
or something. That's all they can believe at that point in this lifetime.
Mm-hmm.
And whether this is, this world is not celestial, nor is it hell. It's, what do you call that
in between the two?
Purgatorial.
Purgatorial, yes. This world is, to my view, purgatorial.
But, for me…
You can worry about purgatory some other time. You better worry about it now.
Right now.
This is purgatory. Why? You've got your choice between heaven and hell right here, right
now.
But wouldn't I prefer to hang out in heaven?
Would you prefer to hang out with my kitty cat who might calibrate at 350 as opposed
to a Komodo dragon at 40?
Well, that's because you're spiritually committed, you know. So as a spiritually committed
person, yes, it would be important whether people are of a higher level or a lower level.
But the people below, they're looking for sensation and stardom and money and…
Well, they'll find that if they cuddle up with a Komodo dragon.
Huh?
They'll find that if they cuddle up with a Komodo dragon.
Yeah.
You know, I'm wondering, I've been to the lectures and the satsangs, and I noticed
that oftentimes people will ask the same questions. Sometimes even the same people will ask the
same questions. And so I'm just curious. Your answers are very consistent. Why can't
we hear you? Why can't… What's our block from taking the information in?
Oh.
Well, it may be I didn't articulate it as well as I should have. Plus, I'm aware there's
an audience listening. So I'm trying to answer it not only in terms of meaningful to the
questioner, but so as to answer it in the consciousness of everybody in the audience.
They're bringing it up for everyone, you might say, you know?
Yeah.
Yeah, and sometimes I'm repetitious because sometimes people are coming up, they present,
you know…
What they're really presenting as a psychological, psychiatric problem, you know, social problem
with their family is really not a spiritual question, you know? And I try to redirect
them that they really should have a counselor that's not really a spiritual. They're
not really asking the spiritual meaning or aspect of a situation.
Right. And I've heard you say…
Yeah. Everything's physical, mental, and spiritual. So some of these disorders that
people bring up…
Yeah.
…are not just spiritual. They're also physical and mental, you know what I'm saying?
Yes, definitely.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So you're trying to direct them in the right way.
Yeah.
And also the whole audience is listening as well. Now, I've heard you say at times
if someone says, I'm depressed, Dr. Hawkins, and you would say, well, you're not depressed
enough. Go into the depression more. So I'm just curious, how does one know when they're
hitting bottom in a therapeutic way where they can, you know, find something else or
when they're just juicing, you know, a particular state of mind?
Well, I don't give that recommendation to everybody willy-nilly.
Oh.
I'm talking to spiritually-oriented people who are seeing this as a phenomenon that they're
working through. A person who is just an ordinary person not spiritually committed or in a spiritual
learning system, it might be quite dangerous for them to surrender to a depression and
commit suicide, you see?
Mm-hmm.
So I'm thinking about as a spiritual, once you join a spiritual evolution, now how you
process things has different significance. What you're looking to get out of it is the
meaning and the spiritual growth that's hidden within that situation. For people that are
not safely in that kind of a context, it would be foolish of them to try and fight a depression
because they'll just end up paralyzed in a hospital, you see?
Mm-hmm.
So I say everything's physical, mental, and spiritual.
And you should look at it psychologically, spiritually, and also get help for it within
the physical domain, you know?
Right.
Yeah.
All levels. Well, speaking of your audience, I'm curious, what is your sense of the best
way for your live audience to demonstrate their recognition of the presence of God within
you as their teacher?
They do so beautifully by being there.
Yeah.
I think highly of somebody. I go and listen to their lecture.
Yeah. Yeah. They do show up.
They do.
They do adore you.
And that I consider the greatest compliment going. You see, it's the fulfillment of my
obligation to share with the world that which I've known and I know to be of value. And
therefore, they help me fulfill my own potential. So I'm grateful to them for being there.
You see?
Definitely.
Mm-hmm.
And one of the things I admire in your life that I notice about you is that you spend
a lot of quiet time in contemplation, meditation with nature, and then you go out there in
the world in a really big way. You work with people as a spiritual teacher, as a doctor,
as a therapist you have. And my question is, how does one navigate these seeming polarities
and stay in integrity as you do?
They're not polarities. They're all potentialities.
Mm-hmm.
And this, as I say, like a pipe organ. So with this one, I play the bass notes, and
with this one, I play the high notes. So the overall orientation is to be of service to
the world in whatever way you can be. I went back into practice because there was no other
psychiatrist around to see 50 girls there in desperate condition and no doctor. I had
no intention to go back into practice. And then I found there was a shortage of psychiatrists
around here anyway. So I went into part-time practice.
And that's because there's a need for it within the world. When your own needs are met, then
you try to fulfill the needs of the world. You're trying to complete the fulfillment
of your own potentiality as an actuality. Each one has a gift. Some people have the
gift of benevolence and capacity to comfort others, to look after others, to inspire others.
Each one fulfills their karmic destiny.
Does the contemplation and meditation help you to fulfill your own needs so that you're
able to go out in the world?
I don't really have any needs about it, no.
Okay. Would it help me maybe to fulfill my needs and others to go out in the world and
help people as you?
Those things happen automatically as a consequence of that which you have become. So I believe
in meditation and contemplation to be, should be a continuous lifestyle. As we're talking
now, the meditative part of me is functioning not predominantly because they're not playing
that on the organ. But all the while we're talking, there is that which is reflective
and nonlinear, aware of exactly where we are with it all. It's, you might say, observing.
Yes.
Interpreting, being aware of, interpreting from various levels of consciousness simultaneously.
So the awareness is not only of what we're being said in a linear vocal style, but on
very many dimensions, including beyond this lifetime. All of us here in this room in this
moment are fulfilling our obligation and our capacity. All of us, everyone in this room,
right now.
Yes.
Is fulfilling that potentiality. You see how potentiality is evolving into an actuality
just by the sheer presence of us all being together. It's not by accident we're all together.
You know, each one is serving a critical function. Yeah.
Well, I want to go back to something you did speak briefly of before. I know from your
writings and your lectures that you emphasize that peace begins within an individual. And
the world is in such a state of distress these days.
And I just wondered if you could speak briefly for the magazine about the individuals that
might be involved with the peace movement today.
Well, don't ask me about peace as a movement and a political, politicalization. Because
I think it's very provocative and it provokes its opposite. Why? Because it becomes politicized.
And as politicized, it becomes wanting to control. And it's, you know, from the viewpoint
of the yin-yang of it, it gives you something to oppose, you see. The way to have peace
is to be peaceful. And people who, this is going to sound ambiguous, but those who declare
they want peace are not telling the truth. Because if you choose peace, you have it.
And if you have it, why would you be protesting about it? So peace, peace is an interstate.
Would you say that the peace movement is a waste of time then?
I'd say it's very provocative. It's the opposite.
And how would one access choosing peace?
Peace is an inner decision, you see. So how do you bring about peace? Well, people ask
this very often. Through the collective, through the collective. In other words, each person,
by choosing peace within themself, raises the level of consciousness.
So the way it's set up in our world is divisive and conflictual. The peace movement against
the war movement. Now, recently we had a peace demonstration, and if you calibrate some of
the leading figures, you'll find that they're all below 200. All of them. All below 200.
So how would one, is there a way that one could access that peace within, within the
peace movement, without going, without being concerned about the peace movement?
All right, so you can't do it by war, war against non-peace.
Right.
What happens is, as each person chooses truth rather than falsehood, and integrously moves
forward in consciousness, they lift the collective, the collective consciousness of mankind.
Collective, collective, collective consciousness of mankind, then, is like the light of the
level of the sea. And as you raise the level of the sea, it raises all the ships on the
sea. What the peace movement tries to do is pick which ships they're going to lift above
the level of the water.
Right.
They're not going to. And therefore, they all, you know, eventually fail. What happens
is, a society reaches a level of collective awareness, and then because of that which
it has become, the peace is in place.
The peace is an automatic consequence of the reality of that which they are.
Mm-hmm.
So, to me, most of the peace movements are fakes, and they're just out there, and I get
all kinds of solicitations in the slick, slick-looking things in the mail. And when you calibrate
them, they're below 200.
Right. Very good.
You're out there to create war in the name of peace.
The interview you mentioned about the children that never liked authority growing up, it's
kind of that same thing.
Yes, they're just opposing anything, you see.
Okay.
Because peace would require the resignation of positionalities, and don't you see these
people value their positionality greater than they do peace? All these people out harassing
the President of the United States, do you think they're bringing about peace? No, they're
fomenting hatred.
Yeah.
You know, after the Vietnam War, you saw the hatred these movie stars solicit. They're
playing on hatred and pridefulness and everything.
Yeah.
Pridefulness and arrogance, that's not peace.
And that's what they're bringing into their own life.
They get a lot of time in the media, but that's about all. Because the collective consciousness
of mankind reaches a certain degree of wisdom, and out of wisdom it becomes obvious to everybody.
You don't have to sell people what's obvious, you see. You don't have to sell them what's
obvious.
I would like to ask you about dance.
About what?
Dance.
Dance?
I've seen you dance. I love dance. I've studied dance in my life, and it's a way,
I guess, for me that spirit gets to be inside the physical body. And I've seen you dance.
I've seen you do the octopus on stage, and I think anyone who's ever seen you dance would
have to agree, you've really got a special relationship with movement. So I wondered,
is that a product of past life experience? Is it a product of your field of consciousness,
or did you actually get childhood training?
No, it was an interest and a talent. And, you know, people, at a certain level of consciousness,
you remember past lives, you see. Maybe we shouldn't talk about such things, because
a lot of people don't believe in that, see.
What level of consciousness?
One time I was a temple dancer, and it came to me in one lifetime, one time when I was
dancing in this lifetime, that whole lifetime, and how I was trained. And in that lifetime
as a temple dancer, I see in my mind a design, and I merely act out the design that I already
see in my mind. And that's how I was trained. I can see a descending spiral. Now I just
become the descending spiral. I become.
I just become the pattern.
That is already within.
And you've already.
You know, see. That came to me that one time, all of a sudden I remembered that lifetime.
You're trained into the pattern, and then the body merely conforms to the pattern. And
you can also forget all that, because past life is not something that most people let
give any credence to.
What level is it, 600 that you remember past lives?
Yes, yes, about, yeah, 600.
What were you doing?
It's a recall. It's really a recall.
Okay.
You don't see it as a past life. Well, yeah, see, I guess you do see it as a past life.
A different role, a different role. Now, whether that is just something within the collective
that you, because you know, now you identify with the whole collective consciousness, whether
you recall it because you have owned the entire collective consciousness of mankind as one's
own, or whether it actually happened in a linear chronologic, you see, is irrelevant.
All I know is I know what it is to be that dancer, and I know what it is to dance in
that context of worship of God.
What was the moment that you had that memory? Do you recall what you were doing? You were
dancing when you had the memory in this current lifetime of this other?
I was in a state of ecstasy. I was by myself in a state of ecstasy. And then came the recall,
aha, of merely tracing out a pattern. What you're taught is the pattern. And then the
dance is merely just the fulfillment of that pattern within. At a certain level, you don't
dance anymore. You're being danced, and it's effortless. And in that state, you can dance
for hours. I've danced for maybe 24 hours nonstop. No food, no water, nothing. In that
state of ecstasy, I had to call.
That's when I called that ecstasy to a halt, and I realized I had to surrender that to
God.
Are there any consequences to dancing that long? When you're in a state of ecstasy, do
you become tired afterward?
Not that I know of, no. You don't get tired, no, because the energy is continuous. You're
not depleting anything, because, as I said, I had to let it go. I saw that this, too,
I must surrender to Thee, O Lord. And that's when I surrendered that.
Then I went into that state of satchitananda, this, too, O Lord. And you weep with joy. If
I talk about it now, I would break up, so I can't talk about it forever. It brings the
joy back.
Well, I'll move on to a different question. The law of attraction, have you heard of it?
Yes.
It's this, you know, this big buzz, this secret, the DVD, New Age DVD. Everyone's talking
about it in the spiritual community.
They just discovered it. It's been around forever.
It's no secret, is it?
But I wondered...
But the hole in mine tends to materialize. I mean, that's an old saw, isn't it?
Now, is there a correlation between your model for attractor fields and this law of attraction?
No. No. Nominally, just the word attractor. In a vague sort of a way, you're attracted
to, yes, see, an attractor field, I could use a term from non-linear dynamics. It's
an energy field, and you're attracted to your own energy field, yes, that with which
you resonate. You're attracted to that which you have become. So once you reach a certain
level, you prefer a rural, easygoing lifestyle with nature and an emphasis on beauty and
aesthetics, and you're not interested in the law of attraction.
Hmm.
And you're attracted to the world and accomplishment and all that.
Well, I would wonder that even if the intention, if your intention isn't from a good place,
if your attention's from a lower level of consciousness, isn't there a danger that what
you're intending to bring into your life with this law of attraction could also be sourced
from a lower motivation?
Let's not go out there. Let's just take the law of attraction. First of all, it's not
law. It's just observation.
Mm-hmm.
What you hold in mind tends to materialize.
You tend to bring it into your life because you're holding the pattern of it, and naturally,
you're identifying with that pattern. That which you hold in mind tends to materialize.
Every place I've lived for 50 years, each place arose as a consequence of holding, envisioning
that which I would appreciate the most.
Hmm.
And not through searching.
I would just picture a little house near the creek someplace and the woods all around,
and next thing I know, somebody called me and said, you know, the place next door is
for sale, and you're the only one I want living next to me.
Yeah.
And back east, the same thing happened. I pictured woods and the beautiful things,
and sure enough, it turned out 25 acres of woods and an elegant lifestyle, et cetera.
So whatever you hold in mind tends to materialize.
Right.
Well, there's a lot of people holding in mind Cadillacs and mansions, so I'm wondering,
wouldn't that be the source motivation of what you want?
Now, for you, nature brings contemplation and quiet and a sweet space.
Yeah, I'm just wondering about the source motivation.
I think you've already answered it.
Wanting it tends to keep it away.
You don't picture wanting a Cadillac.
You picture yourself having a Cadillac and being in a Cadillac
and being joyful in it and appreciating it.
So I have a beautiful Cadillac.
It already worked.
It's an 84, and it's been restored, and I love it.
So somebody says, wouldn't you rather have a new one?
Frankly, no, because I know where everything is.
I can drive the 84 Caddy without even thinking.
If I got into a new Cadillac, I'd have to go to school for a month with all the dials and gadgets
and it would be distressing.
In fact, we have a new car in the family, and I don't know how to drive it.
It's so complicated.
I don't know how in the world they'd even make it work.
Let me ask you a question about if I did my math right, you're going to be 80 this year,
so maybe I can be the first to wish you a happy birthday in a few months.
Congratulations.
I am wondering, as you grow older, have you gotten any provisions or structure together
to ensure the legacy of your teaching?
The legacy of your teachings before you leave us in form, which none of us want to be soon.
I've tried to provide everything in written form, verbal form, audio form,
in all the possible formats that facilitate teaching,
and we've created a nonprofit 501c3 Institute of Spiritual Studies that goes on into perpetuity.
And the responsibility of the Institute for Spiritual Studies is to continue on,
make sure that the materials become available, stay available into perpetuity.
Beautiful.
The reason is, for instance, I'm not too verbal this morning.
What do you call it, Wang Ho?
I can't even think anymore.
Anyway, many of the most valuable teachings,
or from 800, 900 years ago, or something like that,
some teacher that lived in India 900 years ago,
and it was recorded, and we're still reading it today.
So very good, we'll be able to still...
So whatever the essence of the truth of it,
to make sure that it's available.
What's valuable about the work I do, I think,
is that I've bulwarked an obvious statement.
If you're in a high state, you can read something,
like the Great Sage said 1,000 years ago, and it's obvious.
But if you're not in a great state,
it requires a great deal of bulwarking and explanation.
So to me, what's missing is the explanation.
Now, a lot of the great teachings of ancient time was nonverbal.
So the difficulty with a book, or even the verbal translation,
especially in Buddhism and Hinduism,
there's a lot of misconception of what was meant
by what the teacher said.
The reason is because when it was said,
it was said, first of all, in a certain context.
Secondly, it was said with certain gestures,
with certain emphasis,
with certain physical expressions.
And the meaning is conveyed in the totality.
And out of the totality, they extract a linear verbalization.
It's a wonder that anybody gets what was meant by that,
because...
True.
Now, even when I'm, you know, having a lecture,
I can tell by one gesture and the way I'm holding my hand,
they got what that is.
Now, how would a translator put that into a verbalization?
At the point where he says,
happened of its own.
Instead, you get it nonverbally.
You obviously saw it happened of its own.
There's no...
I don't say to your thing about,
gee, I think I'll do something clever in the middle of our talk
and it'll be unusual or something.
It just happens spontaneously.
So the emergence of reality is spontaneous, see?
And so what's lost in the translations
is what they meant by that.
I noticed as we started up that you and Susan had this look,
and I thought, you have such a symbiotic relationship.
So I wanted to ask, when and where did you first meet?
And, you know, was it love at first sight?
We first met in a dancing class.
Oh, there you go, the dance comes back.
Yes, and the recognition was instantaneous.
I looked across the room and I felt this incredible surge of energy shoot
between the two of us, and it just knocked me out.
And I thought, that's it.
All nonverbal, nothing.
It was just like a sudden knowingness.
Well, it's very sweet to witness the support and the caring.
And you're currently working on a new book.
You referenced that earlier.
I'm working on four books right now.
Oh, okay.
I always work on a few at a time.
My goodness.
Do you have any?
I'm working on, let's see, three, four, about four books, yeah.
Do you have a little sneak preview for us, or is there any synchronized?
Well, I'm working on one called Spiritual Reality in Modern Man.
And then we're working on a book of charts, you know,
all the lecture charts that we put out, about 105 of those.
So each one, I picture a chart on one side and a page of explanation on the other.
It's a rapid recapitulation through the content of the course.
And then I'm working, we're working on a dictionary of calibrations,
and we've done thousands of them.
So we're constantly calibrating everything.
And then I make, I jot them all down,
and someday I'll get myself collected to bring them up to date.
And then there's the book.
I did lectures years ago on healing, self-healing and healing.
And those are being put in book form.
So right now I'm correcting the manuscript to the book form
because it was given verbally and very informally.
And now in book form, you have to change the languaging.
You know, what you say spontaneously to an audience,
you can't just forbid and put it down necessarily.
Right.
You have to translate it more into what people are used to in reading, see.
So we're working on those four.
And then in my spare time, I have to write,
I'm always preparing something for the next lecture.
Now the next lecture is God versus science, I think, you know.
So I had to put together, you know, when we check all these things out,
then I make a list of them so they will come,
the information will come out in the next lecture.
So there's also, besides the four books,
constantly preparing slides for the next lecture.
Right now, right now, environmentalism is, you know, very big.
Right.
You see, the minute you put an ism on a thing,
it becomes a politicized power play.
And all the politics and game playing, you know,
is environmental, you know, environmental warming
and environmental pollution, oh, global warming.
Global warming.
And there's global warming.
And then there's environmental pollution.
The mistake is to put them together as causal
because global warming is independent of environmentalism.
Man's input into the environment doesn't affect the temperature
on Earth more than 0.8 degrees Fahrenheit.
So pollution is one thing, and it has detrimental effects.
Earth warming is due to the magnetic activity of the surface of the sun.
And is independent of man.
The global temperature fluctuates over the many centuries.
That was found by core drillings at the,
ice drillings at the polar, at the poles.
You can get the temperature back over 10,000 years.
And it is concordant.
And so the next lecture,
which is next Saturday or a week from tomorrow or whatever,
I'll give the scientific references, you know.
So when we do, see, when we do consciousness research,
we come out with the truth of the thing,
irrespective of what mankind believes.
So when we find the disparity,
I've discovered over the years, we're always right.
If her arm goes weak when I say
temperature change on the Earth is due to man
and her arm goes weak,
she's always right.
I mean, that arm is always right.
So I believed it too.
I thought, well, you know, it's probably man's activities.
I believe that too.
So we got to know.
I said, hey, what is that?
So then I began to research it.
And I finally know that the explanation is independent of man's existence.
Man contributes to 0.8 degrees Fahrenheit.
So pollution is a problem of its own.
Now, what is the cause of pollution?
I'll tell you the secret of that.
Overpopulation.
Right.
You can't live as a human being without creating problems.
You're going to eat.
That's going to create garbage, isn't it?
You're going to go to the bathroom.
You've got to have sewage.
So environmentalism, environmental damage,
is due to just the sheer population.
That would be good for people to hear
because that's not the popular belief.
Well, overpopulation is the cause of pollution.
Yeah.
And earth temperature is due to the effect of the sun.
And man's not going to do anything about that.
It's a little bigger.
Man's not going to affect the temperature on the earth.
So all you can control is pollution.
The only way you can control pollution is stop having so many children.
Well, I'll be doing my part to help you there.
Well, the Western world is already doing that.
The birth rate has fallen precipitously in Europe,
falling in the United States.
In civilized countries, Western world,
the birth rate is declining rapidly.
There's some books out now about it.
I forget the name of the book.
But America Alone, I think, is the name of the book.
That if the birth rate continues as it is,
as it is already doing in Scandinavia especially,
the birth rate is so low that every civilization ceases
when it no longer can repopulate itself.
In our Western society,
the population is declining at a rapid rate.
People are putting off having children.
They're viewing it as an optional lifestyle.
In traditional America, there was no question about it.
Everybody got married and had kids.
Sure.
Everybody thought,
gee, should I stay single and childless my whole life?
I don't remember a single person contemplating that.
No.
Except people who joined nunneries.
Right. But it is a choice we have today.
Yeah, other than religious people.
Nobody thought,
it wasn't an option.
I think I'll stay single my whole life
and never have any kids.
I don't remember even thinking about it.
It was just presumed.
You would get married, have children,
and have a job,
and support your wife and children,
and that was pretty much the way it is.
Then you retire at 65 and you get a watch.
Then you hire an RV,
and you have a, what do you call those things
where you drive around the country?
Oh, yeah.
You're 65, you retire, see?
Yeah.
And you either rent or own a...
Motorhome.
What do you call it?
The RV, motorhome.
Motorhome, yeah.
Then you explore the U.S. for a year.
And then you come home
and you have your heart attack and die.
Exactly.
And then your wife goes and lives with the grandchildren
and becomes granny
so that the mother of the children can go to work.
So it all worked out very neatly,
and that's the way you presume life would be, you know?
Perfect.
Well, I want to thank you very much.
I really, I have many more questions,
but I also want to...
Oh, thank you so much.
Thank you for your precious time, so...
Yes, well, it was enjoyable.
Yeah, for me as well,
just to be with you here today.
Thank you, Dr. Hawkins.