I want to just conclude, and then a few remarks about why addictive persons react the way they do to any threat to their addiction.
You can see now, if happiness is something that lies outside of you, and if you've given the power over your life to that out there,
you can now see why you react the way you react to any threat to that, what you now believe to be the source.
Whether it's a relationship, that person might leave my life, the terror at that, I might lose my job.
You can see why people now react the way they react, and in knowing that, you know much better how to handle them.
A person here, if you tell them they cannot drink anymore, if you put them in a hospital, if you pull them into treatment, will go into grief.
What is the mourning and the depression about?
It's not because of the loss of alcohol for your life, it's because you're cut off from this state,
and the feeling that...
Well, one will never more experience that state.
The state of apathy and hopelessness that almost led to suicide came out of the conviction that I am now and forever cut off from any access to this state.
Not from alcohol.
By that time, alcohol made me throw up, you know?
Half an ounce of it had a violent and terrible negative effect.
I hated it, and I detested it.
So it wasn't grief and mourning over the loss of alcohol.
It was grief and mourning for the same reason that the person...
in Lost Horizon is in grief and mourning over the loss of that state.
That's why you go into fear.
Any threat to your supply, then, is not the fear of the loss of the drug.
It's the fear of the loss of this state, that you will have to live on this planet forever, the terror,
that you will never again experience a connection with that which is real, because it's their connection.
Another name for what's on top of the board is reality.
You will never experience...
that which is real again.
You will always be in the plastic world of the solar plexus and the foreverness-chasing of the forms of all that.
The desiringness is obvious.
That's part and parcel of the entrapment.
The anger.
If you stand between a person and his source of supply, he may well kill you.
And it does happen, because you are cutting him off from God.
It's really what you are doing.
His experience of that which is his own godness, his own higher selfness,
and...
people.
People will, of course, go into a rage.
So now you see the reactions to when we threaten a person's addiction.
When you call him to question, when you say,
George, don't you think you're drinking too much?
Look what you're bringing up in him.
You see what you're bringing up in him?
All of his survival.
You think you're experiencing God too much?
It's really what you're saying to him.
That's what you're saying to him.
So what you're implying now is a threat of his connection.
So when we get through talking today,
I'm sure you'll see a much different way,
of holding the situation,
and therefore how to approach the person,
so that they don't go into a panic over loss, or a rage,
or end up hating you.
They will divorce you, you know?
If you threaten their supply,
they'll say, well, you and I are not getting along,
and I'll have to leave.
They will leave out of anger, out of fear,
of the loss of their supply.
Any threat.
So I just wanted to clear that up,
of why people react the way they do to the loss.
What the loss is that they're feeling threatened.
It's not the drug, and it's not the alcohol.
You see, after a while, a person doesn't care what it is,
as long as it accesses this energy state.
You see, the psychological explanations of addiction
don't hold water clinically and experientially.
The psychological explanation is that they're running away
from reality, that the person drinks because they
are trying to escape their fears, their anxieties,
their angers, their resentments.
Thorazine will get rid of your anxiety for a couple weeks.
One good shot of Thorazine, and you won't feel nervous,
until probably Christmas time.
Antidepressants will get rid of your depressions.
A combination of the two will get rid of your anxiety
and your depression.
Pharmacologically, I did that for 30 years as a psychiatrist.
I got rid of people with psychopharmacology.
But nobody ever calls you for a refill.
Nobody ever says, Doc, my prescription
for antidepressants and Thorazine went down the toilet.
With Percodan, it always goes down the toilet, doesn't it?
Doc?
My four-year-old daughter ate the prescription
for Percodan and got thrown out with her diapers
because you gave me a repeat.
Nobody asked for it.
The elimination of these negatives
is not what is sought.
In fact, these are born willingly
in order to access this.
Because as the addiction goes on,
the experience of these higher states
becomes briefer and briefer.
And they're followed by prolonged states of agony.
And the person is actually willing and will accept.
That this is going to bring them prolonged agony,
even for a few moments of that experience.
And people will tell you when they come back into the program
who've been out,
I knew it wasn't going to last more than a couple of minutes.
But I just had to, what?
Reconnect with that experience.
At whatever the cost.
So it isn't the running away and people will say,
I didn't drink to escape from life.
I drank so that I could enjoy it more.
So that I could be more with life.
I didn't drink so I could avoid going to the party.
I went so that I could go to the party
and be more with life.
More with the party than I would have been
had I been in my normal state.
See, that which is sought now begins to explain
really what's going on.
These energy states are,
these fields of consciousness,
as I said, are impersonal.
And they totally dominate how we experience life
and how we experience the world.
So we did one column over here
called Brain Chemistry.
We can put columns all the way across the board.
So we're going to start marching across the board now.
And we'll put here the world.
How do these energy fields,
see these energy fields are so powerful
that they literally have control
over what happens in your life.
Because of what you're holding in mind.
See the difficulty in people and consciousness work
is to be able to grasp what is the power of mind.
That it is so all powerful that they can't even get
that it has power.
The energy field is so powerful that it literally
controls your perceptions.
It controls the experiences that comes into your life.
You might look at this energy field as a grid,
an energy grid.
This grid then
creates and controls what goes in and out.
So that a person,
in this state of apathy, let us say,
state of apathy,
when they look at the world,
what do they literally see?
What kind of a world do they experience?
They experience a world of hopelessness.
I can't even read that myself.
I don't know how you can.
Hopelessness.
I must be into apathy about my handwriting.
I just got that, right?
Hopelessness.
As you see, it is not hopeless.
It's legible.
But anyway, the energy field of apathy
creates a perceptual field
and an experiential
field in which what you see
is hopelessness in the world.
Everything you look at is hopeless.
You open the paper.
It talks about an international situation
with so-and-so, and you say,
well, that's hopeless.
It talks about world hunger, let's say.
Well, that's hopeless.
Hunger has always been with mankind,
so it's hopeless.
I mean, the mind will always find
intellectual rationalization to justify
the position of the energy field.
This relationship is hopeless.
You know?
My sister-in-law and her husband,
it's hopeless, that marriage.
So you begin to see hopelessness everywhere.
And because you're holding hopelessness,
it brings into your life
the experience of hopelessness.
If you think it's hopeless that you can train your dog,
you know, to do it outside,
you can be sure that
if you're holding that this dog is hopeless,
then you're never going to get him to the train
because you are holding a powerful energy field
that says he is hopeless.
The dog is coming from a much less powerful energy field,
and he will just go with your hopelessness
and do it on the rock.
So, from the most mundane
to the most profoundly spiritual levels, then,
our energy fields are dominated by that
which we're holding in mind.
Our relationships, you know, reflect that.
At this level down here of guilt,
we start going into the hells,
the hells going from there on down,
in which life seems to be an endless source of pain.
So, coming out of guilt, then,
we have the world of pain,
see, at the bottom.
Here we have the world of hopelessness.
It's hopeless that the pain is going to be inevitable
because from this level,
pain is part and parcel of all of life,
all of experiences accompanied by pain.
The next higher levels,
this is a sad world, see?
The world of grief,
it is a sad world.
So, the person in hopelessness walks down the street
and sees the hopelessness of society,
hopelessness of civilization,
hopelessness of man,
hopelessness of man's condition,
hopelessness.
This person, instead, sees sadness.
So, in walking down the street,
the person sees the children
and how sad that is,
knowing the pain that they're going to go through
as they grow up, etc.
You know?
The sadness, they look at the old people and say,
isn't that sad, the old people?
I was at a restaurant in Sedona
one time when that happened, you know?
I was looking at some people at the next table
and they looked to me like they were in a state of bliss,
they were all in a state of total oneness.
I mean, they were so connected
and had known each other for so long
and nothing needed to be said,
they just sat there blissed out with each other, you know?
Just so happy to be in each other's presence.
And the person with me said,
look at those old people, isn't that sad?
Isn't that sad? What was sad?
I don't know, I couldn't see anything to be sad about.
Apparently, the person was referring to
what they're projecting onto the situation.
There is no sadness there.
But when you open the paper,
there is much, if you are into sadness,
to be sad about, is that not so?
There is much to be hopeless about,
if that is where you are.
There is nothing but sin.
If you are into a refueled of 30,
in which the world of pain is the world of sin,
you see page after page of sin, right?
Sin and wrong, being wrong.
As you move up, you move into,
out of the sad world,
you move up into the fearful world.
And this is the world of fearfulness,
of course, everybody is familiar with,
from robbers, to muggers, to rapers,
to the IRS, to God knows what,
what people think of you, people's opinion,
whether you'll be well, help, wealth,
all the endless fears,
and the enormous amount of human energy
that goes in to then defend themselves
against these fears.
You know, a typical apartment in New York City
has six locks, and then it has
L-shaped crowbars around it,
and then it has alarm systems,
and then it has bars in the windows.
And when you go out, you may well get mugged,
is being held in mind.
And I know people who have been mugged six times in a row,
and still living in the same high-rise apartment building.
I've been mugged six times in this building.
I say, yes.
And when are you moving?
Oh, I'm not moving.
Why aren't you moving?
Well, how could I get a rent, you know, like that?
How could I get a rent like that?
So you see, there's the self-reinforcement,
the self-reinforcement.
Although it's fearful, the person has,
an investment that this is a fearful world,
because the investment in this being a fearful world
then makes everything in their life meaningful.
If they weren't living in a world of fear,
if they couldn't put that investment into the world,
then none of their life would make sense,
because they're busy preparing for old age,
incurring themselves with insurance,
and locking their doors,
and double-locking their cars,
and their whole life is one prevention
of the fearful happening in their life,
which, of course, makes it manifest.
Without the investment in fearfulness,
then the life suddenly has no meaning.
What is your whole life about now?
Just like this person's investment is into
this is a sad world,
and if you try to take that away from them,
now what is the context of their life?
Their whole life has been to prove
that this is a sad place,
where you lose everything,
where loved ones turn against you,
where bosses don't appreciate you,
where those whom you invest with cheat on you, etc.
Their whole investment.
So there's an investment
that's a secondary gain and a secondary payoff.
It merely reinforces it.
It's not really what sets the energy field
as far as intention goes,
but it's certainly the secondary payoff.
In psychoanalysis that's called secondary payoff.
The secondary payoff reinforces the field.
So you see that which you set by your own intention
then sets the energy of the field.
That field then determines what you see.
Now you see why people move.
They move so slowly in consciousness
because it's almost a deadlock,
and that which you think the world is
perceptually comes back to you as that,
which reinforces your belief
that that's the way the world is,
which reinforces again
that that's the kind of experiences that you have.
This person here,
this is a frustrating world.
Frustrating.
The person into that solar plexus wanting this,
desiring this is never happy.
They're endlessly critical.
They want everything to be different than the way it is.
The endless criticalness,
the endless lack of satisfaction,
the desiringness, the wantingness.
And now we can see why making more millions
actually is not very helpful.
See?
People who are dissatisfied,
they're worth 50 million,
and that same dissatisfaction,
that wantingness,
instead of saying,
wow, I've got it made,
I think I'll go and be happy
and bliss out someplace.
No.
The same energy that earned the first 50 million
now drives them to earn more millions.
There's no end point.
There's no point at which the person can feel complete,
satisfied, contented, happy.
Because happy,
as we said,
happiness is an energy field
that begins at around 500.
Down here,
what you get is satisfaction and pleasure.
So it's possible,
let's say in this energy field,
to get satisfaction.
You can plunge the dagger in your enemy's heart
and say,
oh there,
bastard.
It feels good at the moment that you do it.
You see,
you get pleasure
and you get satisfaction.
But that will not hold you up tomorrow morning.
So the person has to then go back in memory
to the satisfaction
and the person is then dependent on the memory
of these past experiences
because the present reality
is not the source of their happiness.
The awareness and consciousness
of the truth of who they are
and the present reality
is not the source of it.
The person in frustration then,
you see,
desiring this,
as we said,
is seeking more and more.
But because they're on this energy level,
we said that all that the world offers
is about 200,
all the money.
So 50 million will bring you
a solar plexus,
satisfaction,
and enjoyment
in which we calibrate.
The energy field of that is about 200.
And when you earn another 20 million,
you will still have
energy experience of 200.
So more and more sex,
going to bed with more and more people,
more and more status symbols,
more and more money
leads people who feel like that eventually
into suicide
and they become strange
when they get old
and they end up in the tabloids
with long fingernails and weirdness
and no one can understand
why with that many billions of dollars
this person is not happy
and instead they're paranoid,
totally isolated from life
and live a very wretched existence.
This eventually leads up to anger
because of the frustration
and so we get a world of conflict.
We get the world of conflict.
The angry person sees
life as many wars
and competition.
Everything is competition.
Down here at the bottom of the box
everything is lose-lose.
At the bottom of the box,
everybody loses.
At the middle of the box,
it's win-lose.
In the middle of the box then,
if I win, you lose.
And therefore relationships,
business dealings,
all transactions
are held in a win-lose
proposition in the mind.
Down here, everybody loses.
If I go back to live with the family,
they all lose.
They're miserable.
I'm miserable.
They lose their TV set.
It's lose-lose.
Dad's automobile insurance gets canceled
after racking it up again.
So it's lose-lose for everybody.
This is win-lose.
And the angry person then sees
everything as conflict, competition
and they have to guard against that.
So there's the chip on the shoulder
as one moves into pride and ownership.
With pride goes, of course, ownership.
And this is the world of status.
The world of status symbols.
See, this is all the same person
walking down the street.
See how differently,
I mean a different person
walking down the same street.
This one is seeing nothing but
that which he hopes God will punish
for its sinfulness.
This one is seeing the hopelessness.
Hopeless.
Look at those newspapers on the street.
Look at the dirt.
Look at the poverty.
Look at the...
They're seeing hopelessness, right?
This person is seeing the sadness of everything.
This person is scared as hell
walking down the street.
There's a mugger or a raper
or somebody out to get him every second.
And of course they spot him, too.
There's an old friend of mine
who used to be a mugger
before he started teaching
the Course in Miracles.
He's now dead, God bless him,
Paul Steinberg,
who was the national coordinator
of the Course in Miracles.
And Betty Martin used to talk a lot.
And he used to say,
as a mugger,
they just knew who was muggable.
They just stood in the doorway, he said.
And the one that would walk by
furtively like that,
they would instantly head for them.
They were very easy to knock over.
So the fearful, like, pull it.
Pull that which they fear to them.
So the world of status, then,
the person is walking down the street
and they see your Gucci shoes,
they get your Neiman Marcus handbag,
they get your Saks Fifth Avenue sweater,
they get your so-and-so hairdo,
they get your so-and-so glasses,
they get your, you know,
everything is status.
They want you to get in your so-and-so car,
hopefully not dented,
hopefully this is yours model.
Not only that,
but a Cadillac is not good enough.
It's one of the Cadillacs,
you know what I mean?
I find out that there are various
gradations within Cadillac, right?
You find out about these things
if you look into them,
that all these things
have gradations of status
within them.
I always thought a Cadillac
was something fantastic,
but I found out it's
which Cadillac, not any of them.
That attractiveness,
that seductiveness of things
which we project onto it,
which doesn't exist
within the thing itself,
which Madison Avenue capitalizes on.
See, when you smoke a cigarette,
that doesn't mean you're going to be
riding across the horse
with a 10-gallon hat
and looking like Mr. Seductress,
you know,
Mr. Movie Star.
It just means you're going to be
smoking a cigarette.
That's all it means.
You wear a certain perfume,
you're going to smell good.
It doesn't mean that all the men
are going to fall down
like dominoes, does it?
So, this whole energy,
this whole miasma,
this charisma that is
spun around purposely.
So, the world of status, then,
is very much that world
of all what we have projected
onto things, symbols,
because these things
are all only symbols
of taking care of that lack
of inner self-esteem,
which, if we had,
all these things would be enjoyable
only for what they are,
but not for what our fantasy
adds onto them.
In the world,
what does the world become like
at the level of courage, then?
What does the person
who is holding that energy field,
coming from that space,
how do they experience
the same street?
What is the world like?
It's a fascinating challenge.
It's exciting, is it not?
This is a world of exciting opportunity,
growth, challenge.
People in that space
will say,
well, I only got one life
and I want to experience
everything there is to experience.
I want to learn
what there is to learn here.
from my mistakes.
I want to learn
I want to face them,
handle them,
cope with them.
Whatever it takes
to handle this,
whatever it takes
to overcome this,
I want to do that.
So, life is seen
as an exciting,
the world is an exciting challenge,
and the experience of life,
then, is exhilarating.
So, a person in that energy level,
you know,
is excited to get up
in the morning
and see what is the challenge
of this day
and the empowerment
that comes out of that.
What happens
as you move up into neutral
is a world of okayness.
This is the world of okayness.
This is not a challenge anymore.
It's okay how it is.
It's okay if I get into college.
It's okay if I don't.
There isn't any resistance now
to how the world is.
The world is seen as okay.
One is into neutral about it.
It's sort of a detachedness
or it could be a non-detachedness.
To how the world is,
is all right.
So, there's a letting go
of resistance.
The benefit is
the release of a lot of energy
that was being held
in resistance down here,
a lot of that resistance
is let go of.
It's okay the way it is.
So, the downside
of this energy field here
is flat.
The upside is okay.
The downside is flat.
So, people say,
would you like to come to the party?
Well, yeah.
It's okay if you go to the party.
It's okay not.
So, very often you come across as flat.
So, there are people
who do a certain consciousness technique
that they are not even aware of,
but it dumps them into neutral.
And a lot of them are described
by other members of the community
as flat.
They'll say,
you know, these people are flat.
Please don't invite them.
Please don't invite them
because they are so flat.
The restaurants don't even like to see them
come in.
Because they are so flat.
It's okay if they leave a tip
and it's okay if they don't.
So, they don't.
So, the waitresses don't like them.
The downside is egocentric flatness.
The upside is an okayness
and a willingness to go along with.
So, its upside is that willingness
to go along with life
without resenting it,
without resisting it,
without getting depressed about it,
without being angry,
without being moralistic,
without getting into right and wrong about it.
So, it is a move up
towards acceptance.
And, of course, then we get,
as we move into acceptance,
we move into a world of harmony,
a world of easygoingness,
and we move into an energy field
of cooperation.
Competitiveness comes in about 180.
Cooperation comes in about 400.
So, as we move into acceptance,
we move into a world of togetherness,
of not togetherness
as Hollywood looks at it,
but a togetherness in which
things are included in,
things are included in.
Cooperation, then, means
the respecting of the rights of others
and the moving together.
So, a person in this energy level
who has a used car lot,
he hears that another used car lot
is opening down the block,
he goes into competition with that guy
and feels that he's going to lose.
See, he lives in a world of win-lose.
Consequently, he only can see
that he's going to lose
by the other used car lot opening up
on the same block.
This person up here in cooperation
when he hears another used car lot
is opening up on his block
says, fantastic,
that'll pull more used car buyers
from all over the city,
will become, you know,
the center for used cars,
and maybe the two of us
can get together and, you know,
advertise together.
And so, he sees working with that guy
that you pull in more
so that two used car lots
will now pull three times
as much customers, you see,
instead of twice as many.
So, he wants to join his energies
with someone else
so that everyone benefits
because he's in to win
and win-win.
So, this energy level then
is called win-win.
I sell more used cars
and so do you.
The more you advertise,
the better for me.
The more one art gallery advertises,
the better for all the art galleries.
So, what's better for an art gallery
than to have four or five
in the same building
because it pulls all the art buyers
from surrounding communities
into the same building.
Then we move up to the god of,
we move up to the world of,
we move up to the world of love.
What's happened over here, you see,
the process of one is one of revelation
and the release of certain endorphins.
So, now the person begins to see
and experience phenomena
that people down here are not seeing.
They're not seeing or experiencing
the lovingness which is also there.
This person may see the envy there,
but they don't see
that there is also love there,
that although there is envy,
there is also love.
The cancellation, the not seeing,
the unable to see,
the loveness that goes on
between all human beings.
This lovingness is going on
all the time between everyone
and every circumstance.
As this field opens up,
you see that.
As you say hello to the doorman,
you realize that there is
an enormous lovingness going on there.
You're loving the doorman,
he's loving you,
and you become a part
of his joy of life.
And when I used to live
in New York City on Fifth Avenue,
I had a whole routine of doormen
that I said good morning to.
And if you missed one day,
they would say,
where were you yesterday?
Something was missing from their life
that was a touch of joy
that that mutual greeting brought,
and I miss seeing them.
I miss seeing their happy face.
So, there is a lovingness
that goes on all the time
in all circumstances,
and it's just not visible,
it's just not visible
until the energy field reaches that point,
and then you begin to see that.
You begin to see that
going on all the time.
That it's true, there is this,
but there is also that.
See?
Down here it's either or,
and this begins to include in
so that you see the lovingness
that is going on all the time.
You begin to see the response of nature
to your own consciousness.
You begin to become aware
that that which is growing around you,
that the energy field
that you are vibrating out
is affecting all of life around you,
all of life around you.
I once killed a plant with consciousness.
It was once a plant that I hated,
and I didn't like what it stood for.
I didn't like what I remembered because of it.
I didn't like what it was doing in my life,
and I just consciously hated it.
And in about eight weeks it was dead.
Poor little plant.
It's like the plant I ever killed, like that.
All right, St. Peter, I did it.
I killed it.
Christ cursed the fig tree.
That's my out.
The energy that we radiate out then
affects all of life around us,
affects all of the life around us.
And as we move up to this level here,
we begin to see,
you cannot read that, of course.
I can't either.
What becomes revealed to you,
because this is called revelation,
is the incredible beauty of life.
As you move towards the top of the box,
it's incredible perfection.
Not aesthetic beauty.
Aesthetic beauty is something else.
Aesthetic beauty is a prettiness, etc.
It is a perception.
We're now moving out of the world of perception
into the world of knowingness,
the inner experience of the incredible essence of all things
as they express themselves through their perfection.
This came to me one day as I was sitting at home
and the kitty was sitting there on the rug.
And I looked at the kitty.
Instantly, I got...
You know, the kitty is sitting there
as an absolute perfect expression of its kittiness.
You know what I mean?
The kitty sits there and it is itself
perfectly, absolutely,
in the incredible beauty of its isness being what it is.
And you begin to see that everywhere.
Everybody has those experiences.
Everybody in the audience, I'm sure, has had those experiences.
It'll come when you're walking through the woods
and suddenly there's that inner silence.
There's a hushing.
You can tell when it's going to happen
because all of a sudden everything becomes hushed.
And then it slows down
and it's always to me like a slow motion movie.
All of a sudden the incredible,
magnificent,
perfection and beauty of all things
and you are one with that
and you are not different than that.
That that is what you are.
And you see the truth of all of it.
God is all that is.
So that incredible perfection, see?
And now how do you see people?
Well, the rose as it is half unfolded,
see, it's unfolding its perfection
and absolute perfectness.
The incredible beauty, the harmony,
its expression of that which it is,
the unfoldingness of that
is perfect in its unfoldingness.
And so you look at another human being,
you look at someone,
and you see the incredible beauty
and it radiates out from their inner self
almost like a light.
You see the incredible beauty
of the unfoldingness of that which they are
as they are coming into the awareness, let's say.
Stealing is no longer really good in my life.
Right, that's the lesson I'm getting.
Whatever the lesson is,
booze and drugs are driving me
into insanity and self-destruction.
Whatever that lesson is.
So those are the perceptual worlds, see?
The world being holographic, a hologram.
So you all know what a hologram is, right?
It's a three-dimensional representation
and it's done by the interface
of a laser light which is aligned photons
and normal light bouncing off an object
and creating a photographic plate.
And when you take a fragment of that photographic plate,
and you run a laser beam through it again,
it recreates the whole,
and it recreates the whole spatially
in space, three-dimensionally.
Everything is connected with everything else
because every person and everything
is off a vibration.
Obviously, these vibrations all interface, do they not?
If you give off a vibration
and you give off a vibration,
then the two must intersect somewhere.
Consequently, all things are connected
with all other things.
Everything is separate from anything else.
And that's the holographic dimension,
which is the title of several very popular books.
So this hologram then,
the world then, as we see it now,
from the description of these various,
these are really portholes.
These are perceptual portholes
in which we project out
that which we are holding
and then experience back our own projection
and say, see, isn't it so?
So the world then, the street that we were talking about before,
is like a hologram.
And starting at the bottom,
so as you walk around this hologram,
it goes from all the same hologram.
All depends on where you're looking at it from, you see?
It's the same world.
But looked at from here, it's pain and suffering.
Oh, look at the pain and suffering, isn't that terrible?
And the person literally re-experiences
this pain and suffering.
They literally see it on the face.
They hear it in the voice, in the sound,
in the vibration.
The person in this energy field
then gets back that energy field
and they experience that as what is so.
Just as the person up here is entranced.
You know, they look at the old people
and it almost makes you weep.
You look at them and you see the incredible
state of peace and joy that they are into,
and inner peace and joy
in the divine presence of each other.
So that's the world of perception,
that's the hologram of the world.
So how if we see how one experiences
the world that way, then how does one,
we'll extend that to God, huh?
And we'll see something of significance perhaps.
So how does God come out then
in all of this?
At the bottom of the box then,
out of that apathy,
you see,
we can say that God is dead.
The person who believes in death
and absolute destruction,
then God is dead.
So one can become a great philosopher.
If one has a high IQ,
what happens is that the mind
then tends to justify
one's inner position.
The intellect comes to the service
and tries to make explainable and acceptable
that the essence of human life is nausea,
that man is hopeless,
and that God is dead.
So you can become quite popular for a while.
Selling books that God is dead.
God doesn't really care about all that.
So the books go on.
So all you're really telling,
what are you telling the world then
when you write a book about God is dead?
What you're telling the world
is your own inner spiritual position
is one of hopelessness and apathy.
And therefore,
to that person,
there is no experience of God,
and to them,
God is dead.
To them,
The mind being so powerful,
if it holds that God is dead,
then I can assure you
God will be dead to that person.
God will be dead to the person
who holds that God is dead.
There will be no experience of anything
outside of one's own personal ego.
So through one's own inner experience,
one can say,
I've never experienced anything
other than that which is in the box.
Instead of therefore concluding
I'm a very limited person,
and not through conscience,
instead the person projects that
and says God is dead.
As we get up higher then,
we get to the conceptualizations
of the God of the worm.
The sinner you see is a worm,
and I being a hopeless sinner.
So these are people who hold that
there may be a God,
but he would not want anything
to do with me.
And many of those people indulge
in all kinds of self-flagellative activities.
You see,
the pursuit of suffering then
as an assuagement for guilt
and the hope that one will reach God,
indulging in an energy field of 30
ad infinitum
will not get you to the experience
of that which is at 600.
Therefore the futility
of wallowing in guilt,
and penance,
and sinfulness,
and guiltness,
because it takes you exactly
to the opposite end of the box.
God is not experienced
in an energy field of 30.
As you move up into grief,
the God who doesn't want anything
to do with you,
those are the people
who are abandoned by God.
Abandoned by God.
I called out to God
and there was no answer.
Abandoned and separated.
As we move up to fear,
then you move into levels
where God is the great punisher.
God is what you are terrified of.
God who is the avenger.
The avenger, the punisher,
he really becomes the persecutor.
He really becomes
that which is demonic.
The angry person,
the fearful person,
the person who is full
of sinfulness then,
can only conceive of a God
who is the same thing.
These are the demonic gods.
In this way of holding God,
he is capricious,
willful,
he is fitful,
and then God took pity
on the people of something or other
and decided not to demolish their city.
This God is also jealous.
So he's paranoid.
He's jealous and he's paranoid.
He's capricious, he's fitful,
and he's the ultimate in destruction.
He is not only out to destroy man
and his civilization,
he's out to destroy your soul.
So for one sinful thought,
he will throw you into hell forever.
This doesn't leave much room for the devil.
What would the devil do
with this kind of a God around?
His job has been taken away totally.
What would you fear
next to a God like that?
The worst has already happened.
Does it not?
This is really the God,
the demonic God of hell.
It's important because
the next energy level is one of pride
and this demonic conceptualization
of God is what often leads
to the next level.
On the level of pride,
you've got two positions possible.
Because of one's intuitive perception,
inner awareness of truth,
one throws this out.
And you may take then on one side
the position of the atheist
or the agnostic
who comes from the pridefulness
of the intellect unknowingly.
He thinks that's all there is.
He looks at the demonic conceptualizations
of God and says,
that God isn't even as good as my aunt.
My aunt is a more loving being than that
and throws out
the demonic conceptualizations of God.
And then concludes having done so
that he has thrown out God.
That's the error.
Mixing the map with the territory.
He confuses the map with the territory.
Having found an error in the map,
he throws that out thinking
he's now destroyed the territory.
Throwing out the baby with the bathwater.
Having thrown out,
what has he thrown out?
He's thrown out concepts.
But a concept is not the thing.
A concept is a symbol for the thing.
And in this case,
a distorted concept.
So he throws out the distorted concept
and now he has thrown out the thing itself.
That he has handled the matter.
So the agnostic says,
I won't take a position about it.
It's been handled.
It's all nonsense.
Forget it.
No proof one way or the other is possible.
Thinking that the intellect
is the sum total of human experience.
The intellect alone and unaided
cannot prove the existence of God
or disprove it.
And the other side of this field would be
the person who takes the opposite position.
That my knowledge of the truth
is the only truth there is.
Therefore you are wrong.
And you have the endless religious wars
and bigotries.
That go on from my position
and my way of seeing it
is the only truth and the only way.
So the arrogance,
the contempt,
see the denial of the truth
the truth is possible for anybody else.
The contempt for their spiritual positions.
The defensiveness about one's own spiritual position.
And therefore the endless angry
confronts and endless religious wars and all.
That go on on this energy level of pridefulness.
What happens when we get to the level of courage?
Because so far we've been below the line.
What happens when you get to the level of courage?
You start running into the God of AA.
See?
God of AA.
You start running into the truth.
For the first time now you're above the line.
And what is the truth?
The truth is you don't know anything about God, do you?
The truth is you have a lot of hearsay.
Written by very authoritative and impressive people.
Coming from authoritative sources.
And what is your own inner knowledge and experience of the truth of that?
It's zilch.
And so,
in AA they talk about the God of your own understanding.
The God of your own inner experience.
The truth that has come to you.
Not the truth that has come to some saint 2,000 years ago
on the other side of the planet
walking on the road to something.
When you're walking down the street and your knees go to water
and you need a drink or you need a fix
what happened to somebody else a couple thousand years ago
is not going to come to your aid.
What you've realized, the experience of that which is present within you now
is what you need right this second.
When the desire to drink or take a drug hits you
you've got to have something that is right here, right now
and rock-like connected within you.
That services you.
That's experienced within you.
That's real.
That is.
That is for you what is real.
And so you have the God of eminence
you know, in theological terms.
The God of transcendence is out there.
The God of transcendence is not of much use.
The God of transcendence is what everybody tried in religion.
And people in AA, including the priesthood that's there
will say the God of religion I tried.
I tried that.
The God who is out there was of no use.
I had to come into AA
to find the inner experience of the reality of the truth.
The God that is within me.
The God that in theological terms
is the God that was imminent.
That which is within myself.
So that's the God of AA.
God as you understand him.
And it's understood in AA
that as you grow, as you transcend in the box
your experience of God will then
parallel that inner growth
and your experiences will be commensurate with that.
You then move up, as we say, to a God of mercy.
This is the God of unforgivingness.
This is the God of forgiveness.
This is the God of love
and mercy.
AA says
it acknowledges only one authority
and that is a loving God.
And they mean by that a loving God expressed
through your own individual experience
and through the group consciousness.
Through the conscience of the group.
And so people learn to rely on sponsorship
because they ask
that through that
the will of God be known in their own personal life.
And they begin to experience
that that energy field which is coming through the group
is that expression of God
as it comes into their life
in the group experience.
The God of love, the God of mercy.
We start moving up into the God of oneness.
The God of oneness.
We start moving into that God of perfection.
And finally as we get near the box
the top of the box
we move into the experience of the presence itself.
The experience of the presence itself
which is often called illumination.
Those states described by the saints
usually associated with sainthood.
The total overwhelming experience
of the divine presence.
Ineffable.
Overwhelming.
Transforming.
Even a few moments of that experience
transforms one's life.
It was the experience of Bill Wilson of course
when Bill surrendered.
In that moment he asked
is there a God?
And if there is, I asked him
I asked to experience him.
And in one instant the room lit up.
And he felt the infinite presence.
And out of that moment
out of that second
all of AA was born.
All of the transformation that has occurred
in social consciousness.
The whole self-help group movement
in all of America
of which AA was the beginning.
They now run into the hundreds.
There is no human ailment or dilemma.
That there now is not some place
that you can go
and experience human understanding
and help from that absolute authority
that comes from only having lived that yourself.
The power of that.
See, having lived it yourself
gives you the power of healing that
which you have healed within yourself.
That whole awareness of that
came out of that one second.
What a powerful moment that was.
That moment transformed
all of therapy in the United States.
Transformed the whole mental health movement.
Took us out of hopelessness.
In this case, in the beginning
it was just alcohol.
The condition of alcoholism
was a hopeless condition.
Hopeless.
There was no cure for it.
There was no help for it.
Interestingly, out of Carl Jung
it was Carl Jung's integrity
and honesty
that accounted for the birth of AA.
Because when Roland saw Carl Jung
and thought he was cured
and then he went back to the United States
and he fell back into this state.
He went back to Carl Jung
and Carl said,
Alas, but my science, my art cannot help you.
But there have been times
in the history of mankind
where people with this affliction
have thrown themselves into a spiritual group.
And there have been reported throughout man's history
isolated cases
in which out of this experience
a recovery has been possible.
But I myself offer you no hope.
And so Roland went back to the United States
in a state of hopelessness.
Total hopelessness.
But he followed Carl's advice
and he went to the Oxford Groups.
The Oxford Groups being based on
basically the 12 steps.
A shortened version of the 12 steps.
It was out of that hopelessness then
that Roland surrendered.
And out of his surrender
he achieved sobriety
and then passed it on through Bill.
So,
you see the great power then
of surrender.
The space that allows for grace.
The great power of grace.
In just the moment that Bill
experienced that experience
all of what came forth
it's as though he
in opening himself to that power
of God within him
it's like he opened a window for the God energy
to flow into the planet.
And from that experience then
all of AA and all of it was born.
The enormous transforming power
of such moments.
And as a child I experienced some of these states.
And in teenage
I had a paper route one time.
It was in northern Wisconsin.
It was 20 below zero.
A terrible blizzard.
And to get out of the cold wind
I made a hole in a snow bank.
And as I sat in the snow bank
to get out of the blizzard
an incredible state came on.
Of infinite peace.
Incredible. Indescribable.
No one was touched by
God himself.
And all that I was was
replaced with light.
And this incredible infinite state.
And that which was personal
David no longer was
experienced.
And so those states
come into everyone's life
briefly or
in this case unsought.
But there was no context in which to hold it.
There was no context
in which this 14 year old
could hold that experience
meaningfully.
And when it returned in
January 1965
again
there was no pre-existing
context in which to hold
the experience of the presence
of the infinite omniscience
and omnipresence.
And that lasted for about a year
in that period.
And then in January 1981
again that state came on
running up in the numbers in the
United States.
And so having personally gone up and down
the whole scale
of those experiences
and then
coming out of that with
the desire to create
the context
to create a way in which to hold all that
so that all can be purified
within the way that you're holding it
so that it becomes a permanent
experience.
So that those people who've had those experiences
come out of it with that
realization.
With kinesiology we'll
just test the truth
of some of these experiences especially
the essential
point that I'm trying to make
and that is what one is addicted to.
Once you realize
what you are addicted to
what it is that you seek
by addicted to I mean that desire
to return to that experience
the overwhelming desire to return
to that experience.
Once you've experienced the presence
there is nothing that this world has to offer
at all.
It dissolves into a space
through it that you move through
to return to that experience.
All of life then becomes transformed.
It's all held within a different context.
And so
I thought we'd do some kinesiology.
How many here have never experienced kinesiology?
Maybe a third of the class.
Alright. Kinesiology is very
simple in that what you're testing
is energy and energy field
as it expresses itself in
particular power.
How about if I get a subject
a willing subject from the audience.
I may want to be the subject.
Who's seen kinesiology before?
Would you like to come up and just be the
person that I demonstrated with?
What kinesiology is testing
is the integrity of an energy field
as it expresses itself
in the harmony and balance of
the acupuncture system.
The acupuncture system
running down twelve meridians is everybody
in California
generally sophisticated about such matters.
Running down the
twelve meridians, right?
The minute you
see the minute you go above the line
when you go above the line you instantly
go strong. When you go below
the line you instantly go weak.
So it's a very neat way to test
the truth of anything by
asking for the integrity of the energy
field. What you're testing is the integrity
of an energy field. But
what we'll do today is demonstrate the truth
of some of the things we've been saying with kinesiology.
So what we do is we ask
the subject and we're going to do this as a class.
We'll become ones and twos.
One becomes the tester, one the testee.
It's important to experience the truth of this
because otherwise you'll just hold it in intellect.
Once you experience the truth of what we're saying
it really changes your life.
So what you do is you raise
your left arm, the person is being tested
and you have them look at the wall.
Look straight ahead at the wall
and don't smile at the person because
if you smile at them you're radiating out an energy
field up in here and you're affecting
the response. So you try to be
detached, clinically detached
and have them look at the wall
and then when I press down you resist.
Okay, thank you.
Now, you can let her down.
When you test, you test with two fingers
and what you're testing is for a general feeling
of the person's muscular strength.
You're not trying to break their arm and see.
You know. You're just trying to
get a feeling for their power, for their energy.
You press down with two fingers.
Two fingers.
When you do that, I'm going to ask him to hold
something in mind.
Okay, I want you to hold in mind somebody you don't
like or somebody you've experienced
unpleasantly or something in your life
that's not so great.
Now that is something that is below the line.
Somebody he fears, somebody he hates,
an experience that is unpleasant,
a regret, a grief.
Okay, now I'd like you to hold in mind
someone you love.
It could be your kitty, it could be your dog,
it could be Jesus, it could be your mom.
Got it? Thank you.
See?
That which is above the line, the truth,
love being that
not different than that which is the truth,
empowers.
That which is a lie weakens.
And the integrity of the energy
fuel can be tested out instantly.
It has widespread
applications once it begins to dawn on
you that you can get the truth of
things that are beyond your personal opinion.
Before you read
a book, before you wander in the metaphysical
shop and decide that
Swami so-and-so is going to be your savior,
it's very neat to test out
what his integrity field is and what his intention
is and the space that he's coming
from. So you'll find
that it has very important
clinical applications and we'll
experience some of them today.
So let's divide up into ones and
twos and we're going to test out three or four
propositions and
then at the end you can ask a secret
question and get an answer to that which you've
always wanted to know the truth of.
And get a
reasonable assurance that you're
getting the truth. So why don't we just
divide up into ones and twos
and all of us stand up.
Number one is going to be the tester,
number two is going to be the testee,
then we'll switch. Number two will
become the testor, number one
the testee.
So here's what I'd like you to do is
to not say anything. This can all be done
in silence. If you just listen to me it'll go
very fast and it'll be quite a rewarding
experience. Just decide who's number
one. Number one put up your hand so we
know who's your number one. Okay, you are the doctor.
And number two is the testee.
So the first thing I'd like you to do
is just to ask them to hold out their
arm and test
their arm just like I did with him
with two fingers. And don't forget
you're not trying to break his arm, their arm.
You're just trying to get a feel for their power
and their strength. Try to be detached
and impersonal as though it was
a clinical research.
So you look
at the wall and just
ask them to resist.
When they're ready, have them resist.
So you get a feeling for their power and their energy.
Okay? Got it? Okay.
Now everybody then, the first thing I'd like
you to do, those who are being tested, is hold
in mind or picture or
remember something or someone
that's unpleasant in some regard.
Some loss that you've experienced,
an accident, something coming up in the
future that you wish you didn't have to face,
a ticket you got for
something. If all fails
picture yourself tied to a railroad track in the
train is bearing down and getting closer.
Someone you don't like
from the past. Someone you don't like
in your present life. Somebody you fear.
Somebody who scares you, really.
Somebody who really scares you when you
come up against it.
Has everybody got that?
Now I'd like you to hold something
or someone that you love.
As I said, it could be your kitty, it could be your
dog, it could be your mom, lover, girlfriend,
mom, dad. You can change
arms if you want. First get acquainted with the
power of that arm.
As I say, don't push so hard you wear them out.
With two fingers
you can get a feeling. They're either weak or they're strong.
That's all you need to know.
There's got to be somebody you love.
Some value that you cherish.
Some space that is very
sacred to you. Anything that
is loving.
That's an amazing
experience, is it not?
The next thing I want to test out is a proposition.
So get ready to be tested.
I'm going to give you the proposition. I want you to hold this
proposition in mind.
And then when you have got the proposition in mind,
nod your head so that the person can
press down and test you.
The proposition is that the drugs have the power
to get you high.
The power is in the drugs.
It's drugs that get me high.
It's drugs that have the power to create
that experience within
either myself or those who are addicted.
Makes no difference.
It's just an alternate proposition
so you can get ready to be tested
and hold this concept in mind.
The truth is that the drugs remove the obstruction
to the experience of that which I am
and allow me to experience the bliss
of that which is my own higher self.
The drugs block the not-self
and allow me to get closer to
the experience of my own inner self.
The power comes from my own inner
godness.
That is the source of the power
of that experience.
Now the next thing is you're going to ask
a question.
Anything you always really want to know
the answer to.
If you have an addictive problem
and you have a question in your mind
you can say,
Am I really addicted?
Am I really an alcoholic?
Do I really have a problem with that?
You can ask any question you want
and then just indicate to the tester
as long as it's answerable by yes or no.
So you don't have to share this question
you can just keep it in mind.
If there's anything you really want to know,
ask either that.
Is the boss planning to fire me?
Should I really see a doctor about that?
Whatchamacallit.
Whatever you really want to know, ask about.
Does my mother really love me?
I mean, you know.
Is my kitty really pregnant?
I mean, any kind of question you want.
Am I really pregnant?
Okay, now we'll switch.
We'll switch and again
if you're silent I'll just guide you
through it and we'll do it quickly.
First test the strength of the person
so you get a feel for it.
Just use two fingers.
Have the person resist.
Resist with all your strength.
Okay, got that.
The next thing you hold in mind
is someone you don't like.
Something you don't like.
Something painful.
Painful memory from the past.
Something you wish hadn't happened.
Something you fear might happen.
Somebody who blows your mind
when you see them.
The devil.
Hold the devil back there.
Alright, now in contrast
just hold in mind the presence
the memory of someone you love.
Their image, their thought.
A memory of being with them.
Sound of their voice.
What they feel like to you.
What they look like to you.
Hold it and test that.
It's really dramatic, isn't it?
I mean it is so definite.
It is so strong.
It is so powerful.
It is so overwhelming.
Okay, the next thing because we're
into the consciousness about addictions.
We want to hold in mind, get ready to be tested
and then hold this concept in mind.
It's the drugs that have the power
to get me high.
The experience of bliss comes from the drug.
Drugs have the power to create that experience.
Test the truth of that.
Okay, now hold the contrasting proposition in mind
to be tested on this one.
That the drugs block off
the experience
of my lower self and allow me
to experience the energy field
or get close to the energy field
of that which is my higher self.
The experience in consciousness that comes about
from the use of drugs
from intoxication
is literally the experience
of my own inner presence.
And now everybody gets a secret question.
Or questions.
Secret question.
What do you really want to know?
Let's face the truth of the answer.
The answer you get now, of course,
is the way it is now.
It's not set in cement.
So if you get an answer that you don't like,
realize it's not set in cement.
That you have the power to transform
that entire relationship
or situation
and transform it within your life
so that you can get a retest sometime later
holding it from a different space
and get a different answer.
But that is the way you're holding it now
and the way it's going to come out.
The way you're holding it now.
So that's sort of a fun experience, isn't it?
A way of
ascertaining the integrity
of an energy field.
What you're testing is the energy field.
So if you hold something or someone in mind
you're asking what is the
integrity of this person's intention
or energy field in my life.
Generally, the experience
that I get when I work with families
is the same as we do with the addicts.
With the people who have become addicted
we've been doing it for a couple of years
at the villa and the answers have always
been the same.
When we ask, does the drug have the power
to create the experience
within yourself, they all go weak.
And when we say
is the truth that the drug
blocks that which you are not
so you can experience
or at least get into the ballpark
of the experience of the truth of your
inner godness, they all go strong.
So at least within the addict population
which is the one I've had the experience with
it's been verifiable right across the board.
It is obvious
as you listen to
what we're saying today
that no chemical has the power
to create a 600 experience.
What are the energy fields
of some of the things in our daily life
and our daily experience
and what can we learn from that
and how can we use that
in a way that's beneficial.
How can we end up holding
this information in such a way that
healing comes out of it.
That being the purpose of the communication.
We notice that
the science and medicine
that which pertains
to the mind, to the intellect
to the mind with a small m
that which pertains to the intellect
and calibrates in an energy field
of about 425.
See that's the difficulty of the atheist
or the agnostic.
Coming from an energy field of the intellect
which is 425
how can you have any experience
of that which is outside the domain
of the intellect and calibrates
at 600 and up.
That which is 425 cannot experience
that which is 600 and up.
At 450
we run into that
which we call harmony.
That which is cooperative.
So competition is 180.
We say competition
is 180
and cooperation
is about 450.
Actually cooperation runs about 480.
Harmony,
comparison as they move through
education
you might say
moves up through into that which is harmonious
and that which is cooperative
and at 475
we see is the calibration
of hope.
In AA they talk about
we share our experience, our strength
and our hope.
What are the energy fields that are being
shared?
Our experience of having gone through this whole experience.
The hope.
The inspiration that comes out of that.
Our experience, our strength
and our hope.
And strength being over here.
As you move up into
these heart levels then
at about 530
we have simplicity.
In which the complexities of life
are now experienced because of one's
inner values
and they're held in a different way.
They're held in a different way.
And at 540 you have gratitude.
So you know 12 step groups
talk a great deal about gratitude.
Gratitude to the program.
Gratitude to Bill.
Gratitude
gratitude for their sobriety.
Gratitude to the grace of God.
Therefore the gratitude itself
because this is the same
energy level as healing.
Healing and AA and gratitude
all come out about the same.
That which is grateful
that which is healing
and AA all come out about
the same. So gratitude then
is really a way of self healing.
To be able to hold a thing
from gratitude.
Now you begin to see then how
some of the things in the lower part of the box
can be healed.
They can be healed
from the way in which they are held.
From the way in which
they are held.
So we said that worldly success
was about 200.
That doesn't mean you should throw out
worldly success at all.
What it means is
one can be grateful for that worldly success.
If one can say
thank you God
for this enormous abundance.
For the enormous opening I have
to utilize
that which I have power over
to communicate that which is helpful to the world.
So
to hold from love then
one's sexual opportunities
one's power in the world
one's status. All these things.
Now the way you hold them
begins to transform them.
The way you hold your own past.
If you say thank you
as painful as it was
I could not have learned that lesson
without having experienced it out.
It was possible for me to learn that
some other way I would have.
Obviously because I experienced it out
for me it was necessary
to move from this space to that space
to have lived it out
and experienced it through.
So it opens then
an awareness of how we can begin
to hold things
so that they become healing
so that they become sacred
because of our touch
because of the touch of how we are holding them.
And at 570 then
you become aware
of that inner beauty
the incredible beauty
in all of creation.
And that beauty
and its perfection
the incredible beauty
we see that the source of it
is that which is sacred.
The sacredness of all of creation
is the sacredness of life itself.
The incredible beauty
of its expression
and its absolute perfection
as one gets near the top of the box.
And out of that
out of that experience
then comes compassion.
The importance of these three things
of courage
of love
and of compassion
because those are points of decision
which you can access
the higher states of consciousness yourself.
To face the truth about things
even though it may be painful.
Your commitment to lovingness
as the way you wish to be
as the experience
of how you want to experience your life
and how you value it
the lovingness for your own life
and that of others
and the development of compassion
because of the revelation
because of the release
then on the physical plane
the endorphins
the opening into the understanding of the human heart
to clear up something else
that came up during the break
that release of the endorphins
is coming from one's spiritual position.
It's important to realize
that the body
and all that goes on with it
is coming out of life.
It is life that creates the body.
It is one's spiritual position
it is that commitment
and the exercise of that lovingness
which releases the endorphins
it is not the other way around.
You can't, in other words
take endorphins and find yourself
in a high spiritual state.
That's a confusion of causality.
This world being the world
a manifest world of the expression
of that which you are holding.
It really is not linear
it is not as though there are two different levels
it is not as though
what is being held in mind is now
cause and what is being expressed
in the world is effect.
Although in a certain way
of holding it that would be so.
Actually they both go on
simultaneously cause being
outside of the field of both.
Cause is outside the field of both.
That which is cause
creates both its representation
in the manifest world
and the way it is held in mind.
Is that interesting?
I get going on causality
that's a whole other trip.
But that compassion then
is that desire
that ability
that dedication
to understanding.
To understand the heart
and as you see it's
way beyond condemnation
it is beyond right and wrong
it is an understanding
of the nature and the essence
of life itself.
And just at that level then
at 600
comes about things that we call wisdom.
And
intrinsic to a person at that level
is an inner gentleness.
And with gentleness
goes strength.
That which is the most powerful
in the universe
is the most gentle.
And as that experience comes into you
the thing that totally
wipes you out
is its profound gentleness.
It is so exquisite
as that awareness
dawns on you
that it's almost
insufferable to experience it.
That is the response
of the remaining ego.
As the presence
as you become aware of the presence
it disappears
as the presence becomes all it is.
But in the beginning
there is that feeling of awe
and the incredible nature
of that exquisite gentleness.
Also
its incredible power.
It is not only exquisitely
gentle beyond description
but its power
is indescribable.
Its power is
absolute and therefore
the experience is curiously
one of this
exquisite gentleness
the presence of infinite power
and at the same time
it is rock-like.
I've never read that in any place but
there's a rock-like
nature to the quality
of that which is exquisitely
gentle and also
all-powerful and
perfect.
And in that level
comes that which we have
at the top of the board
that which is beyond all
the peace of God.
And as that state approaches
the intrinsic innocence
with all things
which is part and results
in compassion.
Exquisite awareness that within
that the essence of all things
in its perfection
is that absolute innocence.
How can you see
that innocence?
It's as though the mind
is like a computer.
of the child.
What happens to the mind
of the child? The mind of the child
is in a state of innocence.
And then what happens
the mind of the child
is like the hardware you might say
is that the programs of the world
come in like the software
and begin to program it.
And what makes the child programmable?
What makes the child
programmable?
Is it not its intrinsic innocence?
It's because you love your mother
that whatever she says
you incorporate as your own.
Because you love your dad
because you love your country
you love your teacher
because you hold them in respect and honor them
that's why you believe what they say.
It's because of the love of your peers
and wanting to be one of them.
Out of your love for them.
So that intrinsic innocence
which is there
never changes.
The hardware of the computer
never changes no matter what software
floppy disk you put in, right?
That which is the computer itself
never loses its innocence.
You just can hear different programs
put in a different program.
And so
the awareness of the presence
of that within
because it never leaves you.
And that's what's listening to my voice
right now, is it not?
Is it not your own intrinsic innocence?
That is listening
is very second.
Understanding, listening,
believing, incorporating
in faith and trust
that that which is being spoken is the truth.
Even if you disbelieve it
then you reject it
from some opposing program.
And where did you get the opposing program?
You bought that out of your innocence, didn't you?
Even if you disagree violently
with what I say
what's disagreeing with that is a program.
That's your own innocence you bought.
So your innocence is unsullied
whether you agree, whether you disagree.
It makes no difference.
The truth of that which you are
is totally unchanged.
is unchanged by the experiences
that go through consciousness itself.
Therefore the realization
that that is its nature
that that is the nature of what you are
of what we all are
the nature of what we all are
is totally unchanged.
It is exactly that which we have always been
and always will be
that that innocence is
unassailable
and not be defended.
It is what it is.
The undoing of all that it is not
allows one to experience
the truth of that which it is.
And that is the purpose
of all spiritual work
is the removal of that which we are not.
So it is the removal
of the clouds from the sky
so that we can experience the sun
always shining.
In the proposition we were testing
with kinesiology
what we were really asking was
does the removal of the clouds
cause the sun to shine?
Does the removal of the clouds
Or is the sun always shining
and when we remove the clouds
we are aware that it is always there?
That's really comparably
the metaphor of what we were asking.
The seeing of this
entire way of holding clouds
and things then
reveals to us
and after this lecture
things will begin to unfold
because the mind is always looking
there is that within us
which is self-healing.
It is always looking for that
means, those tools
the ways of healing ourself.
Because it begins to dawn on us
that there are ways now
of holding things
that will bring about a healing
that will come out of merely the way
of holding it.
The healing of many of these things then
is that you are holding
from the lovingness
from the truth of that which you are
that which you are not
but you are holding it
from that which is greater
rather than from that which is lesser.
When we are identifying with
that which is lesser
we can't look at it
because we think I am that
because of the false identification
with the small self.
I cannot look at that within myself.
If our motivation
if our intention is
the healing within ourself
and when we do it within ourself
we do it within everyone
because we are the world
we are everyone.
The whole implication
of the holographic conceptualization
is that it reveals
that you are everyone
that your consciousness is all that is.
So as we heal
that within ourself
we heal it within the world.
Some people get into a conflict
about myself
and or the world.
That which is myself is not different
than that which is the world.
When I heal it within myself
then I heal it for everyone.
As each of us heals these things within ourself
we raise the consciousness of the world.
Everyone benefits.
So when we heal ourself
it's a win-win situation
because out of that lovingness
to perfect the awareness of that
which we are
then comes the power.
Empowerment.
So the intention coming from this level
empowers the person
to heal that within oneself
which needs to be healed.
It's coming out of the way
that it's being looked at.
It's coming out of the way it's being held.
Out of that we begin to see
that whatever we were
in the past was necessary
for us at that moment.
It is out of the desire
for happiness.
It is out of the love of life
that all of it came. Did it not?
Let's say, angriness.
What is the angriness coming out of?
The angriness
is coming out of your love for life.
Is it not? And the thought
that someone is going to impair it in some way.
So the way to get out of the guilt
about that
is to look and see that underlying it all
is that innocent,
naive love for life
the thought that
this is blocking my happiness.
All the negative feelings
are coming out of the thought
that my happiness is out there
and something is interfering with it.
I always say, and I don't know whether it's true or not
I invite everybody to dial this in
and test their kinesiology
that you can't really love unless you've hated.
If you don't care enough
about life to hate somebody
who you feel is threatening life itself
then you will never rise
to the level of loving it.
If you're in apathy
if you don't care enough about life
you wouldn't even get angry, would you?
I mean, it's hopeless.
It's so sad that you can't even get involved in it.
Kitty Genovese or whatever it was
people just withdrew from the field.
There wasn't the commitment of life
enough to even be angry about it
to even do anything about it.
Everybody went into apathy.
So when you look back
at the things that you condemn within yourself
the way you heal it, as you say
in the becoming awareness
of that which I am
it was necessary for me to experience that then.
But at that time
that's what I needed.
At that time, that's what had to be with me
because who I was at the time
thought that that was the best thing to do.
And doesn't the mind in its innocence
always choose
that which it thinks is the best thing to do?
Does your mind ever do anything else?
It always chooses what it thinks at the moment
is the best decision, does it not?
Even if it gets into an impulse
that it hates itself for later
it still makes the decision
that for me at this time
the best thing to do is to throw the brick
through the son of a bitch's window.
Later I may feel guilty about that
but at that moment the feeling
that I must express my aliveness
in that form that is meaningful to me
may well be necessary.
I'll never forget the first time
I met a guy coming in
out of the parking lot
and I was always a very
I guess what you call people pleaser, right?
And so we got into conflict
about who had the driveway
and so I gave him the finger.
Well I'll tell you
I was ecstatically happy. I had never done that before
in my life. I never told somebody
to go you know where. Never did it.
I was fifty something
years old before I finally did that.
And I was so pleased with myself
you see, that I'd gotten up to that
you know, not out of hopelessness
not out of fear
not out of fear that you won't be a
spiritual person if you do that.
You won't be a spiritual person man
if you tell somebody where to go.
But I got such a, I got hysterical
laughing over it you know. First I told him where to go
and then I broke down and I almost went off the
road laughing at the whole thing
because it was such fun. And then I went
around doing that a little while because I was getting off on it
and then finally gave up on it but
it was really fun to do that.
You know where to go. You can go there.
Hey, here, look. It was really
great fun.
Necessary, necessary to know that I
could do that. Necessary that I could hold
it that way. That I could
experience it in a self-healing way.
See? And not go into guilt
about it and self-condemnation.
So, that which we've been
was necessary in the evolution of
our becoming that which we are
becoming aware of. All of that
is necessary. For the
addicted person then, in
the interest of his own consciousness growth
it is absolutely essential
and it is absolutely necessary
in this lifetime, at this time
that this be what
the person is experiencing.
Absolutely critical to their
life. That confrontation
with the absoluteness
of facing the truth about yourself or
dying. And that's what it takes.
That's what it takes a lot of us.
That's what it took me. It was in the
teeth of death itself
that the transformation took place.
It took all of it. It took all of it
to bring about that surrender.
And some people
know the ego is not so strong.
It doesn't take that severity, that
degree. In the old days in the
AA, it was thought that everybody had to reach
the pits of hell before they
gave up. And of course we know
that is not true.
It is not at all true that anybody
can learn from this education.
And from the education, from
this awareness itself, it raises the
bottom so that people don't have to go
to this level called destruction
before they finally surrender.
Okay, we've got time for
a few minutes for questions and answers.
So, anything that you want to
discuss or you'd like to have elaborated,
you can just
bring it up. Yes, please.
Right.
The energy field,
and I didn't talk much about that, so I'm glad
you brought it up.
The question was, why do we
have to keep moving up and down in the field?
And it is something that
we didn't discuss before, and I'm glad you
sort of brought it up. That the energy
field comes about as a result of
one's commitment. In other words,
I have the power
to create a certain energy field
by my free will,
by my agreement, by my assent,
by the alignment of my goals,
my purpose, my intention.
Now, that sets the power of the field.
Now, within that,
there may be daily variations
like the stock market. There is
jiggles up and down. So a person who is
committed to lovingness
may still experience these feelings.
And feelings, as you know,
move very rapidly. Sometimes
change half a dozen times without
a second, those fleeting
fluctuations. So this is sort of
scintillating, changing. Those
who see auras, especially auras
in color, see that scintillation
of the constant shifting of the emotional fields.
But the person's commitment
hasn't changed. Their commitment
hasn't changed.
You are the same person before and after
the experience. The person
who changes their commitment, that is a different story.
But your commitment
is the same. So you can be committed
to a loving relationship
and suddenly get mad as the
devil at them. Suddenly angry
at them and that will flare up
from the solar plexus. But that
doesn't change your intention.
It doesn't change your commitment.
You can be mad at your boss. That doesn't mean you're quitting
today. It just means that you're angry at him today.
Your commitment to do a good job
and your commitment to work for this company or your
commitment to your career
is going to remain the same.
Some days you may be enthusiastic about it.
Some days you may feel it's hopeless.
I'll never become a whatever.
So you can fluctuate in the
scintillating emotionality
but the commitment
remains the same. The commitment
remains the same and therefore your power
is in the field of the commitment
because it's the commitment that holds the power.
It's the commitment
that has set the energy field.
The energy field, see let's
say one time at the
bill a girl said to me, after hearing your lecture she said
I really feel bad about my
resentments now. And I said, well that's
easy to get rid of. You can get rid of
that very easily. Just hate the son of a
bitch. I mean if you set this as
your goal then
resentments won't make you feel guilty.
If you set this as
the goal then
so whatever level we set for ourself
what becomes unacceptable
to us is that which is below it.
In a group where
angriness is okay
then you don't feel upset about resentments.
But when you move up to a commitment
to loving this, now resentments
become painful. And
the desire is to be rid of that resentment
as quickly as possible.
Some people have utilized
this intuitively
in grand
social demonstrations.
So if you want to remember how to utilize
these energy fields positively
just remember
the social demonstration of the black
people in the United States.
In my lifetime I watched them move
from the bottom of the box all the way to the top.
When I was young
they all lived at the back of the bus. Black people
belonged at the back of the bus.
And they were into hopelessness and apathy.
And that hopelessness and apathy
was represented in the physical
attitude and the way they
walked and the way they shuffled
in that hopeless apathy
because nothing was ever going to get better.
It became a caricature
a stereotype on the stage
of that walk
of hopelessness and apathy
and the grief over
the grief over
how men express
primarily by the women
over the hopelessness of the situation
over the cost, over the realization
that her children would never have a chance
in this world. All of this
controlled by the tremendous fear
the fear of the lynch mob. If the black man
protested he got hung from the
nearest tree. And so the intimidation
and the terror, progressive
systematized terrorization.
Then along came television
and the submerged
part of the world, the third world
the black people in America began
to see, began to see
through television that which the rest
of the world has. They began to see
what other people have. The kind of houses
they lived in and the way they
the style, the lifestyle, etc.
Out of that desiringness
and wantingness came anger and the frustration
of that. And then we saw
the arriving of black pride
the pride in one's blackness
now. No longer the shame
the self-effacement
the fear about it
we saw the black anger and the
angerness. The energy
the upside of that angerness
was then
through the intuition, through the inspiration
of some of their great leaders
led into black pride. Out of the anger
then the energy of the anger
is built into black pride.
There was some expression of the downside
some of the teenagers, the expression of the
angerness in the form of anger
and destructiveness as
happened also in pride.
But a great, enough of that energy
was utilized in a positive way.
And so out of the pride you saw the courage
to face and cope with
what are the problems that have to be handled
here to change our way of life.
And there you saw
the legal battles and you saw
the bringing in
of the courts and of social conscience
and the enlistment
of the energy and the power
of the white population
as they become inspired to
a higher view of man.
So we saw them move through courage
up through
the acceptance of that which needs to be
handled and needs to be done
and the acceptance of equality on the part of
white people who had never even thought of it in their
lifetime now began to think
that perhaps black people are the same
equal to us and the emergence
of love. And you saw the success
of many social movements and of course
the black people who were now once at the back of the bus
in my lifetime are now mayors of cities
and great entertainers and millionaires
and leaders of industry
and senators and congressmen
and all the rest. So not all
of their population but certainly a size
of Lamont has demonstrated
how to utilize
these levels of consciousness.
How to use the upside. How to use
the energy of it. How to
utilize the energy of the anger and the
indignation to mobilize
social forces to bring
about changes in the senate, in the congress,
in the governors, in the
laws on the municipal
state federal level.
How to enlist the moral support
of the country. You know
great power coming out of that
inspiration, that dedication
to a cause that is greater than one's self.
The dedication to a cause
that is greater than one's self
then allowed the power
to express itself in that social
transition. In powerful
social changes. Yes?
That's a very good point.
That when you fall below
that which you are committed to, what you run into
is pain. And therefore it is
self-educating. You know that
it's out because it doesn't feel right anymore.
See when you're dedicated
to hating this, you're dedicated to
hating this, everything below it is
painful. When you're dedicated to
pride let's say.
When you're dedicated to pride then fear
is no longer acceptable. And that's
part of the passages of the adolescent
boy. It's part of the passages
of becoming
the United States Marine Corps let's say.
The expression
or the overt acknowledgement
of this is no longer acceptable
because now what you're committed to
is pride. They'll say brace up boy.
Brace up boy.
Those are only bullets.
They'll tear your guts to pieces.
I mean they'll only go through you.
What's to be afraid of?
And so
and then when I was in the Navy I was on a
minesweeper and of course we swept
mines in the East China Sea so
minesweepers were blowing up all over
so it wasn't you were going to get bullets
you were going to just get blown up.
So we all went into neutral.
We all went into
if you blow up you blow up and if you don't
you don't.
When we went out to sweep mines you
battened all the hatches and you had to take your
stuff, whatever stuff you needed for the day
from below you know.
Because they battened the hatches nobody was allowed to be
below hatches because if you blew up
the compression there would like, I don't want you to go
into an anatomical description but
you stayed above decks.
But that was the way it was handled.
It was handled in
so fatalism we might add that as a
neat way of neutral.
The fatalist then is a good expression
of that energy field.
If you blow up you blow up and if you don't you don't.
And you know what difference does it make?
I mean when you go
so that's the fatalistic
and many men in our
society have developed that
you know as a result of their experiences in the war
it was really the only way you could handle it.
I mean you can't walk around in a panic all day long
and it's socially unacceptable.
There's nothing to be angry about.
You can't be into apathy
I'll tell you that.
And lovingness just doesn't seem
the lovingness is the
bonding that goes on between the men
and so there are those profound
bonds of love which last
many years. This last year I
happened to get together with a friend I hadn't
seen in 40 years who was
with me in the navy back in
1945.
But 40 years later that
commitment, that bonding of love
had not changed when I
saw him or loved him just as much
as I always had as though 40 years had
never gone by. So that
bonding and that love. So that was the strength
then, the strength
out of which that strength is coming
to handle the threat to life
itself on its most dramatic
expression from moment to moment.
So all these things have their
positive
way of holding them positively.
It's certainly better to be detached
certainly better to be into fatalism
than to be in a state of panic
which is paralyzing you.
Because in neutrality we can function
and we all do.
...
and knowing that it's there
and it's attainable
and yet having setbacks
and conscious
awareness and working of
within my mind
the things I need to do to come back
to that higher level.
The desire to return to that
level. What? What? Yes.
Yes. Am I
a creature of nature and
I go back there automatically?
Can I use my left brain to bring myself
back there? Can I apply
logic to
the attainment of ecstasy?
What we've been talking about today is
is a balance between
left and right brain.
Being, having grown up as a left
brain person, then having become
excessively a right brain person
and then coming back to balance.
What we try to do is
express all of this in a balanced way
because the left brain
so often will take
the position that the right
brain way of viewing things
is illogical.
And so by the research we've been
doing you see that
the truth is approachable equally from
either left or right brain.
Once the left brain
begins all of this, it now no longer
has any objection. It is logical,
it's scientifically
demonstrable, but
they're generally, you can test them with
kinesiology, you can get the same,
you can test each other with kinesiology, you can just say
you know, if I hold in mind pride
is it over 150, or 160, or
170, or 170, about 175 a Sunday
a week? It is not above 175.
So you can set these and verify
them experientially, the truth of this
within yourself. That removes
the objections of the left brain.
To the fact that this is not logical.
See?
Nobody was a more skeptical left brain person
than myself. I didn't believe
any of this. You see the mystic
is not, the wisdom of the mystic
is not accessible to the left brain
person. Because the mystic
experiences it, but he can't
communicate it to a left brain person
in any way that's useful to the left brain person.
And therefore
what we tried to do is translate
it into language.
Because the truth is the truth.
If the truth is true, then it's true on all levels.
And it should be as understandable from
one side as the other.
Death being zero, that's rather obvious, right?
Okay.
If you start with the proposition
that death is zero,
then you can use like kinesiology
that we use today. You can say if death is zero
then what is the relative energy fueled
of apathy?
You can calibrate this for yourself.
Then what is the relative energy fueled
of desire? Then what is the relative
energy fueled of anger? It's very simple.
You say, I'm holding anger
in mind. Is that over 70?
Is that over 80? Is that over 90?
Is that over 100? Is that over 120?
Is that over 140? Is that over 150?
And at 150 your body will say
that's its relative strength
as compared.
And if you keep doing that all the way up,
you'll end up with the same numbers that I have.
Because we've verified this
with a number of people.
If you use those energy fuels, those are about the kind of
numbers that you will come up with.
And what is the value of it?
The value of it is mind-boggling.
For those who can see,
it is mind-boggling, the implications
of these numbers
and the reversities of these
energy fuels.
It gives you a way to hold
all of human experience now
from a way that becomes self-healing
through that understanding.
And that is the whole purpose of today's
talk.
The talk is really about self-healing
and of course self-healing
explicitly as it applies to the
addictions, but we're talking about
the basic principles
of self-healing in general.
What we say today really applies
to everyone and
of course we related it specifically
to the addictions.
What we're talking about is the nature of consciousness
itself, you know,
aside from the addictions,
but with its special
application to the
addictions themselves.
What is it you'd be willing to give up
if really asked for all?
For what would you give up
all of it? For what would you say
take it?
What are you willing to die for? What are you willing
to commit to?
What are the limitations
and the considerations?
When people get sober, we ask them to make
the same commitment as
they did before.
And in the fifth chapter
in the book Alcoholics Anonymous, it says
that those
who succeeded in getting sober
were those who did not
draw any line in how far they were willing to go.
Whatever was needed,
they were willing to go the whole way
for whatever was needed.
That they did not hold back.
That sobriety came only to those who were willing
to go the whole way.
Whatever was asked, the willingness to go
the whole route. And it was out of that
that sobriety arose.
The willingness to go the whole way.
To hold back nothing.
Even if life itself is asked.
With that spiritual awareness
then, there comes
an unlimitedness to what one is
willing to let go of
in the name of that
intention, in the name of that goal.
Even life itself.
Okay, so
here's Leo. Thanks Leo
for this opportunity to be here today.
Well, we would like to thank
Dave Hawkins. I'd like to give a hand.
Perhaps a few of you would
want to say a few words of thanks.
I wasn't here for the whole day
so I can't really comment. I know
the parts that I heard I was very much
impressed with and very much
enlightened and moved by.
Would anyone want to
say a few words
of what they got out of today or something like that?
Yeah.
It's like hearing it
explained to me. Somehow giving it some
understanding.
I've just been grateful all day that you do this for me.
Well, I forgot
to say today, and I usually do, that
you won't hear anything today that you don't
already know. You're just not
conscious that you know it. And therefore,
it's an intense feeling of familiarity.
As we talk about this, it's like
I always knew that. Part of me
always knew this, and that part
of me that always knew it, but
forgot it, brought me here today
to remind itself
of that which is useful
in that knowingness.
Simple exercise.
Well, that's
the source of my joy. The reason I
give these talks here or any place
else is the sheer joy I get
out of doing it, frankly.
The sheer joy
out of just sharing it. That
which I experience benefit
from myself. And
the joy of sharing that
with other people. That's the great
joy of it. I appreciate how you gave our
left brain something to focus on while
you were creating this whole context and energy
field with your energy
field and really inducting us into all the
information. Great maneuver.
It feels terrific.
Thank you. All of it happened
as it was, does it not?
Okay, fine. Thank you very much, Dave. We are truly grateful.
Thanks again, Bill.