You share what you've learned and try to bring it to the words of people.
Anyway, I don't know whether he did or not.
I suspected that, you see, I knew Helen.
She got it from interdictation, and I thought there was a translator.
I thought from Christ to Helen, there was a translator that translated
into a level that comes out at 600, which is at least reachable by human authority.
There go the invisible helicopters.
Wait a second, because this doesn't bring up a question.
First of all, spiritual truth stands on its own.
It does not stand on the reputation of the speaker of it.
The truth is the truth, whether Jesus spoke it, Buddha, or Nero.
Truth is truth.
Even if Adolf Hitler said, loving your mother is good, it's either true or it isn't true.
It depends on it.
It doesn't depend on who says it.
So the truth that's caused miracles.
It does not depend on whether Jesus Christ is its source or not.
I always felt that there's a tone.
There's a shift of tone in the textbook as compared to the workbook.
That shift in tone is what I was objecting to before.
What it seems to be a pitfall of setting up a duality, a positionality, and a polarity
and viewing the ego as an enemy to be vanquished or something like that.
I thought that came somewhat from a different consciousness on the other side.
It's a little different view than the workbook.
The workbook seems more pure to me.
I don't know.
I never calibrated the two compared to each other.
My guess would be the workbook would calibrate higher than the textbook.
The textbook is great in explaining many things that you couldn't get out of the workbook.
The workbook gives no explanations at all.
It's just something that sounds mystically ridiculous.
You get what you get out of it.
God bless you.
The textbook at least gives explanations.
So that you can grasp it perhaps better.
The only defect, as I say, I don't think you want to set up a polarity with the ego.
You see, the whole problem with spiritual development then is one of polarization based on positionality.
The whole ego is based on positionality.
It cannot exist without positionality.
The minute you have an opinion about something, you're screwed.
I think.
Just add it.
You see, the 12-step groups say we have no opinion on outside matters.
And the power versus force, I use the 12-step groups because they are to me really the paradigm of the purely spiritual,
the pure spirituality as different from religion.
Religion becomes dogmatic and secular interests.
12-step groups have no secular interests.
They don't own anything.
They don't own any buildings.
They have no pomp or circumstance, no money.
They're all poverty-stricken, all the groups.
And they have no position on outside matters.
That was extreme wisdom.
So the source of the 12-step groups is real spiritual genius.
It has no positions on outside matters.
And those spiritual traditions throughout history that have taken no secular positions have survived the purists.
The Buddhist teachings of the Buddha are the teachings of the Buddha.
And.
And they still remain in 900.
But so the purity of the teaching then is partly based on having no position on outside matters.
So I myself don't have any position on outdoor matters, outside matters from a spiritual understanding.
I can take it apart and see how it's put together.
That's not a criticism.
I'm just saying that's how it's put together.
That's how it's put together.
It's neither right nor wrong.
You know, China is where it is because that's the evolution of that culture.
I mean, the leader, don't forget, the leader of China is as much a prisoner of his culture as everybody else.
He can't just say anything willy nilly that he wants to right off the bat.
He's held on by a whole tradition of culture that goes back thousands of years.
He can't just say, blah, blah, blah, you know, no way any more than the leader of our country could get up and just say anything comes off the top of his head.
So he can't just willy nilly go out there and violate all kinds of premises that have been, you know, enculturated for many generations.
So he's not.
So you can't blame one leader for, you know, he's a product of his own culture.
So that's part of our compassion is understanding that part of our compassion is understanding that consciousness is innocent.
It's like the hardware, the computer, and everybody is the prisoner of his own software.
Everybody is the prisoner of his own software.
Everyone is the victim of his own software.
So instead of condemning people, we feel compassion for them because we can see they're run by their software.
And they don't know any differently.
Are you about 700 on the planet?
Yes.
Do you know who they might be or where they're living?
There was a guy named Dick Brody there at Clarkdale that was running the cement business there.
And he moved.
No, I don't know.
But what we do is we get, we're trying to get the overall balance of spiritual energy on the planet.
So let's just ask.
There are beings on the planet who calibrate over 1,000 right now.
That's true.
Oh, my God, there is.
I think the last thing we found was over 900 is four people, something like that.
At one time, there was 12 that calibrated over 700.
Twelve at 700 totally balanced the total negative.
At the time.
I wrote the book.
Totally balanced the counterbalance of the negativity of all mankind.
One in 1,000 counterbalances the entire negativity.
Four at 700, yes.
There are a couple of people right now that calibrate high 900s, actually.
Would you calibrate Sai Baba?
No, I want you folks to do that kind of thing, see?
See, the legendary Indian figures that everybody goes oohs and ahhs over, when you calibrate them,
you'd be surprised what you discover.
It's all hearsay.
Yeah?
But people go by as sort of a myth, spiritual myths.
Myths.
And it's repeated from one person to another, especially in new age groups.
Certain names bring all kinds of ahhs and oohs.
You calibrate them, there's nothing that are ooh.
The reason I want to teach people the technique is so that they use it because you'll be driven
to use it if you have your own curiosity.
If I answer it, I'm extinguished.
Your curiosity and now your motivation to learn how to use it for yourself is gone, see?
But really, if you really want to put what we said today into practice, other than saying
to China, I do would like you to take all the books in your library and see which ones
make you go strong and which ones make you go weak.
And those that make you go weak on this side, it'll answer your own, see?
And you don't have to look at the name on the book.
This book here, this book is over 500 resist, over 600 resist.
610 resist.
This book is at 600.
I don't know, you know what it is, you see?
I don't have to read the name because I don't want to suggest any thoughts to myself or
anybody else.
I can turn it upside down and just calibrate everything.
Then you turn over the cards and see what you've got.
Wow.
And a really amazing awareness dawns on you, how you've been.
Now, how does that happen?
It has to do, the White Brotherhood was transmitted by, what's her name?
Alice Bailey.
Yeah, okay.
There's one there called Glamour.
Excellent book, excellent book.
It's the glamour of a lot of these supposed gurus that you're sucked in by, right?
Glamour is a negative energy, is an energy.
Glamour is what gives certain media figures great power over large populations.
It's because they're glamour, not because of who they are.
Who they are is nothing really.
But they have learned how to present a certain glamour.
It's the glamour of certain spiritual figures that appeals to people.
Glamour.
Alice Bailey.
Yeah, it's a series of books.
They're all gone in blue.
Supposedly channeled from the White Brotherhood.
Each one of those I wouldn't go for just because it's channeled by the White Brotherhood.
I mean, I don't care who it came from.
I'm still going to calibrate it.
So, anyway.
Glamour is an interesting spiritual awareness that people are...
You see, because if your hardware has no built-in safety mechanism,
your hardware has no built-in safety mechanism,
human consciousness cannot tell truth from falsehood.
To this day, the population anywhere in this world cannot tell truth from falsehood.
I can persuade, because I know the tricks of all the trades,
how to imitate that which I know will attract them,
because I know what they're attracted to.
I will become that which I know is influential to them.
It's like I could sense with you, let's say I could sense with you,
that only a big fat person with a beard would have any influence on you.
See?
And I can come on like that big fat person with a beard that you would then respect.
And you would give me...
So, I don't have that power.
You give it to me.
Because you fell for glamour.
And so the glamourization of all these spiritual figures,
you say, what the fuck does this guy know?
He doesn't even have a turban on or a white shirt.
He doesn't even have a hat.
He doesn't even have a turban on or white clothes or sandals or nothing.
You know what I'm saying?
I spoke at a group one time, and they had several speakers,
and they were all dressed up like that.
And I thought, God, Jesus.
Whoa.
You know what I'm saying?
I mean, how did Jesus dress?
If Jesus were alive today, what would he appear on television?
That's a question I always play with.
What are you going to achieve with him?
Do you have a lot of hair?
Yes or no?
Yeah.
How are you going to achieve that?
I mean, we take out light fixtures.
I mean, would he drive a car?
I mean, how did he get to the blazer and all that?
You see our images?
How they are, what I'm saying is the image.
So, how would you recognize that which is Christlike?
Because that which is Christlike is probably walking down the street looking like nobody.
You know what I'm saying?
Another thing I think I said in the book and I'll have to explain, is,
you can't trust the man in the suit if you don't have a tie.
I think I modified that a little bit in the book.
I did modify it a little bit in the book.
But it was very interesting.
I think I modified that a little bit in the book, but the way it came out originally in my awareness
is you can't really trust a man in a suit and a tie. Let's see.
Generally speaking, that is a fact. Resist.
Generally speaking, that is a fact. Now why is that?
Well, because the minute you put on a suit and a tie,
you have just bought into a whole different ballgame of what goes in society.
See, the minute I become part of the establishment, the business establishment, the governmental establishment,
a whole new set of rules applies now.
Spinning the truth a little bit is part of the whole game. It's accepted.
Everybody knows that politicians spin the truth a little bit.
Everybody knows you have to cut a few corners to make a few bucks for the stockholders
or else you're going to be president of this corporation.
Am I right?
You automatically have to be part of a whole different culture with a different truth than spiritual truth.
They're not committed to spiritual truth.
They're committed to pragmatism, showing a profit, expediency.
Expediency is the law there. Not God, but expediency.
Not just greed, it's expediency. Expediency.
There's a magazine sitting in our hotel room that says,
How I Saved a Billion Dollars.
Sweetheart, we should read this before we leave the room.
We've saved a billion dollars.
God, geez.
It's mind-boggling, isn't it?
What would you do with a billion dollars?
I mean, God, your life would be a nightmare unless that happened, isn't it?
What do you really need or want?
Well, if I inherited a million dollars, if I suddenly came into a million dollars,
I'd have a couple of dents on my car I'd take out.
That's the kind of life I'd like, and it has a few dents I'd like taken out.
And then I'd rebuild a chicken coop.
You know, in reality, that's really how your life is really run, isn't it?
I mean, there's a couple of dents that probably got in the car you'd like taken out.
And I don't know what we'd do with a billion, sweetheart.
I don't know what we'd do with it.
I don't know, I wouldn't give it to anybody because it corrupts them.
You know what I'm saying?
What would you give it to?
What would you give the billion to?
Your own children?
You'd be condemning them to hell, wouldn't you?
The worst thing that can happen to anybody is to win the lottery.
You read those statistical analysis on what happens to the people who live in the lottery.
It's horrendous, you know?
Divorce rate is 60%.
Suicide rate is 35%.
Bankruptcy is like 42%.
It's incredible.
The worst thing that can happen to you on this planet is to win the lottery.
It's just horrible.
It crushes people.
It demolishes them.
It's horrible.
And here's God telling me how to save a billion.
Calibrating.
Would that affect the...
No.
So I'll speak to the objectivity of the kinesiologic test, which I first wrote of in a fascinating
volume you'd love to read called,
Quantitative and Qualitative Analysis and Calibration of Levels of Human Consciousness.
I'll keep you up late at night working.
With a very impressive statistical analysis in which P was less than 0001.
Very impressive.
If P is less than 001, that's very impressive.
P less than .01 is very good.
If P was less than .0001, staggering, correct.
Anyway, in which we scientifically validated the reliability of the kinesiologic method.
The difficulty in understanding kinesiology is because we tend to think of ourselves as
a body, and we tend to think locally, and we think of causality as what causes things
to happen is local causality.
So when we look at kinesiology, it seems to us like what the test subject is thinking
or feeling must be influencing the result.
We personalize it.
So in a curious way, we anthropomorphize that which is not human, because consciousness
is neither human or non-human.
It's neither male nor female.
It's the unmanifest out of which all of evolution evolves.
So it's a non-local phenomenon.
It doesn't depend on human.
It doesn't depend on the person's personal opinion.
Now I did a, to clarify this, I did a, I remember a videotape in which I used children.
I used a child, she was an eight-year-old or a ten-year-old, and she had no knowledge
of any of the things we were testing.
She never heard of Saddam Hussein or Adolf Hitler or anything like that.
And we would just put a picture of somebody in an envelope and hold it over a solar plexus
and she would go weak.
And if it was like Abraham Lincoln, she would go strong.
So she had no knowledge of what was there.
And then we did something that was in opposition to prevailing human belief systems.
We held organic tobacco.
Tobacco that's raised organically without any pesticides.
And if you tested out kinesiology, organic tobacco that's raised without any pesticides
makes you go strong, much to the surprise of everybody.
Everybody thinks, oh, tobacco will make you go weak, huh?
All right.
Standard manufactured cigarettes will make you go weak, yes.
So we did some research.
We found that up to 1957, tobacco products did not make you go weak.
After 1957, they did.
And it was apparently due to the fact that they put some kind of a pesticide, some kind
of chemicals on the tobacco as it grows in the field.
And from 1957 on, it was injurious to most people.
People in the Course in Miracles, we know better.
We know what we hold in mind is what we're subject to.
So if you think cigarettes will kill you, goodbye.
If they have nothing to do with you or reality, then you can smoke them.
So unless you've taken the Course in Miracles, I don't think a person could smoke.
Because I'm sure the prevailing thought system will give them something bad.
But anyway, we had this little kid holding all this tobacco.
And of course, she went strong.
So I mean, that was about, in other words, what they're showing is the complete.
And of course, adults will do the same.
If we put organic tobacco in a package and they don't know what's in it, it makes them go strong.
And a package of Lucky Strikes will make you go weak.
So I would say, unless you've done the Course in Miracles, you probably should avoid smoking.
Anyway, I saw the paper this week, and there was a thing left.
It said, you know, statistics from California showed that the incidence of cancer of the lung has gone down 14% in the last decade.
Due to its fierce anti-smoking campaign, etc.
Of course, if the death rate from that has gone down 14%, I've got news for you folks.
The death rate from other things went up 14%.
You've still got to get off this planet one way or another.
So 14% of people listen and take this exit out.
14% more are going to be taking that exit out.
See what I'm saying?
So it's just an interesting way of looking at things.
You said before about conscience.
When a person leaves this, they're at a certain calibration.
And it's not going to change.
So if you believe that the soul, the individual conscience,
is part of the whole, evolves, how can it evolve,
if its consciousness is 200 and it dies and it stays at 200?
An interesting thing you can discover is that every infant, the instant it's born,
already has a calibratable energy level.
The instant it's born, come in at 300, come in at 200, come in at 50, come in at 400.
When you look at the nature of consciousness, which is beyond time and place,
you're periodically incarnate.
You incarnate into physicality.
Because only apparently within physicality, I've researched this all out,
only apparently in physicality are certain things learnable, let's say.
Or you're committed by thinking that you're physical to the physical domain, whatever it is.
Consciousness, then we also discover that consciousness evolves about five points per lifetime.
Every person's consciousness goes up five points in a lifetime.
I think in the book, Omniology, this fellow brought up some interesting statistics.
He'd researched that he found the average number of lifetimes that it takes
to get to the point where you don't have to come back anymore.
I think it was 58 times or something.
I didn't have a chance to check it out.
Anyway, I wrote a review of the book, I didn't check out everything I read,
but he'd gone into some things I'd never had time to look at.
He'd said the average human being has been here 58 times before,
they don't have to come here anymore.
I suppose there's slow learners and fast learners.
You know what I'm saying?
Probably some people get it the first time.
I said you don't have to redo the Course in Miracles.
What I meant is you can read it 50 times, and then once you get it.
So you only can read it once.
You really only get it the one time, because now you've got it, you've got it.
People will read it over and over again, and then suddenly in one instant you get it.
It's in that instant that you just did the course.
You know what I'm saying?
You were looking at the course before, but now you really took it.
You see, when we're sending love to the leader of China,
it isn't something you've got to sit down, put both feet on the floor, and fold your hands.
You know, like doing Est.
All of you did Est, remember that?
Okay, both feet on the floor.
Okay, now put yourself on space, and cross your hands.
It's a funny little thing.
You don't have to do that.
You can just be peeling your potatoes, and you think sort of, just send them a loving thought.
I mean, what the hell?
That guy's got a hell of a job.
You know what I'm saying?
You just send a little bit of loving human compassion.
Wow, what a job.
Imagine facing the karma of this guy when he goes to bed at night.
A quarter of the population depends on his every judgment and thought.
Whew, boy.
So, you know, all those little things are how we do our spiritual work.
Sometimes it gets defined as such a structured, heavy-duty sounding kind of deal.
You've got to sit cross-legged, breathe in certain ways, you know, and not eat meat,
and all those kind of stuff.
You say, oh, the hell with it.
I'll do it some other lifetime.
You know what I mean?
If I have to wear sandals to get to heaven, I mean, I, you know, I can't do it.
So you mean after the person dies, they have some kind of meeting, and they make some kind
of decision about how much they learn, and how much they do?
I don't know that.
I'm just saying, from the science of consciousness, it's obvious that you have a calibrated energy
field.
Yeah.
And where you're going after you leave the body is going to be pretty much determined
by what your calibration is.
First of all, anything less is going to be obnoxious, so you're not going to be attracted
to that.
And anything too high is not going to be meaningful, so you're not going to be attracted to that.
You're going to be attracted pretty much to where you understand yourself to be, because
what we tend to see is our self projected out there.
You understand what I'm saying?
If you see yourself as loving this, then that which is loving this in the next domain is
what you're going to be attracted to.
You see?
If getting high and killing people is what your thing is, you're not going to be attracted
to heaven, because that would be looking very boring.
You know, I talk to a lot of these kids at the girls' ranch, you know, about peace.
I've learned not to use that word.
Peace is not what anybody on this planet really wants.
You know, they talk about peace.
The guy gives a lecture on peace, and goes out, and somebody drags him to the fender
of his car, and he's in a raging fit.
He doesn't really want peace.
If he wanted peace, he wanted peace.
He wanted peace.
If he wanted peace, he'd say gee, I'm sorry that happened.
And gosh, here's my insurance card and here is yours, and you can't drive 10,000 miles
a year without getting a bump.
It's not possible.
You know what I mean?
Where's the compassion for the other person's problem?
You understand what I'm saying?
Compassion is feeling sorry for the other person that they just goofed, you know ?
Yes, go ahead.
You said the average person just goes up five points in a lifetime.
What about people like us who are really working hard at it?
I just did a statistical average.
No, people like in a group like this will probably go up hundreds even in a lifetime.
I've never asked, but I've experienced myself jumps that were well into the hundreds.
So people that are spiritually committed, I think, can precipitate.
As I say, you grow, you evolve slowly this way, but also you can make very sharp, sudden.
You know, Zen is based on sudden awakening.
Zen is based on sudden awakening.
My own experience was very sudden.
Each of the things that occurred to me occurred spontaneously.
All of a sudden with no warning.
One minute you're in one domain and an instant later you're in a totally different domain
with no warning at all.
Just bang, all of a sudden.
And you're overwhelmed by it.
You can't function.
It's just very awesome at first.
Because what is left of the ego witnesses the opening of the light coming in and it's blinded for a short period.
There's a moment in which you're stunned out.
It's just stunning.
And it's like a stunning shock.
It's like you spend all your life in caves and suddenly you walk out into the brilliant sunlight.
You suddenly can't see.
I remember it was quite a stunning shock.
And the nervous system had a hard time handling it.
Very hard.
It wasn't built to handle that kind of energy.
So spiritual evolution is probably perceived at the rate at which our karma and our capacity can handle it.
Sudden jumps could be quite incapacitating, I think, without some preparation.
And suddenly there's no mind, no thought, no thinginess.
All this profound silence.
The focus is different.
The focus, when you're in the ego state, you're focused on form.
And you're focused on sound.
And you're focused on logic and significance and all those kinds of things.
When you're not in ego, you're not focused on sound.
You're focused on silence.
And what I hear, I use the term hear all the time,
is a profound silence.
My perfect environment is one in which is absolute silence.
The Hotel Romeo right now is fantastic.
Absolutely silent.
Big carpet.
Just silent.
And the sound is all wonderful.
Now, some people, that would drive them crazy.
They come and visit you in your house in the country,
and after three days they can't stand it.
Because of the sound of the streets and the people and the direction.
So, the mind.
The mind, I mean, whatever you call that, that is there now,
is into non-form.
It's into silence.
And it takes energy to focus on the world and the form that it insists you pay attention to.
It's exhausting to tiring.
There is an energy that translates what that means.
So that in the silence there is an awareness of what it is.
But it seems to take energy.
And so a lot of things don't get done.
Because they just, they're not, it's hard to do.
You can't do it.
Like balancing your checkbook.
You don't have to bother balancing your checkbook.
Did you realize that?
You don't have to bother.
You get a checking account that if you overdraw it,
it pulls it up here, it charges it to your charge card.
And that way if you don't get any notices, you know you're okay.
If you get a notice,
they just had to transfer $100,
then you put a minus 100 in your checkbook and now you know where you are.
So unless I get an overdraft debit notice,
I figure the figures are probably all right so I never do more of those things.
But there was a time when I couldn't have slept.
Couldn't have slept if the checkbook wasn't balanced.
So those are just the fun things.
What do you do if you're alone in town?
You need to calibrate something.
If you're alone, the reason I recommend kinesiology with two people
is because there's an energy between the two people
that doesn't exist when you're by yourself.
For instance, the person that you use as a test subject habitually
eventually becomes very psychic, very adept at pulling.
What you're thinking about, they will pull the answer out of the universe
and say to you, what about so-and-so in a plant?
That was it.
Where did you get that?
So there is a benefit to two people in working with the same person all the time.
There are techniques which people use by themselves.
You know, the strength of the ring, pulling on the ring to see.
Because the energy of truth makes you strong
and its absence makes you weak.
So if you say, my name is George,
I guess that was not the truth.
What the world calls me is Dave, resist.
The world seems to call me Dave, not George.
That's what it says.
So there is that technique.
Then there's techniques where you can just resist pressing your fingers together.
So people have different techniques.
When you've done kinesiology a lot, you can tell by the sense.
As soon as you ask the question, you get a sense of what the answer is already.
You can feel it run down your arm before your arm even goes,
before the muscle even reacts, you already will get an answer.
It's just, I feel it run down my arm for it.
Or it even hits.
So there is that technique.
There are other techniques.
The book Omniology, Dr. Lee,
Dr. Lee, not a circle,
Dr. Lee,
recommended was, well there is also one I knew of by the Hawaiian,
I can't think of the name now.
They had a calibrated level pretty much like my scale,
a number of inches from the body of the person's aura.
And I guess they would douse it,
the width of the person's aura.
And they would come up with similar characteristics.
The loving person's aura radiates out.
Dr. Lee suggested a method of where you hold a brick.
You hold a brick in your hand like this.
And when you hold truth in your mind,
it's easy to hold the brick up.
And when you hold something that's not truth in your mind,
the brick is hard to hold up.
You get very tired holding it up.
So there are other techniques that people use.
You can train any part of yourself.
It's just a matter of training too.
I must train my arm to be a pendulum too.
I'd say, your name is George.
He says, no.
Your name is not George.
It's a fact that your name is not George.
He says, that's true.
My name is not George.
You know what I'm saying?
So there are some people that feel faint.
There are people that can tell they're in the solar plexus.
A lot of times if you look at your solar plexus,
you'll get the answer right away.
Just the feelings.
The sensitivity in your solar plexus.
People get that sixth sense, you know,
in cosmopolitan areas.
I can remember walking down 10th Avenue in New York City
and I heard footsteps somewhere down the block
early at night.
And my solar plexus instantly knew
that these two guys were muggers.
I mean, I instantly knew who they were.
My solar plexus told me that.
So when they asked for a match, I laughed at them.
I said, yeah, right.
And they laughed back at me that I knew
who they were.
You know what I'm saying?
Yeah, right.
Yeah.
Sure.
So I thought there was something interesting on TV
the other night about the electroencephalographic study
they'd done on the difference of the cerebral metabolism
between men and women.
Did you see that?
That was really interesting.
In a conversation, in a man, only the left hemisphere goes on.
In a woman, both hemispheres go on.
Isn't that interesting?
It explains a lot of human phenomena, for one thing.
See, because to be a man, you have to cut off your feeling about stuff.
You can't go out there and shoot people and kill.
You can't shoot and kill and be a soldier and all that kind of stuff
and also have feelings.
No way.
Oh, no.
You shut it off.
Soldiers, stand up there straight.
Yes, sir.
I don't give a rat if your mother just died today.
Just stand there.
I mean, you don't say, hey, my mother died today.
For Christ's sake, I'm telling my mother.
Are you a soldier or not?
So you've got to learn to shut off all that emotionality.
You can't function in the male world if you're going to be in a feeling-ness state.
A woman, biologically, functions best when her feeling-ness is there.
It's her feeling-ness for her children and her family and for her country
and for the qualities of life.
The woman traditionally stands for the qualities of life.
A man is supposed to bring in the capacity, but she gives it the quality.
Mm-hmm.
She gives it the meaning.
So she engenders meaning and significance and quality into life, whereas the man just
brings his practicality.
He brings you a dead animal.
There it is.
I don't know.
I'm wearing this one.
Come on.
Now, she's supposed to make it into something attractive and nutritious that uplifts mankind
and doesn't give you nausea when you look at it.
Yeah, but he's supposed to not have any feelings.
See?
He's supposed to be able to shoot the deer.
If you open up your right brain and look at a deer, you can't kill it.
No, no, no possible way.
You look at a deer and you realize that it loves its life to the same degree that you
love yours.
Every animal loves, is a person, for instance.
It's a person.
And it loves its own existence to the same degree you love yours.
No more, no less.
Once you look into the eyes of the deer and see who it really is, you can't kill it anymore.
You can't kill it.
See, you can't hunt and also have your right brain moving on.
You can't do it.
The minute your right brain opens up, you can't kill another deer, unless it's the last
deer you ever kill.
You can only kill a deer when you've got half your brain working.
You've got total brain working, you can't kill anymore.
Your killing days are over when your right brain opens up.
You see, it's an incredible beauty.
I remember one time I was stag stinging the pasture ground where I lived.
And he stood up there and said, it was so incredible.
It's magnificent.
It's the incredible beauty.
It's standing there.
Incredible.
Gorgeous.
Beautiful thing.
And the thought of killing it is just like unbelievable.
You know what I'm saying?
So that's what holds up the evolution of consciousness too.
Because your love for all that lives then would constrain you from a lot of negativity.
And it's only by cutting off that love that you could possibly kill another human being.
So when people are not involved in consciousness, we use right and wrong.
Right and wrong.
Because they lack spiritual awareness.
So we tell the child, you know, it's wrong to cross the street without holding mommy's hand.
Then we give them a spank if they do that.
They need right and wrong because they don't have any sense of reality.
A mature person looks down at the street and looks up and now I see there's a truck coming.
There's a truck coming.
They don't walk across the street.
Not because it's right or wrong, but because they have a sense of reality.
So if people are not involved, we have to tell them killing other people is wrong.
And when they're more involved, it wouldn't even come to your mind to kill somebody.
It would be ridiculous.
What do you call it if you like killing somebody?
I always say, you can tell you're making spiritual...
I always say this in every lecture.
You can tell you're making spiritual progress when it gives you great pleasure to let somebody in in traffic ahead of you.
Somebody's trying to get in and you say, ah, come on in.
Give them a break.
Because your pleasure makes you feel good to do that.
You know you're making progress.
You're over 500.
You've got to be at 500 to really enjoy letting people get in.
I mean, really genuine joy.
You can see the happiness on their face.
I mean, it just knocks people out.
Every time I do it, you have to think, okay.
Wave the hand frantically.
I mean, it's the most wonderful thing that's happened.
It's made their whole day.
You know what I'm saying?
I don't know what our schedule is.
You'll have to keep me on score.
Good.
All right.
So we've got to what?
15 minutes left.
And then we're going to do the book time.
Okay.
Anybody have any more questions?
We'll stay as long as people have questions.
I have one for my son.
He's seven.
And he was really sad thinking that I was going to die one day.
And he said, why do we have a body and why do we have to die?
And I wondered if you had an answer for that.
Well, those are certainly good questions.
Why do we have a body and why do we have to die?
Well, apparently the body ceases to exist as a living entity.
So we know, speaking of death then as a physical phenomenon, we know that all that arises
on this planet from life expires from life.
So we know that the physicality, so the source of the body is the universe.
And we know that the physicality is going to arise and cease.
So when he says die, you'd have to say, well, what happens when the flowers drop off and
the leaves drop off the tree in the fall?
Is they go into adornment?
Is they go into a dormant period?
And after the dormant period, they renew their energy and they burst forth again with new
life.
That's what Dr. Lee said in Omniology.
It was rather interesting.
He says, what happens is we energize, we come back into another physical body and the human
life and the vicissitudes are pretty exhausting.
And we leave it, we go into a period of dormancy where we like renew our energies.
And once our energies are renewed, we're ready to resume the growth pattern again and we
get reborn.
So it'd be like spring and fall, sort of like we go into a period of dormancy and then
reemerge in the spring with renewed energy, renewed understanding, renewed commitment.
And that was his explanation.
That's probably as good as any I've heard.
There's another way of looking at it.
So long as you identify self-care.
Identify self as the ego, which is the physical body and mind and structure and form, then
you would reincarnate that which you think you are, which would be another body.
So long as you think you're a physical body, you'll reincarnate as another physical body.
Because that's your identification of who you think you are.
It would be attractive to you.
Does spiritual growth take place only during physical manifestation?
No.
Eternal spiritual growth takes place all the time.
I haven't done much research on the so-called inner planes.
In other words, what goes on between incarnations.
My presumption is that consciousness being what it is, it continually seeks to evolve
itself with or without form.
One of my guess would be.
Those that are committed to spiritual evolution in the body would certainly be so with the
same auto body, right?
That's a likelihood.
But that's just a guess.
Let's see.
Do we go to school between physical lifetimes?
We do.
Yes, we do.
It's always been taught that we sort of go to school on the other side.
And I was presumed that that was the fact.
That you had probably spiritual duties to do, you know?
Maybe greeting new souls as they come across and they're coming from culture shock, you
know?
Thinking they're a physical body and they finally are not.
And you've got to handle their grief and upset over that.
You know?
Probably there's all kinds of work to do on the other side, too.
If there's a lot of work on this side I suppose there's a lot of work on the other side,
don't you think?
I imagine there's a lot of work to do.
And people have to drink.
As far as the relationship with the physical body and spirituality.
Well, many times I've—yes a lot of physical illnesses are expressions of one or two things makings
it.
You know?
And, I think that there are numerous situations where we have people start to emphasize the
opposite towards themselves.
I think that's important.
things from this lifetime it can be the physical working out through the
physical domain of negative energy a person can resolve a spiritual conflict
and make up their mind I have to go in a certain direction and then it like works
itself out through the physical body I think there's a negative you know the
energy works itself out so nice with this but then I think there's karmic
there's a once you get into the details of karma when as I say it's karma is not
really too interesting to get over 600 but under 600 you don't remember those
things you couldn't intuit them though and guess on it with any theology you
can check them out you can learn a lot of interesting things over 600 you
remember them and and you can see their significance from one lifetime to
lifetime and how it manifested within the physicality of this lifetime yeah
it's very definitely so I'll tell you just one for fun anyway anyway so in
this lifetime I was a knight see in yeah for for Christ and it's probably around
the year 10 something and I was in the Crusades so I'm in the Holy Land
someplace there and I'm fighting this Islamic
India
this infidel and he's fighting me because I'm an infidel and so the two of
us are both pretty committed and I decided to kill this guy dead on a
mackerel and I did I mean I really killed a son of it and he at the same
time killed me I mean he did a good job too I mean we really run each other the
same time went out of physical body and looked at each other and broke into
laughter
I killed you for Jesus he said I killed you for
for me from mohamed her bag anyway we both crossed the 200 on there
one to kill him for Jesus you would want to kill me for another have anamoja
who's another religion oh yes all right so he killed me for Allah and I killed
him for Jesus and and when we saw that was hysterical we were like instant
buddies and then we just adored each other you know and we had served each
other you know I mean I had served him this is necessity of Christ it was you
know I mean I had served him this is necessity of Christ it was you know if
us I work with you birth on this theusing which was good for us we can be
him this is necessity across that threshold and that we served each other
equally so you're a better to each other I don't know what I brought that up for
heard they do with karma oh yes then so one time I was having a
hernia operation and I didn't have any anesthesia all right when I get a
surgery I never bother with anesthesia and usually I just to go into a great
space and don't even feel it you know it's great and but this time that did
not happen oh so I'm getting this rid of surgery and supposedly I had a spinal or
something you know anyway nothing happened the spinal didn't take any he
got sort of a lovely says you feel this yeah well the anesthesia was only that
top surface of the skin it was not below the skin and so as he chopped away it
was agonizing I mean I went through a couple hours of real agony severe
agony
look down at me and I love that came through her she said it's the worst I've
ever seen and they tried to talk me into taking anesthesia but I wouldn't do that
because that's a whole different spiritual thing so anyway I went
through this or she would go anesthesia it was really and by her looking at me
sort of impersonal love and I like connected with her to love got me
through it I also remember the other thing got me through was remembering I
remembered that
in Civil War people got their legs blown off and went broken to surgery and
your legs sawed off and all with no anesthesia so I thought they can do it I
can do it it's survivable it's survival to go through live surgery without
anesthesia and so identifying with that was a profound health and then I
remember and then I remembered with a now sword the spirit with a spear killed a
and then I remembered with a not a sword a spear with a spear killed a
I'm sorry I'm sorry I'm sorry with a spear killed a
a man and I got him in the right groin and the spirit of the agony that I
caused him in his right groin was exactly what I was experiencing now I
come it was like one for one so when you reach a certain level of
consciousness out of curiosity you can find these things out with kinesiology
you can research words so most things come from someplace things don't just
come out of the blue understand what I'm saying all of creation is integrated
into some kind of a meaningful understanding so nothing is arbitrary
you don't have asthma for arbitrary reasons or you don't have arthritis for an
arbitrary reason all these things are manifestations of something that's
carried over and almost everything this happened to me in my lifetime I can
trace back and I see where it came from but I remember exactly what I did that
brought on that pain in the right side of the groin it was horrific and it is famous
horrific when you know I got that guy and so there was a
there was a
direct lack of forgiveness there that had brought about the re-experiencing of
it through forgiveness one wouldn't have to re-experience it understand I forgive
him for it what I had not forgiven was myself for having done it I forgive
myself and gourd this man through the right side of the groin right where you
have a hernia with a I remember the spirit all you know it's pretty graphic
and pretty clear memory and so sometimes you get a one-to-one karmic
repetition of something that was done or not done of course with forgiveness
of the course of miracles you shorten the karma you might say if I forgive
myself for having poured that man to death and the agony I put him in I lost
courage to kill him I bored him and I realized the agony was in and I should
have killed him to relieve his agony and I didn't have the spiritual strength to
do it I should kill this man and finish it for him he's gonna lay there in agony and die with anger and anger and stuff
but I didn't so out of that guilt I saw to it that the death was repaid I
should have killed him I didn't know what it took at the time no I wouldn't
spiritual cowardice I didn't have the courage spiritual cowardice to finish the
job you understand what I'm saying I let them lie in slow death instead of just
giving them a clean quickie
mercy of his husband I expressed that so that guilt pertained and then came
back it's that experience so if you're interested you can track back karmic
kill lifetimes and exactly what happened and the likelihood of it and you can
track it down to be pretty exact your intuition sort of leads you there your
intuition sort of knows all the time most of the things you check out you
sort of had that feeling most of your lifetime such and such a thing was a
likelihood and when you check out the kinesiology you'd be
find it was it was it was the fact anything more and then we'll quit yes do
some illnesses occur to help those around you to bring them do some
illnesses occur like I'm thinking especially of children getting sick do
some illnesses occur to help the people that love you around you like maybe
bring you closer all right see that that's our teleologic reasoning reasoning
I know it's Betty Betty Edie's book she mentioned that about a girl getting
sick oh yes yes yeah I get the thought behind it it is sort of those somewhat
teleologic reasoning because the thing ends up as such that's why that's what
its purpose is it might be used to serve that but that's not necessarily its
purpose being born sick yes that's what we referred to we said that people have
a calibratable level of consciousness at the moment of their birth there is
things to be undone things to be relived oh you'd have to see with kinesiology
each thing is a research project you could check out what is the child's
level of consciousness why is it that what is it what does it come from what
is it done in previous lifetimes to bring it to this level hmm etc each one
could be answered as an individual research question and it's just a matter
of time
research out certain research things why is this particular child born into
this world at a 200 and this one's born informative you could ask what about
previous lifetimes what have they done before you know what have they committed
to what have they agreed to in this lifetime so I'm sure there would be
individual reasons what I'm what I'm what I try to convey primarily is a
comprehensive overall feel for the field of consciousness and the mechanism
in which it operates and the ways in which those mechanisms express
themselves the reason I mention karma because I don't think it's well
understood it's not understood at all Christianity and extremely well
understood in Buddhism and various other cultures all cultures all accept that it's
a fact Christianity does not explain it at all it explains karma as the
the consequence of one's spiritual choices in this lifetime
will have profound influence over time in the future.
So, comma, yes, Christianity does not talk about reincarnation at all.
And there may be a good reason for it.
Maybe it could be a misleading preoccupation.
Maybe it's not something people should even worry about or think about.
What difference does it make?
You know what I'm saying?
Oh, yeah.
As intellectualization, does it make any difference?
Does reality make any difference?
Because you only live one instant at a time anyway,
so it doesn't make any difference.
You can't live a lifetime.
You can only live this instant right here and now, right now.
Is that it, Ben?
Are there events where atrocities are visited on a population
where there hasn't been a previous karmic connection?
I don't know.
Some of these things I would have to research out.
I would say there's probably such a thing as collective karma.
Yes?
Probably such a thing as collective karma.
Certainly, a whole nation has to take responsibility that it committed to that
which is a basic violation of human ethics, et cetera.
I would imagine a whole nation that's committed, you know, made a serious error will probably
in some kind of a national sense have to undo that in some other way perhaps.
That would just be my inner sense of it, but I haven't researched it out necessarily.
Yeah? Well, we've answered all the questions that have puzzled Van Zandt since the beginning of time.
We've done it for all eternity, and that's a good afternoon's work.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Uh-huh.