It's not that a channeled teaching is necessarily negative. It may well be positive.
You should know who is it, you know, what is the level of truth of the consciousness,
because many people go into, ooh, ah, it's the old Master Baba Dung Dong,
and, you know, you go, what is the energy of Master Ding Dong?
I'm going to think of a very famous Baba right now.
We have permission to ask this.
The Baba I'm thinking about, it calibrates over 200,
now over 300, over 200.
He used to calibrate over 200.
So we discover new things all the time.
We discover new things all the time.
Many of the so-called, many of the sort of legendary spiritual teachers,
a lot of them are all in India or somewhere in a foreign place or some foreign culture or some foreign time,
when you calibrate their energy, it's really negative.
It really makes you weak, you know.
And you don't want to upset your friends,
so you don't do that.
You don't want to tell them about it.
But I always recommend, what you should do is go through your spiritual library.
Everybody here probably has as many books at home.
And all those that make you go strong, you put over on this side of the room,
and all those that make you go weak, you put them on that side of the room.
It's really a profound experience.
And you realize some things that you never realized before.
Oh, oh, oh.
All of a sudden you get where spiritual falsehood comes from.
It comes from erroneous context.
Because a lot of the gurus are very slick.
I've met some of the slickest.
They know the right things to say.
And they have enough spiritual truth in their bag of tricks that they can convince anybody.
And the reason you can't detect it, because what's out is the context.
And the context is out of your range of awareness.
And you're not spiritually advanced enough, the third eye isn't open,
that you can see the context out of which the other speaker is speaking.
So you don't get what the error is,
because the error is outside your,
outside your vision, you can't see it.
So being able to calibrate, being able to discern the level of truth,
is very, very, very practical.
It can help you find lost objects,
and it can save your lifetimes of agony.
Because following a false guru,
and then discovering disillusionment at the end,
can be exquisitely painful.
Exquisitely, it's probably more painful than losing a loved one.
Losing a child, I've lost children.
Losing,
being a spiritual rake is probably the most painful of all human,
possible human experiences.
That you've been misled by some guru,
that you've given up everything for in worship,
and believed everything he said to Zoe as a god.
You know, because there are teachings like that,
to make your guru into like a god-like figure,
and surrender to your guru.
And then you find out he's been ripping you off.
It's really, really savage.
And I've seen some patients,
I saw one, it took her six pros act a day to hold back the suicidal depression
that was precipitated when she realized that
the person that she thought was, you know,
her sacred guru on earth was just, you know,
taking her for a ride.
In fact, his heart chakra was negative.
Well, the words were all correct.
So, it didn't come out of India.
It's a nature and tradition in India.
Americans are very naive.
A slick guru, guru-ism, comes out of India.
It's a slick evolution.
Thousands of years of evolution.
They're more clever than you are.
Everything you can think of, they've already thought about
a couple thousand years ago and took care of it.
There's no way your intellect is going to discern it.
Without kundalini-ology, I don't know how anybody can protect himself.
And the spiritual rationalizations are so clever and so intriguing and so seductive.
So, it's the seduction of false spiritual glamour
that is the track to the average spiritual seeker
that I've come across.
We've all done all these things.
We've all studied Reiki.
And we've gone to these workshops and those workshops.
And we've followed Master so-and-so.
We got channelings from so-and-so.
And psychic readings.
And the magic dice.
And what else have we done, right?
The magic mantras and the cards and all the deal, haven't we?
So, everybody in finding out what is spiritual truth,
it's a normal thing to check out what's going on.
Because it's labeled spiritual, right?
Spiritual readings.
Well, they must be spiritual, right?
So, there's Madam so-and-so.
And she's got Master so-and-so on the other side.
And she sees that, hmm, hmm.
And now you sit there and your ears are just perked up
because you're just sure there's some great wisdom of the centuries
that's about to be laid on you as a gift.
Do you understand?
All right.
If you can calibrate the level of truth of the speaker
and that which is on the other side,
then you're safe.
You're safe.
I don't care how many readings you get,
as long as you know the calibration of the channeler
and that which is being channeled.
All right.
So, she reminded me that the world runs on time.
Oh, quarter to 12.
I don't know what our time schedule is today.
We were supposed to start at 1230, I think.
Right?
Okay.
We're going to run from 10 to 1230.
Thank you.
She distracted reality in this world for me.
Very good.
I wouldn't know where I was if it weren't for her.
I said to her this morning, I don't know where I am.
She said, don't worry about it.
Don't worry about it.
If I'm going to speak someplace,
suddenly I feel like this energy comes on.
It's like a huge deep breath suddenly.
And then there's the presence intensifies
and there's a feeling of an incredible joy.
And then it's hard to know where you are in the world
and where you're supposed to go
and what you're measuring and all those things.
Anyway.
So, those are the kind of phenomena that happened.
I just thought you would do the phenomena.
Then there was, besides the Kundalini positive energy,
there was very intense spiritual work,
something else also,
because it was almost as though
as you reach a certain level of consciousness,
you pull up its opposite.
And there was also years of clearing
what's out in the human consciousness itself,
not in my own personal self or karmic background.
But there was years of,
of clearing that which is out in the collective of mankind.
And there was a great deal of physical pain.
There was a great deal of the nervous systems,
very often wracked with extreme pain,
considerable pain,
until that particular dilemma was worked through.
And that used to worry me until,
I remember the Buddha said that.
The Buddha said that he had years
in which his body was wracked
as though his bone,
even his bones ached.
And Susan pointed that out.
She said, look at the good ones then.
Oh, right.
So, there are various physical phenomena
that go with this intense spiritual work.
I like the Course in Miracles extremely much.
So, now we'll resume.
What time do we resume?
You know, what time do we resume?
1.30?
We're going to quit from 12.30 to 1.30.
Okay.
I want to talk more about
the Course in Miracles this afternoon.
Because I, at one time, taught it.
I brought it to Sedona.
And I knew Helen, of course,
and the psychologist that she worked with
who died of heart problems, etc.
And so, I have a profound interest
in the Course in Miracles.
And an understanding,
what we were talking about this morning,
sort of gives it the concept
and the conceptual context
in which to understand
the Course in Miracles.
How it is that to ask
the Holy Spirit for a miracle,
to ask to see it as it is the truth,
all you're really asking for
is to move from perception to vision.
All you're really saying is
if I get out of an arbitrary positionality
and the entire picture is revealed to me,
I'll see that there is no problem.
There is nothing to be solved
because there isn't any problem to begin with.
So that out of the wholeness,
the oneness, the wholeness of reality,
then, vision prevails over perception.
Miracles are only miracles
from the viewpoint of the ego.
From the viewpoint of enlightenment,
they're only the way things are.
There's nothing miraculous about it.
You think of a certain thing
and then when you get there,
it is that,
but that's the way it is in that state.
But to the person who spends every day
in Newtonian paradigm of reality,
they would term many of these things miraculous.
Miraculous became commonplace.
It's just the way things work.
What you hold in mind tends to manifest.
One of the nice things about that,
knowing this too,
is that
you see on the levels of consciousness,
you'll see that all the
things that calibrate below 200,
all the negativity,
anger, resentment, self-pity,
all these things,
well, the calibrated number
is the logarithm of a relative power.
So you see that hatred,
where is hatred on here?
I don't know.
Hatred.
Hatred is way down the line.
And fear.
All these things that are like 100 or less,
well,
what we worry about
is our negative thoughts and feelings,
isn't it?
Spiritually driven people
are usually bugged by
what they consider their problems,
is things that,
you know,
you get a resentment,
you feel bad about it,
you feel angry,
you get into self-pity.
Anything negative we feel bad about
because we're trying to evolve beyond that,
you know what I'm saying?
So we know we're in some kind of an error.
So not only do you feel guilty
that you're guilty,
but you feel guilty
that you're feeling guilty
that you're guilty,
you understand what I'm saying?
If I was seeing things correctly,
I wouldn't be feeling guilty,
so I must be screwed up.
So now you're guilty
about feeling guilty
about being guilty,
you see what I'm saying?
So spiritual people really have,
really a problem
that other people don't have.
They just feel guilty
in the hell with you
and they enjoy it.
Hatred,
or something,
makes you deserve it.
So,
tired.
They get,
they like it, see?
But we don't like it anymore.
Now,
if you think,
God,
oh,
Lord.
That's the Holy Spirit
to see this differently.
And now they see this
as in truth,
you know?
Not that he's a hateful,
evil person
that I want to get even with.
So,
we worry about our negativity.
Yes,
but you see,
from the consciousness level here,
don't forget,
these are all logarithmic.
Love is 500.
Wow.
But we're talking about
the log 500,
right?
So a negative thought
is,
well,
I don't know
how many people
in the world
think that
a negative thought
is so weak and puny
that,
frankly,
don't quote me,
but you could spend all day
thinking negative thoughts.
Don't even worry about it.
Have one loving thought,
love your kitty,
say,
sweetie pie,
I adore you.
You're God's little
gifting mommy.
And,
man,
you just outdid
all that negativity.
So,
now,
if that wasn't so,
when you realize
85% of the world's
population
calibrates below
200,
life would not even
be possible
if a negative thought
had the same power
as a loving thought,
this planet would have
blown apart
millennia ago.
Because 85% of the people
are walking around
thinking,
screw you,
you son of a bitch,
I'm getting even with you,
and I can squeeze
an extra dollar
out of there
and kicking old widows
out in the street,
I love it,
you know,
raise the rent on them,
give grannies free pillows
on Medicare,
get out.
So,
hatred and anger
and all that stuff
would have absolutely
destroyed all mankind.
The interesting thing
and we'll do some drawing
on the board
after this afternoon,
we said that
mankind is like
a pyramid,
you see,
and 85% of mankind
falls below
the consciousness
level 200.
Oh,
I forgot,
we're not tied up here.
Oh,
look at that,
I can walk around.
I've been hanging out
there all this time.
Afraid to get away
from this guy here.
You can still hear me?
Wow,
this is magic.
Well,
this is sort of
like it was
when you're out of body.
You're like floating around
and everything's still going,
you see.
And when you think
you're a body,
you're tied to this.
You say,
God,
I don't dare leave
this body here
because I won't be able
to see, hear, feel, think
or enjoy anything.
I went out of body
with just like this,
same feeling,
like you're light
and you're floating around
and you see
and hear
and feel
and everything's just fine.
And there's the physical
body lying there,
you see.
And you're like,
oh,
that was wonderful.
So,
now here we have
15% of the people
in the world
calibrate over 200.
Wow.
All these people here
will make you go negative.
What do they live by?
They live by
the unjustifies
the means.
You calibrate
the unjustifies
the means.
The interview
with the
unjustifies
the means
is clear.
Oops,
sorry.
The unjustifies
the means.
The reverse
of that.
That's true.
Okay.
All right.
The unjustifies
the means
means that
you can now justify
any ravagement
of mankind
because you can
always justify
the end
one way or the other.
It's for the good
of genetics
that we eliminate
all genetic defective
people in
the population
and take them off
the extermination camps
and so on.
Anyway,
85% of the people
calibrate below
200.
All right.
0.4%
calibrate
over 500.
0.4%
of the world's
population.
Huh?
Enlightenment
at 600
occurs to
1 in 10 million
or something.
Now,
the interesting thing
is that this
small percentage
here
counterbalances
the totality
of this.
That's the
thing that's
crucial.
One being
at 1,000
compensates
the entire
negativity
of all
mankind.
I forget
how many people
at 1,700
but 3 or 4 people
at 700
counterbalance
all the negativity
of mankind.
So,
what's interesting
is not the prevalence
of negativity
but the fact
that positive
energy,
loving energy,
capacity
and the willingness
to forgive
counterbalances
all the negativity
out there.
You see,
whatever we accomplish
within our own
level of consciousness
benefits all of
mankind.
The most interesting
realization is
every forgiveness
is a gift.
Every positive
thought
that replaces
a negative
thought
reverberates
throughout all
of history
and benefits
all of mankind
now and
forevermore.
Every thought
is important.
Every positive
thought
is a gift
to Jewel
and the
diadem
of mankind
and it lives
forever
and can be
discerned
forever.
10,000 years
from now
we will
be able
to say
what did they
talk about
there in
Concord?
What was the
level of energy
of that group?
You know,
what was the
effect?
So we all
have a permanent,
you know,
we're all part
of the whole.
So what we do
is not really
for ourself.
In the beginning
we think it's
our own consciousness
but as you advance
you realize it's
not your own
consciousness.
It's consciousness
that's benefiting
you.
You hold it
that way
you realize
it's precious
and it's holy
and it's worth
everything that we
put into it.
Alright,
so we'll
meet again
in an hour,
yeah?
I think we tend
to in the
certificate
just,
you know,
hour for hour
put down
as many
hours as
usual.
That you
were awake.
Two and a half.
So I think
we're
gonna have
about
three or four
minutes
of
time
to
talk about
the rest
of people
who come
back from lunch.
Do we have
many people
still missing?
We do.
All those
that are missing
please raise
your hands,
yeah.
We'll wait
till they
come back.
In the meantime
while we're
waiting
for the
next
speaker
to come
in,
I think
we'll
have
a few
more
questions
in a
few
minutes.
I think
we're
gonna
have
a few
more
questions
in a
few
minutes.
So,
I think
we're
gonna
have
about
six
more
questions
in
a few
minutes.
So,
we're
gonna
have
one
more
question
from
the
audience.
Okay,
so
we
have
about
more
questions
in
the
time
so
pace with a greater comprehension of every other area of human information
and knowledge well for one thing there was no tool no tool with which to
investigate things so you might say we know that we have sort of like for the
first time in human history we have a telescope we can now reinvestigate what's
believed about the heavens with use of a telescope you see it's got Galileo into
a lot of trouble but having a different means now telling truth from falsehood
you can really go back through the spiritual teachings throughout history
and validate the truth or falsehood of an understanding and also its level of
truth and there you find certain errors and when you find the error then the
history of spiritual difficulties throughout the ages becomes quite clear
why it arose and what the blockage to the
understanding of the truth is and the understanding of the truth is the
understanding is I would really need two or three bodies to do although what
I'd like to do I'd like to do research in comparative religion throughout
history of all the major religions and track out exactly what happened with
each religion and what is calibrated level of truth was century by century I
did a little bit of that in power with his horse I don't have to stand by this
thing in that you see
the level of the levels of truth of certain spiritual teachings have have
disintegrated very little since first initiated first spoken other teachings
have disintegrated over the centuries and are nowhere near the level of truth
of the original and it'd be very interesting to go back especially the
Council of Nicaea to discover she and I don't have time to do that but I'm going to do it.
all these things but it'd be good to go back to the Council of Nicaea and see who
was there what was said what secular influences must have come in because the
level of truth of Christianity dropped from the 900s down to jobs several
hundred points after the Council of Nicaea so some grave error came in there
and corrupted the original purity of the original truth that did not happen in
Buddhism Buddhism has taught is still a
in the 900s so very little has been lost but other other others have gone
down considerably and some of the world's religions which I don't want to
even mention have become actually fallen below 200 in the negative range and
become sort of cults so a lot of religions were then corrupted by cultism
see so when people study the history of spirituality they really are coming
from a very naive viewpoint to look at it like that.
they look at it like studying history most of the Christian churches constantly
repeat historical documents which first of all are not even accurate if you can
calibrate them yourself you can see they're not accurate at all and now they
become ingrained in our society and revered so here you've got falsehood
revered in our society and passed down generation after generation so I'm
trying to discover you know what is impeded the development of the
man's consciousness throughout time. That is really what I'm addressing in this
particular book. And we will address some sacred cows. We will look at some sacred
cows. And I'm getting old enough so I don't care what they do to me. Now is a good time to do it. I'm getting older anyway.
So, if I got shot for the Enterprise. I'm just kidding, but we will address some
sacred cows. Because why does ignorance prevail century after century?
Such profound ignorance blinds mankind. You know, mankind is just newly sprouted,
newly sprouted. And what prevails primarily is profound ignorance in just
about every level of human endeavor. Modern society only started a couple
hundred years ago. I mean in time it's like yesterday. So, how does such
profound
ignorance prevail century after century? Modern society only started a couple hundred years ago. I mean in time it's like yesterday. So, how does such profound
ignorance prevail century after century? Modern society only started a couple hundred years ago. I mean in time it's like yesterday. So, how does such
is it suddenly stopped? We don't all still think the world is flat, do we? Do we? She thinks the world is flat. She thinks the world is flat, but the rest of us don't.
And yet, when it comes to spirituality and religion, most people still think the world is flat. I mean, that's really their level of understanding. It's nowhere, nowhere at all.
So, we are going to, in this particular study we're doing now, address the evolution of consciousness throughout all of mankind, mankind's history, and try to track out why and what is holding it back.
Why, how come it's not up to 300, you know, 400? What's keeping it, why isn't it 500? Why isn't the unconditional love prevailing in our society? Why doesn't it?
So, that's the kind of things that we're...
looking at right now.
Alright, so I guess we're all reassembled this afternoon so we can resume.
I was talking about the nature of consciousness as the evolution of consciousness is experienced through this particular track of historical memory here.
And one thing that was peculiar, the other thing that was peculiar about the sudden presence was
the feeling of completion, the feeling of not needing anything more.
And that prevails to this day. If somebody says, what do you want for Christmas? I have to think, what does want mean?
Because it's really meaningless. There's no wanting anything. There's no lack, there's no need, there's no desire.
January 10th, 1965, when I really got hit by the presence,
at that moment, in that moment,
all that's considered essentially human disappeared.
Desire for fame, fortune, money, power, influence over others,
all these strange melodies that afflict people seemed to disappear.
They just disappeared. It wasn't through any kind of heroic spiritual effort.
They disappeared of their own nature and have not reappeared.
So,
then I was left in the world devoid of what drives most people,
and trying to figure out what to do from here.
What do you do from here? Well, let's see.
And people would say, well, you've got to pay attention to reality,
and get back to practice, and make some money, and all this kind of thing, you know.
And it didn't make too much sense to me.
I understood the words, sort of, but it didn't ever have any,
there wasn't any inner reality for it to hang into, to activate you.
You know what I'm saying?
You have to be anxious about your own survival to worry about such things.
But, anyway, over some years that I retired from the world,
I did relearn how to relate to the world,
and one handy way of doing that was watching television.
I didn't own a television set.
I didn't read newspapers or magazines or any such thing.
And I just spent all the time meditating.
And I discovered that if you watch TV,
you can find out what's been happening in the world the last ten years, or whatever.
I remember there was Princess something-or-other.
She was very famous on the front page of everything that went in the grocery store.
There she was in front of everything.
I didn't know who that she was, or any of those people.
So there was a relearning of how to be in the world.
When those things happen, people say,
well, what is that like when it happens?
In the high 500s, you go into this incredible being in love with everyone.
And you go through the phase of crying at the drop of a hat.
If you look at two people looking at each other tenderly,
the love just knocks you out, and you start to weep.
And so you go through a stage of crying and weeping over beauty,
and you hear a piece of music, and it just lays you out.
We were speaking someplace or other,
and she turned on the TV, and this incredible symphony,
incredible music came on, and I just lay on the bed.
I couldn't get off the bed.
The beauty was so knocking.
It just knocked you out.
So there's that.
In the high 500s, the realization of the beauty and the perfection of all things.
Each thing shines forth.
The intrinsic beauty of each thing shines forth in its radiance.
It makes you weep with its beauty.
And so there is that difficulty.
In monasteries and places like that, it's common.
Sometimes they cry for years.
If you say anything nice to them or loving or show them a rose or something,
they're gone.
So you can't rely on them to get much work done.
So the high 500s, you see the beauty and the perfection of all things.
And everything knocks you out.
There's a period of time where everything knocks you out.
And if you're not careful, even that knocks you out.
So you see a little tree or a weed.
The average person would say that's just a weed.
But what you see is the incredible.
You see the weed as a magnificent sculpture.
You see its incredible beauty and perfection.
You see the incredible perfection of the weed standing forth.
And you see the design of each thing shining forth.
So the intrinsic beauty of creation shines forth.
And the perfection of all things sort of takes hold in the high 500s.
And then at 600, you run into sort of the near death experience kind of experience I had
where the intensity of the bliss is such you cannot function.
You cannot function.
There is no need to eat, drink.
The body functions just come to a halt.
There's only the radiance.
And because you're outside of time, there's no way of knowing whether weeks, months,
or whether it's even the same lifetime.
You sound crazy, but you don't even know if it's the same lifetime.
And whether you survive or not really depends on having people around you.
Even now, if it weren't for the presence of a loving, if it wasn't for Susan,
I probably wouldn't even eat for weeks at a time.
I don't know.
It just never comes to mind.
It just doesn't come to mind.
And so it's good if you do intense spiritual work to be aligned with a spiritual group.
Be aligned with a spiritual group.
Because any spiritual practice you do, you can just suddenly take off.
You see?
Because spiritual evolution is both longitudinal like this, see?
It's sort of like, you know, the Dow Jones or something.
As the years go by, you go ups and downs and ups and downs.
And you gradually evolve higher and higher.
And then there's sudden breaks where you suddenly go that way.
You can suddenly go vertically just like that.
You can be playing with a mantra that somebody, some great guru whispered in your ear.
If you get $350, you get $550 or whatever.
And all your life you're out there waiting in the garden.
And all of a sudden, bam, instantly, you're out of this.
And if you're out by yourself and nobody knows what's going on with you, they could think he's going catatonic.
One time I went catatonic.
I mean, I went like that in this divine bliss state.
And I saw the world would think he's catatonic.
And they would take me off.
And I said, that's all right.
I surrendered that one to God.
I don't care if they think I'm catatonic.
And they're going to haul you off to a hospital.
I was sitting on a rock.
I'm meditating.
I was in this bliss state.
And I couldn't get off.
So I said, well, they'll see this person sitting there.
And they'll call the police.
That's OK.
And the police will take you to the hospital.
And the doctor will examine you and say, he's catatonic.
Oh, OK.
And then they will put you in a mental hospital.
I'd say, that's all right.
And they'll probably shoot you full of Thorazine.
That's all right, too.
Because that which I am is not reachable by Thorazine.
You can sedate the hell out of the body and the mind.
But I'm not the body and the mind.
So I don't care what you do with it.
You see how you go.
You're like beyond all.
Well, if you didn't have friends around to see that you ate and got off the rock, you
could still eat.
You could still be that.
You think I'm kidding.
But you know, after Ramana Maharshi, Ramana Maharshi was 15 or 16 or something.
And he was just an ordinary religious Hindu fellow.
Not overly religious or anything.
And one day, he suddenly felt like he was dying.
And he fell down in a weak state.
And he realized he had just died.
Well, then he went into this state of bliss.
And in this state of bliss, he just sat there, I guess, for some days and weeks and was all
bitten up by insects and hadn't eaten.
And he was discovered by some people who did have some spiritual erudition and recognized
the state he was in.
And he was unable to speak.
He didn't even talk for two years.
It took him two years to relearn how to talk.
And so if he had not been surrounded by a couple of spiritual, spiritually oriented
people, you know, I guess they could have put him in a mental hospital in India for
advanced serious catatonia or something.
It's good to have some people who know what you're doing, you know, because it can happen
any time.
Just why?
Because your spiritual orientation is to go in this direction.
Therefore, you are what makes the technique work.
It isn't the mantra that gets you to heaven.
It isn't the spinning the prayer wheel or getting funny haircuts, sitting cross-legged
and breathing in strange and peculiar ways from one side of the nose to the other.
God bless it.
It's because of who you are and your intention that that should get you to God.
And that's what gets you to God.
And in Ramana Maharshi it says, God feels sorry for you after a while and picks you
up and takes you into his arms.
After all that strange breathing and staring at the sun and starving yourself and ringing
bells and chanting mantras and all this weird stuff, the strange haircuts, all the bizarre
things, and the bells and whistles that goes with it.
So those are not what's divine.
What's divine is the entity that is empowering those things to bring them closer to God.
See people going to the holy land.
Imagine how holy that holy land is right now.
After all the killing, warfare, bloodshed, murder, hatred, loathing, persecution, all
in the name of this holy place.
I never calculated the energy of it.
I'd be afraid to.
Imagine what the energy of the holy place is in this earth or life.
Like God's interested in real estate, you know.
This little strip of this country is holy to God, you know.
So one of the things we want to do in the Eye of the Eye is improve God's reputation.
And one of my functions here, according to, just to clear up his name on me.
Why?
Because God gets blamed for all the negativity in the world, don't you understand?
The God of retaliation, the God of fear, the God of jealousy, hatred, and anger.
This map of consciousness we have over on one side, the view of God that that particular
level of consciousness is agreeable with.
See?
If your level of consciousness is way down at the bottom, then a God who's angry at you
and vengeful because he's got low self-esteem.
And gets upset if you worship graven images or something.
And strikes you dead in your whole city.
Burns it up and fit of paranoid jealousy.
You lose control of himself.
Destroys whole cities and civilizations.
There, take that.
But, you know, most of the world believes in God like that, huh?
So when I start these lectures, usually, usually I have this map of consciousness and a transparency,
which I forgot the date.
Uh.
Projected up there.
And the first thing I bring to people's attention is that God is at the top of the chart.
Not at the bottom.
And people say, oh, that's ridiculous.
Oh, yeah?
Most of the world believes that God is at the bottom of the chart.
The God of vengeance.
The God of hatred.
The God of anger.
The God that's paranoid.
That needs, uh, it goes to Thorazine to sleep.
Worried that his power is being undermined by people with all their strange rituals and
stuff.
You eat meat on Friday, I mean, you know, or whatever.
You don't wear a certain kind of hat.
Or you do wear a certain kind of hat.
Imagine Jesus getting upset because you wore a hat in church or you didn't wear a hat in
church.
When I was young, all the ladies had to wear a hat in church.
Because God would be upset if you didn't wear a, if ladies didn't wear a hat in church.
It was sacrilegious.
Sacrilegious.
Oh, wow.
So there we got all that negativity, you know, incorporated into our culture.
It's sacrilegious.
Like, God's gonna be upset with you.
Like, God's gonna be upset with you if you wear a hat or not.
God doesn't even know if you're wearing a hat, you know.
But, if you like to think that God does notice that you're wearing a hat.
God is the hat that you're wearing, so how would he notice it?
See?
That which is can't notice its own self, isness, because isness is isness, and not that which
witnesses isness.
Huh?
Identity knows only its own identity.
And therefore comprehend what God is all about when I say that.
Understand that identity is its own identity and nothing else.
Each thing arises as a creation out of its own essence.
Each thing is complete and total and perfect.
All right, so then that, if that is so, then what?
What goes on with human consciousness?
Why is it not so for all of us?
Hmm.
I want to talk today a little bit about karma, karma.
Another thing I want to address in the book I'm working on now.
When we look at the spiritual ignorance that goes on,
you see ignorance in all kinds of things.
And we said the world is flat.
A lot of people still believe that.
Not too many people.
But in religion and spirituality, a lot of people are really at the level of thinking
the world is flat.
That there's been no examination, reexamination of things that are passed down generations.
I mean, it's like it's, you know, passed down.
Therefore it's, it's written in rock, you know, written in eternal cement.
Because some prophet said it someplace or other and it was misquoted and now it's not
prevailed as law.
Not prevailed as law.
So mankind then is held by fallacious laws that he believes in.
Fallacious belief systems.
When you calibrate the energy fields of what prevails in mankind's spiritual belief systems,
it will, you'll feel like training.
The beliefs in things that are just grossly negative, just grossly make your arm go weak,
is profound.
So fallacy then gains its influence.
By repetition.
By ignorance.
By not knowing the difference between truth and falsehood.
Not knowing the difference between truth and falsehood.
Anything that's true should certainly stand up to kinesiologic test of truth, yes?
Same thing should go weak.
We would say at least it's not exactly up to snuff.
A lot of what goes on in the world does not come up to snuff.
And how does all this perpetuate itself then, generation after generation?
We'd have to look at how does consciousness transmit itself from lifetime to lifetime?
And we'd have to look at what has historically been called karma.
Now, karma is one thing and reincarnation is another.
When people get into discussions, they confuse the two.
When we talk about karma, we're not talking about reincarnation.
That's a different subject.
To re-embody oneself is...
a different subject.
Karma has to do with consciousness itself.
It has nothing to do with embodiment.
All the world's religions teach karma.
All the world's religions.
They don't call it karma.
Christianity, the world, doesn't use the word karma.
But Jesus Christ says that you shall reap as you sow.
He certainly tells you to avoid sin because the consequences are not too great.
And warns us that below 200
will take you into unfortunate places when you leave the body.
And all the world's great spiritual traditions and religions all teach the one thing.
That the choices we make, the options we make,
will determine
future experience of that aspect of the human which survives its physicality.
There's no question that...
Now, in traditional Buddhism,
Christianity, there is no mention of other than one...
There's a presumption you only have one body.
And then, after you leave this body,
you will go someplace befitting what your choices in this world determine for yourself.
Heaven, hell, purgatory, or limbo, right?
There aren't many other places that cover this.
There are options when you leave.
So, herein comes the fear of the Christian then,
that there will be a great judge.
And this judge may take a very negative view of your behaviors in this lifetime.
And the consequences will be unpleasant.
So, we have this negative God that we fear will judge us at the end.
This God is external to the reality of who we are.
Because to be judged by God,
you would have to be this and God would have to be that.
So, that implies a separation.
There would have to be a separation between the reality of that which you are,
this kind of entity that sits out there and judges you,
and then takes action against you via force.
Because throwing people into hell with a fry is sort of force, isn't it?
Not exactly friendly, anyway.
So, there is a presumption and a separation,
and the projection of man's own negativity.
So, you see, Sigmund Freud,
and Moses and Amathia,
Sigmund Freud calibrates at 499,
he correctly deduced that the negative images of God
were projections of man's own unconscious guilt and fear.
And he said, because they're just projections from the unconscious,
they have no reality.
And there he was correct.
But then he made the error.
He said, therefore, there is no God.
Well, that was a jump.
What he should have said is,
these projections from man's unconscious
create a false image of God as a very negative being,
and that particular being doesn't have reality.
No, he didn't.
So, that's why Freud stands at 499.
Carl Jung, who calibrates at 520,
validated the reality of man's spirit.
So, 499 is the great barrier.
It's very, very unusual and very hard to get over 499,
and not many people do.
Even the great intellect stopped at 499,
because there's a jump to a different paradigm of reality.
You have to jump from the linear to the nonlinear.
You have to see the reality of the nonlinear.
So, Carl Jung, who calibrates at about 520,
validated the spiritual reality of man,
and therefore calibrates an entire Freud.
Well, the God that Freud threw out
was the same one I threw out
when I saw the totality of man's suffering.
I threw out any God that could be the cause of that.
So, the misunderstanding was
that I was ascribing to God, blaming God
for that which is the creation of the human ego.
It's the human ego that creates war and pestilence and suffering
and all the miseries that we blame on God.
When you understand the nature of God,
the thought that negativity could be some kind of a weird reality
that emanates from that divinity is absurd.
But when people have had no personal experience of the presence,
they are willing to believe almost anything that you tell them.
And they do.
What does determine then what happens at death?
What is the spirit all about?
Well, we said that everything and anything on the planet
gives forth an energy and a vibration of frequency.
We can calibrate that frequency.
We can calibrate the frequency and energy of anything and everyone,
every saint that ever lived,
every sentence pronounced by every guru who ever lived.
The level of truth of that
thought.
Therefore, all of us are carried with us a spiritual body,
the frequency of which is actually calibratable.
And its fate depends then completely on what its calibrated energy level is.
So I want to give you a different picture of causality,
a different picture of how the universe works.
Each thing, because it is only what it is,
it is not what it is because of something else,
but only because of its own essence.
It's only...
You only...
It is what it is out of its expression of its divinity
expressing itself as what it is.
So it's...
The way the universe is working is not like linear causality
where a billion balls are hitting each other.
Instead, it's almost like little tiny magnets
all circulating around in a great big vast space.
And the movement and the direction and the influences
are all emanating from the essence of what each thing is
in and of itself.
You understand what I'm saying?
It's like its polarity, its power,
is interacting with the field.
You understand?
Like little iron filings in a giant electromagnetic field.
Each filing lines itself up depending on its polarity,
its degree of energy,
how much iron is in it,
and the power of the field.
There's no arbitrary field knocking this little magnet this way.
Bad little magnet knocking it.
See?
Everything is being where it is
because out of the essence of its own divinity
it cannot be otherwise.
Each thing is expressing itself
and like a cloud floats through the atmosphere
depending on the geometric pressure and the winds.
So that which is the spirit body
and, of course, at least the physical body,
nobody experiences their own physical death.
I might as well tell you that.
Nobody experiences their own physical death.
The moment of death, wham, you're out of the body.
You witness the body laying there
and the car just ran over it.
Sort of interesting, but not too.
And anything catastrophic you experience,
you're not dying.
It's horribly painful.
Don't worry about it.
If it's fatal,
yep, you're out in an instant.
You witness it happening.
Now what happens to you?
Well, now what happens to you depends on the energy
and the frequency and the vibration of where you are.
You're now a cloud in the sky
and you will automatically
gravitate to the energy field
which is your natural space to be in, right?
So if we can say,
if the heavens calibrate just like this,
and they do, the other side
calibrates the same way,
you will gravitate to where,
say, everybody is like a cork in the water.
You understand?
You rise to the level of your own buoyancy.
There's no arbitrary god out there
pushing this cork to go there.
Each cork, when you think of what would
divine justice be,
divine justice would have to be absolutely perfect.
Each thing automatically,
because of its own nature
and the nature of the universe,
is exactly where it is due to
its own expression of its own nature.
Understand what I'm saying?
That is absolute,
the divinity of,
the justice of God,
that only that which you have
absolutely deserved of yourself,
can possibly be.
Nothing arbitrary outside of yourself
has any influence over you.
Therefore, just from the viewpoint
of the science of consciousness itself,
then,
the negative gods
have no power over you whatsoever,
because, first of all, they have no existence.
Each one of us determines their own fate,
their own future.
So every choice that we make
from moment to moment,
then,
changes the buoyancy of our cork.
So if our Holy Spirit is like a
etheric cork,
it goes where it's going to go in the universe,
because of its own buoyancy,
its own power,
its own frequency.
Obviously, a spirit that radiates at 500
is going to go to a different place
than a spirit that radiates at 190.
190 is probably going to land in a space
where there's militarism
and war and pridefulness.
And so each spirit's going to be
where it needs to go,
where it wants to go.
It's going to go where it is decided
by its own actions to go.
If that is so,
then,
the drama that we see that goes on
in the human evolution of society, then,
is the outcropping,
the acting out of these levels of consciousness.
To get over 200,
you have to cross the line.
You have to cross over the level of integrity.
Integrity.
That's a big one.
85% of the population is below 200.
How do you get above 200?
200 means out of integrity,
out of integrity,
commitment, then.
One is even willing to give up their life
for something greater than the personal self.
And so we see war is the great opportunity
for spirits to come back,
walk into a rain of bullets,
because they believe in the divinity of the emperor.
I think the kamikaze pilots all went
to a great place when they left.
You willingly give up your body,
or the faith that you believe is God,
because they thought the emperor was
the representation of the sun god.
Hmm.
You cross over 200.
You come out of fear,
and you cross over 200,
and you want integrity for eternity.
Let's see if that's true.
We just said it's true.
I just knew intuitively, spiritually,
the kamikaze pilots, you know,
when you see them,
for each other,
for the love of themselves,
for their love of each other and their country,
and for the love of their emperor,
they surrender their actual life
for that which they believe in.
I mean, that's a profound spiritual step.
We don't care what it means politically,
now we're talking spiritually.
Spiritually, it's a profound step.
So we see all that goes on
in the human endeavor, then,
is really an opportunity
for the evolution of consciousness.
There is some point in the evolution
of your own consciousness.
Every man here who can remember past lives
will remember a lifetime
in which you had to stand up,
walk out of the trenches,
and face certain death.
And you had to do it for the emperor,
you had to do it for Nero,
you had to do it for the Roman Empire,
you had to do it for Christ, whatever.
And that moment is a profound moment
because you cross over.
And, uh,
when people go over 600,
they tend to remember past lives, you know.
We're talking about karma.
So, anyway, past lives.
I find it difficult how people can have
a really profound, solid spiritual understanding
or a belief system
without comprehending karma
because it would leave you
with no understanding at all
of what happens in human life.
You know, a little baby's born,
and at two months old,
it gets hit in the head by a crock pot
and it also has cancer.
It has AIDS when it's born,
and it screams and goes into
an epileptic fit and dies, you see.
What does a child do to deserve that,
you know what I'm saying?
The intellect can't believe in God,
really can't believe in God,
because there's no rationality,
no rationality,
no rationality to what you witness,
no explanation whatsoever.
Without understanding karma,
you look without any explanation whatsoever.
Anybody that isn't an atheist isn't too bright
because if you look at things with the intellect,
it'd be stupid to think that
some kind of God is in charge
of all the wickedness that prevails
in our human civilization.
No, there would have to be some explanation
because once you understand
how the universe and the mind of God work,
everything works together perfectly.
Absolute perfection and cohesion
to the whole thing.
There's no outness to it.
No, no little baby accidentally
gets dropped on its head
and born with AIDS
and dies to sell the salvation.
Africa is full of it, isn't it?
By the millions.
They're born into starvation,
malnutrition,
they have convulsions,
they get AIDS and starve to death.
The mother who's dying of AIDS
can't even lift their little bodies anymore.
She just lays them by the side of the road
and walks off.
The flies come.
What's the explanation for that?
What's the explanation?
Is that accidental?
No.
There's nothing accidental in the universe.
There's not,
no accident is possible in the universe.
In the universe,
where everything interacts
with everything else,
no accident is possible.
From the viewpoint of Newtonian
linear reality,
this thing causes this
in the universe.
From more advanced consciousness,
all that is in the universe
is what it is
because of what it is.
This is here,
not because it's caused by this here,
but unless this was here,
this couldn't be here.
Understand what I'm saying?
Because this is here,
this can be here.
But this is not causing that
to be here.
No.
It's not causing it to be here.
So if a soul wills itself into hell,
it does so of its own volition,
not because some angry God-like figure
picked you up and said,
well, you stole from the supermarket,
now you're going to pay.
And throws you a little spirit body
down there to fry.
I mean, you know,
that's really ridiculous.
The whole world lives in fear of that,
and certainly the Course in Miracles
addresses that profound ignorance,
which prevails
in man's consciousness.
And the Course in Miracles
was really the first one
that brought it up,
really brought it up
to be looked at
and reexamined
as such a negative image of God,
a possible reality.
And the Course concludes
it's not even a possible reality,
it's an absurdity.
It's an absurdity,
but because it's repeated so often,
generation after generation.
Well, you see,
mankind is very influenced
by the herd.
So if everybody in your society
believes a certain thing
is a certain thing,
it's very hard not to think
the same thing,
and it's very hard to be,
to think differently
and to even question things.
And throughout mankind's history
it's been pretty dangerous
to question things,
you know,
you get fried,
executed,
bad things happen to you.
Bad things happen to you.
Even if you reach
an advanced state
of consciousness,
you see,
the profound ignorance,
even in the spiritual,
religious domains,
throughout Christian history,
you know,
it's very hard
to think differently
and to even question things.
You see,
the profound ignorance
even in the spiritual,
religious domains,
is something
you believe
in,
and it's a good thing.
So,
you know,
when you get into
that stage in Christian history,
if you became enlightened,
if you went into
the state
of the infinite oneness
and started to space out,
they,
you were called a mystic,
and,
now you're real likely
to be excommunicated
and,
pride for heresy.
Because,
what all
of the spirituality
looks like
from the viewpoint
of 800 or 900
is totally different
than what it looks like
from 410,
that a Christian dogma which revealed you know as ignorant throughout the
century does it kind of calibrates over 200 is it calibrates over 300 a little
over time all right so spiritual ignorance proven and prevailed it
calibrates a little over 200 if we asked about certain belief systems we trying
to calibrate below 200 but mm-hmm so Church doctrine then we say well it's
Church doctrine doctrine doctrine dogma dogma so we live in pure dogma where
that dogma rise it did not arise from the origin there decrees Jesus Christ
said people say the Christian they start quoting from the Old Testament I said
why are you pointing to me from the Old Testament you know that all the books of
the Old Testament make you go weak with the exception of Genesis I said we're
going to look at some sacred cows today spiritual work means you got to be
prepared look at sacred cows if the sacred cows are correct you wouldn't be
looking for an enlightenment you'd be in
late understand consequently if you and mankind are not enlightened it means
some profound ignorance has prevailed in your lifetime and that of all of
mankind in the eye of the eye I'm trying to find out where is that ignorant where
is it lodged where does it get its power from and who keeps propagating it ah
there you go very large segments of consciousness
expressed throughout humanity benefit enormously from man's ignorance and of a
vest
it
the last thing a lot of cults and so-called religions would like would be
to have us examine that releases under the kinesiology as to their relative
truth that's not exactly what they would like exactly what they would like all
right so you might say there are forces within man's humanity in society which
are have a vested interest in
the continuance of man's ignorance they benefit from it they get worldly power
from it physical power own great tracts of land enormous funds sums of money and
there's a lot of competition amongst various so-called religious and
spiritual groups for just those things influence money power position titles
that which is truly of God has nothing to gain that which is truly of God
charges no fee I'm not going to tell you God's so-called spiritual power is not
that which is given freely there's no charge that which I know was given to me
as a revelation it just became apparent out of itself out of its own truth so
apparently what a lot of the religions do is a spiritual groups is they try to
get control over the members so we want to talk today about false gurus we want
to talk about Carmen I talk about false gurus because seekers after truth are the most vulnerable
they're the ones that the spiritual charlatans go after you're the
customers you folks in this right out here are the customers that everybody
looks for and tries to get their allegiance and apparently the desire for
this legion is to get power over people how do you know they want power because
they they're very into some getting followers they take a very hostile view
if you try to leave their group
you belong to the holy jumpers and so so-and-so and when you want to leave they
have even a ritual where you're pronouncing that you never bored you burn
or smokes I mean this guy's taking it hard and then you can't lose one one one
follower without having a rupture about it you know I mean I've seen so-called
spiritual leaders you know apparently passed out because some leads some
member especially he's prominent a lot of money I mean titles and names is leaving
his flock holy smokes so that's how you know the difference the real
spiritual to show I have nothing to gain by your following them there's
absolutely nothing any search over there contained from having a million
followers it's totally boring how many people are following you imagine walking
around there's a million people following you I mean what a drag that
would be everywhere you go people want to pull your buttons off and you know
touch your hem your gown and this guy video would be really nice to try but a
people eat that up and having millions of expensive cars there was one guru
there that had them ninety nine hundred and forty Mercedes Benz's that went over
there this is kind of like sir Rolls-Royce's
that grew at the time was below at the time the world is changing the world is
changing the world is changing very rapidly and we've discovered something
very recently that sort of blowing our mind our mind is still blown thinking
lovingly of very very negative people takes a lot of negativity and they're
crossing over above 200
it's the
miraculous
is becoming commonplace well let's say at a consciousness level below 200 the
miraculous would be pretty rare wouldn't you know the pictures of the saints start
to cry and all kinds of weird things happen smoke goes up from stacks and
stuff people make great pyramids if you're pilgrimages you know above 200
when you think about it I guess the miraculous would become increasingly
common would it not you see don't forget at 190 you've got enormous
forces against the expressions of divinity in humankind at 207 now the tide
is shifted in the other direction all of the consciousness of mankind henceforth
now supports the miraculous the expression of divinity in the evolution
of consciousness. The prevalence of love over hate is now sustained at 207. Under 200, prevalence
of love was not possible. Even in recent history like Cambodia, what was that terrible killer
guy that died recently? Yeah, there was a whole society where about half, almost genocide,
about half the population got killed. Anything that sounded and looked like love, even the
word was condemned. You could be executed for anything that was done in the name of
or for love. Love was forbidden in our society. Can you believe that? It's true. Oh, boy.
So, you see, at 190, you can get away with that. At 207, the whole world would come up
in arms about that, and the whole world is coming up in arms. We see shifts in society.
So, what we need is a, oh, hey, what we need is a project for this. All right, let's do
it. Okay. All right. Now, so, well, I watched an interviewer. What's his name? He's a very
experienced with interviewing leaders in various countries. What's the name of that guy? Anyway,
he's on 60 Minutes. The guy that gets depressed, he wrote about it.
Mike Wallace. Oh, yes, Mike Wallace. Yeah, yeah. Anyway, he's interviewing the leader
of China. And he's coming from that cocky American moral superiority. Don't you think
it's time for your country to afford human rights? Snide superiority. He's talking to
the leader of China, one-third of the world's population, who's probably forgotten more
than Mike Wallace has ever forgotten.
So, we're going to know in his lifetime, having evolved through many a lifetime to
become, you know, the emperor of the greatest, most powerful nation on earth. China is really
the greatest and most powerful nation on earth. Outnumbered Americans seven to one or whatever.
So, here's this guy from nowhere, if you ask me, just because he's been on TV a lot, doesn't
make him somebody. And he's very impertinently, I thought, impertinently approaching a man
who has been in the administration for the last eight years and says, Mike, I don't
know. And he's very adamant about it. But when you say we should be more than one third
of the world, we should be more than one third of the world. But he's come and gone. And that's
his dream.
He's gone.
It's not his own dream.
The only one of his dreams.
It's his own.
No, it's not his dream.
who, if you calibrate his level of consciousness,
you find that his consciousness level has jumped real up.
Way up.
All right.
So all of us that have this intense spiritual commitment,
if we all focus lovingly on China,
what's the leader of China?
I don't even know his name.
I don't know what his name is.
We all gotta find out though.
Or get a picture of him or something.
Anyway, we should all,
this is a project of this group.
Our group is gonna be to turn around China, okay?
We can do that easily.
We just hold loving, beautiful thoughts
about these people and their leader.
And hold them within our hearts.
And we lift them up unto the Lord, you might say,
by the divinity of our own love.
Don't forget, all love is divine love.
There is only one kind of love, and it's all divine love.
All right.
So a group as powerful as this group,
this is a very powerful group,
we unite.
And just as a group project,
let's say at least once a day,
think something lovingly about the people of China
and their leader,
and picture the softening of his heart,
and his caring about his people,
his caring about his people.
So that all we're asking him to do
is to open his heart to his own people.
That's all we're asking him to do.
We're not telling him what to do.
We're not telling him anything that's wrong.
I don't think there's anything wrong with his society at all.
His society has evolved to a certain point,
and it is what it is,
because that's what it is.
It is what it is at this point.
But we as a group can certainly potentiate its growth,
and that's what we're going to do.
All in agreement?
All in favor of turning China around?
Anybody opposed?
Greatest thing that ever happened in Chinese history
has just happened in this room.
They don't know it yet.
We're not going to tell them.
We're not going to tell them,
because that would set up a defense, you understand?
We don't want to set up a defense, see?
So if we said, we as a group are praying for you,
to help you people,
it would set up enormous resistance there.
Who are these goddamn Americans trying to tell us how to end the crisis?
We were civilized by then.
You people were still hanging around in trees,
you know what I'm saying?
If I was a Chinaman, I'd say,
what, that's what folks were still hanging in trees,
for God's sake, aren't we?
So you see how the American attitude sets other people on edge.
It's sort of a little embarrassing, you know what I'm saying?
A little embarrassing at times.
When you see the lack of humility,
talking to a great leader with great potentiality,
to move his people.
I saw it happen in North Korea, so I know it can happen.
And I also know that we have the capacity to do that with China.
Let's see if we do.
I just said it so much, China.
We can raise the level of the consciousness of the leader of China
by over 10 points' resist, by 20 points' resist,
by 30 points' resist, holy Christ, by 50 points' resist, oh my God.
So this group, they're, you know, not necessarily meditation.
While you're buttering your toast, you can just think,
gosh, you're not such a bad guy.
You know what I mean?
You butter your toast.
It says that we can raise his level of consciousness 40 points.
That's enormous, enormous, 40 points.
30.
That's an incredible jump.
Anyway, it would.
Are we being grandiose?
Are we being real?
We're being real.
See, what happens is you deny your own divinity.
You understand what I'm saying?
You see, I'm not of divine essence.
I'm just an ego.
What allows you to be an ego?
People like me, they wouldn't have the power
to influence the future of a giant, the biggest country on Earth.
The Chinese are what, one and a half billion people
or two billion people or something out of the six billion that exist.
I mean, this little group of people here in nowhere California,
they're going to shift the whole .
Why not?
See, the miraculous, there's nothing to the miraculous.
The miraculous is the obvious.
The miraculous is the way that it wants to go.
The miraculous is what brought us together and brought up this subject so that we should do it.
God said, gee, I need a group to get together and help out China there.
How about you bringing it up, Dave, at your next talk?
Okay.
It only came to me as I said it.
See, I never know what I'm going to say.
I hear it as it's said.
There's no knowing that it's going to be said.
And usually there's no recognition that it was said.
I depend on her to recall that.
But that which erupts of its own is out of divinity.
You understand what I'm saying?
You can tell by the energy of it that it's true.
It's so.
The collective power of the divinity within each and every one of us
expressed out as love towards that country and its leader will have a profound influence.
That's for certain.
To deny it is to deny your own reality.
It's to say, I'm only a weak ego and I have no influence in this world.
I'm just a nothing.
I'm just a toad.
No, that's not so.
Each one of us here reflects the divinity of God expressed through our own beingness in this lifetime.
It's good karma time, folks.
Put this one, wrap this one up for eternity.
And you get there, you can say, yep, we were part of what pulled the chain out of the mud, you know, and got them sailing again.
No, it's just the joy.
You see, the joy of one's existence, the joy of one's existence is the joy of the awareness of the reality of that
which you really are.
And then you begin to own the power of it.
The power of everyone here is Christ-like in that by thinking of that in a loving way,
in a loving way, for our love of the people of China, Lord, many miserable,
and our love for the leader, see, because I found out one thing about these great leaders,
is many of them have great power, but the heart isn't open yet.
The heart isn't open.
The heart isn't open yet, see.
And they really are concerned, and they are very, very capable.
A lot of these people are political geniuses.
They're not fools, you know.
Even Hitler was a political genius.
I mean, he wrapped your friend's finger like that.
And what's out then is the heart.
What's out is the intention.
And if you radiate the knowingness of that, the divinity of that intention,
then you're inviting that beingness to respond to your love.
And against love, there is no defense.
Against coercion, there's many defenses.
So to try to coerce the Chinese into the American way is absurd.
And of course, the leader of China is telling me, what's his name, the interviewer there,
he said, what's his name again?
Wallace.
Yeah, it's like criticizing China, huh?
China, thousands and thousands of years old, and here's Mike Wallace telling this guy,
why don't you folks straighten up, you know what I mean?
And the leader of China looks at Wallace and he says, there are many things in your society
that do not necessarily meet our approval either.
Drugs, sex, violence, gangs, I mean, there's a few things, graffiti that we don't care for in China.
Rock music, kill, murder, and rape your mother, and slice up your sister,
and watch the blood squirt all over.
I mean, you listen to the lyrics of some of these things, you say, I don't believe that our kids are listening to this.
They're sitting there with earphones on, a hypnotic trance, they're a little bit stoned,
and they're getting programmed, programmed, programmed, programmed, programmed.
Kill, kill, kill, kill, and then they go out to their video game and they kill 10 or 20,000 times more,
and then they appear on the front page of the paper.
Why did you do it?
I don't know, I just wanted to see what it felt like to kill somebody.
I just wanted to see what it was like to do it.
What I've been doing all day, every day for years and years, Mom and Dad,
and the music that are being poured into my ears.
So, that's what the leader of China was objecting to.
I got instantly, intuitively what he was saying.
He was saying, no, after looking at your society, we have downsides.
He admitted he had downsides to his society.
Yes, we have downsides.
We have areas in which we can improve, and you likewise, so don't be throwing stones.
What he's really saying is, those who live in glass houses shouldn't throw stones.
But he...
He was too diplomatic.
Wallace doesn't have that degree of diplomacy, but the leader of China held back.
He held back.
He didn't lash out at all.
He could have, you know, he could have taken Wallace apart, but he didn't.
He held back and said, well, there are a few things about your society
that we don't necessarily want, you know, to happen within ours.
And without mentioning anything in specific.
So, what it means then is that the man did, you see,
he did...
I felt like he did have his heart there with the interview with Wallace.
And Wallace overlooked his heart completely.
He was so into moral superiority, you know, the puritanical positionality that we get into
right and wrong.
What most people in our society consider to be spirituality or religion is nothing but
puritanism.
Puritanism is not spirituality.
Puritanism is not even ethics.
Puritanism is a distortion of spiritual reality.
And it's based upon the duality of right and wrong.
So, we can't see the people of China as either right or wrong.
We see them as needful of our love and our consideration.
And certainly the leader, I felt he had his heart there.
And then his heart was turned down.
He could have been turned on.
I wish I'd had a chance to talk to him.
I'd say, you know, I really admire your country.
And I admire your great culture.
And we've made progress in what we consider to be spiritual.
And what we consider to be certain areas that are significant.
But it's probably not time for them to consider that to be significant first.
First you've got to have a working society.
And then you try to upgrade its spiritual positions on things.
It's more the way he may be looking at it.
I don't know.
But anyway, I wish I'd been up there.
But I didn't get a chance to talk to him.
Because I'd like to just win him over and tell him I dearly love him.
Maybe China would have changed by today already, you know.
But you see, everybody is vulnerable to love.
Everybody is vulnerable to love.
The leader of China is extremely vulnerable to love.
That's my intuition.
Let's see this.
The leader of China is vulnerable to love.
His heart chakra is over 200.
His heart chakra is already over 200.
So we don't have to turn around somebody who's negative.
We don't have to turn around a monster at all.
His heart is already in the positive.
We didn't ask how high.
But certainly our love is sent to him and sent especially to his heart.
His love for his people.
There's his opening.
See, his opening is his love for his people.
Let's see if that's so.
His opening is his love for his people.
That's true.
Yes, that was Gorbachev's opening too, see.
Gorbachev, when he calibrated his heart chakra, very enormous, 700.
Out of the love for his people, he gave up his political positionality, communism.
And the leader of China will do the same thing.
Out of his love for his people, through his heart, that's his opening.
And we pour our love into him, and he will pour it back out onto his people.
And you'll see a transformation in society.
Without throwing a single brick, without firing a single shot, we in this room have
just changed history.
Let's see if that's so.
We have indeed just changed history.
See?
Okay, so it comes about spontaneously.
Spiritual work is not just personal progress and calibrating how my little consciousness
is going as compared to last month and that kind of thing.
Spiritual work is a response to a person.
Responsibility towards mankind in general.
It's the spirit of all.
We're very responsible for the people in China.
Why?
Because very few groups have the insight, the knowledge, the tools, you know what I'm
saying?
The motivation.
How many groups on the planet are committing themselves to this little project today?
Anybody want to guess?
There is another group committed, just as we are today, resistant.
They're committing themselves to this.
What's the difference?
One of them is silent.
No, he's one of them.
there could be more groups
spawned out by us.
We could spawn out other groups
and do the same thing.
Make it sort of a local
Course in Miracles project
for the year 2001.
Course in Miracles 2001.
Our project this year is...
I dearly love the Course in Miracles.
We're going to talk more about it tomorrow.
Now it's 10 to 3.
I'm not sure what we're supposed to do now.
Do we ask for some questions
and answers or what?
Oh, you want to see how to do kinesiology.
Anybody here want to do it?
Work what with that?
Oh, oh.
Yes, well, let me just mention kinesiology
because it's a useful tool.
One of the greatest discoveries
in the history of mankind, yes.
How to tell truth from falsehood,
which no man has ever had up until now,
right, in the recent days.
You find somebody that you can work with.
So let's start like we're just
starting.
Let's start with each other.
Let's do it, okay.
I keep forgetting that I'm on even here.
Okay, now, when you pick somebody you want to work with,
I think the best thing to do, first of all,
you don't want music in the background.
You don't want to influence people with visual images.
So I think the test person would be best to close their eyes
because as you know, anybody who's read John Dinah's work,
if you just look at a curve like this,
it will make you go strong.
If you look at a curve that goes
like this, it will make you go weak.
So even looking at something could have an influence.
No jewelry across the midline and what do you do
when you get into that space?
Well, no jewelry, yeah.
Let's see, you'll have to talk into this.
Tell me what you do when you go into the space.
When I say, let's check something out,
what do you go through?
What do you do?
Basically, I close my eyes and try and relax and try
and clear the line of any outside.
And then just let the.
All right, now we sort of recently discovered
that the first question, the first thing you should do is ask
the person to hold in mind somebody they love.
Say, we're going to all do this.
And I'm going to show you first what we're going to do.
Then we're going to go ones and twos and we'll all do it.
Hold in mind somebody you love.
Could be your kitty.
I'm going to hold in mind my kitty.
I love my kitty.
All right, so the first thing is love makes you go strong
and that which is not love.
Like hatred.
Can you think of hatred?
Think of hatred.
Can you?
It gets harder after a while.
Think of something negative.
Let's see.
Think of all of those little kids dying in Africa of AIDS.
Hold that in mind.
Resist.
Okay. We're running out of negatives.
I'll tell you why.
Because as you keep using a negative example
to make the person go weak, you yourself are starting
to radiate energy to that which used to make you,
you know, go negative.
You know there are images, negative images
that used to make people go weak.
I used them in front of thousands of people
in many, many lectures.
They don't do it anymore because of constantly referring to them
and using them.
Their energy has actually shifted to the positive.
There was a group we were going to test that used
to make you go weak.
You know, makes you have to go strong.
Hmm. Strange.
So that's the power of, of course, miracles.
See? Its power can be demonstrated and calibrated.
So love makes you go strong.
That which is not love makes you go weak.
So let's start with that.
Let's divide into ones and twos and we'll go
through a real quick drill.
I'm going to go and divide into ones and twos.
All of you that want to do it.
Those that don't want to do it, don't do it.
Sit down and don't do it.
Yeah. I'm going to do it.
Sit down.
Okay.
Okay. Yeah.
Okay. Just pick a partner.
Decide who's going to be number one,
who's going to be number two.
Who's ever the oldest gets to be number one?
No lying.
Whoever the oldest is, is, is the doctor.
And the youngest one is the patient.
Okay, doctor.
You look at your patient.
Patient, hold out your arm to the right.
Patient, hold out your arm.
All right.
Now, doctor, you're going to press down on, on,
on her wrist with two fingers and say resist.
Say resist.
Resist. Two fingers.
You see? You're not trying to push their arm down out of strength.
You're trying to get a feeling for their relative,
you know, strength, you know.
You push down with two fingers.
And the person, I want the patient to push back equal
to the pressure downward, see?
When I press down with two fingers, she pushes back equal
so that her arm neither goes up nor down.
You see what I'm saying?
So the more, the harder I press down,
the harder she would have to push back.
So you only, you don't need a lot of pressure.
You just, you just want to get a feeling
and I say to her, resist, resist.
See how easy that is?
We're not, it's not a hard deal, see?
It's sort of an easy thing.
It's an easy going thing, see?
Okay. Now I say to the person, and don't forget now,
patients, close your eyes.
Okay, now hold in mind, patients, hold in mind somebody
you love and doctors tell them to resist and press down on them.
Everybody go strong with love.
Now, okay, patients, I want you to hold the opposite in mind.
Hold the little starving kids in Viapra.
Hold somebody you don't like.
Picture your favorite pet being run over by a truck.
Oh.
Yeah.
Okay, anybody, anybody who's having trouble with love makes you go strong
and that would not love makes you weak coming up here
and Susan will, will, will, will track out with some .
It's very common, there's a couple of things that cause it all the time.
Yeah.
Come on up here, anybody who's having trouble getting,
love makes you go strong and non-love makes you go weak.
Anybody having trouble getting that answer, come up and we'll work with you.
No, if your husband and wife, yeah, okay, good.
Husbands and wives don't work together.
together so the first question the first question really to ask me is this a good
person this is a good person for me to work with see okay this is a good person
for me to work with with physiology resist I guess yes she is you might get
to know because a lot of times husbands and wives for some reason don't work
well together but you'll have to get a relative yes the best test subject is a
child a child who knows nothing about the subject whatsoever you can hold a
picture of something that's positive or they're sort of like this to all the
strong and when you hold something negative they will go weak they never
heard of Sadat Hussam or whatever his name is there and but they'll you know
so children are are excellent subjects but to find somebody
to work with first say is this person good this person all right so you don't
ask a question you make a statement this person is good for me to work with you
don't say is this person because there's no way to answer that yes and yes or no
there's no way answer that so you make a statement this person is good for me is
going to be satisfactory for me to work with is this love mixer goes strong
resist and that which is not love makes her go weak resist all right so that's
all you want to know can you all do that
anybody can't do it come up to the friends who's the work with
once you have it down pat I want you to switch doctors and patients switch sides
and doctors hold love in mind and the other
one
and if you're the patient don't forget to close your eyes
and it's just
okay
oh
don't you don't you must hurry up
don't leave
very
very good
everybody got all three of them getting ready to work out sit down
once you get it sit sit down if you've got it working so that both of you
you go strong with love you go weak with not love
have you all heard what's on his melhor
Rusia
yeah but you have to say take that all right
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
If you're not getting the right result,
then try down at the signing school
and you should go straight to them.
Sometimes they're gonna get interested in you.
The music is really good.
Just take that.
Anybody that still needs help, you stand up
and Suze will come over and help you.
She's a very good test subject.
Yeah, she is, she's a good test subject.
Now, what is the value of this?
What is the value of this, you know?
Well, the value is rather profound.
What is the value of this?
Let me just talk while you're experimenting.
There's so much I want to share with you today
and we're gonna run out of time.
When I first learned kinesiology,
I used to do it all over the place, you know,
and the thousands of doctors all over tried it out
and we tried to trick it, you know,
we tried all kinds of tricks.
And trying to disprove it, you know,
I mean, we were all trying to, you know,
we were all trying to check out its validity.
So, I was gonna give a lecture on kinesiology
to a group that night.
Well, who started the first attitudinal healing center?
Huh?
Oh, yeah, Jerry, yeah.
So, Jane Polsky and his whole crew had come to my house
in Long Island and they spent the weekend.
They're glad they're in heaven, they said.
And Jane Polsky shared with us
how they were using it as attitudinal healing.
So, the second attitudinal healing group
in the United States was started in Long Island
at the clinic I was running at the time.
I started an attitudinal healing center there.
And the spiritual, the Course in Miracles group there
act as facilitators and so we started
the second attitudinal healing center.
And to help us get it started,
we had Jerry Jane Polsky and his staff
come and train us and share with us
what he knew about it.
Well, one night I was gonna give a lecture on kinesiology
and I was in my office in Long Island,
I had a huge clinic there.
And some of my friends who were doing
the Course in Miracles were in another adjoining room.
So, I had a break between patients and I said,
you know, I gotta give a lecture on kinesiology tonight
and I need a couple of volunteers.
How about you folks?
So, I had two or three of them and I knew them
and so I tried the standard things
for which kinesiology was first used.
Fluorescent lights make you go weak.
What are the common things?
Pesticides make you go weak.
All these things that make you go weak.
So, anyway, I was testing out some of these people
and they happened to be working
in the attitudinal healing center.
And I said, come on here a second.
And they said they'd be happy to help me
with the lecture tonight, see?
So, I would have them look at the fluorescent light
and they didn't go weak.
I said, what?
And I had them look at pesticides.
Hold the pesticide in your mouth.
Didn't make them go weak.
Artificial sweeteners, artificial cigarettes,
everything that makes people go weak
had no effect on them.
I said, what in the world is this?
Well, we discovered that once a person,
in doing the Course in Miracles,
once you get past about less than 90 or so,
all the things that make everybody else
in the universe go weak
no longer make you go weak.
They no longer have any power over you.
So, then I had a chance to research it out
because a couple of other people I knew
that I'd recommended, I said,
why don't you do the Course in Miracles,
had started the course.
And I had a chance to check them out
with the Course in Miracles
before they did the course
and then periodically as they went through
the Course in Miracles.
And I did the same thing with Susan.
And when they reached about,
it's actually less than 76,
but it's around,
by the time you get to less than 90,
all the things that once made you go weak
won't make you go weak anymore.
You're only subject to what you hold in mind.
You've disempowered
that the world has any power over you.
There's nothing out there that has any power over you.
So, you can't just go and do less than 76
and then expect this miracle.
You've got to go through the course.
And, but we noticed by less than 90,
if we'd taken, if we'd gotten
to the lobby there and grabbed somebody
and had them come in here
and look at the fluorescent light,
they would go weak, I guarantee it.
And if we take the people here
who have gone beyond less than 90,
you know, fluorescent light will not make you
go weak anymore.
Pesticides will not make you go weak.
You're not subject to.
And when I discovered that, I said,
well, in that case,
my belief in poison ivy is ridiculous.
So, I said, I'm only subject to what I hold in mind.
I'm not subject to poison ivy.
And it did put me in the hospital a couple of times.
And I went out and I picked it.
I went out and picked it
and, in fact, I dug it up
and put it in flower pots
and had it around the house.
I could play with poison ivy.
It had no effect on me.
I said, whoa.
And, you know, things that kill bugs,
pesticides, sprays, or whatever you call them,
would always give me migraine headaches.
I had to be driven home from the hospital one time
with a migraine headache that was so severe,
it was unbelievable,
from exclaiming for pesticides.
So, anyway, at that point,
also pesticides had no hope.
No effect.
So, you can demonstrate the effectiveness
of the Course in Miracles by,
and it'd be fun if your own group,
if you get some new people,
say, you know,
the traditional things that make people go weak,
fluorescent lights are guaranteed.
And thinking negative thoughts.
Pesticides.
You can hold pesticides.
I've done a kinesiology with, you know,
thousands at a time.
Hold two apples up.
One is pesticide, one is organic.
And have all the people look at the organic apple.
They all go strong.
They don't know which is which.
I just say, and I don't tell them
which pesticide one's organic.
I just say, here's an apple.
Everybody look at this apple.
They all go strong.
I say, okay, now everybody look at this apple.
They all look at this apple.
They all go weak.
Just looking at a pesticide apple,
the energy, the frequency of that vibration of it
makes you go weak.
When we were in Korea a year or two ago,
was it the first time there or the second time?
I forget.
Whatever.
Anyway, there was a large group there,
made up of Buddhist monks and wonderful people.
I was crazy about them all.
And anyway, the leader of that group, Dr. Moon,
Dr. Moon is a former assistant to the Dalai Lama.
She was the one that came over from Korea
to twist my arm to go to Korea.
So Dr. Moon, without telling me anything about it,
said, here's two bags of things.
So here I've got this big crowd,
and she gives me these two baggies,
and they both have greenery,
some kind of greens in them.
And I said to her,
so I hold up these greens,
and everybody went strong,
and then we hold up these greens,
and everybody went weak.
And I said to her,
what's the difference?
She said, well, this one's got pesticide,
this one doesn't.
That's amazing, isn't it?
Just to look at it, see,
the energy and the frequency and the vibration.
So that's non-locality.
In other words,
even to think of it as a connection.
You get that?
Wow.
That's why this group has such power over China.
See?
Because even to think,
just to think,
just to think.
Because even to think,
just as looking at that,
not looking at that pesticide,
looking at that,
it was cabbage she had.
Just to look at the cabbage
made her go weak,
and to look at the other cabbage
made her go strong.
So consequently,
we're not confined by locality.
You understand?
The fact that he's in China,
on the other-
our visual perception
as the other side of the world,
forget it,
he's right here now.
His consciousness is right here now.
You get it?
Yeah.
you think of the difficult life this man was had to be responsible imagine the
karmic worry you know you got a quarter of the population or a third whatever it
is the planet and the whole country on your head whoa whoa how does that guy sleep without
Ovaltine I don't know every decision is going to influence the lives of thousands
and millions of people right you picture eternity in pain for all this whoo boy
boy I tell you he needs a guru to help him I'm telling you this guy I mean it's
a tremendous responsibility so compassion for the tremendous responsibility he has
karmically this man is responsible for an entire nation and I'm saying he's
answerable moment of death he's gonna be looking at what did I do with my power
on behalf of a quarter of the population of this planet whoa you know me I worry
I see this black fetal there and he's on his back and he's looking like this thing
can't go around his tummy and I'm the karmic
implication is that he's responsible for the entire nation and I'm saying he's
looking at what did I do with my power on behalf of a quarter of the population this is profound you know I mean can
I walk passes me you know I got to take a leaf and turn over so захid won't go
on I mean I might just fit I want to face that feelings coming back I mean
where were you when I needed Joe you gonna see fun like this and you walk
past me didn't Jesus say you should stop by and help you know what kind of
Christian are you who like that so imagine what this guy is is handling
over there I don't know his name but we're going to find out his name oh
I mean, you know, actually, when you look at it from your own heart, you realize what a tremendous burden.
You know, like in World War II, Winston Churchill, you know, I used to look at Churchill and think, wow, man,
here's the symbol of the British Empire and its survival, really embodied symbolically in the energy of one man.
And what he was, the nation became. What he was not, the nation was not built together.
So the spiritual power, then, of this leader of China is enormous.
And instead of looking at him in any negative, there's no point to look at him in any negative way at all.
He's where he is, and what he's waiting for is, he doesn't have the energy, you know, no, he doesn't have the love energy.
Okay, let's see what it is. He hasn't gotten the love energy that he needs.
Who's that?
Resist. But we can supply it. Resist. Oh, yes, okay.
All right, what tips the scale with this man is, his heart's over 200.
Let's see how high it is. We have permission to ask this for spiritual reasons that this group resists.
It's not for publication. Anyway, it's over 300. It's over 400. It's over 500.
Over 400. 480. 490. 480. 480. Wow, that's very high.
Okay, this guy's up to 400.
480 already in his heart. Wow, that's tremendous.
So we've got to hit start with him. We've just got to push him over to 500 level.
See? We just hug him. We just grab onto him and talk.
Come on, you old bear there. Come on now.
And we just love him to death.
And he finally can't, one day he wakes up in bed and he says, oh, then he says,
hmm, God, I don't think it's right to put all these people to death just because they don't belong to our political party.
Maybe we should let him retire.
Instead of executing him, we'll let him retire. You know what I mean?
And he'll do anything. Wow, what a great idea. You know what I mean?
And he'll feel really good, you know, like Scrooge on Christmas morning.
Everybody prays for Scrooge.
And what happens is one morning Scrooge wakes up and he's in a different world. Isn't that so?
All right, so we can't deny the power of our own spiritual, our own divinity.
A Course in Miracles teaches us to own it. Own it. Instead of denying it, own it.
Affirm your own divinity.
One way you affirm it with absolute conviction is when you put it into practice and see it happen.
That is really convincing.
It scares Susie and I all the time.
All right, so,
because we all come from the human
society, and it's evolution in which the separation between the ego and God is so
inculcated,
the denial of our own divinity is the automatic position we first take.
Oh, I didn't, I couldn't have caused that. I couldn't have, you know, on the contrary.
So today we're going to re-own through our own truth, through our own, as a spiritual exercise,
re-own our own power. That we have the power literally to save the people of China,
and that we will do so, and that we will try to inspire its leader through our love,
towards him, and towards his heart.
So what we just got with Susie is that he, the reason that it's where he's at, is he hasn't received enough love from his people.
You see, if he was loved back, if they radiated back an adoration to him, his heart would bleed. You understand?
There's no loving adoration directed towards him. Probably due to fear.
Fear, fear.
They want his respect, and they straighten up in front of him, loving him. No, no, no. It's hard to love.
Somebody who stands for arbitrary power like that, okay?
It's easy to love a teddy bear. It's very hard to love somebody who looks like a militaristic dictator.
So, happily, we don't know him, so it's going to be a lot easier for us.
We don't have any impediments of some perception of him as being other than a lovable old bear.
And we're just going to love him up in our hearts, and watch what happens.
Alright, so we'll stop here.
I think we have to stop here.
But this time and then, we're going to switch to questions and answers. Is that correct?
Anybody want to take a short break?
It's been a busy afternoon. We just saved a third of the planet.
I don't think we can't do it. I know we can. It's a fact.
See, what I believe in is putting the spiritual belief into actual experiential reality.
I've known people who have gone around in metaphysical groups for 40 years,
and they're still in the same position they were.
They're still in the same position they were the first time.
How many times do you have to hear truth? Once. That's all.
You don't have to hear it 42 times.
You hear it once. Make it work once. Now you're done forever.
There's no point in taking the course of miracles over again. Is there?
The reality of who you are stands forth and radiates from this group right now.
The minute you own it, in this instant of time, you never have to ask it again.
You understand what I'm saying?
That's how enlightenment occurs.
Enlightenment is the absolute grasping of reality.
And truth, in this moment, now.
It can't happen tomorrow.
It can't happen next week. It can only happen right now.
So the real power that leads to enlightenment, it rises out of the heart.
You see what I'm saying?
Out of your love for the leader of North China arises your own salvation.
Because you only discover the power of your love when you express it.
You understand?
You experience it and you realize divinity is that which is within you,
and out of which your own existence arises.
So our salvation, as a group here, depends on our saving China.
Otherwise we don't know the truth of our own reality.
So let's put it to the test.
The reason spirituality has worked for me, and it works incredibly well,
is because I always put it to the test.
Either it is or it isn't.
I'm tired of bullshit.
I don't want to hear preachers talking about it.
Things that they haven't even experienced.
What I've done is somebody on the road to someplace in history who cares.
I want to know what happens to me on the road to going outside here right now.
That's where reality is.
Reality is not somewhere a couple thousand years ago.
It's all popcock.
Experience the reality and the power of our own divinity right now.
So let's take a break, and then we'll have questions,
and China's enough to work on everything.
We'll start on Africa next year.
We had to recapitulate creation throughout all eternity.
The entire evolution of all of mankind recontextualized the human experience this afternoon,
so we had to move on.
Actually, we did it, didn't we?
I want to discuss one more analogy, and then we're going to have questions.
One more analogy that really fits in well with A Course in Miracles.
It talks about the innate innocence within each and every, all of us.
In the analogy of the computer, you see, consciousness is like the hardware,
and the ego is like the software.
Each of us, the hardware, you see, is uninfluenced by the software.
You can play any program through the hardware of a computer,
and the hardware of the computer is, you know,
not affected by it.
So we're all run by our software,
but we never lose the innocence of our hardware.
The reason we're all so programmable, then,
is because of our innocence.
You see how the innocence is the opening through which
that which denies spiritual reality can creep in?
It's because of our innocence that we're programmable
by that which is
what you say, averse to human happiness.
We're programmable.
We're programmable because there is no truth switch on our computer.
You can program this computer, the human mind, with anything you want on a computer.
I recently saw a very interesting series of documentaries on the History Channel
of Hitler's youth, the years when these innocent young children,
how they were brought up.
And you could see,
they couldn't help but be other than they were.
They were brought up in this wonderful campfire kind of camaraderie,
singing these wonderful songs for the good of their motherland
and the pride of their family and culture,
and, you know, it was fantastic.
How could these kids be anything other than what they were?
They loved it.
They looked forward to going to camp,
and they were all trying to be a better, you know,
it was very much like the Scouts,
very much like the Scouts.
It's just that the Scouts went this way and the Hitler youth went that way.
But the techniques were almost identical, you know,
cooking hot dogs by the fire and singing the songs,
the camaraderie.
And so we saw the innocent.
You see how innocence is vulnerable.
That's how innocence is vulnerable.
But the innocence is never lost.
And as we evolve spiritually,
we look past the programming,
and we see the innocence of the spirit within.
Huh?
We see the innocence of the spirit within.
So the spirit cannot be damaged,
but it's when we stop identifying the myself as the ego,
you know, when you stop misidentifying the ego.
The only thing I don't like about The Chorus of Miracles is the textbook.
The workbook is perfect,
and the workbook alone,
will take you the whole way.
The thing that I disagree with in the textbook
is the way it tends to set up the ego as an enemy.
You know, you get polarized.
You get polarized with the ego as an enemy.
Well, your software is not an enemy,
it's just incorrect.
Two different things.
It's not your enemy.
It's just incorrect.
And the problem is not the ego or the software,
it's identifying with it.
The problem is not the ego.
The problem is identifying with the ego itself.
You can't destroy the ego, you know,
to set up the ego as your enemy.
Then you get into the problem with force, right?
The more you condemn the ego and fight it as an enemy,
the more you strengthen it,
because you've polarized it and given it an existence
when it has no existence in reality.
That's a subtle point,
but that is one error, I think, in the textbook,
is the proclivity to set up the ego
as an enemy.
So that's all I wanted to say about the course
and the analogy.
That intrinsic innocence, then, is our reality.
The programming that goes on, then,
that's maintained in the spirit...
I read an interesting book.
I heard they were review books,
but once in a while I get one,
I calibrate its energy,
and I thought, hmm, I'll read this one.
It was over 600.
It came from Korea,
and it was called Omniology by Dr. Lee.
Everybody from your industry can be named Lee, right?
I don't know how they keep track of each other.
Yung Lee.
I mean, they all sound like they're all Dr. Lee.
So, anyway, I must know 20 different Dr. Lees.
Anyway, it was an interesting book.
I calibrated it.
It's over 600.
And he said that, you know,
there's the physical body, the mental body,
the spiritual body,
and that part of the spiritual body
is what he calls the...
He called it the...
Well, let's see.
Oh, the informational body.
All right.
Part of the...
So, the karmic inheritance, then,
is the informational body.
Your karma comes...
The spirit continues from lifetime,
reincarnation to incarnation,
and then it picks up the vibrations
of all your decisions, etc.
And so it carries that from lifetime to lifetime,
and he calls it the informational body.
In other words,
part of the spirit would be,
like, the programming part.
You know what I'm saying?
Each lifetime, you make a decision,
and you come from a certain positionality.
And now, the next lifetime,
you've got to pick up,
because you're starting with that set of programs
to begin with.
So, you pick up your own software.
You pick up your own software,
and you continue with it
until you realize you're the hardware,
not the software.
You don't have to keep going through all this
to perfect that software, you know?
Because if you're not your software,
there's no point in perfecting it,
you know what I'm saying?
All right.
So, any questions?
I don't know,
and I've never asked it.
See, Jesus Christ calibrates at 1,000.
A Course in Miracles calibrates at 600.
Doesn't mean that Jesus Christ couldn't have.
To me, what I thought was,
my own personal opinion,
is the teachings of Christ
as translatable into human understanding
at this time would not be above,
I mean, 600 is as high as anybody can get
in this average population.
That the teachings themselves could,
he doesn't necessarily have to teach at 1,000,
because at 1,000 there's really nothing to say.
There's only being what you are,
and being what you are is sufficient
to save all of mankind.
So, other than breathing in and out,
there's nothing to do in 1,000.