We're ready to explain the difference between causality and creation.
We're going to go back to the beginning of the universe.
We have quite a project for this afternoon, don't we? Explain existence
and how this all came about. If you go back to the levels of consciousness,
which anybody here can do through simple meditation, you will see that there are
various levels. Reality starts out at its highest level as the what Krishna would call the supreme
spirit. The Buddha would call the void. Christianity would call Godhead. This is
the level of the unmanifest. The level of the unmanifest appears as nothingness
actually. It is allness. It is actually no thingness, however. It has the capacity to become
anything. All right, so the unmanifest is the infinite potentiality of divinity beyond form.
Advanced theoretical physics states that in one cubic centimeter of empty space, the potential
centimeter of empty space is equivalent to greater than the total mass of the universe.
The universe, as you're aware, is expanding at the speed of light. As it expands at the
speed of light, the infinite potential energy within that cubic centimeter of space also
expands at an infinite rate. Consequently, the infinite potentiality always balances
the manifest. Out of that which is unmanifest, and it says in Genesis, in the beginning there
was the void, no thingness, arises awareness, arises consciousness, and consciousness is
the beginning of the patterning of form. So the manifest is the outcome from the unmanifest.
So how does reality arise? The unmanifest becomes manifest.
And it does so by virtue not of causality, but of creation. So there's a great leap in
awareness here at this level of consciousness. Nothing within the manifest universe has intrinsic
power. Nothing in this universe can create its own existence. No rock can will itself
into being a rock.
So we would say, the primordial, the unmanifest, is the universe.
So we would say the primordial, the unmanifest, is the universe.
So we would say the primordial, the unmanifest, is the universe. So we would say the primordial,
intrinsic, basic, initial action, if you will, of the unmanifest, the supreme beingness of the
universe, was to move from unmanifest to manifest. As it does, if you meditate yourself, let's go
back in the other direction. We went from the unmanifest to the manifest domain, down to the
levels of consciousness, going through awareness, consciousness itself, the witness, the observer,
the experiencer. Let's go back in the other direction, as you would in meditation. In
meditation, you notice that thoughts are going through the mind, sensations through the physical
body, and with a little bit of observation, you will see that you are not the thoughts. The
thoughts come and go, but the you remains the same. You'll notice the same thing about the
body. If the body has sensation, parts of the body may come and go, but the you is
there.
The body is still the same. If we amputate one leg, the guy still says, I'm me. If we amputate the
other leg, he's still me. If we take off two arms, he still says, I'm me. So the I-ness, that which is
I, then, is obviously not the physical body, or it would actually diminish as we chop off arms and
legs. I lost a thumb one time. I went bye-bye. It's waiting for me in heaven. Bye-bye. And I still
felt like,
me. So me minus the thumb, I just felt like me. So me was really unaffected. The sense of I-ness,
then, does not reside within the physical body. When you go to see somebody in there asleep, you
leave and you say, well, he wasn't there. Did you see Joe? No, he was asleep. So obviously, Joe is
not his body, because you saw Joe's body lying there. If Joe was his body, you'd say, yeah, I
saw Joe. You'd say, no, I didn't see Joe. He was sleeping.
So obviously, you're not your body, that which is you, that which is I, the self, is not the body.
Now, the mind is also a very transitory thing. So if you just close your eyes and witness what
goes on in meditation, you're aware that these thoughts, like fish, are going through the water.
You observe now that something is observing the fish. So beyond the content of the ego is the
observer. How do you know what's going on in your thoughts? How do you know what they are?
It's only because there's an observer there and there's an experiencer. So there's that which
is the self manifesting as the observer, the witness. And beyond that is the watcher. The
watcher watches all this. And the watcher is unaffected by what it watches. So you might say
consciousness is impersonal. To become enlightened, you have to get rid of the thought that there's a
personal.
It's a separate thing called I that's unique in the universe.
What's going on?
If you just meditate for a short while, you'll see that witnessing is not a personal phenomenon.
You're witnessing whether you like it or not.
Try telling yourself, telling your mind, stop witnessing.
It goes right down to witnessing, you don't have any control of it.
Consequently, you will quickly discover that consciousness is impersonal.
You've never even decided that you have consciousness.
When you woke up as a small baby, there it was, looking at your little toes.
The capacity, consciousness then is self-existent.
The unmanifest comes to manifest, it first expresses itself as consciousness awareness
before it even begins to come into form.
So that we will observe that evolution occurs on the level of consciousness and then manifests
within the physical being.
So that we will observe that evolution occurs on the level of consciousness and then manifests within the physical being.
Evolution does not occur as a physicality creating a different physicality, creating
a different physicality.
It's on the level of the invisible domain.
Within the invisible domain of consciousness, evolution of consciousness evolves and then
it manifests within the physical domain.
What we see in the physical domain then is the physicality, the externalization, the
expression of the unmanifest.
You might say the divinity within of the self with a capital L.
Yes, within us.
The Empire State Building did not arise on 34th Street, it arose within the concept of
its designer.
One day he got it.
Tallest building in the world, or not 34th Street.
There it was born, in the invisible domain of the consciousness of its creator, who then
excited people with this concept, excited people with this vision, think what it will
do for the city of New York, think of the rentals we get.
Then the contractors, the designers, the sculptors, the stonemasons, the steelworkers
all got involved and the banks got excited.
The lawyers got in there and the real estate appeared and it became manifest.
But as you see, it went from the unmanifest, from the invisible domain, directly into the
physical.
34th Street did not evolve into the Empire State Building.
So we want to overcome another delusion of mankind.
I would like us all to be aware that God is at the top of this chart.
It's that way to God, and this way to the other place.
We laugh at it, but do you realize that a good part of the world, especially throughout
history, has had it in the opposite direction?
It has.
That the force of creation comes from the bottom and goes up.
Now when we understand the material world, we realize it has no power of creation within
it.
The physical world can create anything.
There's not a chair in here that can create another chair.
Not one.
No.
Creation comes from power to lesser power.
As we see, the bottom is lesser power.
The physicality has no power of creation.
The physical world arises out of the invisible domain.
That brings us up to sort of defining the nature of God then.
So let's clarify something about God and clarify another great misunderstanding.
1.
The human ego
God has been greatly maligned throughout history, and the human ego is what's from 200 down.
Here's the ego.
We see the human ego has to do with revenge, retaliation, jealousy, competitiveness, sensitivity,
paranoia, rage, revenge, destructiveness.
That is the level of demons, isn't it?
That's not the level of angels.
Angels are this way.
They're this way.
Devils are that way.
Right?
Let's get clear about that.
All right.
Throughout time, because man didn't know much about anything, really.
Man really didn't know much about anything.
Still doesn't, probably, on the grand time scale.
But, you know, our present life is only written within 100 years, you know, and I've lived
through a good part of it myself.
You know, radios were brand new when I hit this planet.
Much less TV or anything.
So what we consider the modern world is really just the way it is today.
You know?
The modern world is really just the last second.
Throughout most of mankind, human life throughout history, we said the consciousness level of
every century was about 190, which is below truth.
Below truth is easy to sell people that which is false.
That which is most prevalent and still exists considerably in large parts of the world,
including our own country, in certain branches of certain religions, is the confusion of
God with the demons.
The human ego tends to blame God for its own creations.
War is an invention of the human ego.
It is not of divine origin.
Well, the difficulty with a person who is well into the 400s, which is the intellect,
the advanced intellect, is that the negative depictions of God have made atheists of many
honest men.
They know intuitively that God couldn't be that way.
It's hard to believe in a God who is arbitrary, vengeful, savage, angry, fitful, paranoid,
jealous, right?
Sensitive.
So what happens, Freud was correct.
Freud and God monotheism.
Freud said that God was a projection from the human unconscious.
Then he made a mistake and he said, and therefore there isn't any.
That's why Freud calibrates at 499.
The leading scientists in the history, Sir Isaac Newton, Sigmund Freud, Einstein, they
all calibrated 499.
That's a great big block to get from 499, which is the intellect, to 500, which is the
heart.
It's very hard to make that jump.
In our society, it's very seldom made.
0.4% of the population ever gets from their mind, from their head, into the heart.
So Freud made the mistake in thinking, if there is no false gods, therefore there are
no true gods.
What he should have said was, the negative gods, the gods who kill you and savage you
and throw you into hell forever, are a projection from man's unconsciousness out of his guilt,
out of his guilt and fear he rejects onto deity, which he really knows nothing about
unless he's experienced the presence of God, his own imaginations.
Carl Jung went beyond that.
Carl Jung affirmed the spiritual reality of man.
Carl Jung calibrates at 540.
540.
Einstein, Freud is at 499.
Carl Jung affirmed the reality of man's spirit.
Calibrates at 540.
So the correct conclusion is, if the negative gods are really man's imagination, projections
of his own unconscious guilt and fear,
then the real god must be something beyond that.
If a false god is all that is negative, then a real god must be something that is rather positive.
Well, probably to this audience that seems rather obvious,
but if you look throughout mankind's history, you'll see that is not obvious.
The negative gods, all kinds of sacrifices made to them, etc.
One time I had a catatonic patient.
I hadn't spoken in years and he was laying on the floor.
And I was pretty telepathic in those days.
I'll tell you some of my own experiences later to explain that.
Anyway, there was a period of years where I was extremely telepathic.
So this catatonic is laying on the floor.
He hasn't spoken in 20 years.
I used to specialize in schizophrenia and they brought patients from all over the world.
So this guy got flown in from someplace, Hamburg or Paris or someplace, wrapped up in wet sheets.
And he laid on the floor in this catatonic stupor, mute, wouldn't speak.
So anyway, I just sort of looked at him.
And I thought, well, God, what do you want me to do with this one?
And telepathically, I got what was going on with him.
And telepathically, I answered him.
I said, you're blaming God for the machinations of the ego, productions of your own ego.
And he jumped off the floor and he started talking and the nurse about fell over.
And the reason I knew it is because I might as well tell you my own spiritual experience.
It's sort of comical.
But I had been through something of the same thing.
So I intuited exactly where he was at.
Because at a rather young age, I had a lot of unusual spiritual experiences.
And after a number of them, one of them was I was standing out in the woods.
And suddenly out of nowhere came a vision of the totality of human suffering.
I mean, in its complete entirety and totality.
It was like some infinite part of consciousness to which I was connected.
Which was capable of comprehending some such a great immensity.
So this, it was non-intellectual.
It was the sameness of the totality of the suffering of all mankind throughout all of time.
It was so staggering that I instantly became an atheist.
And I said, any God that could allow this cannot be a God to me.
So goodbye, God.
I became a rabid atheist, a very devout atheist.
And I got straight A's.
Theology.
And I was always interested in the subject.
Anyway, this, to attribute a negativity to God is to totally misconceive of the nature of God, you see.
That which is unmanifest, that which is unmanifest, which radiates forth its infinite potentiality
and calibrates in extreme high numbers, then,
is the level of God.
Who knows nothing of human frailty, couldn't care less.
And much less would feel offended and have to, you know, seek revenge.
To seek revenge, your consciousness would have to be 200 below.
Because you would first of all have to see yourself as a separate entity who is vulnerable to attack.
Which would mean you're not divinity.
So anything that seeks revenge cannot be divinity by definition.
The truth of that which you are is absolutely invulnerable.
Unassailable.
Hmm.
So now, we did mention a few things that made these kind of subjects perhaps interesting to me.
I was on the radio today for a couple of hours.
That's not a good thing to do before you're going to give up all of your drives.
But it came out that way.
So from 9 to 11, I had a two-hour program.
And they asked me about some of these things and so I know what they were interested in.
So I'll just say them to you because you're not asking questions.
Because I could just hear them.
But the interesting thing about this particular lifetime...
First of all, everybody in the audience presumes there's a Dr. Hawkins here speaking to you.
Well, that's interesting.
Actually, it's consciousness itself.
It's actually consciousness itself.
You see?
When you stop identifying yourself as a physicality or a specific ego or locality,
then what you realize, what exists is consciousness itself.
And the way it came about in my own experience was...
When I was about three, when I was about three years old, there was no awareness of existence.
Suddenly at age three, there was a profound confrontation with existence.
I realized that I exist.
There were no words for it.
It was not a verbal experience.
There was a stunning awareness of existence.
And instantly came its dualistic opposite, nonexistence.
Instantly, I saw the dilemma of existence versus nonexistence.
And it became obvious that if I exist, the potentiality had been there for me not to have existed.
And so out of assuming I existed, because that seemed to be what was going on,
there came the possibility of nonexistence.
And there was the conflict that so-called duality of existence versus nonexistence.
Hmm.
To solve that duality,
consciousness has to be around 850 or 900 or so.
The duality of existence versus nonexistence doesn't even come up to about 850 or so.
Anyway, this was a profound confrontation,
and it really was the setting of the spiritual lesson project,
the spiritual project of this lifetime.
And then in teenage years,
the personal individual self,
if I thought, who am I,
would begin to disappear.
And there was just an infinite presence.
And that would sort of scare me that my self is disappearing.
So I would cling to my personal self and give it lots of energy
and think the word David sitting in his seat.
Well, I was pretty bright also at the time.
I graduated at the end of my class in kindergarten.
Got a straight A in crayons.
Anyway, so I had these peculiar phenomena,
which I never talked to anybody about.
And when I was around 12 or 13,
I had a huge paper route in Wisconsin,
18 miles, the biggest in the state.
And it was out in the sticks.
And one time it was like 20 below zero on a blizzard,
and I got caught in this blizzard.
It was dark.
I was many miles from anywhere.
And so I dug into a snow bank to stay out of the cold.
It was 20 below.
And it was ferocious out.
It really was.
And I snuck into this.
In Wisconsin, the snow bank's by the side of the road,
you know, about 15, 20 feet high.
And so I dug a hole into this snow bank
to get in out of this fierce wind.
Because my knees were frozen stiff,
and my pants were stiff,
and they even cracked instead.
And I climbed into this hole.
And before long,
the most exquisite experience
of my life,
came upon, came about.
Any personal self disappeared,
only an infinite, growing presence,
beyond all time and all space.
And the knowingness that that which I was experiencing
and that which I am are one and the same,
beyond all time before all universes,
before all thoughts and worlds.
Long after all universes come and go,
and that which I am exists beyond all time and space.
And that was obvious.
And this is all wordless.
The mind was silent.
And the exquisiteness of it was...
And every time it recurred,
the same exquisite disinclination
to reactivate the body,
re-identify with the body.
And I'd have no idea how much time.
This is all out of time,
and timeless experience.
The next thing was my father shaking my leg.
He'd finally come out in our 29 model 8 Ford
to find him,
to find his son who was lost in the blizzard.
And I looked at him,
and I saw that if I did not come in the back,
in the body,
he would presume I'd died,
that the body would die.
And he would be very upset by this
because he believed that I am my body,
and he believes he's his body,
so he believed I'm my body.
And if I didn't resume it,
he would go into enormous grief.
Well, I love my father a great deal.
So for his sake,
I came back...
which I've sort of since regretted,
but anyway...
I came back in the body,
and I tried to acclimatize myself
to how the world sees reality.
And I never spoke of this to anybody,
and the next time it happened again,
it happened...
one time it happened with a friend.
I was doing a technique called rebirthing,
and I went out of body
with the same infinite glowing infinity,
and I had no decision to breathe anymore.
I stopped breathing,
and everything stopped.
And...
I saw that this was going to be
very upsetting to my rebirther,
who was going to lose his first subject in death.
And I could see the headlines,
and I got...
telepathically, he's saying,
breathe, hey, breathe.
You should love me, breathe.
In that instant,
I just really loved him intensely,
and frankly, I did breathe for him.
I really did.
I hang him up with a dead body here.
And see, because the world consumes that
when this stops breathing in and out and all,
that you're dead.
You know, this is very naive,
but that's the way the world sees things.
So, you have to go along with the world
and sort of humor it in a way.
And in 1965,
it was a state of incredible despair.
Don't forget I was an atheist at this time,
and a very devout one.
I was a devout atheist, you know.
I was against these negative gods,
and wasn't really an atheist.
I was just against all these concepts of God
as a monster.
I didn't have any positive concept of God,
but I knew that whatever people believed in
didn't hang in with my experience.
So, anyway,
I was at the depths of spiritual despair
and physically ill
and in a catastrophic state.
And I went into a state of black despair
beyond all description.
There's really levels of hell.
Levels of hell.
There are a lot of levels of hell.
And the higher levels
where you're being tortured and fried and all that,
that's just the beginning.
That's kindergarten.
And you go to an existential despair
in which the blackness is beyond all description.
And then I said,
if there is a God,
I didn't hold my breath,
all right, I'd ask his help.
I thought, well,
you know, before you die,
you go on the other side.
Probably best to play it safe.
Get on the other side,
and he says,
you know,
you were saying.
Anyway, it was,
that's what I did.
As a profound atheist,
I really did not hold my breath.
I didn't think I was going to answer.
But, you know,
hollering down an empty alleyway there,
and there's nobody there to hear,
but you did it.
So it's on the record that you did it.
So I hollered down the empty alley,
and then everything disappeared.
Everything disappeared,
and I have no idea how much time went by.
But on January 10, 1965 then,
suddenly that which had been David,
that which the world calls David,
disappeared completely.
There was no individual self.
Thought stopped.
No mind.
Only an infinite presence,
which is and still is all that is.
It expresses itself
as the creation observed and witnessed
by the senses,
but the divinity of its nature
is shown forth with a radiance
that is so stunning as to
leave no question.
And then the body went about its own business,
which it still does.
As you see,
it moves and it's like a puppet.
It goes,
it runs itself.
It has nothing to do with the person itself.
People think,
well, I decided to move my arm.
That's an illusion.
No, the arm moved itself,
and then instantly the ego jumps in
and says,
I moved it.
No, no.
It moved itself before the eye says that.
In meditation you can discover that.
So this body was there
like another piece of furniture in the room.
I really had no interest in it.
And the mind had disappeared.
There was no thinkingness,
and everything happened of its own
in this infinite presence.
And that condition lasted.
It wasn't possible to think in words.
No words came forth.
All that is is known forever,
and to understand one grain of sand
is to understand the universe.
So there's nothing you need to know
because once you are all that is,
there's nothing you need.
So the sense of completeness was present.
To this day there's nothing I need.
People say,
what do you want for Christmas?
There's nothing I want for Christmas.
Do you want to win the lottery?
No, I don't want to win the lottery.
There's absolutely nothing I need or want.
Because once you are all that is,
there's nothing lacking.
And if there's nothing lacking,
there's obviously nothing you would gain
by getting anything.
So there was the loss.
The first thing that happened
was the loss of all the drives
that are considered human.
The desire for success,
for money,
for security.
All the things that people consider
important in the world
suddenly became meaningless.
And so by ordinary human standards
I was motivationless.
No motivation for anything.
And the body went about its way,
which it still does.
It's like a karmic wind-up toy.
It's like a puppet.
It's like my little friend.
A lot of times I wish it had fur.
I'd say,
you know if this thing had fur
I'd really like it a lot more.
It'd be more fun,
like a kitty.
You know what I'm saying?
So this thing is my happy puppet
and it goes about its business.
It's been doing that since 1965 by itself.
I don't have to do anything.
It just does whatever it's going to do.
So that condition,
that condition then was difficult
to function in the world.
And actually I did leave the world.
I had a huge practice in New York.
And I moved to a small town
where I lived by myself.
And it's a monastery for one person.
Just a monastery for me.
And I lost identification
with the physical body.
And I can remember one time
I hadn't eaten for some days either.
That was a hard thing
for me to do too.
And I walked past the mirror
and there was somebody in the house with me.
It gave me a mental shock.
I saw this person walking through the mirror
and realized it was me.
Oh God.
It was shocking for a second.
Anyway,
so the loss of identification with physicality.
So what we're saying is that
in certain peculiar persons then
this spontaneous occurrence
that also occurs as a result of meditation,
I had done Zen meditation
and some things before that experience.
But all of a sudden
one can transcend the identification
with the linear world,
the Newtonian paradigm of reality
and shift to the non-linear.
That's all we're saying.
And what the world considers spiritual
is really just the non-linear.
And what it considers material
is the linear.
Now the two coincide.
At the same time
that there is a linear reality here,
the chairs and the desks and all,
this is all here within space.
So you can identify either with the chairs
and the physicality
or as what happened to me,
I am the space
in which all of this occurs
throughout all of time.
And so the panorama,
the witness,
the movie of what's going on
comes and goes
and it actually has no effect on me whatsoever.
Usually it's amusing
if anything.
So for some years
I had trouble communicating with the world
because the mind is silent,
which it is to this day.
That which I am is silent.
It says nothing.
And there was having to learn how to speak
which people would say things
and it didn't make any...
I mean they would talk
and it made no sense at all.
It was totally irrelevant
and not even believable.
And then I found that within myself
I would ask the spirit,
what does that mean?
And then I would get what that meant.
And it was like a translate.
A translator within myself
that would transform
what is being said
in the world of form
so it was comprehensible
in the world of non-form.
That's the only way I can explain it.
All right.
So this then has to do
with the two different dimensions
in which life can be experienced
from the linear
and from the non-linear.
How to move from the linear domain
into the non-linear.
We talk about that as spiritual work.
Spiritual work, what is it?
Spiritual work is merely a willingness.
People say,
how can I evolve
in my level of consciousness?
It's very simple, you know.
Choice is here at all times.
And what we do is
we choose to be forgiving.
We choose to be helpful to others.
These are all options
that are available to us at all times.
The willingness to be kind and considerate
to all that exists
from moment to moment
within and without.
So to be kind and forgiving
means towards yourself
as well as to everything that exists.
Everything that exists.
Somebody asked me,
how do you define God?
I said, well, in my experience,
God is the capacity
to manifest existence.
Nothing has the capacity
within itself to exist.
It doesn't have enough power.
It doesn't have within itself
the power of creation.
That which is unmanifest then,
is the source of existence itself.
You ask, where is God?
Well, the capacity to exist,
the fact that you are,
is the most direct manifestation
of the presence of God
within yourself.
So the current book I'm writing on
is called
The Eye of the Eye,
spelled E-Y-E of the eye.
The Eye of the Eye.
When you say eye,
what is it you're saying
when you say eye?
Who do you mean by eye?
Do you mean your physical body?
Is that the eye?
Well, the eye owns your physical body.
It has one.
Do you mean your mind?
What is it that allows us to say eye?
The person assumes
that there is an individual,
specific thing called eye,
a me, me, it's me.
This eye, this self,
and that it's temporal,
it's temporary,
and everybody therefore fears death
because they say,
well, when you croak,
say goodbye to eye.
Actually, it's the other way around.
It's, there is an infinite eye.
When we say consciousness itself,
consciousness itself is a quality,
impersonal quality,
within your own consciousness,
which accounts for your awareness,
your capacity to know,
to know that you know.
It's coming out of an impersonal quality
called consciousness.
This consciousness manifests itself
in the belief, mistakenly,
that you are a very limited thing
that just got here
and is going to be leaving
before a few years,
and you had a beginning
and now you will end
in this physicality.
That which really says eye,
if you do it just,
it doesn't take very long in meditation
to go to the source
of what is it that is saying eye.
What enables you to even say
that you exist?
That the capacity to say personal eye
is coming from the endowment
of an impersonal eye.
The impersonal eye,
which is the same in all of us,
the self and me with a capital S,
is the same as the self
in everyone here.
Everyone here exists.
We have agreement on that, don't we?
We do agree we all exist.
We do agree that there is a capacity
to know that one exists.
It is not provable.
You cannot really prove that you exist.
You can put forth all kinds of data
and that will impress people
in the low of the 400s
as convincing logic,
but knowingness,
to exist is a knowingness
which is beyond logic.
All right, so science will take us up.
But we notice that the level of the intellect
is in the 400s.
The 400s, things always act mysteriously too.
I think they are wonderful.
Anyway, you see here the,
I have a little thing,
a little light thing.
It probably doesn't work either.
Oh, no, it does work.
I don't know how it works,
but you push a button and it lights.
It's wonderful.
I don't know, the world of thingness
has not been my,
I don't have a computer.
I'm as lazy as I think
how it operates or what it says.
Anyway, you see that the level of science
is the 400s.
Now, science then is capable
of understanding logic.
And the only thing with man's knowledge
is people don't put the limits on,
the limits on their knowledge.
Science cannot say anything about
the nonlinear domain.
It has no validity.
I don't care what science says
about spirituality
because it has no capacity
to comprehend it.
It wouldn't have the slightest idea
where to start.
Likewise, it's best
that spirituality stays out of science.
When the church makes pronouncements
about Galileo and the sun
going around the earth,
the earth going around the sun,
it's out of its bailiwick.
And you like having an opinion
on outside matters.
One thing that's beautiful
about the 12-step programs
is the purity of the spiritual essence of it
is that they have no opinion
on outside matters.
That's really a wonderful thing.
And as you're driving along,
just think how relieving it is
not to have any opinion about anything.
Gosh, I don't have to have an opinion
about anything.
Wow, what a relief, you know what I mean?
You don't really need an opinion
about anything, no.
In fact, it's great not to have
any opinions about anything.
One way to tell whether you're making
good spiritual progress,
and here's a very good test,
is if you enjoy letting somebody
get ahead of you in traffic.
If you get like a feel-good glow,
come on in, fella.
Give them a break.
Gee, the person goes,
whoa.
And you can see them fall over, you know.
Just a little bit of love
knocks people out, you know.
You come up to the stoplight,
look at the person in the next car
and smile at them.
My God, it causes terror and panic.
Call 911.
There's a man smiling here in the next car.
Make sure they're not the opposite sex.
That's the safe side.
On the other hand,
maybe even the same sex nowadays,
I don't know.
It's best not to smile at strangers.
All right, so you see
the evolution of consciousness
become sort of automatic
once you're familiar with certain things.
Just the things we've talked about today.
Your consciousness is not the same as it was.
You realize that it's on a trajectory.
Let's see how this consciousness works.
These energy fields in chaos theory
and chaos theory,
nonlinear dynamics theory,
are organized around an attractor field.
These levels of consciousness
dominate the human mind.
The human mind, like, picks up
and is entrained
by these powerful energy fields.
The field holds dominion
over man's consciousness.
The minute you ascribe to a certain attitude,
you now become subject to being dominated
by the entire set of attitudes
that go with that field.
The minute you give a lot of energy
to right and wrong,
you are now stuck.
Right and wrong is one of the great dualities.
But to become involved spiritually,
you have to transcend
and see right and wrong are very irrelevant.
It really makes no difference
whether the thing is right or wrong.
Once you jump that duality,
you're not stuck there,
and instantly your consciousness
will rise up into the high five hundreds.
The high five hundreds
is not interested in right and wrong.
The people who hand out turkeys at the mission,
they don't try to decide
who's justified in having a turkey.
Or not having a turkey.
You know, the divinity of God,
the love of God,
radiates equally on all.
It doesn't get involved in judgmentalism.
So these are levels of consciousness,
and we'll just sort of go over them
so that you get what they're about.
Very at the lowest we have
feeling miserable.
The world is a miserable place.
So this is our view of life.
If your consciousness is down here,
this is how you experience life.
This is what life looks like.
Miserable.
Shame is the predominant.
And its energy is 20.
I'll teach you the pictures you see
on the front of Time magazine
of starving Ethiopian infants
who are born with AIDS
and have starved to death
probably by the age of six months.
The mother doesn't even know
what to do with the body.
She just leaves it by the side of the road
where the flies gather on it.
That's all these people here.
Whole subcontinents come in
at these levels.
Not enough energy to pull
enough energy from life to even exist.
Interestingly enough,
we can calibrate the level of consciousness
of an infant the minute it's born.
You're born into this world
at a certain level of consciousness.
Where did that arise from?
Consciousness, then, is an ongoing thing.
In my own observation,
this is my own observation
and my own conclusions
and my own research,
that consciousness evolves
from down here
on up to divinity itself.
And it may take many physicalities
to do that.
I view consciousness
as a continuum
that seeks periodically
to physicalize.
When we talk about karma,
what we're saying is that
every action manifests
a vibration or a frequency
which registers somewhere.
And this somewhere carries on.
And it has consequences eventually.
Every religion says,
as you sow, you shall reap.
It doesn't say
that you'll necessarily physically manifest again.
But it does say
if you're going to go
from one level to another
and where you go to
depends on
what kind of vibrations you've set up
in your spirit,
your soul,
or whatever.
My own view of it is that
these levels here
really are of the spirit.
And these,
you're like a cork.
You're like a cork in the sea.
In the sea of consciousness,
your calibrated level determines
where you rise or fall as a cork.
And when you leave the body,
this is just,
you don't have to buy anything I'm saying,
when you leave the body,
the spirit leaves the body
and I've been out of body
and I know the spirit does leave the body
because I've been down there and up there
and we'll look after the body down in a bit.
And where the spirit goes
would then depend on its vibration,
its buoyancy.
So these frequencies then would determine
if there is such a thing as a spirit
that supersedes the physicality,
where it goes.
Where it goes is it would just float
to its own level.
This to me is the absolute justice of God.
God is incapable of injustice
because each one of us by our own actions
sets our own karmic vibrational pattern
and thereby determines our destiny
in the great beyond,
which is actually here,
but it sounds like the great beyond.
So these people came in here
at a pretty low level.
And here we see people who see God as condemning.
Here God despises us.
Here God is vindictive.
He's always getting even with you.
Here God is that which condemns you
and disdains you and is punitive,
denies what you need to survive life,
is vengeful.
So you see the view of God
depends on your life.
It depends on your level of consciousness.
The life view is life is miserable.
This is an evil world,
a hopeless world,
a tragic world,
a frightening world,
a disappointing world.
It's a world of anger,
a demanding,
or is it a feasible,
satisfactory,
hopeful world of opportunity?
It's all how you look at it.
God is either a punitive,
horrible thing that you live in dread of,
or he's the source of freedom,
inspiration,
mercy,
wisdom,
love,
and it's actually your own self with a capital S.
Here we go through these emotional levels.
We go through these calibrated energy fields
and we see the emotion that is associated with them.
Down here we have blame.
People spend their whole lifetimes blaming everything.
We have whole continents.
The Middle East spent the last couple thousand years.
First they blame one,
then they blame the other.
They shoot over a bomb,
then they retaliate with another bomb.
This amuses them by the millennium.
They go on for thousands of years doing that.
They live off the spleen.
They live off the energy of hate.
Hate and blame.
When you get a little bit better,
you go into depression.
Come out of hate and vindictive killingness,
and you lay on the floor and sob.
You at least come up to regret,
which is,
that's the beginning of decency,
you know,
at least you regret that you bombed all those people.
Now you get a little bit anxious about,
am I doing the right thing or not?
Now that you can get your energy up to cravingness,
this is the level of the addictions.
Here's the addictions.
You're stuck in the solar plexus.
I'm in this wantingness.
It cannot be satisfied.
Cravingness is an energy fuel.
Therefore, you cannot satisfy it.
The minute you get through this,
you're planning on the next.
There's no way out of this.
Then we get up to the levels of hatred,
levels of pride and scorn.
And these are what's happening in the process in consciousness.
Here, what happens is you eliminate yourself.
Elimination is what happens here.
Here we have destruction.
Before you get eliminated,
you get destroyed,
pounded into powder
before they dump you in the dumpster.
Here we have despondency,
withdrawal,
enslavement.
Here's the level of addictions,
which many of us work with.
The level of enslavement.
You're hooked in the solar plexus of wantingness.
There is no satisfaction for it.
So it goes on and on continually running you.
You're enslaved by cravingness.
Hatred leads to aggression.
You've got Adolf Hitler
and militaristic hateful people
with inflated egos
who are scornful of others
and live out of pride.
Deutschland über alles.
Any sane person, when you think of it,
what do you mean, Deutschland über alles?
70 million people bought it
and so they all died.
Anyway, so here you have this inflated ego.
Now, once you get above it,
you have the level of truth.
You see the emotion here is one of affirmation.
You take the first step in the 12-step group.
I admit the truth about myself.
Wow, the minute you admit truth about yourself,
I'm not a genius.
Oh, gee, that's a hard one.
But I was at the head of my class in kindergarten.
But you're not a genius.
Okay, so affirmation.
This leads to trust, optimism.
And here is a very important level for all of us
because many of us work in the health field.
Forgiveness.
How do you see a thing?
In comes the kid to your institution
who's done really awful things
and is awesomely negative,
telling you where to go with their finger
the minute they say hello to you.
So forgiveness.
The capacity to be compassionate.
These are the levels of transcendence
and understanding.
And we move on up through reverence.
The reverence for all of life.
The reverence for all that lives.
Why?
The reverence that the source of existence
of all that is
is divinity itself.
The moment of revelation was so stunning
it's just profound.
It's just like you walked out of a dark cave
that you lived into all your life
into a field of snow
in midday.
It was just beyond all comprehension.
Totally wiped out.
All these belief systems
thinking this.
You come into what's called
the ineffable.
And that's called enlightenment
in which you realize that
that which is divine
and that which is the source and the essence
of your own self
are one and the same thing.
The various religions may have confused it
by using different terminology.
But in essence all of them say
that the ultimate reality
is within you.
Jesus said where he said it was
heaven is within you.
It's not elsewhere.
It's not some other time.
You are spiritually committed.
What's the most intense way
to reach a state of enlightenment
or greater awareness?
The realization that
reality can be only discovered
in the absolute instant of now.
It is in this absolute
split nanomicrosecond
of now
that the reality shines forth.
It's like
the mind is so
beclouded with clouds
that you don't see
the sun in the sky
except for a split second
between two clouds.
That's what the Buddha said
and I discovered that what he said was true.
He says that the great infinite void
the infinite beingness of the universe
the godness, the godhead
the transcendent divinity
of the supreme of all
is found between two thoughts.
And therefore there are many
meditative techniques
in which one witnesses the thoughts going by
stops identifying with them
and there are certainly
some very exquisite techniques
to do this very thing.
But it is true, it is within
the infinite presence of now.
And how does one transcend
the infinite now?
You witness out of the mind
how everything is arising
and falling within mind
like a musical note.
When you listen to a note of music
it arises and
within the creation and experience
of that note is already
it is already disappearing
and a new note is already
so you don't get caught in the melody
you stay on the moment of
the sound that is arising now
you don't try to cling to it
you don't try to anticipate the next moment of now
and you discover that what the ego
is trying to do all the time
is anticipate the next split second of now
and control it.
If you watch in meditation
what your mind is doing
is trying to grab the next moment of now
verbalize it
give it a name, give it an image, give it a form
it is like there is an energy
of thinkingness
which comes out of a primordial matrix
which is beyond form
it is formless
but it is out of this powerful goo
that wants to constantly come into
being as a thought
you have to catch it, the willingness
to let go of thinkingness
you will see that thinkingness
is an independent function all its own
there is no I thinking
as you become enlightened you see there is no individual I
there is no doer behind the doings
there is no doer doing
what is being done now
it is happening of its own
everything is the expression
everything comes into being
as the perfect expression
of its own essence
and it does so in this instant
each instant it is
it expresses the essence
of its own beingness
its own reality
and that is its divinity
so divinity expresses itself
as existence
as beingness
is that what you are at this moment
and the way to catch it at that
is to ride the crest
of this exact instant
it would be a nano instant
I like nano, that is a new one
I always liked micro
but there is another one used in astronomy
meaning even lower than micro
I forget what it is now
but nano seems like the greatest
of the littlest of the littlest
and I just love the thought
that there is nano manufacturing
going on
little molecules can be taught
how to make themselves into a little factory
and create I guess a whole Ford automobile
who knows
anyway
there is a meditative technique
which you can do throughout the day
no matter what you are doing
one is always
as you look about you
there is your macular vision
and your peripheral vision
macular vision is the center
when you have intention about something
the macula of the eye
is focusing on a specific point
because you are going to do something with it
you are going to eat it, kill it
mate with it, buy it
store it, paint it
the peripheral vision is only aware
of your general positionality
in life
and the more spiritually evolved
you get, the more you tend to live
in peripheral vision
what is going on in macular vision
becomes less and less important
it is just the work of the ego
and the more detached you become
the details of what is going on
becomes less and less important
what is important is the essence
you do that yourself
when you walk into a room
you are aware of two things
you are aware of what you are looking at
but you are also quickly getting the whole deal
you know what I mean
the size of the amphitheater
the likelihood of finding a seat
the type of a crowd
the energy field
all the boards go by
and bushes go by
and you don't get caught in any of them
and you are aware that something
that is not any of that out there
is witnessing all that out there
and that type of meditation brings you to
the awareness that there is something witnessing
that witnessing
is happening of its own
it is totally impersonal
there is no personal eye that is witnessing
any more than there is a personal eye
making your body do what it is doing
I remember when I caught the body
in a trick
I caught the ego one time
I was driving somewhere
and a rabbit ran across the road
wham, the brakes went on
saved the rabbit's life
and instantly I caught that the ego
took claim for that
said I break the brake
no, this time I caught it
it had breaked itself before
I decided to break and save the poor little bunny's life
oh no, it was happening of its own
that which you are then
is an absolute reality
that which you are
exists beyond all time
space and dimension
the truth and reality of the self
of everyone here
we are all one and the same
the self that is speaking to you
is your own self
just coming back to you
there is only one consciousness here
it activates what the saying-ness
the wording-ness is going here
that is what this body is here for
what is this body bumping around here for
I could have done without years ago
I mean, how would you talk
if you were just in visible space
in the middle of invisible space
you couldn't talk to people
and if you did, they'd get spooked
you have to look like an actual person
and talk in verbalized language
so that people know what you're talking about
which takes us to the end of the discussion for today
and I thought then we'll have time for any questions
we'll take a little break
if anybody has any questions
we've tried to cover now
everything I think within the syllabus
this is the first time I've ever spoken from a syllabus
now it's more difficult in foreign languages
where you say something
and now you're getting enthused about it
and then you have to stop because the translator
has to translate it into Korean or something
and by the time she's translated
you've gotten what was it I was going to say
that's more difficult
alright
so what I've tried to share today
is an overall view of consciousness itself
creation versus causality
causality
illusions that the world holds
that blinds itself
blinds it to what is actually the truth
the difficulty in spiritual work
because of positionality
there's only one enemy
to all advance of consciousness
and that's
adopting a positionality
that positionality then
twists your view of perception
you cannot see the wholeness and oneness of all things
and it divides them into
thinness and
dualistic error
so we tried to define
consciousness
duality versus non-duality
non-duality is the new dimension
I'm speaking again at
in Albuquerque in April
science and consciousness
conscious
science is knocking at the door
of the linear to the non-linear
because advances in human consciousness
are in the non-linear domain
so I want to thank you for being here
and I'll stay for
any questions you might have
you get to get a syllabus
and a certificate of attendance
on your way out the door
calibration
the energy of this audience was 411
when we started the lecture
it went to 421 by the end of the lecture
the consciousness level of a human being
advances about 5 points in a lifetime
and we jumped 10 points today
we jumped 10 points
so the
the advance in spiritual awareness
was really what you would get out of
two whole lifetimes
and the information alone does that
so we went from 411 to 421
that's very big
you see because we're talking about a logarithm
we didn't go up 10 points
we went up the log
10 points
those of you who understand logarithms can explain it
I forgot what logarithms mean
but anyway it's a big jump
alright now what I tried to teach people
is the technique of kinesiology
and some of these people
ask specific questions
and the way to find the answer
is to do what I told you today
you just go
is it over 200
over 300 over 400
like that
now a lot of people like to know their own level of consciousness
and I find this very useful
yes it's very useful
to know your own level of consciousness
you can just
through kinesiology
the best thing to do is to find somebody who's close
so they're available so you can do it once in a while
and just practice a little bit
it's really not difficult
it's pretty simple
the reason you want to know your own level of consciousness
is it tells you
what lessons you're up against
see
to know what you're at
tells you
what direction to head
a lot of people in spiritual groups
are in the 400s
they have gotten to the intellect
they're able to read and comprehend
they're intellectual
they've read about this now they're curious
they've realized that there is something beyond
the intellect
so lots of people in consciousness groups
all over the world
calibrate in the 400s
that's the level of increasing awareness
and
a very good jumping off place
it's
the trick there is to
is to stop
verbalizing and naming everything
and begin to
experience its essence
rather than its definition
the confusion of definition
the essence
what a thing is
Korzybski of course
Korzybski pointed out
that the word is not the thing
the map is not the territory
which led to the development of
along with Hayakawa
Professor Hayakawa from Hawaii
developed
what was the name of it now
it was a whole movement
anyway they had a periodical called Etc
and the point was to
become aware
that verbalizations only exist
as a verbalization
the fact that you can verbalize something
doesn't mean it has a reality
that's why there is no opposite
to truth
that is one of the most profound things to learn
the only thing that exists
is truth
only truth has existence
only that which has existence is truth
that which is untruth has no existence
so there is no point to fear it
because it has no existence
it's something conjugal
conjured up
because we say
if there is a god there must be an anti-god
if there is good there must be evil
this comes from a dualistic
I was going to reconstruct
the dualistic universe for you today
but we ran out of time
the definition
the thinking that a thing exists
because there is a word
is the fallibility of the ego
in the
level of the 400's
that which has reality
has no opposite
there is no opposite to god
oh I know how to define this
by really defining a kinesiologic response
we said
consciousness only knows truth
it doesn't know falsehood
falsehood has no existence
so how would it know it
consequently if the statement you make
has truth it has existence
and consciousness recognizes
acknowledges existence
by making your arm go strong
say it has no tooth to it
it has no existence
because it has no existence
it has no energy
it can't make your arm go strong
say your arm goes weak
so all your arm is saying yes
or not yes
that is different from yes from no
this is a very profound and advanced understanding
and I'll explain it in a way
that you'll get it rather easily
in a wire
either electricity is on
or it's not on
there is no condition known as offness
you cannot turn on offness
offness has no reality
onness is either there
or it's not there
the same with light and dark
there is no such thing as darkness
except as a sensory observation
light is either present
or not present
there is no such thing
as an opposite to light
there is no such thing as non-light
light is either present
or not present
if it's present strongly
it's brilliant
as it is less and less present
we call that darkness
darkness is not the opposite
of light
there is no such thing
just as offness does not exist
you can say that water is full of offness
it's not full of offness
it's only truth
and
because only the truth is real
there is nothing to fear
in the universe
you see the nature of divinity
you realize
there is nothing to fear in the universe
because divinity has no opposite
the only thing
that can grade
can gradiate
is your awareness of the divinity
of yourself and all of existence
so that the clouds
obscure the truth
but they are not the opposite of the sky
the sky has no opposite
there is no non-skyness
that you have to fear
no
without the consciousness
of a Christ consciousness
then
below 200
the darkness would be so obscure
one would never get to see the light of the sky
and therefore
with help from others
from that consciousness
we are lifted out of that darkness
this is the difficulty
of what we are saying in kinesiology
what kind of testing have you done
to rule out that a person's life view
or experience is not influencing the result
the basic work out of which
power versus force came
was
a dissertation presented to the university
and
well received by the university faculty
called
quantitative and qualitative analysis
and calibrations of the level of human consciousness
wow
calibration
I always forget it myself
anyway
that was a highly scientific
dissertation
in which we used traditional academic standards
of
advanced
statistical analysis
in fact I hired a statistical analysis firm
they took all the data
ran it through their computers
P came out
P was less than .001
the chances of findings being
in error were less than 1 in 100,000
or something
alright so scientifically
those who are interested in it
it's available through the publisher of power versus force
called calibration and
oh heck I'm not going to say it all again
anyway
it has the scientific data
for those who like P is less than 1.001
and those kind of things
it's based on the null hypothesis
proving and disproving the null hypothesis
with valid data
so it met academic standards
I wouldn't have gotten a PhD for it
so
so that was the scientific validation
the clinical
I'm a clinician rather than an academic
I'm not an academic person at all
I'm a
clinical person
spiritually I'm called a mystic I guess
a mystic
how do you know the person's
experience is not influencing
I'll tell you how to verify it for yourself
there's two ways that are simple
you can put information
you can put a picture of
Saddam Hussein
or somebody like that
or a mole discovered in the CIA
you can put that in a envelope
and give it to a child
tell the child hold this over your tummy
and hold your arm out
and now you say this person's energy is positive
the child doesn't know anything
about what's in the envelope
he never heard of Saddam Hussein in the first place
so the child
is the best demonstration for yourself
that the child has no position on it
they don't know
the child has never heard of Saddam Hussein
or something
so you can use a child
the innocence of the child
the most powerful thing on this planet
is the innocent arm of the child
the innocent arm of the child
tells the truth
or the falsehood
of anything in this universe
that ever is or was
formidable
the innocence of the child
and his little arm out there
defeat Hitler and Mussolini
and all the terrible
beings that are out there
live in dread of the innocence of the child
because it cannot be fooled
you see the consciousness
is like the hardware
and the ego is like the software
but the hardware of a computer
is uninfluenced
by the software you run through it
the hardware is not influenced
by the programs you run through it
it remains pristine
so consciousness
as a self
is intrinsically innocent
and as you advance in consciousness
what you witness is the innocence
of everyone around you
that's why it's not possible
to judge people anymore
it's not within the realm of reality
you see that each person is
uniquely
the innocent self
which then has gone unconscious
and gotten programmed by all this software
and now this computer
thinks it's software
and it's forgotten that it's actually
it's own hardware
to be enlightened
is to wipe out the software
and you realize
oh I was the hardware all along
that's true
so anyway you can prove to yourself
the nearest small child
who is innocent
and so you can have him
tell you what mankind
has never been able to figure out
the kinesiology
you know the muscle test itself
I think you should say
is this person good for me to work with
yes verify it
because sometimes spouses for some reason
do not work well together
I haven't had time to research it
I did research it one time
and I came up with an answer
but I don't know what the answer was
it was like the secret of life
I learned it on the way here today
I was going to share it with you
jeez the minute I got
what the hell was it
I know I knew what it was and I also realized
and it came back to me
and I thought oh golly
I've got to share that with the audience
anyway
you experiment
you say this person is good for me to work with
yes no
then you do the simple
your subject holds love
and then you hold something that's not love
and it's really very simple
it's not really hard to do at all
various things may influence it
and you'll find out what does
music in the background
the environment
what are the other things that influence it
because she always
she clears herself
don't look at anything close your eyes
you saw that if you look at something
that's like a smile you go strong
when you look at something that looks like a frown you go weak
just a visual image can influence it
so it takes a little practice
there's a very good book
Your Body Doesn't Lie by John Diamond
it's also got another name
Behavioral Kinesiology
it's been selling all these years
a lot of paperback
and that really goes into kinesiology
you know for me
kinesiology was like the
telescope to Galileo
Galileo wasn't interested in telescopes
he was interested in the universe
so I'm not really interested in kinesiology
except for its handiness
it's very handy and if you have somebody that you work well with
you'll notice that
we very often in lectures
you know we'll research something
right down the spot we've never asked before
let's ask something right now
the level of consciousness
of this lecture was over 600 resist
700 resist
780 resist
750 resist
760 resist
the level of consciousness of this lecture itself
which I promised I would calibrate
is 750
750 what it tells you is what level of truth that is
that's what level
because truth is only truth
when defined in the context of its own level
what's truth on one level
is falsehood on another
truth is only true on its own level
it's not true on other levels
and one of the great difficulties
in spiritual and religious confusion
is the confusion of the levels
things are quoted
that are applicable to one level
and misapplied to another level
onward Christian soldiers
doesn't mean that you slaughter people
it means that
the courage of Christ is within you
to face truth
so
misinterpretation then comes from
mixing levels
quick mixing levels
the spiritual warrior is not the same
as the killer warrior
the killer warrior is a whole different trip
now
there are various
there are various ways of doing
this muscle testing
some people have learned
the ring method
you hold a statement in mind
my name is George
my name is David
the circle goes strong
falsehood makes it go weak
there are ways where you can squeeze your fingers together
so people have learned
different techniques
you get intuitive about it yourself
if you do this kind of testing
for a period of time
of truth versus falsehood
the minute you state the question
you already feel like a buzz
you know what it is
like when I ask her a question
I can almost feel what the buzz is going to be
she already feels the answer coming down
before her muscles react to it
she already feels it go through her consciousness
so that's
just bicycle riding
until you get really familiar with it
so there are those different techniques
I once taught
my arm to be a pendulum
and false was this way I'd say
I am my own grandfather
no I'm not my own grandfather
I have two grandchildren
that's a fact
so you see
then I have people that say they feel they are going to fall over
I have patients who are pretty
advanced in consciousness
the minute I hold a statement in my mind
if it's false I feel like
I'm going to fall over
so everybody has these different ways
so it's a sensitivity
that you train yourself to observe
see most people take for granted
the space in this room
most people take for granted
their own consciousness
awareness
never aware that awareness
is a certain level of consciousness
they just fear
you always see your nose on your face
so people lose awareness
of awareness itself
and they also confuse
awareness as a personal event
rather than an impersonal one
the infinite self
that which you truly are is impersonal
it's not an individual
separate being
that rises and falls
and has a name like David or something
life is impersonal
alright so
calibrating something by yourself
those are the various techniques
a lot of people use the finger technique
and with a little practice
you get it
you just keep practicing one thing after another
until you get it
so these are sensitivities
that you develop just by experience
yeah that's great
wow what a profound question
we discovered that
the consciousness of various people
change over time
this apparently has to do with
the effect of prayer
we've experimentally demonstrated
the power of prayer many times
it has really a very profound effect
anybody here who has done
the course of miracles
you know that when you ask for a miracle
about a thing it transforms
it changes
and you say
well that can't be because of what I did
no it's not because of what you did
but through that specific pathway
the science of mind
all those spiritual pathways
people have become healed
of every illness known to mankind
I've known people throughout the years
that have recovered from every disease
known to mankind
multiple sclerosis
and all kinds of cancers
and heart attacks
and diseases of every kind
fatal illnesses that have promptly recovered
I myself have recovered from half a dozen
progressively fatal illnesses
and if it weren't so I wouldn't be standing here
all that exists moves towards more enlightenment
yes
with the assistance
of other beings
that's the power of prayer
it could be that people who
have had very terrible names
some saint-like creatures
have actually prayed for them
some very high beings
because you'd have to be a pretty high being
to pray for certain unmentionable
figures in history
and it could be
that their spirit has actually
benefited by profound prayer
on the parts of large
numbers of people
because I've noticed that some people
that used to make us go weak
we use them for demonstration all the time
don't make you go weak
somebody recently had
touched my life peripherally
had calibrated extremely low
and suddenly we were surprised
to find calibrated a mobile 200
very interesting phenomena
clinically unique also
clinically unique
a person with two levels of
with two different consciousnesses
within the same body
one consciousness was in 300
and the other one was below 200
very strange
and it just sort of intuitively came to Susie and I
I said maybe there's two personalities here
one time this person would be below 200
and I said we just calibrated him below 200
and we got
he's got one at 350
and he's got another sort of demonic one
way down around 50 or something like that
so you discover all kinds
of amazing things
so all that exists moves towards enlightenment
yes that is true
I just reviewed a book
I don't read books
but this one came from Korea I think
a professor there
and I calibrated the book with 600
so I said look if it's 600 I'll read it
and
his
paradigm of reality
had to do with
the consciousness of the universe
is designed
to support evolution
of consciousness
in which I am in total agreement
and that all that exists
does indeed move towards
enlightenment
and that is the ultimate
conclusion of
man's consciousness
his advancements towards enlightenment
we
we're happy to do it
we've done a lot of research in front of audiences
and been boggled by what we found
you know things will come up we never thought of
this one I'm going to ask permission
we have permission to ask
this question resist
we have permission to ask it in front of this audience
resist
this particular person here
who was world famous
during World War II
this person's
consciousness at the level of World War II
was above 200 resist
was above 75
resist
was above 80 resist
was above 80 must be around hatred
let's see
this person symbolizes
in history the ultimate
expression of hatred
this entity's
consciousness has advanced since
physical death resist
wow
has gone beyond 200 resist
this consciousness is in purgatory resist
we have permission to ask
whereabouts resist
um
this consciousness
was affected by
high beings prayers resist
wow
we didn't know that
well we can't use him anymore
wow
well we learn something every day
so that was
there was a certain entity in history
infamous in history
those who watch the history channel
very famous person
probably you know one of the most evil people
in history
and he calibrated the level of hatred
and we always used him
we'd say image so and so
and everybody would go weak
and today the first time we imaged him
and didn't go weak
a child of five speaking to someone or thing
unseen by our eyes
is on what level of consciousness
don't know
you'd have to calibrate it
see I emphasize calibrating
because our life is so full of illusion
of ascertaining truth for yourself
one of the most interesting things
is to go through your spiritual
most people in spirituality
have a whole book full of metaphysical
and bookstore things
and you go and you hold the book
and you say this is true or not true
and all the books that make you go weak
you go on this side of the room
and all the books that make you go strong
you put on that side of the room
and you leave them there for about a week
and amazing you see
oh wow
so the difference between truth
and its misrepresentation
so the value of differentiating a true guru
from a false guru
which is one of the things I emphasize in my writings
always calibrate the level of truth of a speaker
because there are
there are gurus out there
that are so clever
they are ten times more clever than you are
and they collect the Cadillacs
and the money and the wealth
and the followers
and they seem to be motivated by control
over large numbers of followers
and so the
whatchamacallits
so the child of five speaking to someone
could be an imaginary friend of childhood
that's rather common in children
who have an imaginary companion
I would calibrate the level of it
it could also be
speaking to a thing
well speaking to a thing
would be either imaginary
or could be hallucinated
and whether it's in evidence of childhood
mental illness or not you'd have to know
it could be just one of the imaginary
plaything of childhood
you can use kinesiology
to assist any project you're up to
in self-improvement
any project
and I still find it to this day extremely useful
in discovering things I never knew before
today right in front of this audience
we discovered that
somebody you would imagine would be at the pits of hell
for eternity
is actually moving up in consciousness
wow I didn't know that see
you're learning things
that change your whole paradigm of reality
and the evolution of human consciousness
a lot of young children remember previous lives
you know about 15% of children
up to the age of what I forget
remember previous lifetimes
and unless you tell them to stop talking about that
it's imaginary and crazy
quite a few of them actually
do literally remember
it's as though the amnesia that's supposed to occur
as you reincarnate
there's supposed to be an amnesia
and when do you recall previous lifetimes
real significant and useful
we asked that just this week
once you hit 600
it's really of academic interest
before 600
put 600 on
it is possible to actually recall
and see the significance
that who you are has been
in evolution for a great period of time
and I found that out
especially about physical ailments
physical ailments
tend to be almost
karmically precise
to something that's happened
in some previous lifetime
you don't have to believe any of this yourself
I just say use kinesiology
and check it out yourself
and you can say
this came from some other life
oh good what was it
so it's fun
and all of it
requires an open mind
a true spiritual student then
has an open mind
and prays and says
do God please reveal to me that which is useful to me
that which I can understand
that which I can integrate
that which can benefit myself and others
and it's sort of like
the third step in AA
where you totally surrender your life to
God as you understand him
and then you wait to see what happens
and comes into your life
so at one point a thing is very significant
and at another it's not
and what I'm telling you about today
is covering a huge panorama of things
some of which may or may not be significant
at a given point in your life
you may forget about
or say they're absurd
and then one morning 10 years
now you wake up and you got it
I got it happens to me
as I drive down the highway all the time
I'm driving down the highway and all of a sudden
wow something is so obvious
I'll say wow
the same with jokes
I don't know
it's hard for me to stay serious in the world
and I have a great deal of time
trouble trying to stay serious
because everything presents itself in sort of a comical interpretation
and I keep saying
where in the world did that ever come from
so life is a joy
and we'll just make one last statement
and then we'll finish
where is the source of joy and happiness
is it in the future
in heaven
where is the source of joy and happiness
awareness and enlightenment
it's in the joy of one's existence
in this very moment
to discern
to be aware of the source of your existence
this instant
to be in a state of joy at all times
because that is the presence of God
the presence of God is
is that which you are
at this moment
so the source of all joy
joy is not in the future
it's not in the past
it's right in the awareness of your own existence
in this moment right now
thank you