you guys um let's see what's your energy um resist resist she can't resist here's a person
we've used throughout as a test subject throughout here you use you just listen to heavy metal music
resist think of somebody you love resist i just want you to witness that uh listening to that
heavy metal music only for a few minutes blew out our acupuncture system do what i do think
of somebody you love smile and go ha ha ha ha ha ha ha okay now we fixed it okay which arm up
resist okay you're fixed i'm fixed but you notice that the music blew you out and uh it'll blow you
out for about 20 minutes uh combat two those things where you tear the guts out of other
human beings and uh destroying other animals and shoot and kill and murder um have extremely
negative energies
um
so you have a whole adolescent generation blowing out their acupuncture system
um programming themselves into negativity with uh endless computer games in which they program
themselves to kill kill kill kill kill kill and of course the more and better you kill the higher
the score you get so what you're training yourself is to become an automated killer
in which your reflex is you see the difficulty with um computer games and this kind of music
and all and then you throw in drugs and you're like oh my god i'm gonna die i'm gonna die
in this
the most round yeah you're in a state of so when you listen to rap music saying kill
the cops
uh you play computer games that program you millions of times millions of times to kill
maim rip asunder etc and you listen to music like this so you put on earphones now it has
nothing to do with what you think about it i like the rolling stones um the energy of
the rolling stones is positive
No. The energy of the beetles is positive. Resist.
All right. The beetles put out, let it be.
The stones put out, let it bleed. That gives you a little hint.
So you have a whole generation concerned with killing guns on TV.
They watch homicides, and they play killer games.
They listen to rock music, and then you throw in drugs.
So with the drugs, you're in a very suggestible hypnotic state.
And what happens to these people is they become dominated by negative energy fields.
Their consciousness becomes dominated by the attractor energy field,
and we can demonstrate this over and over again.
So the rise of street crime and criminal activity by adolescents,
the public is well advised to be alarmed.
These people are programmed negative killers.
Just waiting.
And there was one on TV the other night who shot another one of his young classmates.
When asked why he did it, he said he didn't know.
No, he didn't know. He's in an unconscious hypnotic state.
He just pulled the trigger.
The same as he does on combat, you know, the same as the...
So the negative lyrics of this kind of music are pounded into your consciousness
in a highly suggestible hypnotic state in which your negative...
your energy fields are already negative.
And that's why it's so complicated by the music.
This is the real tragedy of modern society,
is that a whole generation of youth is being wiped out.
A whole generation is being wiped out by computer games, heavy metal rock, every cover.
And we've tested every kind of music, and of course classical music makes you go strong,
country western makes you go strong, reggae, soft rock makes you go strong.
We did a study, which I mentioned in the book,
at Sedona Villa, cocaine addicts after discharge,
those who continued to listen to heavy metal rock,
the recovery rate was zero.
Zero percent.
In other words, nobody recovered if they continued to hang out in that energy field.
Is it the music itself? No.
It's not the music itself.
It's the energy that accompanies that music.
Kinesiology is a great research tool for parapsychology.
The current techniques used in parapsychology
to either prove or disprove a phenomena are equally fallacious.
You can't prove or disprove the presence of other invisible entities
by using infrared or Geiger counters or ultraviolet.
I mean, those are all in a different domain.
You can't prove the immaterial in the universe
by using techniques that are suitable for the material universe.
We could use...
Lady, come on over here.
There's a guy who makes a living running around
knocking parapsychology, the great Randy.
The energy of the great Randy is positive. Resist.
The energy of the great Randy is negative. Resist.
He emanates a very negative energy
because his motivation is to disprove the spiritual
and the gross dedication to...
Also, it's based on a false premise,
that if you can imitate a phenomena,
therefore you've negated it.
I mean, that's obviously fallacious.
You can imitate any real phenomena,
but by imitating it doesn't disprove
that the real phenomena actually exist.
I just thought that parapsychology,
because a lot of people are interested in that,
its use in politics and government,
of course, is extremely interesting.
Let's test out the government's present policy
on...
The energy of the president's war on drugs is positive. Resist.
It's effective. Resist.
It's political BS. Resist.
It's political BS.
The war on drugs, the energy of it is over 160. Resist.
It's about 150. Resist.
The war on drugs calibrates at 150.
It's already a negative energy field.
All right, let's see what we would need
to effectively affect the war on drugs.
The government's program would have to calibrate
over 350. Resist.
Over 360. 350.
You'd have to have a program,
government program funded program,
that calibrates at 350 to handle the drug problem.
You cannot handle a drug problem
with a program that calibrates only at 150.
It's used in politics, it's used in sociology,
it's used in politics, are endless.
I just thought sort of an interesting one
has to do with psychology,
the so-called false memory syndrome.
More and more lawsuits are being brought against therapists
who inculcate false memories.
Let's just check out this whole false memory syndrome.
These memories of our early childhood sexual abuse
that are foggy and really only come to life
via the therapist,
those are real memories, resist.
Those are false over 60% of the time,
70% of the time, 80% of the time,
85% of the time.
I get that these repressed memories
of childhood sexual abuse
are false about 80% of the time.
One out of five, it actually happened,
four out of five, it's false.
Kinesiology demonstrates this very well.
Lots of innocent people have been accused,
lives have been destroyed,
families have been destroyed.
Everybody forgets that Freud discovered that
at the beginning of the century.
All his female patients laying down on the couch,
somewhere along the analysis,
they would remember early childhood incestuous fantasies.
At first, Freud was flabbergasted.
He thought, how can all these fathers
be molesting all these little girls?
Just statistically, from a criminologic viewpoint,
the percentage of the population
that does this kind of thing
is very, very small, actually.
How could it be?
Then he found that these were
unconscious fantasies, incestuous,
and of course, this was part of the Oedipal complex.
Society has gone into repression
and unconsciousness again.
It's called the return of the repressed,
and now tries to make it real.
Why is it real?
Because you can be compensated for it.
Victimhood really pays in today's world.
Therefore,
the use of kinesiology can be very, very useful
in psychological research in general,
as far as theory goes,
and as far as an individual case.
I'm going to think now of an individual case
of a patient I'm treating now.
The sexual abuse which took place in her childhood
was real.
Resist.
Yes, it was real.
It wasn't BS.
The case I'm thinking about now,
the childhood sexual abuse was real.
This is one that was suggested to a patient of mine
by a therapist, you know.
The idea here, the way the scenario goes is
I don't remember anything before I was eight years old.
Instantly, the therapist figures,
oh, there must have been a lot of sexual abuse.
These are people who have not been trained
in psychoanalytic theory, you know.
Childhood amnesia is normal.
Normal people don't remember what happened
up until they were five.
It has to do with the rest of the story.
It has to do with the resolution of the edible complex.
And so, in my view of it,
current pop psychology does not explain phenomena.
The energy of current pop psychology
having to do with this repressed memory
and all this kind of stuff,
and it's supposed to contribute to eating disorders,
bulimia, and all these kind of things,
is scientifically accurate, is it?
Yeah, it's funny.
Freudian theory is much closer to the truth about it.
Freudian theory is a lot closer to the truth about it.
So that's the false memory syndrome.
The mode in which I've been using it
and describing it in the book
is in the field of consciousness
and especially that field called spirituality.
So let's just test out some of the,
because this affects the lives of all of us.
Here's a fellow right here.
You want to hold that over here.
This man's energy is positive.
It's over 540.
It's over 550.
540.
About 540 is the energy.
You see, in the book he wrote,
Bill Wilson, the founder of AA,
the language of the heart.
So the 500s is the language of the heart.
So people who were born,
if you calibrate what was their level of consciousness
when they came into this life,
people who calibrated in the 500s
are preoccupied with love and its expressions
and what is love, how to define love,
the difference between spiritual love and personal love,
how to let go of attachments,
and love, you might say, universally.
The meaning of love.
Now let's move on.
We've got 540.
Here's, I mentioned before, A Course in Miracles.
A Course in Miracles is very interesting.
We'll see why in a second.
It calibrates over 590, resist.
It calibrates over 610, resist.
It calibrates over 599, resist.
600.
620.
It calibrates approximately at 600.
Yeah.
Do that again.
A Course in Miracles,
we'll be more specific.
The workbook in A Course in Miracles calibrates at 600, resist.
The textbook calibrates over 600, resist.
The textbook is a little less useful than the workbook.
What's interesting about this
is that 600 is the level at which form
begins to disappear into formless.
And 600 is also exactly the level of kinesiology.
And the reason people have used kinesiology for many years
will still say, I don't believe it,
is because it is that level at which
the ego is not familiar.
The ego dominates the levels below 600.
The ego does not dominate from 600 on up.
Well, a different aspect of the ego,
the spiritual ego dominates.
But the ego is not used to working
at 600.
At 600 or over.
So anything 600 or over,
so the scientific people who
poo-poo anything that is not within
the physical, mechanical, measurable domain,
do so because their level of consciousness,
as we've seen, goes up to 499.
They can't comprehend things in the 500s.
They don't get essence.
They don't get significance beyond
the measurable domain.
In fact, there was a recent article in Science
that said something about
there is no reality except
that which can be measured.
I think the name of the article was
Reality is Measurement.
So, reality is measurement
is a level at 499.
Because that which we all consider
worth dying for,
and people in the 500s and up,
has to do with the non-measurable.
These are people willing to die for love,
for sacrifice,
for the welfare of mankind.
For spiritual principles.
Those are not measurable.
You can't weigh them.
They don't even exist anywhere in time.
They're universal.
So let's move up the people then,
one bit even higher.
Here we have the Bhagavad Gita,
revered of ancient Hindu wisdom,
and it calibrates over 700,
750,
740,
740.
Here's,
these are very interesting people.
They are enlightened gurus
in our time.
Typically with
the teachings of Jesus, etc.
Or Buddha is,
after 2000 years,
people who didn't understand
what it meant in the first place,
repeated it to other people
who didn't understand
what it meant in the first place.
And nobody really has any idea
what Jesus Christ said, you know.
Because,
you know,
if you put together everything
in the Bible and the New Testament
that Jesus Christ said,
it doesn't cover more than a few pages, really.
And yet, in those years,
he gave all kinds of lectures.
These are interesting people.
This is Nisargadatta Maharaj,
who only died in the 80s.
And he's an enlightened guru.
The name of his book is,
well, what he spoke about was,
he identified with awareness itself
beyond consciousness.
That's a very high level consciousness.
Nisargadatta Maharaj is 700, resist.
Over 750, resist.
710,
720,
730,
somewhere in the low 700s.
Here's another guru of recent vintage,
a saint,
Sri Ramana Maharshi.
He died about 1958.
So let's just ask with this whole bit.
The energy of this spiritual teacher
is over 700,
720,
730,
740,
750,
somewhere in the low 700s.
So, that which the world calls
really pure spiritual teachers,
real gurus,
not false ones.
Let's check out another supposed guru.
See, because one use of this
is to tell the false from the true.
All right.
What's the name of the organ?
Oh, yeah.
Rajneesh has a positive energy.
So,
what's the other one in India
that stresses out our beauty?
Sai Baba.
The energy is positive, resist.
Mm-hmm.
So, a lot of the ones that people in the new age,
you know, go ooh and ahh over.
Mm-hmm.
The difficulty there is that the error,
the spiritual error,
is on such a level,
it's beyond the awareness of the student.
So, the naive spiritual student,
his consciousness goes up to here.
The guru goes up to here.
Therefore, he seems impressive to the student.
But the guru himself
is out because his integrity
is out on a level of consciousness
that is beyond the student's capacity to see.
The only one who can see where that guru is out
is somebody who himself has been
to that level and beyond.
See?
Anybody who tells you they're higher than Jesus Christ
is a false guru.
There is no being on the planet
that has ever been higher than Jesus Christ.
There has been a being on this planet
whose consciousness was higher than that of Jesus Christ.
Resist.
You know who claims that?
He claims it all the time to various people.
Lucifer claims to be higher than Jesus Christ.
Resist.
It's Lucifer that thinks.
So, when you see demonstration of power,
money, collections of automobiles,
and riches, you see,
Ramana Maharshi lived a life of absolute simplicity.
He didn't even bother with a plate.
He ate off a leaf in native style.
To say that you're as high or higher than Jesus Christ
is obviously fallacious.
The Buddha calibrates over 990,
over 1,000,
over 1,100.
Krishna calibrates about 1,000.
The great avatar is calibrated at 1,000.
The human body is capable
of coexisting with a consciousness
greater than 1,000.
Resist.
No.
It would seem that,
as one says,
when one's consciousness approaches 1,000,
that seems to me the capacity of the human nervous system.
The reason I say that is that subjectively,
on January 10, 1965,
the consciousness that came on here was 850.
Resist.
The nervous system was able to handle that energy.
No.
The energy,
due to the miraculous event,
suddenly,
that which had been disappeared,
and instead,
there was an infinite presence,
infinite,
I mean infinite presence,
of power so awesome
that the individual mind of the person
that had been called dead,
you know,
stopped.
It never had another thought.
It had no will of its own.
It was one with the presence,
and it's the presence that speaks.
It's the presence that
acts through the physicality,
here,
which the world calls David,
but that is just a...
In theology and spiritual truth,
that which is called awareness
is also in English called Godhead.
Resist.
That which is consciousness itself,
pure consciousness,
is called God.
Resist.
Okay?
Awareness is,
because it's beyond existence and nonexistence,
beyond truth and nontruth,
because it is that out of which
consciousness itself arose,
is the absolute Godhead
beyond which there is nothing.
And out of the Godhead arose
the infinite potentiality.
So as you go into a divine space,
you see the divinity of all things.
Well, that's divinity expressing itself
from formlessness into form.
So God is therefore the creator.
Consciousness,
which is not different than God,
is the creator of all things visible and invisible.
Awareness,
because it's beyond all things visible and invisible,
is the Godhead out of which Godness arises.
We've talked a lot about spirituality
and theology and causality,
and Kitty wanted to be part of it.
You can hear her meow
in some other parts of the video.
Let's check out Kitty's consciousness.
Kitty's consciousness is positive.
Resist.
Kitty...
is very responsive to love.
Resist.
She's attuned to love.
Well, the reason I wanted to
get Kitty in the picture is because
consciousness...
When we talk about consciousness,
everybody thinks we're talking about human consciousness.
Consciousness is vast,
and it goes way beyond human consciousness.
It goes within the physical domain
up to a thousand.
Beyond a thousand,
we go into other domains.
So consciousness is...
When I say I am,
that's consciousness itself.
Resist.
All right.
So, now let's see.
We wanted to talk about causality from a different level.
We talked about causality from a Newtonian viewpoint.
Causality within the Newtonian viewpoint,
which goes up to about 499.
Now, we talked about causality here in this tape.
We talked about cause being on...
in the invisible realm,
and that the world we see is a world of effects.
That is obvious when you're in the 500s.
Resist.
That is still true when you're beyond 600.
No.
As you go beyond 600,
what you see is that time does not flow.
Time, in reality, with a capital R,
time stands still.
Resist.
This is a holographic universe.
All right.
So, what is actually happening as you go beyond 600,
you see that this is a holographic universe.
Everything in the universe sends off a vibration.
The acupuncture system, the etheric body,
is like an antenna that both sends and receives.
You see that there is an intersection of the vibrations
of the essence of all things radiating forth
in a standing hologram.
Now, what seems to,
the illusion that something is happening,
let's see,
in reality, nothing is happening.
Correct.
Resist.
In reality, there are no events.
Yes.
So, what seems like motion,
when you walk through a hologram,
as I walk around a hologram,
it seems to move.
You know, everybody's had the experience,
at least in an art gallery,
you walk along and the eyes seem to follow you as you move.
So, having a fixed level of motion,
a level of perception,
which is a function of the ego
to fix one's perception to a given point,
as you move around the hologram,
it seems to move.
So, what seems to be events
are really not events at all.
You understand what I'm saying?
As you move around the hologram,
you get the illusion.
So, below the level of 600,
the level below 600 is the world of duality, resist.
The world beyond 600
is the world of non-duality, resist.
All right.
So, as you move into a higher state of awareness,
what you see is that all things are connected.
In reality, there is no here or there, resist.
All things coexist simultaneously.
Everywhere present, resist.
You see, the vibration,
the vibrations which exist,
which are registered by consciousness itself,
is not like a radio wave.
It doesn't, like, start here
and go there.
The thought that I hold right this moment
is as it's held everywhere present
throughout the universe and beyond.
It's like on everywhere instantly.
Hmm.
It's said in theology,
all hearts are open and all thoughts are known
to the mind of God, resist, resist.
That's a true signal, resist.
Consciousness,
the entire field of consciousness,
is equivalent to the mind of God, resist.
It's what people refer to
when they talk about the mind of God, resist.
All right.
The mind of God goes beyond consciousness
onto the level of awareness, resist.
This is the Godhead beyond consciousness.
The awareness is the Godhead, resist,
out of which consciousness arises, resist.
So,
if we're all antennas
and we all vibrate
at a frequency
that's instantly available
everywhere in the universe,
this would be a good way
to communicate with astronauts, resist.
Yeah, it would be a great way
to communicate with astronauts.
You can see logically on the ground,
you could know everything they're thinking,
feeling, saying what they need.
It would be a grand way to communicate.
And I just thought
that's another practical thing
that's interesting.
When we said consciousness
is far more than just human consciousness,
we're talking about realms
that the world calls,
religion calls,
angelic, resist.
Beyond 1,000 are the levels
of the angelic realms, resist.
All right, that was interesting.
So, we saw that a lot of gurus
get up to 740.
There seems to be stopping off points.
There are critical spiritual gates
which one goes through, resist.
It seems like,
it seems like large masses
or smaller masses you go,
reach certain levels of consciousness
and then it's like a bunch of people
that stand outside a certain gate
and then there's some kind of
a critical spiritual awareness
that has to take place
to get beyond the gate.
The great block that I was concerned about
and one of the reasons I wrote the book
was in our world, reason,
reason seems to be the great blockade.
Very few people get beyond reason.
When you push reason to its ultimate,
you end up at the level of genius, resist.
499 is the level that the world
considers genius, resist.
Very few people get beyond 499, resist.
Oh yeah, we said 0.4% of the world's population
gets beyond 499, resist.
All right, so it's the great blockade, reason.
The opening of the heart then
opens up love
and then 600 is the next big gate
going from duality into non-duality.
Then I haven't really checked out
the levels from 700 on up,
but we noticed before
when we were doing the tapes
that Maharaj, Nisargadatta Maharaj,
Ramana Maharshi,
there seems to be a number of gurus
in the low 700s.
Huang Po, Huang Po calibrates
over 700, resist.
740, resist.
750, resist.
740, there seems to be another great gate.
I see.
740 is the level of the mystic, resist.
The mystic has mastered
the spiritual domain and our world, resist.
He has mastered also the physical world, resist.
Okay, to go through the gate
from 740 up to 800,
one has to maybe master both the spiritual
and the physical, resist, simultaneously,
resist.
Then there seems to be a great gap
from 740 on.
There seems to be a gap.
I can only go back on my own experience.
There seems to be a confrontation
at 800.
At 800 is another gate, resist.
At 800, one has to personally,
in quotes,
face Lucifer himself, resist.
To reach 850 means
one has what?
Included within the domain of one's
awareness, consciousness, and mastery
the levels of Lucifer, resist.
Yeah, it's like one pulls up one's opposite.
All right, what's the energy
of Lester Levinson, resist?
The energy of Babaji, resist.
That's a being that fell
in the confrontation with Lucifer, resist.
Fell before that, resist.
Never reached that level, resist.
When you hit the mystic level,
very often you leave the world.
It's very, very difficult to function.
And you feel this enormous energy
flowing up your back, into your brain.
The nervous system feels like it can't,
like it handled too much voltage,
as though there's not enough insulation
on the nerves.
And I guess many people just stop there.
And then for some reason, perhaps destiny,
some come back in and master the world
as well, or something.
But there is a point at which suddenly
there is a major confront
with that which is Luciferic.
That which is Luciferic is the gate
through which the world calls gurus
has to go through, resist.
Yeah, there's a point at which
not needing anything from anyone,
being complete and total and whole,
one has enormous power over others.
Enormous power.
And the temptation is to,
you can see where one could hold onto that power.
Well, those are just interesting sidelights.
I don't know if everybody's really just
interested in that.
What I really wanted to share was that
consciousness, in this domain,
goes up to a thousand.
Beyond that are the angelic realms.
Alright, so evolution, we said evolution
does not take place on the physical level.
That is true, resist.
It takes place on the level
of what we call the angelic level, resist.
Great beings who, once a being's energy
surpasses one thousand,
they no longer have a physical body, resist.
The physical body can't handle it, resist.
Very interesting things.
Alright, so we found out that
the body is an antenna.
It's an etheric body.
It's an acupuncture system.
Everything you think or feel or do,
every thought held in mind, then,
has an instant consequence
throughout the entire universe, instantly.
These vibrations intersect with each other,
creating a hologram.
This hologram, then, is experienced
depending on one's own level of perception.
To move up the level of consciousness,
probably the most powerful tool is humility.
Most powerful tool is humility, resist.
Let's ask something else.
One is able to move up the levels of consciousness
unaided, on one's own hook, one might say, resist.
only by, with the help of the Holy Spirit, resist.
With the Holy Spirit as reflected through angels, resist.
Higher beings resist.
So, one cannot really do it unaided.
That's what Scripture says.
It says one asks God,
or whatever one holds in mind
as one's spiritual guide,
to help them with the evolution of their consciousness.
Because without that, it's not possible.
And without humility, one would not ask for assistance.
So, humility seems to be the cornerstone
upon which all of this rests.
You know, a lot of times in this tape,
for demonstration purposes,
I just try to get the range of something,
and sometimes I get a little different numbers.
The energy of this book,
Horror vs. Force,
is over 840, resist.
It's over 850, resist.
It's over 855, resist.
853, resist.
850, resist.
850, all right.
The consciousness level of this tape,
video tape,
is over 840, resist.
Over 852, resist.
850, resist.
Yeah, 850, resist.
What we're trying to do is make the incomprehensible
comprehensible and demonstrable.
Because the world of the mystic,
the world of...
The world, once a person goes beyond 600,
the reality that they describe is difficult to see,
difficult to comprehend.
By using this map of consciousness
and this whole presentation
is to create a context that is so inclusive
as well as logical and demonstrable,
that it makes understandable
that which is ordinarily held to be not understandable.
To make the incomprehensible comprehensible
is really what the purpose of it all is.
I wanted to catch up on some of the things
that got passed over and maybe not explained.
That what, for instance,
what people consider tragedies in their life
are always opportunities.
The black night of the soul
is the very springboard to letting go.
The ego is very tenacious.
I mean, it doesn't let go until
all is the state of unbearable agony sets in.
In my own experience, it was unbearable agony
that finally made it let go.
And in the lives of the saints, etc.,
they talk about the black night of the soul,
that that is the opportunity to let go
of all one's positions
and surrender completely to God, you might say.
When you do that,
a new experience of self and reality
takes the place of the old.
It's as though a new self is born
and the old self has died.
The higher levels of consciousness,
from 500 and up,
have very specific effects in the brain.
I think we calibrated that at about the level of 500,
the brain releases endorphins.
The function of the brain
in this whole field of consciousness
I didn't make clear either.
The brain, it seems as though
the brain is a receiving set
for levels of consciousness.
The energy fields of consciousness then are like,
sort of like a radio wave,
and the brain is like a receiver
that picks up on them.
But this is the same conclusion
that was reached by Sir John Eccles,
a Nobel Prize winner in neurophysiology,
who has written a whole series of books,
and those of you that are interested
in the scientific basis for this conclusion
can read Sir John Eccles.
The people say,
well, I thought the brain was run by
electrochemical events,
electrical impulses and neurotransmitters.
That's true.
They are all sustained,
sustained by the energy field of consciousness.
So it's the power of the energy field of life itself
transmitting through a certain level of consciousness
and the brain is picking it up
like a radio wave.
We know that a thought held in consciousness
is very often picked up all across the planet
by a number of people,
and some of the thoughts that I've had
and worked on, I'm sure,
were just sitting there in the ether,
you might say,
and picked up by a number of people simultaneously,
and among them some people will act
and others will not.
So it's the consciousness that supports the brain,
and the brain then acts as a receiving set,
much like a radio.
What is it that the brain is picking up?
Well, it's really picking up a carrier wave
transmitted through the acupuncture system,
the etheric body.
We said that the reason to avoid negative energies
is not because of the thoughts,
not because of the content,
not because of the musical notes themselves,
not because of anything specific about it
except the specific,
you might say, carrier wave.
So these levels of consciousness,
you might say, are like carrier waves.
The content is not so important.
It's the energy field of the carrier wave itself.
We also said that 2.4% of the people
are consistently negative in their responses,
and their responses are opposite to the normal.
Love makes them go weak.
They're repelled by love.
And things that are negative and repulsive
are attractive to them.
This 2.4% is apparently the same people
that F. Scott Peck wrote about
in The People of the Lie.
What can be done about them?
I haven't this latest idea.
Underneath a lot of the difficulties
in emotional pain,
if you reflect on these levels of consciousness,
you'll...
certain secrets will reveal themselves.
Underneath, for instance,
a lot of anger, resentment,
a lot of painful feelings,
humiliation, shame, disgrace, feeling victimized,
is the energy of pride.
So, let's say,
when a person makes a mistake and feels humiliated,
and goes into shame, goes into a shame attack,
and feels guilt,
what is all that about?
Can it be unhooked?
Yeah.
Because underneath all of that is pride.
Let go of pride by realizing
the nature of humanness itself,
and you realize that mistakes are really
the problem of humanness.
They are not really your personal problem.
And when you let go of the pride,
then the chagrin, the humiliation,
and the resentment and all that disappears.
The value of using kinesiology is
that you know what level you're dealing with.
Never study a guru,
never take a spiritual course,
never follow a supposed master,
until you know what level they're representing.
That will solve one of the major problems
of spiritual seekers,
and that is getting caught and trapped
in a negative spiritual field.
Don't forget that everything is only true
at its own level.
Truth is only true.
Everything that the world believes
is no longer true
at a higher level of consciousness.
Each thing solves itself at the next level,
and what was the truth at one level
becomes not a lie,
it becomes irrelevant.
So people let go of things
that were once meaningful
and caused a great deal of suffering,
and move into a far more comfortable energy field.
These differing levels,
so during the tape we've moved,
for instance,
the subject of causality.
First we looked at causality
as it looks to people in the 400s,
the Newtonian level of A causes B causes C.
Then we looked at causality
as it looks in the 500s,
where that which is held in consciousness
manifests sequentially in the world.
Causality is not horizontal or linear,
but from the vertical,
it's from the vertical to the lower,
and so we see manifestation and creation.
And this again in the 600s,
we transcend that and we see
that there's a holographic universe,
and that nothing is really causing
anything else at all.
In the 700s,
there is only is-ness.
Everything is already complete and total.
Nothing is causing anything.
There is no here and there.
There is no me and you.
There is no separation
between subject and object.
So as you move from duality to non-duality,
then there is no causality
and there is no creation,
because all is complete and total
in its absolute perfection.
In using the technique,
it's best to always look at one's motives
and you'll get the best answers,
if you yourself are coming from integrity.
One has to ask,
before you ask a question,
can I handle the answer
and be honest about it?
Perhaps sometimes it's best
to leave a certain question alone
and return to it at a later date.
Intuitively, you'll sort of know
when is the right time to do it.
I wanted to talk a little bit about the book,
because most of the people who write
for these videotapes are interested
in the subject matter of the book.
What's the importance of the book?
Well, it conveys an understanding
of the universe and of consciousness
and of causality and all these things
from a sort of comprehensive level.
The purpose is really to help resolve
the problems of individuals and society.
And I believe that the answers
to life's problems,
both individually and collectively,
arise out of an understanding of consciousness.
Not only can advanced theoretical physics
not move any further than it is
until it understands consciousness,
but mankind as a whole cannot really resolve
any of its problems
unless it comes to grips with
the enormous influence and power
of consciousness itself.
We looked at the example
of the drug problem,
and we saw that the position of the DEA
and the drug laws of the United States
calibrated at 150.
150 is a negative energy.
And we saw that an effective solution
would have to calibrate at 350.
So a knowledge of consciousness,
techniques, etc.,
all the subjects that we touched upon,
we barely touched upon them.
And so, in the field of archaeology,
paleontology,
I would hope that study groups would form.
You could spend, you know,
practically a whole lifetime
just exploring archaeology,
retracing history,
recalibrating events in time,
correcting errors
and adding to man's knowledge
at a very rapid rate.
So a crew of five or six people
who are very knowledgeable
about their particular field of endeavor
would then know the right questions to ask.
Many of the subjects that we touched on
we did not pursue to any great depth
because it would take too much time.
The book itself was done in order to
express my own experience of
or knowledge of
and comprehension of
my own subjective, personal, spiritual experiences
and then coming back into the world
and trying to integrate it
with current scientific knowledge
and try to put it into language
and a conceptual format
that's comprehensible
because ours is primarily a left-brain society
in its approach to many subjects.
The idea was to make
that which is apparent to the mystic
comprehensible to the left brain
so that there would be a crossover
of understanding.
The level of 850,
which was the level of the book,
is the calibrated level of the sage.
I think Ken Wilber,
Ken Wilber's stratification
of the perennial philosophy
goes guru and then sage
and he has these various levels.
So when you look at a videotape
or you listen to a lecturer,
you now have a tool
which to discern
is this the truth at all
and so what level of truth
is being reflected.
To merely view the videos
and to merely read the book
and think about it a little bit
has quite an advantage
to one's level of consciousness.
Each step that we take up
has enormous benefit.
You know, we talked about
very large figures
in truth what happens is
let's say a person moves
from consciousness level
300 to 3.02.
That's a very big jump
and it will have an enormous impact
on a person's life
because we're talking about
logarithmic figures.
A move of even a few points
can make the difference between
let's say being a worker
on the production line
to jumping to foreman.
Just a few points makes the difference
gives one the additional power
that one needs to supervise others
and be comfortable in that position.
What spiritual techniques,
what consciousness techniques
can one use to advance
one's consciousness?
We talked about the understanding
of the nature of humanity itself
and the compassion that arises
out of that.
There is a specific physical exercise
that one can do.
People are always asking me
about meditative techniques
and various things like that.
I like that which is simple,
very direct,
but which produces effects
due to persevering.
It's only necessary to understand
one single spiritual concept.
All spiritual truth is contained
in all other spiritual truth.
To understand and use one single tool,
let's say kindness,
at all times and all places
to yourself and to others,
or compassion or willingness
or surrendering it to God
or letting go, wanting to change it,
whatever,
what one does is use this as a tool,
as a scalpel,
and you persist with this one technique
relentlessly.
The last time that there was
a great expansion of consciousness
in the world
in my own experience
was the result of 11 days,
11 days I fixedly
never allowed one single thought
to manifest.
At first you start with thoughts
that are practically paragraphs,
whole stories,
and you let go of those,
you let go of paragraphs,
you let go of sentences,
you let go of phrases,
and then you watch and you see
thoughts are beginning to arise
in the mind.
Well, you become aware of that
which is witnessing the mind,
and you become the witness of the mind.
Then you see that thoughts are arising
from some kind of an energy
that wants to manifest as a thought,
and you get back earlier and earlier
in the thought,
and so finally the mind falls silent,
and after 11 days of that,
suddenly that already incredible state
expanded into its present,
whatever you want to call it.
What is the simplest thing
that one can do?
I think one should just sit
and hold out one's hands like this,
not to receive,
as many spiritual teachers will tell you,
this is to receive the energy of God, etc.
On the contrary,
to sit like this
and radiate out into the world
that which you will for the world.
Very revealing.
Just sit quietly someplace,
hold out one's hands thusly,
and express non-verbally
what it is that you wish
for the world and for humanity.
You just keep doing that,
and that which humanity needs
will reveal itself to you,
and then that which intrinsically humanity is
reveals itself to you,
and eventually that which is not
is the real Self shines forth
in all its radiance and splendor
and magnificence and stillness
in which you see all things expressing
their own essence in an absolute
harmonious perfection.
Nothing is causing anything.
Everything already is as it is.
There's no discontinuity.
Everything is One.
That is self-revealing,
and it is also
healing to the world.
So that motivation
to heal the suffering of the world
and assuming this position
automatically begins to reveal to yourself
in a non-verbal way
which jumps the intellect.
The intellect is the great block,
people say.
Well, that isn't logical.
Nobody said it was logical.
90% of the things you do
during the course of a day
is not logical.
It's an automatic pattern recognition
and an automatic action.
And the ego then takes credit for it
a split second after it occurs
and claims that it decided to do that.
No such thing happened.
If you really watch how your mind operates,
you'll see that actually
it's going on by itself.
It doesn't need a personal need to run it.
One is just the witness
of the mind and its shenanigans
and the body and its
going here and going there,
which it does itself,
sort of like a karmic wind-up toy.
The body just runs itself
and it doesn't really need a you
and the mind runs itself.
It babbles on.
It doesn't need a you to run it
and finally comes the realization
of that which is the self,
which is something quite different
than the body and the mind
in the history that began
when the person said to themself,
I am.
So when was I born?
I was born at age three.
Suddenly I became conscious of existence.
Before that there was no consciousness
of existence.
Suddenly there was an awareness
and a consciousness of I am.
Instantly there was the fear
that if one is,
there was the hypothetical possibility
of one's non-existence.
And I remember fear arising about that.
So with the birth of the ego
arises fear and the desire
for continuation and survival.
And with the grace,
by grace one transcends
all these various levels
and reaches the state of healing
and being healed.
And so that is the meditative practice
that I recommend when people say,
what do you think
is the best meditative technique?