Now let's go back to your life frame.
You sound like quite very successful, you know,
psychiatrist, there are lots of people wants to see you
and you're almost overwhelmed by this number of people
wants to see you and you said you're so frustrated
because in spite of such a big need to seeing you,
you can only deal one patient at a time.
So you start to wondering is there any other way
you can address this problem in a more collective way,
whatever I can say.
So then you eventually having seven years of your own time.
So maybe we can go back that more period
and tell me more about what has been going on
in your own inside.
There's this phase where you're in love with everyone
and people become healed by this love, you see.
It's that recognition of the truth of who they are
and loving them on that level that heals the inner pain
and suffering from which they came.
And they came in great droves, you know,
like I think I told you they were backed up
in all the major airports in the world.
And I saw people from every country in the world.
They used to fly from Paris once a month to see me,
you know, things like that.
So yes.
The sheer volume.
The sheer volume of it, you know.
To see so many patients, you know,
you can only see so many in a day.
And I would see 40 at the hospital
and then go to the clinic and see more.
And then in the evening I would give talks
or things like that.
But you're still only reaching, you know,
literally a certain limited number of people.
And even though I used to give lectures and classes
and whenever I gave a lecture there would always be
a thousand people.
And they always hired a whole for a thousand
and it was always filled.
But even then it seemed like, see,
I had seen the totality of human suffering.
As I say, it was like revealed.
And that still remained to be addressed.
These were specific people suffering specifically
and there was still the general problem.
One day I was walking down Fifth Avenue
and I was walking down Fifth Avenue.
I had an apartment at 952 Fifth.
And I was in that incredible state and I was aware
that the negativity of the city, the negativity,
the total negativity of New York City is so immense
that it would literally blow the city apart.
Except for the fact that there is that
which counterbalances it.
To counterbalance the total negativity of New York City
which is almost 13 million people only requires
a few individuals that calibrate maybe 700, 800, see?
Their power, so it's like the presence of God
and its expression as the power of that
which is universally loving counterbalances
all the negativity.
But it radiates out from some individuals you might say.
At that moment I was walking down and I was,
I was that energy that was counterbalancing.
And another man, he looked like the world might think
he was a bum, you know?
Walked down Fifth Avenue down the sidewalk
and we looked at each other and recognized each other
for who we were.
I think there was maybe two people at the time
counterbalancing that total negativity.
And he was a sage and we looked at each other
and then passed on, you know?
There's nothing to say, you see?
Well, to learn how to manufacture talkingness
was part of the project and I love the world
and I saw that the greatest gift one can give mankind
is to perfect oneself.
You know, when I say oneself, I'm talking about
to perfect that state, to perfect that state
and to look at it in silence and to sense out of that state
and to spiritually sense out of that to be a perfect mirror
back to the world of the shining forth of divinity
through the expression of creation itself.
To be the perfect mirror back to that, to mankind
was what I was doing.
And so I left the distraction of the city and moved into a
rather large home.
Which was a monastery for one person, myself.
And I decorated it with all the various ways to God.
I had all the holy books of all the world's religions there.
Because each one, you know, is its own pathway to God.
There's 10,000 paths to God.
So you spent most of the time for reading and meditation?
No, not reading.
I never read anything.
You would call it meditation.
Just being in that state is itself the meditation.
You see, the meditation goes on continuously.
What the world would call a meditation is always going on.
It's going on now.
Because this talkingness is coming out of the silence
through a certain volition which I train myself to do
to express back out that which is not expressible.
All what I'm talking about is not actually expressible.
What can you say about silence? Nothing.
I know, but I'm trying to get a sense of what you mean by perfecting yourself.
Oh, yes.
Because it's very hard to understand.
At that point it's more a subtle shifting of awareness itself.
It would be more like the surface of the ocean is still,
and then there's a slight rise a little bit like this.
It does it of its own, and one is reflecting slightly differently.
Maybe the moon has brought it up a little higher at this end of the ocean.
It's more like that is happening.
Well, I just remember the cathedral rock
because this rock looks very different from which angle you're looking at.
And I don't know which form is the perfect,
but maybe I can imagine what you're saying to me in that sense.
Because I like one particular angle of cathedral rock.
And it's coming like, boom.
Yes, that's perfect.
Kind of sense.
Anyway.
When one is addressing God, you want to know how it is with myself now, yes?
There's no verbalization.
There's no visualization.
It has no form.
It's like one reflects a need of the world, of humanity,
through oneself so that God is presented with that.
It's more almost like a mudra.
It would be more like if I want to know God's will, it's something.
I just go like, in my spiritual body,
I just go like so.
That would be how one asks the question, you see?
It would be like more a posture.
So one's posture speaks to God
because there's no verbalization.
There's no visualization necessary
in that God knows all that is.
So that which knows all that is knows what's being asked
without having to ask it.
It would be like saying to God,
you're so stupid, I have to verbalize this for you to get it.
No such thing is necessary.
Well, what you're talking reminds me of this,
maybe 10,000 Buddha's posture.
If you go to any of these Buddhist temples,
they're all different forms and sitting pose
of Buddha.
Yeah.
Well, you see, as I said,
that which is unmanifest is beyond form.
Right.
The next level down would be
existence versus nonexistence.
And then below existence itself
would be existence as life.
And then there are the various hierarchies.
So you might say, let's say,
for example, as is commonly understood,
there would be God
and then there would be the various levels of heaven.
There would be the archangels,
the great archangels,
the Lord Jesus Christ, the great avatars.
Then there would be ordinary angels.
You know what I mean?
It's like God expresses itself through us
like a step-down transformer
until you get to physical expression of humanness
on the planet as an avatar,
which calibrates at a thousand.
Then you get to the very advanced consciousness
of the 900s.
I don't know anybody in the 900s.
I haven't found anything in the 900s.
Well, I haven't researched it, that's why.
And then you get people down through the gurus
and down through the spiritual teachers
and enlightened beings
and then the teachers in the high 500s
and then the people in whom the heart is just opening.
And then you get the intelligent people in the 400s
and then you get the salt of the earth
that are in the 300s.
And the hard workers in the 200s
and then animal energy itself in the 100s.
In other words, you understand what I'm saying?
Until you finally get down to the one-celled organism.
So all these levels.
So at each level, one serves differently.
One serves differently.
One serves God by tending the sheep.
If one's consciousness is at 200,
then to do one's duty.
And to tend the sheep is serving God at 200.
It's serving life.
Unless you are really reaching the same level of consciousness,
probably it's almost an impossible possibility
to describing and having a conversation of it.
So it's probably my limitation.
But anyway, once people hear about all these stories,
then they start to wonder,
how does one reach this state of awareness?
Oh yes.
So let's talk about,
you briefly mentioned about
the way people can develop
or the way people can evolve themselves.
Yes, I think,
you see there's various yogas
classically described throughout the centuries.
Kali yoga, I mean all these various yogas.
Raja yoga, all these things.
Bhakti yoga.
Right.
Actually, one does all of them at the same time.
But I think the whole thing hinges on willingness.
First of all, humility.
So the suspicion that there is something other than
what the world thinks is reality,
that has to be there first.
You begin to think,
huh, maybe things are somewhat different.
For one thing, you see that people are different.
You see one person gets angry in the situation.
Another person gets sad in the situation.
Another person is unaffected by it.
You see that some people are very positive
and some people are very negative.
So you begin to think,
huh, there is some kind of variation possible.
There must be other ways of experiencing life
so that you're not always upset.
So some people begin to desire peace and harmony.
So I think there has to be the desire to love,
the desire to forgive people,
the wish to see things differently,
to be dissatisfied with negativity.
So you become dissatisfied with negativity.
You say, I'm tired of being angry.
I'm tired of always wanting something.
I'm tired of being frustrated.
I'm tired of all that.
There must be a better way.
So you start seeking a spiritual pathway.
Well, then there's taking spiritual teachings seriously.
As I said, if judgment is mine, saith the Lord,
when you become spiritually oriented,
you begin to take that seriously.
And you say, well, God is saying judgment is up to me,
not up to you.
So you begin to be willing to let go judgment.
So I think a certain desire to be loving towards other creatures,
a certain respect for life.
There's a point at which one perfects one's sense of mastery
and masculinity to be the great hunter, let's say,
is fine when you're 16.
But then there comes the day
when you look through the telescopic side of the rifle
and you see the stag standing there,
and suddenly you're struck.
By its incredible beauty.
There's nothing more strikingly beautiful
than to see a stag standing there in the middle of a meadow,
still as a statue.
And suddenly, BOOM!
Its incredible beauty strikes you.
And you see it wants life as much as you want life.
Its desire for life, it struggles for life the same as you.
You see yourself in that stag
and you realize you cannot pull the trigger anymore
because you're killing life.
You're killing yourself.
That which you are is just standing out there as that stag.
You realize, you know,
if you destroy his life,
you've really just destroyed your own.
How could you love?
So your capacity to love has to increase.
The yoga that I follow, you know,
to use classic language,
the yoga that I follow has to do with
moving from duality to non-duality.
It's the pathway of non-duality.
It is said that it is not suitable for the average spiritual seeker
in this Kali Yuga.
It is said that it's not.
It is said that the negativity and destruction of the world is so intense
that the capacity to leave the gravity of it
and project off into the stratosphere
is the chances of successfully doing that are not very great.
It is suggested generally by spiritual teachers that
karma yoga, the yoga of loving service,
selfless service is more suitable.
Christianity is the pathway of selfless service.
Mahayana Buddhism,
Pure Land Buddhism
are the ways that are suitable for most people.
And Jesus Christ said that too, you know.
It's like Jesus said,
your chances of reaching enlightenment
are so slim in this lifetime
that what you'd best do is
purify yourself,
become as loving as you can,
and when you leave the physical body,
you will go to heaven.
And in heaven we have higher spiritual teachers.
There isn't all that negativity.
And from heaven then you can progress farther.
You see?
Pure Land Buddhism says the same thing.
You believe in Buddha
and then he's your savior.
And when you die, you go to the pure land,
which is like a heaven.
So to me, Jesus Christ was always very practical.
He said, you know,
it's not very likely
that the average person in his daily life
is going to become enlightened,
but he could become quite spiritually advanced,
become a very loving creature
and suitable for heaven.
In my own condition,
don't forget,
these things began of their own.
When I was three or four,
I was suddenly confronted.
And there was probably,
you know, I can surmise,
there was probably many lifetimes of meditation.
So I didn't mention,
you know, in this lifetime,
I meditated for some 25 years,
you know, on a regular basis without fail.
Even when I had the biggest practice in New York
or maybe even in the United States,
I still meditated from, you know,
5 in the morning until 5.30 or so.
And then I meditated again from 5.30 to 7, perhaps.
So for 20 years I did that.
And then when I came out by myself,
I was in a meditative state,
a meditative state all the time.
Well, what facilitated going into
some of these rather incredible experiences was
the technique is really that of surrender.
So it's really a part of the love of God.
If you love God enough,
if Jesus Christ stood here and said,
for me and for the salvation of all mankind,
I want you to give up your ego
and the vanity of thinking that you know anything,
would you be willing to do it?
Yeah.
In the presence of that great being,
you'd say, anything you want, Lord, anything, you know.
So there has to be the letting go of the vanity of,
what should we say, energizing one's ego,
of believing in one's ego,
of thinking that one's thoughts have any value.
One's thoughts have no value, by the way.
It just may sound surprising,
but one's thoughts have no value whatsoever.
Nor do they originate from an individual personal self.
There is no doer behind the deeds,
and there is no thinker behind the thoughts.
Thoughts think themselves.
They don't need you at all.
Just like the body goes about its business.
You saw the body ever since you've been here.
You see it's going about its business, don't you?
See?
It sits here properly.
It does what it's supposed to do.
Because that's the way the universe interacts with itself.
So the universe is almost like a bunch of magnets.
Each magnet has its own function.
It has its own polarity,
and its own power of magnetism.
And so if all these magnets you see
all position themselves with each other
based on their own polarity
and based on their own degree of power,
those magnets are all doing it of their own self.
So the energy that I put out
and the energy that you put out,
so the energy that you put out
was attracted to the energy that I put out,
and that's why we're here today.
It's like two magnets.
You understand?
So it doesn't require an individual Yoon
or an individual David
to make any decision about such things.
It just automatically gravitates.
See?
Because we're going in the same direction.
So you say,
Hey, I'm going in the same direction.
Tell me what you know
because that will assist me on my pathway.
And my pathway is to help you on your pathway
in whatever way my sharing could help you.
So we serve each other.
Because we have a common goal eventually.
All right.
So what happens then is this,
perhaps, you know,
many people hit,
they spiritually advance
when they so-called hit bottom.
What that means is you have followed the ego
to its idiotic end.
If you follow the ego with great intensity,
it will eventually bring you to great disaster.
And when it's, you know,
your life becomes the result
of your own best thinking.
So there you are in a state of catastrophe
of one kind or another.
And it's at that point
that some people get humility.
They say,
Well, there must be a better way.
Some people might even call on God at that point
and say,
God, I think I'm in trouble.
See?
Well, in my own case,
I gravitated to teachers,
I would say,
like Ramana Maharshi.
The first time I read Ramana Maharshi,
I suddenly knew
that he knew what he was talking about
because I had already experienced that state.
The states that I read about
had already occurred
when I read about them.
See?
And then it was very interesting to me
that other people had experienced
these same states.
The way the state came about,
let's say I told you about one time,
11 days I surrendered.
So the technique then,
the technique,
people are interested
in spiritual meditative techniques.
What do you do when you meditate?
What you do when you meditate
is each thought
as it arises,
you surrender it to God.
Each thought,
each feeling,
each sensation,
you let go wanting to change anything.
Now, if everything is absolutely perfect
as the spiritual,
as the teachers say,
so I'm a teacher at this moment,
I tell you everything is perfect.
Nothing has to change.
You don't have to do anything.
You are already perfect.
Alright, if that is true,
then there is no point
to make anything different
than what it is.
So the next move one would make
if one has humility
and listens to the teacher
is to say,
consequently my mind
doesn't have to do anything.
It doesn't have to think anything.
So what happens is,
is the mind begins to surrender itself
as it unfolds.
So let's say you sit down
and go start to meditate
and say,
I want to experience
the infinite presence.
Simple.
It's a very simple thing to do.
All you have to do is
absolutely and fixedly focus
like a razor,
like a laser beam
on each thought as it arises.
Alright, as you surrender each thought
and feeling and impulse
as it arises to God,
at first you surrender whole stories.
I think I told you people
think they have problems.
They have problems
because they read a story
in their head.
Did we talk about that?
Yeah, we did.
We did.
Alright, so we explain also
that nobody has a problem.
That as long as you live
in this instant,
nobody has a problem
in this whole universe.
Nobody has a problem
this instant.
Alright, so what happens is
as you let go the stories,
as you see how the mind
creates stories,
you begin living in the stop frame
of this moment.
And you will see that the mind
likes to create thoughts.
So first you surrender stories.
Then you surrender paragraphs.
Then you surrender sentences.
You don't allow the sentence
to even complete itself.
If it's worthless,
then why complete the sentence?
If your thoughts don't have
any intrinsic value,
if they're just
belong to the world
and not even yours to begin with,
you know, they're creations of the ego
and the energy fuels of the ego,
then there's no point to perfect it.
Alright, so the first one surrenders
one stops creating stories.
Then one stops creating paragraphs.
One stops creating sentences.
One stops creating phrases.
And you will see that languaging
in the form of thought
is coming from an energy.
There's like an energy in the mind
that is constantly creating
like a stream of thoughts.
So you watch thoughts
going through consciousness
like goldfish through a bowl.
See?
The thoughts are like goldfish.
But what you are is the water.
You're not the goldfish.
So the unenlightened person thinks
I am the goldfish.
I am my thoughts.
I am this worry.
I am this fear.
I am this regret.
You begin to see,
you begin to identify
where is consciousness.
Consciousness is what is witnessing
these thoughts.
So thoughts are flowing through
consciousness
and consciousness itself is invisible
and has no form.
So you begin to identify
with the observer
instead of that which is observed.
Anybody who does meditation
knows what I'm saying already.
But this energy behind thought
is itself formless.
It does not have,
it's like this energy wants to come up
and then it begins to express itself
as a thought.
And at that point
you let go wanting to have the thought.
So you're constantly surrendering
your thinkingness.
Now,
you'll notice that what the mind does
is it tries to anticipate
the next split second.
What your mind is doing right now,
Ewan,
is anticipating the next second.
I can hear your mind clanking away
and it's trying to anticipate
the next moment.
It thinks it has to.
It thinks it has to
in order to survive,
it has to master.
So if you watch what your mind
is really doing,
you'll see it's always trying
to get one up on the next instant.
Alright.
By next instant,
I'm talking about
maybe a tenth of a second.
So what a person is experiencing,
they're never experiencing reality.
What they're experiencing
is the ego's interpretation of reality.
So like an audio system,
there's what's called a monitor.
So just as you tape something,
just as you tape a program on the tape,
the monitor feeds into your ears.
You heard what was just required
recorded a split second ago,
but you're not hearing
the program source.
You're hearing what was just recorded.
This is what the average person
is experiencing,
is the monitor tape
of the ego's interpretation of events.
They're not experiencing events
as they are in reality.
They're experiencing
the ego's interpretation.
So as this thinkingness begins to recede,
there's no longer a desire to think.
There's no longer a desire to think.
You see that thinkingness itself
is a vanity,
that it's like a violation
of the true nature of God.
It's like I negate God's Godness,
therefore I have to think myself.
In other words,
God's not going to reveal to me
what I need to know.
I got to go out there
and one up on God.
So what the ego's really doing
is supplanting God.
You begin to see
what the ego's up to
is to supplant God, replace God.
I don't want truth revealed to me.
Oh no, I'll make up my own truth.
There's a lack of trust of God.
And so this mind
is always anticipating.
Eventually the mind,
as you watch it,
it's like you get earlier and earlier
into the formation of thought itself.
As I say, first sentences,
I mean stories go, paragraphs go,
sentences go, concepts go, words go.
The word begins to come up like dog.
Just as the D and the O start to come up,
you see it's going to become dog.
You catch it already
before it even becomes dog
and let go the desire
to create a thought.
To refunction in the world,
I had to will ordinariness.
I asked God to be ordinary
because you can't be of much good in the world
if you are unusual.
You know what I mean?
Right.
If you're peculiar,
if you're not,
if you're odd.
All right.
So the prejudice of the ego is such
that I know that
to reemerge into the world,
I had to be ordinary.
So I'm just an ordinary doctor,
just an ordinary psychiatrist.
And,
whenever I teach,
I'm just an ordinary teacher.
I'm just ordinary.
Now, in the research that I did,
one thing I noticed was that
you could calibrate the energy level
of a person the instant they were born.
The infant in the nursery,
the minute they're born.
In fact, you can calibrate
the energy level of the fetus
before it even emerges into the world.
And you get that this child is born
with an energy field of 200.
This child is born
at 400.
This child is born at 550.
I don't know what I was born at.
I never asked that.
But perhaps born,
you know,
at an already advanced state
of consciousness.
All right.
So,
you see,
it brings up the question
of the so-called bottom-up
and top-down discourse
in,
you know,
there's a,
there was been two conferences
on consciousness
at the University of Tucson.
The first one I went to,
the last one was also
the spring of this year.
And this brings,
you know,
you see this life
that creates the physicality.
Life,
you know,
the infinite source
of all of life
is formlessness.
It is out of form,
only formlessness
has the power
to create form.
So,
out of the Godhead
arises God,
arises all of creation,
arises the avatar,
arises the,
spiritually aware people,
arises the ordinary people,
arises the animal kingdom,
arises all of nature.
You understand what I'm saying?
Right.
It starts from the top down,
yeah?
The strict materialist says,
oh no,
organisms,
chemicals
rearrange themselves
Right.
and created the,
the necessities for life
and then life,
some,
like spontaneous combustion
suddenly came forth.
And then life evolved
through Darwinian evolution,
you know,
you see,
to create
what they consider
the highest level
of everything
the human being,
see?
This is a limit,
very limited perception.
We have to explain
how is it
that various people
calibrate
different levels
of consciousness
right at the moment
of birth?
And I would leave
the viewer
to,
to answer that himself.
Well,
one explanation
would be
that life
continues on
irrelevant
of physical bodies
because
physical bodies
that life
takes
expression
sequentially
of various bodies
to,
so let's say
consciousness
exists
independently
of physicality.
Then consciousness
seeks to learn
new lessons
and
evolve
itself.
So it needs
bodies
to act
out
in
time.
You see,
in the state,
in my state
there is no time.
Um,
thousand years
or a second
are all the same
to me,
makes no difference.
Um,
five years
somebody says
I'll see you
in ten years,
it's no problem.
If I see,
haven't seen somebody
in fifty years
and I see them
it's the same
as I just saw them
a second ago.
So consciousness
then is outside
of time
and space.
But let's say
it wants to
express itself
in time
and space
it has to have
a physical body
and a soul.
So it would be
fitting for that
evolution of
consciousness
for that being.
So if in this
life time
my spiritual
purpose
was to clarify
God
as void
versus
God
as allness
then I would pick
a certain
lifestyle
and way
of being
that I would
confront
myself
with that.
See.
So it would be
like each being
confronts itself
with whatever
It feels it has to learn to evolve to a greater state of awareness.
Other than picking sequentially physical bodies, it would be hard to say how else it could be done.
All right, the Buddha told us that at one point he remembered all of his previous lifetimes.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Many, many.
All right.
The whole idea of reincarnation only arises if you see yourself as a separate ego.
Otherwise, the question doesn't arise.
You see, that which I am is and has been and will forever be all that is.
In as much as I am, all that ever is, has been, or could be.
If I had previous lives, it would only be...
You see, the difficulty of reincarnation is you have to create the artifact of time.
Now, in reality, there is no time.
So, how can we describe form outside of time?
Well, that's where the example of the hologram becomes useful.
Now, you're familiar with a hologram.
You know, it's projected by a laser beam and a photographic...
Going through this plate, the two intersect and recreate three-dimensionally in space.
And if you fracture the photographic plate, any tiny fragment of the photographic plate,
when you put the laser beam through it, will recreate the entire hologram all over again.
All right.
If you walk through a hologram, let's say we have a hologram of somebody walking, see?
Now, as you look at the hologram, if you stand on this side of the hologram, you see the person like this.
Now, as you move back around the hologram, the person moves like this.
And now, as you move back through the hologram, the person is sitting like so.
Yeah?
Actually, in reality, the person is not sitting in any one of those spaces.
At the same time, he is actually coexisting in all of them.
All right.
So, time would just be a moving point of perception.
Is this part of the hologram more advanced in time than this part of the hologram?
No.
They coexist simultaneously outside of time.
So, the world as people experience it then is from a fixed point of perception,
they walk through a hologram of a universe which has already occurred and is already total and complete.
Right.
And think they see movement and change and the progression of time.
No such thing is going on.
All right.
If I am all things that have ever been, then, and if there's no discontinuity between one thing and another,
then holographically, there is no discontinuity between lifetimes.
Right.
You understand?
Yeah.
Consciousness evolves through.
Let's say I was once a...
We could do the ancient, the Hindu belief system.
I came up as a frog, then an amphibian, then I became a kitty cat,
and then I learned to live.
And then I learned to live.
You can say the dog and the cat are learning to love.
They certainly know how to love better than many humans, yeah.
So they're perfecting the emotional body and the capacity to love
and how to master an animal body and a warm-blooded physicality.
So this evolution, so if we take the evolution of all of creation
and we see it as continuous, one continuous hologram,
there is no separate lifetimes.
You aren't one lifetime.
This one lifetime, this one lifetime, this.
That would be only a point, artificial point of perception.
Right.
One is all that ever has been since the beginning of all of time,
and one will be all that ever will be throughout all of time.
All right.
Can you look back at specific remembrances of other existences in other times?
If at this point in the hologram you could look back at some other point in the hologram,
you would say, well, that's a separate lifetime.
Right.
But it would be a different frame, a different frame.
So as the movie unfolds, that's a different frame.
Yeah.
Okay.
Mm-hmm.
Um, in your own meditation, is there any, any images you have noticed?
Let's, let's clarify the Western, um, belief system about reincarnation.
First of all, all the world believes about, all the world believes in reincarnation
with the exception of the Western world, dominated by Judo, Greek, Christian,
culture didn't exist in their belief system. Does Christianity believe in it? Karma? Oh,
yes, it does. It doesn't call it karma. It doesn't use a Sanskrit term. It believes that
Jesus Christ said, as ye do, so you shall reap. Oh, yes. There are great consequences
to everything, and that the Lord has counted every hair on your head, and that no sparrow
falls without God knowing about it. Therefore, Christianity believes very heavily in karma.
In fact, it's because of karma that everybody gets obsessed about sin and avoiding sin,
because karmically, you're creating a future for yourself. So, when you leave the physical
body, you're going to go to limbo, which is sort of a nowhere place,
or you're going to go to a place where you're going to go to a place where you're going to
heaven. There's various hierarchies in heaven. Everybody knows that. Or you're going to go to
hell, and there's various levels of hell. So, Dante described, you know, the heavens and the
hells. Oh, yes. So, Christians believe very much in karma. They say, you know, and that's what all
the praying is about, and all the obsessing, and all the religiosity is because everybody wants to
be sure to go to heaven, you see.
That's what all the praying to the saints is about. Please help me, help me saying something
or other to get into heaven, you know. Everybody worries about getting into heaven. So, everybody
then is saying that my actions will determine a later lifetime in a different form. My soul,
my spirit will continue on despite the demise of this physical body.
And it will have a lifetime, not only that, but it will have a long lifetime. People think when you go to
heaven, you go there forever, or when you go to hell, you go to hell forever, etc. They not only project
another lifetime, they project a time span.
So, what you're saying is basically the wisdom mind understands...
The wisdom mind does believe in karma, yeah. And of course, you're going to reincarnate in a spirit body in a
different realm.
Right.
Oh, yes. But what it only...
Okay.
What it only focuses on is this particular lifetime. Well, that could be a defect of Christian teaching, I don't know, you see.
As I said in the beginning, Jesus Christ calibrates at 1,000, as does the other great avatars. The Buddha calibrates at 1,000.
The Buddha says, yes, there are many lifetimes. Well, we don't know what Christ said about that.
If you take the New Testament and you boil down, you know, and some New Testament is printed, what Christ said is in red.
If you take out all of the New Testament and you boil down, you know, some New Testament is printed, what Christ said is in red.
If you take out all the things that are in red, only what Jesus Christ said, and put them together, you don't have much at all.
No.
All right. And four of the Gospels are repetitious. So you could really boil down all four Gospels, because they're all telling the same story about the same events from a different witness's viewpoint.
If you boil it all down, you have only really a few pages of what Jesus Christ said. So you have no idea what he said about reincarnation. You have no idea what he said about the equality of women.
Mm-hmm.
All we know is that if you calibrate Christianity in the first century, it calibrates at 950.
And if you calibrate it after the Council of Nicaea, it calibrates like, I don't know, 500 or something like that.
Some huge loss of spiritual truth occurred at the Council of Nicaea.
It's like the dark forces on the planet saw Christianity as a grave threat and somehow infiltrated into the Council of Nicaea and got some kind of a gain, some kind of a power, and decreased the...
the... the...
the level of truth of the teaching.
Mm-hmm.
It didn't happen to... Buddhism still calibrates at a very high level, still calibrates almost at that source.
So other religions did not take such a huge hit. Somehow Christianity must have been a very grave threat. So it took a very heavy hit.
Mm-hmm.
And... All right, so out of religiosity then, people that are more advanced begin to leave the negativity inherent in Christianity.
The negativity inherent in that religion and adhere only to the universally true spiritual principles.
The spiritual principles of all religions are exactly the same.
The basic spiritual principles of all religions are exactly the same.
And what happens is the more advanced seeker leaves religion and... and becomes involved in spirituality.
It's like spirituality is the foundation of truth out of which all religions are built.
Mm-hmm.
The religion itself becomes taken over by the world.
Ambitions for worldly power, worldly gain, to establish theocracies where they can rule the country, influence in owning endless property, political power.
So what happens is then the spiritual truths become corrupted by their practitioners, who then in the name of the spiritual truth, you know, violate... violate the... the spirit of the truth.
And so you see the letter of the law violating the spirit of the law.
You see, you know, Christian judgmentalism in its fundamentalist sects, you know, violating.
Christ said that the basic law is one of forgiveness, to love your neighbor.
Well, if that's the basic law of Christianity, then how can you justify condemning your neighbor, stoning your neighbor, putting him to death, executing him, hanging him, putting him in an electric chair?
He's wrong.
Society needs to protect himself from that person.
But who gave anyone divine authority to execute another human being?
Nobody ever gave it to any human being.
Okay, David, let's go back to the reincarnation.
Yeah.
So you as a person believes it about many lifetimes?
Anybody can discover this for themselves.
Okay.
And do you...
You could use kinesiology and ask, have I had previous lifetimes?
Yeah.
So you can begin to track them down.
Then you could see, hmm, can I remember anything about that?
And there are many teachers that teach self-hypnosis.
You know, you can go and out-of-body techniques, out-of-body astral projection techniques.
There's all kinds of teachers that will teach you astral projection techniques.
And you can go into various lifetimes and re-experience yourself as various things, you know, at various times.
And then you can puzzle over whether that literally happened or whether that only happened in one's unconscious.
Right.
You see?
And therefore it's a puzzle for everyone.
Actually, it's not of any importance.
I know.
Reincarnation is of no importance whatsoever.
See, because the way to God is in this absolute moment.
In the absolute reality of this split second of now is the open, is the gateway.
Okay.
Through this moment now, you split the universe asunder.
I split the universe asunder right in this instant.
All time stops.
All form stops.
I'm beyond the world and all of its doings in this very instant.
It's not too interesting what went on in previous lifetimes.
Well, but I see one maybe benefit to accepting those notions because in a way,
if, imagine,
this is not the only human life I can have, then you can, it's just my interpretation,
but I feel people can more easily detaching themselves from all these, you know, cravings or desires for life.
You see, without some idea about previous lifetimes, a thoughtful person would eventually become an atheist.
Right.
I'll tell you why.
How do you explain the newborn infant who was crushed under a cement truck?
How do you describe that the next one is born crippled?
How do you explain the next one is born gifted and a genius?
How would all these things be explained?
You understand?
Yeah.
It's very easy if something painful happens in your life, you just say,
well, it must be payback for something, you know what I mean?
You have a horrible marriage, your wife treats you terribly, she cheats on you and beats you up
and lies about you and she's paranoid and delusional.
And you can say to yourself, well, I must have been a son of a gun in some lifetime.
Otherwise, I would want to accept it.
See?
Because in this lifetime, you've done nothing to justify this kind of experience.
But if there's previous lifetimes, you could say, well, I must have created some kind of karma for myself
and I will do the best I can to live it through without complaining, you know?
Accept it and do the best I can.
And another teaching from the Buddha or the karma or the reincarnation,
they're emphasized if in your own life paths anybody encountering you,
then you'd better do your best no matter what these people do for you
because then it's the way you can cleaning your past karma between the two.
I think that's kind of good.
And a wise way to keeping the relationship, handle the relationship.
I think, you know, it's like you're given a chance to choose again.
So somebody does evil towards you, now you've got your choice.
You can seek revenge.
You can come from the spleen.
You can choose hatred.
You can choose killing them.
You can choose condemning them morally even though you don't do something.
Or you can choose forgiving them.
And out of compassion for the weaknesses of human nature,
you can say, look, it's only human.
Right.
Also in relation to moving up toward the spiritual evolution,
you know, many people say it is not safe to do that journey all by yourself.
Oh, yes.
So then the question is what is the role of the teacher,
spiritual guru or the spiritual teacher?
Mm-hmm.
As a student, as, you know, whatever, whoever you are,
you want to do this kind of evolution,
can you tell me about the sort of image of proper true teacher?
Yes.
You know, it's very important.
It's very important.
And the Western world is rife with false teachers,
rife with teachers who are in error,
rife with teachers who are wrongly motivated,
seeking worldly power and gain, notoriety.
Teachers get on television and become televangelists.
Send me your money, send me your money.
Well, what is a true teacher then?
A true teacher is not interested in any gain whatsoever,
doesn't charge any money.
There's no money to charge.
Spiritual truth is a gift from God,
so how could you charge for that which was a gift to you?
So the best thing the teacher can be is to be what he is to the student,
to be to the student,
to radiate out that energy of benevolence and love
that supports the student through the difficulties that you know are ahead.
Mm-hmm.
It takes a very intense dedication.
A very intense surrender.
A true teacher knows it has nothing at all to do with his personality.
It has nothing to do with this person as an individual.
What has been revealed to you, you then transmit to others.
So you only teach a teaching and explain to others how this comes about
and encourage them and enthuse them and support them.
And don't lie to them.
Tell them it's going to be difficult.
However, however, there is within oneself a drive
Mm-hmm.
to know God that is so powerful that once it is unleashed,
nothing will stop it.
You will give away everything in the world.
When I went through that phase, I gave away everything in the world.
I had the biggest psychiatric practice in the United States.
Mm-hmm.
I had a huge estate which I myself designed and built on 35 acres in the Gold Coast.
I had a Fifth Avenue apartment.
I had every kind of...
Mm-hmm.
I was the director of this and the board of that.
It all went out the window.
Meaningless.
Absolutely meaningless.
So there's no point in personal gain
because once you see that you're the source of all things,
it's like you have the formula for gold.
There's no point to pile up gold.
There's no point to have 50 Mercedes Benz cars.
There's no point to have 50...
What was that one guru we had in Washington there?
He had a Rajneesh.
Mm-hmm.
75 very expensive cars.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
Anyway.
What is that?
What is the point of that?
The point is to be what you are to the student
because what you are powerfully energizes the student,
what you are to them.
And so you hold in mind that enlightenment is a certainty for this person.
Mm-hmm.
Absolute certainty.
Because once the desire to know God takes you over,
the end is certain.
Once you desire enlightenment, the Buddha said that too,
and that is true.
Why is that so?
Well, I'll tell you why it's so.
The average person who lives in time and space thinks that
what they are now is the creation of their past.
Right.
They say, I am what I am because my past made me that.
See?
But that's being victim of one's past.
No such thing is happening.
You can turn it around and say, oh, no,
it's what you are destined to become in the future
that is pulling you into what you are doing now.
It's because you're destined to become enlightened,
that's why you're interested in spiritual techniques and principles.
If you weren't destined to be enlightened,
what would you be doing on a spiritual pathway?
It would be of no interest.
The future is pulling you with absolute certainty.
So the person who is interested in enlightenment,
you can say, well,
you can say I guarantee you'll reach enlightenment all right.
Otherwise you wouldn't be searching for it, you know.
The future is already seen,
and therefore all you do is try to make the path easier.
There are many different pathways, you see,
and I think the other thing is not to make any other pathway wrong.
It's not that the pathway is wrong.
Right and wrong is meaningless.
It's that certain pathways are going to be more,
more effective than others.
So that getting caught up in esotericism,
psychic phenomena, psychic readings,
playing with crystals,
trying to influence entities on the other side,
it's not that it's wrong.
Some Tibetan Buddhism gets caught in that,
trying to create and detract entities from the other side
and then learn how to control them and disappear them
and make them do your bidding and all.
This is a grave distraction, you see.
And also you're playing with fire.
So, David, would you rather say
you have your own spiritual teacher on your path or?
The spiritual teacher is a whole subject, you know,
and we could talk for an hour about it.
First of all, the teacher is one who has experienced the truth
to a certain level.
Now, that's why I say always calibrate a teacher
because you know what level this teacher is talking about.
First thing you want to make sure is that the teacher
doesn't make you go weak with kinesiology.
So you want to pick out false teachers.
All right.
What is the function of the teacher?
First of all, the teacher's love for you,
if he's a true teacher,
is so intense that if he revealed it to you,
it would frighten you.
So one thing I had to learn
was how to
I guess the word would be disguise.
How to
part of being ordinary
is to keep things within
the common experience of human beings.
Because when the state first came on,
it would have a profound effect on people.
I couldn't control it.
I loved them with such intensity.
They were so incredibly beautiful.
Their divinity shone forth
and I was in love with divinity.
And it would actually blow them away,
you know, frighten them.
Or they would fall in love with you
and think it was personal love or something.
So the first thing the teacher does is inspire you
and represents what is possible.
And where is the teacher?
The teacher is within oneself.
That drive to know God
is the God within oneself.
To get in touch with God within oneself,
God wanting to know its own self,
God wanting to know its own Godness
and its expression here
is the Guru.
So the Guru is the drive to know the truth,
to know reality,
to become one with all that is again.
It may seek an external,
it may take the form of an external representation.
I think one is inspired from unseen realms
to begin with.
I think that,
but within the physical domain,
the teacher would take, let's say,
one who appeals to you
and whose truth you've already experienced
intuitively, let's say,
but it's not complete.
So to me, the teachers that were attractive
were Ramana Maharshi,
Nisargadatta Maharaj,
the Buddha,
Huang Po,
Jesus Christ in his true representation.
To me, what is his true representation
as infinite, unconditional love
and all that that implies.
And all the great spiritual teachers throughout time
I identify with.
If I read Meister Eckhart,
I understand that level of awareness.
If I read the struggle of any of the great saints in history.
So every great teacher that's ever lived,
if I become acquainted with their teaching,
I understand exactly what they're talking about.
And if they talk about a certain point of evolution
in their own consciousness,
I've been through that and I recognize the truth of it.
So one true teacher can recognize
the truth of another teacher.
There are certain things that you experience
at certain states which no one knows about.
Only another teacher understands this.
Even the physical body reacts differently, you see.
For one thing, I noticed that the startle response,
once you stop identifying with the body,
I noticed that the startle response disappears.
For instance, I was reminded of that yesterday.
There was a fierce storm right over the house
and lightning was crashing all around.
And a loud peal of thunder
sounded like it hit the house almost.
And the cat, the cat jumped up like this
and I noticed that this physical body
didn't react at all.
You see, you don't identify with the physical body,
so it doesn't respond to shock anymore.
I'd say that the teacher then has nothing to gain.
So beware any teacher who has anything to gain.
You see, you're complete and total within yourself.
You don't need compliments from anybody.
You don't need believers.
It's totally irrelevant whether anybody believes
one word of what you say. That's their problem.
There's no material gain to be gotten.
You're complete and total.
So I have no needs that anybody could fulfill.
If you asked me what I would like for Christmas,
I couldn't tell you because I would only think of something
that would make you happy, that I, Intuit,
might be happy for you to give me,
that would make you happy.
I don't need anything at all.
So the teacher who looks for recognition or gain
or to make his name famous,
the book Power vs. Force,
I regretfully had to put a name on it.
It was really written by anonymous.
The awarenesses that came to me were a gift from God.
It came through this physicality,
so you would have to give it a label.
You would have to put a name on it and some degrees on it
because of the credibility problem in the human society.
So one reason I went to get a PhD
was to give greater firepower to the truth of what I was saying.
They figured, well, an MD says this,
but an MD PhD, maybe it's even truer.
You know what I mean?
So I figure I'm a doctor doctor that way.
There must be some truth in this.
He's not only a doctor, he's a doctor doctor.
Double credit.
Does that do anything for me?
Nothing at all, see?
All right, so every instant is complete and total and perfect.
Every instant is already complete and total and perfect.
So a true teacher would have no need for anything.
You don't have a need for followers.
You don't have a need for titles.
You don't have a need for fancy anything.
The only reason to have a bigger house
is if you have more guests
then you need a bigger space to entertain.
I used to have a great big house.
Spiritual groups used to meet there almost every weekend.
So we would have 50 people stay overnight.
15 people stay overnight.
I'll have breakfast in bed.
So I needed servants and I needed three gatehouses
and a huge house.
Because in those days, that's what I did.
We would have visiting speakers speak
and teach about various things,
like rebirthing or the Course in Miracles.
I was a member of the Zen...
Meditation?
Yeah, the First Zen Institute in America.
I was a consultant to the Zen Institute.
I was a consultant to the Zen Monastery.
I was a consultant also to the Episcopal Diocese.
Yes, the Episcopal Diocese and the Catholic Diocese.
So I used to see Episcopal priests and nuns
and Catholic priests and nuns
and monks.
I came from the Zen Monastery.
And my purpose then was to differentiate
the aberrations that can arise
through intensive spiritual work
and to recontextualize that back to the person.
So you can still find God even if you are psychotic.
So the general understanding would be
if meditation is making you psychotic,
but I would say you can use the psychosis
to find God the same as any other material,
any other conscious material.
If your problem is hallucinations and all,
that's a problem to the world,
but it's not really a way of interfering,
of your getting to God,
because it's another vanity you're going to have to let go of.
Because if you're seeking non-duality,
then all form is duality,
including hallucinations, you see.
So you can use whatever material
and it still serves the purpose of reaching
the awareness of the presence of God.
So what does a true teacher do?
He helps you along the pathway
to experience the presence of God
and the truth of that which you are
and reinforces that commitment and drive.
To reach the state of enlightenment itself
can make great demands.
It can ask you to sacrifice everything.
You accomplish everything in the world
and it says, now give it up.
You have to give it up.
You just, oh, God wants it, take it.
So the willingness to surrender everything to God.
But then, you know, you were talking about
certain spiritual techniques, yes,
they require a drive.
You were saying that not everyone
has the capacity to do that. That's true.
So maybe in some lifetimes
a person develops this one-pointedness of mind
and this spiritual commitment,
this drive to go through everything and anything.
See, 10,000 fall to the left of you
and 10,000 fall to the right, that's true.
And it is, you're walking a razor's edge.
It's a razor's edge, it is true.
And temptations arise because as you advance,
what you do is you summon forth its opposite.
So you're always confronted
with what barrier you're up against.
And the drive to walk through every single fear,
you know yourself from meditative practice,
all the endless fears that arise,
the fears that you're going crazy,
the fears of psychosis, the fears...
Each fear has to be walked into,
and I found that one teaching from Zen
was extremely valuable,
and that is to always walk straight forward,
right through anything and everything that arises.
And there were moments of hesitation
when that teaching was of great value.
Therefore, what the teacher himself
has been doing,
what he's been through and shares with you,
can be critical at a given moment.
There's times when you reach a mental and psychic exhaustion,
and at that point you cannot stop.
At the point that you cannot go one iota further,
you must go through that.
And therefore, what happens is you break barriers.
So in meditative practice, you enter a new domain,
filled with ecstasy.
There's always ecstasy.
When you break through a new paradigm,
there's always ecstasy, ecstatic.
You realize that you have conquered that domain,
and you've now emerged into a new and higher plane.
There's always that ecstasy,
and then, you know, the desire to share that ecstasy and joy.
And then, you find that there's heavens beyond that heaven,
and then there's heavens beyond that heaven,
and then there's heavens beyond that heaven.
And so 850 then represents to me, you might say,
if that's the level of this consciousness now, a barrier.
What is the barrier at 850?
Do you understand?
So the teacher doesn't say to himself,
hey, look how wonderful I am that I've traveled this far on the road,
because he knows it's only a road.
He says to himself, how come I'm only at 850?
You know what I mean?
What is the problem here?
All right, so you can stop for a moment with your spiritual work
and just be what you are to the world
and fulfill whatever the obligation is there.
You see, the teacher sees himself as obligated, in quotes, to others.
He sees no obligation of others to him.
So a teacher will give you everything he's got
and expects nothing to be repaid.
You don't owe me anything.
I'll spend the next 10 years talking to you around the clock.
At the end of that time, you owe me nothing.
Okay, then, David, would you say you have some teachers
or you've gone through all these paths by yourself?
Primarily, I was by myself.
At age three or four, that was by myself.
God has been my teacher.
My teacher is the Lord God himself.
And in prayer throughout my lifetime, it's been to the Lord God himself.
Then how about would you then call yourself
a spiritual teacher for people?
I call myself that.
What I am is a sharer.
I share with the world what I've learned, see,
for whatever value it may be to the world.
To some degree, statistically, what I've experienced is rare.
Therefore, I say to share it with the world is valuable
because it rarely happens.
And then it rarely happens in a person with a scientific training
who can then come back into the world,
and then visualize it in such a way
that it can be comprehended through the intellect.
Usually, a teacher says to you,
drop everything, follow me, sit down, meditate,
let the mind go, and call me in ten years.
See?
Or the spiritual seeker reaches a state of exquisite bliss
and stays there.
So there has to be a willingness to sacrifice even bliss itself.
Because in the bliss state,
you cannot really say anything to anyone.
In the bliss state, you are that to the world.
Let's say if you reach a state that calibrates at 600.
A person at 600 probably counterbalances
10 million people's negativity.
Alright, so if the monk who reaches 600
does nothing but sit in a state of bliss in a cave,
he is already serving the world.
By his own existence, he radiates out that energy.
You know, when I was going down I-17,
and I felt this kundalini energy,
coming up the back and going through
and then out through the heart,
you know, that energy was accomplishing
certain things within the world,
you know what I mean?
So even if I just sat in my car and did nothing,
so you were like a broadcast station.
So somebody, some people out there are praying,
the nearest broadcast station radiates out this energy,
divine love through, you know, serves
because it's willing to be a channel of God's will.
So I think one of the most powerful prayers, you know,
is to repeat that one is a servant of God.
You say, I am the servant of the Lord,
therefore my will, my thoughts and all that are of no use.
To be a servant of the Lord and then to ask God
to express His will for you, in what way
can I be your servant of the Lord, see?
So then God perfects you
because you have now become His problem.
His instrument, why don't we say that?
His problem, I say His problem, see?
Because now His problem is how to make a better instrument out of you.
So when you say, you know, it's like a cat that declares
that your home is His home now,
now you've got to feed Him, right?
I call that rattling the gates of heaven.
The way you rattle the gates of heaven
is you tell God you're His servant
and He'd better do something about it now.
And then you pester Him with prayers and supplications
and finally, you know, Ramana Maharshi says,
He says, finally God feels sorry for you
and gives you what you pray for.
Of course, you know, He's joking on one level.
On another level, He's very serious
because, you know, you start rattling the gates of heaven
and you might say God now has to pay attention to you.
Otherwise, there's this idiot out there claiming He's your servant
and you have to do something about him.
Okay. See, at almost the end of your story,
you said you had a very exquisite, another awakening.
You said, suddenly, without warning, a shift in awareness occurred.
The Presence was there unmistakably, all-encompassing.
There were few moments of apprehension
as the self died.
Oh, yes.
So I guess maybe this is the most dramatic experience you had.
So my curiosity is, can we calibrate which level it is?
That level there, yeah.
Okay.
Because it is...
You see, in other words, you can move from the first great shock.
Well, it takes quite a while to get used to the high 500s
because you're surrounded now by perfection and beauty and synchronicity.
Mm-hmm.
And you realize that life has really changed.
And people seek you out and they seek to be in your company.
And the miraculous begins to occur, you see.
And so there's that paradigm shock to go through.
Right.
Then if you get into a spiritual practice
that takes you out of duality into non-duality,
suddenly you're confronted with a whole other paradigm of reality
that you have to get used to and you have to learn how to function
and your problems with pronouns.
You know, who is the I?
There is no I.
Okay.
But the I that you're experiencing is more profoundly I
than the I which is capitalized.
That which denotes the ego is supplanted.
See, what people fear is they're going to lose that I.
It disappears.
But an I that is more profoundly myself takes its place and continues on.
And you were asking me what?
Well, in the almost close to the end, you were mentioning about...
Oh, yes, that question.
Oh, yes, right.
Yeah, it sounds like a total seize of your ego.
Yes, okay.
Let's ask what that is.
Okay.
At the moment of the great unfolding,
the energy which unfolded before me,
you see, it's self-revealing.
That which was self-revealing calibrates over 800 resist,
850 resist, 860 resist, 900 resist, 800 resist,
850 resist, 860 resist.
870 resist.
880 resist.
890 resist.
I don't know.
It's somewhere in the high 800s.
Right.
We would have to take time out and really calibrate it.
Well, and then you mentioned your big spiritual task in this lifetime
is to see whether God is the nothingness, the void, or the allness.
It turned out to be that that was the question.
To be honest, I don't know.
I don't know.
That was the question to be answered.
Yeah.
It was interesting because somebody who sat in one of my lectures suddenly recovered
from the illness that he had, and it was quite a profound experience.
It just happened during the lecture.
Six weeks later, a truck backed up, and this table which sits here, which weighs several
hundred pounds, he delivered.
He made this table himself out of a slab from the top of the mountain.
It's solid juniper.
It's a magnificent.
He made it as a bench.
It's far too good as a bench.
I said, oh, I need a table for it.
So I used it as a table.
But in the top, curiously, is Sanskrit, the symbols for allness and nothingness.
I thought that was interesting how it suddenly appeared.
So I'm like confronted with, you know, the ancient problem of Hinayana versus Mahayana.
Okay.
You know.
And I'm like, well, I'm going to do it.
I'm going to do it.
So I'm like confronted with, you know, the ancient problem of Hinayana versus Mahayana.
Okay.
You know, God as void.
Now, the difficulty with a lot of spiritual work is that it's mistranslated from the Sanskrit.
Mm-hmm.
So the ideal is not detachment.
That's an error.
Detachment will take you to the void.
Mm-hmm.
The correct technique is nonattachment.
Okay.
Nonattachment allows me to participate in life and be totally at one with it.
Mm-hmm.
I have nothing to gain from it and nothing to lose from it.
Consequently, I can 100% participate without getting caught by it.
Okay.
Detachment means I'm afraid of the world that if I get involved, I'll get caught by it.
All right.
Detachment is like the old story.
Please do not give me a cat because if you give me a cat, the cat will have to have milk.
Okay.
If the cat has to have milk, then I have to have a cow.
Mm-hmm.
If I have to have a cow, I have to milk the cow.
Then I have to have a fence to keep the cow in.
Then I have to have food to feed the cow.
All right.
Then I have to get a job to get the money to buy the food to feed the cow.
Please do not give me a cat.
There's some sense of fear, yes.
So the fear of being caught in the world.
So there's the phobia about relationship.
Mm-hmm.
And the monk has become celibate and all.
Why?
Because he's going to get caught by sex.
Okay.
He's going to get caught.
He's going to get trapped by his ...
All right.
... by maleness, femaleness.
Mm-hmm.
And the monk is going to become celibate and all.
Why?
Because he's going to get caught by sex.
Okay.
He's going to get caught.
He's going to get trapped by his ...
All right.
... by maleness, femaleness, and the attraction.
Okay.
Well, all right.
It's okay for the monk for a period of time.
But the sage, the sage who has reached a high state and now comes back in the world, has
to be able to participate again in life.
Okay.
You have to be able to handle money without getting caught by greed.
See?
Ramakrishna, you know, Ramakrishna.
Yeah.
Ramakrishna.
I experienced a lot of what Ramakrishna, you know, he went into the ecstasy and the
presence of God.
I went to that same ecstasy.
I understood Ramakrishna very well.
But he would only take young men as students.
And the thing I never agreed with him is he would always say the root of all problems
is money and women, see?
Money and sex.
So he forbid either one.
You weren't even allowed to touch money, much less think about sex or look at the opposite
sex.
Yeah.
enlightened means that one has lost all fear of you must be able to walk through life participating
fully you must be able to eat meat without thinking that your soul is going to go to hell
that you have just killed an animal see because you've brought the animal life the cow the cattle
would not even exist except for the fact that you eat them if you stop everybody stops eating cattle
no more cattle will be born because nobody will buy cattle nobody will raise cattle
and all the cute little cows out there won't get to moo and eat grass you still have no reason to
come into existence you understand so when you reach the full understanding of things
there's no reason to avoid them okay all right so don't get caught by them
is different so detachment is different than non-attachment so even a small thing so you'll
see in buddha's literature there's a misunderstanding of the buddha's teaching about that let's let's
check out the truth of what we just said the correct spiritual teaching to reach um the
experience of the presence of god is detachment resist the correct spiritual technique is
non-attachment resist all right so we have confirmation of what i just said yes it's by
being non-attached i can participate fully with you right if i'm detached i would be indifferent
i'd say she wants to write a book about it that's her problem and i wouldn't even give you an
appointment
i'm detached from you and what you're up to and i have no interest in anything outside of reaching
my own enlightenment so you see how detachment leads eventually to a spiritual egocentricity
and that's the downside of the hinayana pathway right that i'm only interested in my enlightenment
and your suffering is just an illusion see so did they not deny the reality of suffering to the
person who suffers is a spiritual error see
so the one difficulty with being in its 720 or something you say well all that is illusion out
there that's just a projection and it has no reality so i don't have to get involved in helping
relieve human suffering because it has no reality human suffering is very real on its own level
and true its basis is illusion but that doesn't mean that it still doesn't fester and cause agony
so
humankind to me is a spiritual error i'm very aware of this agony of humankind it's because
of the agony of humankind that i come back into the world and write a book and and appear with
you today it's because of that agony out of compassion for that agony so to show people
what is the way out of that agony you know is is mankind serving its own purpose
so it's the suffering of mankind that pulls this entity here back into the world and back
into practice and writing books and appearing to try to explain things just you know just a
simple thing to see that the cause of anger is not about what people are but what they are not
that itself can make such a change in your life just that little notion you understand that i'm
angry at the car not because it breaks down but because it it doesn't maintain itself you see
so all
you
Already that creates a shift in consciousness.
It's that shift in consciousness that I seek to support, you know, in mankind in general.
So when the consciousness of mankind crossed over to the 200 line, it critical massed.
So the explanation of it from a scientific viewpoint is really chaos theory.
So things stay the same.
So the consciousness of mankind throughout centuries stayed at 190.
If you calibrate, what was it in the year 1400, 1500, 1600, 1700, what was it in the
year 1100, you'll come up, it was 190.
The consciousness level of mankind stayed at 190, which is below the critical level.
Therefore, the survival of mankind was not at all guaranteed.
At 190, your survival is not guaranteed because that's less than integrity.
That which supports life was not as strong as that which was destructive of life.
The incarnation of life.
Inquisition was certainly a very good example, the dark ages, you know, in which negativity
prevailed.
It was the lifestyle.
Nobody lived past the age of 40.
Everybody died of smallpox, syphilis, and destruction was rampant.
Alright, so chaos theory tells you that through iteration, the process of iteration, it is
through the process of sameness that difference suddenly arises.
So a difference of one digit in the 20 line.
The 26 decimal point will not make any difference tens of millions of times.
But if you repeat it tens of millions of times, all of a sudden, the fact that the 26 digit
is up or down one will suddenly throw a number that cannot even be predicted.
Out of millions and millions of lifetimes of black raccoons, all of a sudden, you'll
get a white one.
Alright, so out of the sameness of that 190, conventional thinkingness of the 20 line,
the ego which prevailed, suddenly it's almost like it gets dissatisfied with itself and
it jumps itself.
So you know, just we could say mathematically speaking, from the viewpoint of chaos theory,
you could predict that if the consciousness of mankind stays at 190 century after century,
if you project far enough ahead in time, suddenly it will jump beyond 200.
My question is, if the human conscience is raising up 204.
Yeah.
It seems to be quite courageous in a way, because in a common sense, the pessimistic
view seems to be getting more stronger somehow.
Yeah.
Well, the pessimistic view is not really stronger.
It's always been there.
And there's always the naysayers.
There's always the people that predict there's going to be more people on the planet than
the planet can supply food, you see.
Because it extrapolates into the future.
That which is in the present, which is an error.
It's a scientific error.
It's a mathematical error.
Because the future recreates itself.
The future constantly recreates itself.
And it finds solutions for itself.
It doesn't have to find a solution to the year 2020 now, it doesn't have to yet.
In the year 2020, it'll come up with a bright solution to the problems of 2020.
So, you know.
Malthus's prediction that the world could only hold so many million people and then
they would begin to starve to death never came true.
The reason is productivity per acre has quadrupled, in fact, I think it's gone up like tenfold.
So although the population may double, our agricultural productivity has gone up to such
an extent that the government pays us to not till millions of acres.
The way to get rich is to own millions of acres and do nothing with them.
And the government will hand you all kinds of money, because there's too much food.
So our problem is we have too much food.
So Malthus was totally wrong.
And so the thinkingness of Malthus-type people, you know, reemerges constantly.
It sees, you know, the negative potentiality of everything and then projects that and recreates.
And creates negativity for us to live with.
I think the thought that nothing is possible.
Nothing is impossible, which was expressed by Christopher Reeves as a very correct thought,
irrespective of his politics.
Nothing is impossible.
So what seems impossible is an artifact of positionality.
And when one transcends that, the answer is standing there clearly and obviously.
There's no problem that mankind has that the answer doesn't already exist.
And what would you reiterate?
Mm-hmm.
What would you anticipate the collective level of human consciousness?
It's going to be coming up?
I don't know.
It could stay.
What did I say it was?
204, 207?
I forget the last time I calibrated it.
My guess would be that it'll probably stabilize there for a number of centuries.
And then it will, like a lion getting ready for a leap, you see.
The lion looks like he's not moving, see?
Okay.
He crouches.
It looks like he's not moving, right?
And you say, then when the lion leaps, now he's moving.
Oh, no.
He was moving already because he has to gather himself up.
Okay.
And the leap is only the end result of what's happened already.
So the great lion of society will again go into a crouch and begin to build up its power
and strength, and it'll leap again.
Oh, yes.
It'll continue to leap.
Mm-hmm.
And the evolution of mankind will continue to leap.
Why?
Because once you're over 200, you're into the level of courage and integrity.
Well, once you're into courage and integrity, the answers to everything from that point
are discoverable.
When you're below 200, you can't find the answer to anything.
When you're over 200, it's only a matter of time before you find the answer to everything,
you see.
Okay.
When your goal is only over 200, you have courage and integrity.
Courage and integrity will lead you to the fact that love solves about 99% of human problems.
So even if you're not at love yet, you discover that love has the power to heal.
Okay.
Thank you so much.
Yeah.
Thank you.