well we're here because we're here because we're here
what a wonderful uh crowd and you've been meditating this morning
wonderful i always say glory to god glory and excelsis deo if that makes you nervous
this is the wrong place to be today
such things become rote if you're a religionist and you forget the power that you invoke into
your life the 91st psalm which is uh one of my favorites says those who call upon me are mine
krishna says those who call upon me are mine so those who call upon god live under the protection
of the almighty
hey that's a comforting thought in today's world
the lady who jumped uh at 13 000 feet and the parachute didn't open
i was wondering what she was thinking about on the way down
guess i should have gone to church or something
uh yes
well today we're going to talk about really uh advancing one's level of consciousness
in today's today's world uh frankly due to the work that's been done the chances of reaching
enlightenment are now a thousand times greater than at any time in history a thousand times
greater
let's see if that's true what i just stated is true or resist okay those of you who are
familiar with the work know that uh we use a lot of words that are not the same as the
words of the church we use a lot of words that are not the same as the church because
kinesiology as a means, as a measuring tool. I've got a, what do you want to call it, a finger,
finger, you know, and it's interesting to meet here. This property, I used to spend a lot of
time, oh, 35 years ago. It was the site of a monastic group, Zen Catholicism, a synthesis of
Zen and Catholicism, and the monks all lived in separate little huts, and there was a meditation
center, and I used to come to the meditation center in the dark at 4 30 or 5 in the morning,
and you had the meditation center all to yourself, a kiva, a meditation kiva,
and I had it all. It was just a big circular building with a nice carpet, and I could meditate
for hours absolutely alone. It was wonderful. Zen Catholicism. They later moved on to Colorado
because Sedona became too crowded. At the time I came here, the population was a little less than
3,000. It's now like 18,000, so when they got 3,000, they got up to four or five. They thought,
I was getting crowded here, and they left. It seems comical, huh? All right, so today I thought
a number of you are familiar with the work I've done, and so I'm going to recapitulate it.
I will tell you how it all originated, you know. I had a huge psychiatric practice, and
it was the largest in the United States, frankly, and we had a couple of thousand outpatients,
and I had a huge staff, and we treated the most hopeless patients from all over the world.
They flew them in from every country, and some had very rich parents. They were Maharaj in India,
you know, multi, huge amount of money, and so these patients had been everywhere,
seeing everybody. They'd seen every professor, and they're all hopeless, the most hopeless of
all cases. So those were the patients that I specialized, the most hopeless of all, and we used
alternate therapies. Medical science itself calibrates as a science about 440, but clinical
science, that's academic science, calibrates around 440. Clinical science calibrates five
points higher, 445. So it takes into account the effect of the healer, the presence of the
physician, and the consciousness level of the physician, too, you see. So I had a huge staff,
of psychiatrists, and I noticed that some had very high rates of recovery, and others didn't.
As it turned out later, those with the higher levels of consciousness had the highest rating
of healings, because they brought the power of intention, and the power of intention. We'll get
around to quantum mechanics later, but the Heisenberg principle, you understand, precipitates
potentiality becoming an actuality. And what hasn't been measured is the power of the effect of
the observer. It's taken as an abstract concept in the work of Henry Stapp at Berkeley, explains the
scientific basis of it. But what we haven't measured yet is there's a difference between the
consciousness level of the observer. So a person with a weak level of consciousness,
doesn't experience miracles, doesn't even see miracles. And to other people, the miraculous is a
continuous reality. The fact that I'm alive and breathing today is already a miracle.
Well, I didn't want to listen to him talk all morning. So I was gonna tell you how this all started.
So, yes. So, we had a Course in Miracles group, so we knew that there was a certain thing that was going to be
in my life at the end of the day. And I don't know about you, but I knew that I would have to go to my
best friends and friends, and I knew that I was going to have to go to my best friends, and my best friend was going to have to go to my best friend. And I knew that he had
group there. It was the second, whatchamacallit, healing center in the United States. The first
one was in Tiburon, and Jerry came out with his whole staff and spoke to our staff. So
we had the second attitudinal healing center in the United States based on the Course in
Miracles. That was for hopeless patients at the clinic. And so we had patients with every
kind of disease known to mankind who practiced the Course in Miracles. So I had studied something
about kinesiology. I'd heard that that's a new way you could diagnose and help treat
patients. And so I went and learned about it, and I came back to lecture to the staff
about what I had learned. And I found that there were certain people, oh, I know what
I did. I said, I need some volunteers for the kinesiology demonstration tonight. And
a few of them were hanging out because they were meeting with the attitudinal healing
center. And I said, come on over here, let me see, and we'll test you tonight.
So when I tested them with fluorescent lights or pesticides, things that make everybody
go weak, these people did not go weak. In teaching kinesiology, I used to just, you
pass out synthetic sugar substitutes or pesticides or look at fluorescent lights, everybody goes
weak looking at fluorescent lights. But these people did not. They looked at the fluorescent
light and their arms stayed strong.
I said, what's the matter with this guy? Then I tried pesticides. That didn't make
them go weak either. So something was different about this group that was doing the Course
in Miracles from ordinary people. So a new group was starting doing the Course in Miracles.
So I tested them periodically. I tested them about once a week. And of course, they went
weak to fluorescent lights. These fluorescent lights would make everybody go weak.
And then I found around less than 90 or so, after they'd been in the Course about three
months, suddenly negative stimuli did not make them go weak anymore. I said, wow-zee,
that's fantastic.
And from that, we then devised a measuring system of one to a thousand. And kinesiology
is not understood by people at all. They think it has to do with, they don't understand that
it's objective.
In other words, in the presence of truth, physiologically, you go strong via your acupuncture
system. And there's other physiologic phenomena, such as the pupillary response. So some people
like to ridicule kinesiology. It's because they don't understand it. Because people who
are stuck in the linear pedestrian domain of intellectual development don't understand
the non-linear.
Therefore, the skeptics...
are stuck with the fact that they have a very pedestrian mentality. Below 200, you
don't understand the non-linear domain. Because reality emerges as a consequence, not only
of content, but of context. And the skeptic is unaware of the power of the field, the
non-linear field of context. Consequently, a physician who believes in God has a higher
cure rate. They want to know what the cure rate is. They want to know what the cure rate
is. They want to know what the cure rate is. They want to know what the cure rate is. They
want to know what the cure rate is. They want to know what the cure rate is. They've
steel-resistant the lecture every lesson from 10 to 18 minutes.
But they don't discover it. They don't have a full view of time. What needed, at home,
is to see the perfect state.
Blue mean proposed.
Red mean prescribed.
We have Amtrak...
Okay.
Yeah.
has never been known becomes instantly knowable why is that because in the infinite reality
of consciousness in the beginning was the light in the beginning was the godhead
out of the godhead emerged divinity as the creator from which reated forth the light of god
the light of god is the field of consciousness itself which is infinite infinite all present
with no beginning and no end so the ultimate context of our work is the field of consciousness
itself which is the presence of divinity in the non-linear domain in other words an infinitely
powerful field and by virtue of that field all things manifest out of potentiality so
you begin to see as your consciousness advances
that there is no such thing as causality in the world causality is a linear newtonian concept of
this causing of that which calibrates in the 400s actually the way things happen is potentiality
actualize actualizes under appropriate conditions potentiality becomes actuality
not out of causality but out of the emergence the potentiality even
an thats
emerges as an actuality the flower is not there's no flower by virtue of force nobody forces
the flower to come forth but within the flower is that potentiality and the local conditions
are appropriate.
It shines forth with the radiance of its existence that's how all things come into existence
its potentiality actualize and our best definition of
it in the linear domain or in the comprehensible domain, is the Heisenberg principle.
Henry Stapp, S-T-E-P-P, out of Berkeley on the Internet, has probably the best delineation
of the application of it.
Potentiality actualizes when conditions are appropriate.
One of the conditions, then, is your own state of consciousness.
So what you hold in mind then tends to actualize.
What you hold in mind tends to actualize, yes, okay.
That is a fact, resist.
What you hold in mind tends to actualize, that's all.
Not based on causality, so you can't cause yourself to become rich, or cause yourself
to become famous, or cause yourself, and you see everybody out in the world trying to cause
themselves to be successful, and .
It's entertaining.
But anyway, the way to success is to be completely and totally the fulfillment of your own potential
to the best degree that you can fulfill it.
To be the best carpenter in town, to be the best shoemaker in town, to perfect whatever
capacities you have, to be the best mother there is, the best father, to be an upright
and responsible citizen.
To be, to have good will towards all of life.
To contextualize your life, all you need to do, you don't have to sit and meditate, you
don't have to go um and om, you don't have to do anything.
All you have to do is have good will towards all of life and all of its expressions, no
matter what.
I'll just give you the example, in previous lifetimes being beheaded.
So you say to the headsman, listen, don't feel nervous, it's okay, it's only your job.
That's not your job.
That's what I always tell them, don't worry about it, it's only your job, and you're doing
a good job of it, thank you, thank you.
There you go.
So your last thought is good will towards the headsman, that he doesn't feel guilty
about this.
It is that he's fulfilling his obligation to the crown, he's fulfilling his obligation
to the crown, and therefore he's worthy of respect.
So I respect the head, I always respect the headsman.
When it's another one of those heads-off lifetimes, which I haven't had in quite a while now.
Okay, well let's start with the, we'll start with how we usually do this.
The map of consciousness then evolved, Lager-Nik, these are all numbers to the 10th power.
So this is 10 to the 600th power.
This is 10 times the 20th power, you see.
So the power, it goes up.
It goes up very, very rapidly as you get into higher numbers.
As you get into higher numbers.
Therefore a loving thought is, I forget how many times, 10 million or some odd number,
more powerful than a negative thought.
So stop feeling guilty about your negative thoughts, because they're weak and feeble.
One loving thought will undo all the negative thoughts you've had all day.
That's a fact, oh Lord, isn't it?
That's a fact.
I never asked that one.
But.
I just know it experientially.
One loving thought is transformative.
It undoes all the negatives.
Why?
Because you see, here you're hitting somebody, the power of that is 20, 20 times 10, 10 times
10, 20 times, 10 times 10, 20 times.
A loving thought is 10 times 10, 500 times.
You see how enormously powerful.
Yeah.
A loving thought is.
So to be, people say, how do you reach enlightenment?
I say, be loving towards all of life and all of its expressions at all times.
That's all.
Goodwill and lovingness towards all of life.
So that lovingness, it isn't love, it's lovingness.
See, love here is at 500.
Lovingness is maybe at about 540 on up to 570.
540 is the 12 step groups.
Alcoholics Anonymous.
Unselfish lovingness and goodwill towards others.
So as you advance spiritually, that which you hold in mind tends to manifest.
And you also discover if you have any negative thoughts, too, as you hear something falling
off the wall, you say, well, God, I didn't really mean to think that.
All right.
So.
What happens then is what people are critical about kinesiology and they can't get off their
own narcissistic orientation towards life.
They presume that everything we say or every calibration is a personal opinion.
They don't get appearance from essence.
There's appearance and then there's essence, as Descartes pointed out.
And the difficulty, as Socrates says, is man cannot differentiate appearance from essence.
The essence is the innate essence.
The essence is the innate truth.
That which is how it is in nature.
Appearance is what you think about it.
I'm not interested in what anybody thinks about anything.
I'm not interested in anybody's opinion about anything because opinions are worthless.
You can go on the Internet and there's millions and millions of and you calibrate them, they're
all under 200.
Well, 200 is a magic number.
We found that anything below 200 makes you go weak and anything over 200 makes you go
strong.
And for the first time, the first time in all of human history, there was a way of discerning
truth from falsehood.
Do you know that in one second, we can discern the truth or the falsehood of anything, anywhere
in time, anywhere in the universe?
Fifteen percent of the audience got what I said, 85 percent do not.
By the end of the day, we hope we'll increase this.
Why is this?
Because in the infinite dimensionless field of the universe, there's nothing.
There's nothing.
There is no center.
Nothing is present, there is not.
There is nothing in the infinite realm.
Everything is a field of consciousness.
There is no center.
There is no center to an infinite universe, neither is there a past or a present or a
future.
Therefore, everything is happening now, yours is discernable now, and everywhere is right
here.
What Napoleon thought about and how he felt before he walked into the Pyramid and how
he felt after he walked out of the Pyramid is knowable right this instant.
Why?
Because outside of time, there is no then, now, or future.
You cannot use kinesiology to determine the future.
Why is that?
Because the future is not a reality.
It's a hypothetical potentiality.
So the future isn't set.
Therefore, books telling you about the prophecies of the future all calibrate negative.
All of them.
Not a single one of them calibrates true.
Why?
Because potentiality is actualizing based on an infinite field.
And part of the infinite field is your decision from moment to moment.
The future hasn't happened yet because we haven't created it yet.
Because what we're holding in mind is what's creating the future.
How can you predict that which has no reality?
It has no reality.
So you cannot predict the future.
You don't have to understand me.
That's a fact.
Resist.
It's a fact.
You can't predict the future.
That's why in the New Testament, the book of Revelations, calibrates it 70.
I treated a lot of people with apocalyptic triumphalism delusions.
That's a realm in the lower astral, calibrates it 70.
People periodically go over there.
There was somebody here in Sedona, very well known, who had quite a few fathers.
And he had gone over there and was predicting end times, etc.
Because at that calibrated level of 70, there's an astral realm where the apocalyptic catastrophic is a continuous ongoing play.
And if you go out of body, your spirit goes over there, you experience it as a reality, you come back here and tell everybody that the end is coming.
And every generation, there's people walking up and down the sidewalks, repent, the end is coming.
The future isn't here because we haven't created it yet.
In human experience, the collective consciousness of mankind, which was at 190,
the collective consciousness of mankind calibrated at 90 at the time of the birth of the Buddha.
It calibrated about 100 at the time of the birth of Jesus Christ.
It slowly rose over the centuries and got as far as about 190.
And there it stayed for many centuries.
It stayed right at 190.
And up until the late 1980s.
It was at 190 and then suddenly in the late 1980s, it jumped to 205.
It then, a couple of years later, that we were lecturing in San Francisco when it did it, it went from 205 to 207 at the time of the Harmonic Concordance.
And since that time, it has gone back down again.
Let's see what it is this morning.
You have to take the world's temperature every day, you know.
Yeah.
The collective consciousness of mankind, we have permission to ask that or resist.
It's currently over 204.
Currently over 205.
204.
So it was up to 207.
It went down to 204.
I was a little disappointed.
I thought it was going to keep evolving in a steady course, but it didn't.
So, for reasons, I don't know myself.
I don't worry about it.
The consciousness of...
I don't know if there's any tax points on it for now, but I hope I do with the states,
and history has, you know, the basic idea of the us has a certain Norman.
So, that thing you have been questioning it lately.
My pleasure.
I was so told so many things that it was almost like a golden age.
It's the kind of lights that keepOnly a boost out of the earth.
So of course, we'd get stuck on rotation.
It's been about five years, I guess.
And historically...
And historically, we have looked.
A lot, perhaps.
Wow, wow.
is that? Singapore is over 430, 435. Singapore is ahead of us. I think they're so good. Well,
where do they see our new iPod-y-doodle? iPod-y-doodle, where do they see our new iPod-y-doodle?
That'll show them Singaporeans. Level of consciousness, then, is correlated with your
understanding of divinity, your view of yourself. The level of consciousness here, we've depicted
it all the way from enlightenment down to suicidal shame, the logarithm, the emotion that goes with
it, and the process going on in consciousness itself. And as you'll notice, these are all very
destructive down here. Then you become a good deal freer. You begin to transcend, transfigure,
illumination, and reach the states of enlightenment, which are really from 600 and up.
I say the 12-step groups are at about 540. Sainthood is at about 570. Mother Therese,
Sainthood, who's, let's see, who's the 570? Father Pio, various people,
Sainthood, the last Pope was 570. This Pope is 565, which is practically the same range. So,
I have respect for the Pope, and you don't have to be a Catholic to respect the fact that his
commitment is to Christianity as he understands it. Okay. And the Dalai Lama, various people,
uh-huh. And anyway, that's neither here nor there. We'll go on to the next thing. Where's the next,
what'd you say?
.
Where's the next slide? Oh. This is the world's population, the distribution of consciousness
throughout the world. And you see, here's the level of truth to integrity at 200. Everything
below here is false. Everything below 200 is false and destructive. You see that approximately 80
percent of the world's population lives in the destructive realm of consciousness. There are
countries where 100 percent of the people are below 200. Therefore, our diplomatic attempts at
conciliation with serenity, peace, honesty, and truth do not go too far in certain places in the
world because this truth sounds to these people like falsehood. So, there's a flip side. We'll
show in a kind of slide later. This flip side has to do with, actually, with brain physiology. From
200, consciousness level 200, which is commitment to truth and integrity for its own sake, not for
personal gain, uh, people process with a different side of the brain. So, these people here process
primarily with the animal side of the brain. And once the kundalini energy begins to rise, the
consciousness level 200, the kundalini energy begins to rise. Once it does, it shifts your brain
processing to right brain, and you see and experience things differently. So, you see and experience things
differently because the brain physiology processes things differently. And we have a slide on that
later. Therefore, how approximation is going to be brought between civilizations, one processes
things with the animal instinct side of the brain, and this one processes things with the kundalini
energy side of the brain. And how you're going to get an approximation, I have no idea. That's why
we need God. God, we need God.
You know.
He said, you already got help. I said, oh, yes, you got help, cause you gotta solve this conundrum of
how, what you're gonna do about all this. So, the purpose to my life of, to my way of seeing of human
life is that this world is perfect the way it is. I'm not interested in improving the world. Why?
Because the world as it is, is absolutely perfect.
It's designed to be perfect.
is for the advancement of human consciousness and if that is the purpose
of human life, the advancement of consciousness, then this is the perfect
world. What's the karmic merit if you don't have anybody to hate, you know
what I'm saying? Who's there to forgive? All right, so anyway, we'll move on to the next.
So this is the distribution of consciousness levels of mankind and you
see people from 200 and up, which characterizes an audience like this, and
the naivety of these people is they project this onto the world and think
these people are like you. They are not like you. You feel constrained to tell
the truth. In their mind, to tell the truth is idiotic and stupid, can probably
get you killed if not fired or executed, because your duty is to do what brings
gain.
Period. Not truth. Telling the truth will get you executed in a good part of
this living world today. Uh-huh. Contrary. So you've got a 180. So in understanding
the world then, you have to understand that many people think completely the
opposite from which you do. Uh-huh. We consider benevolence a virtue. Half the
world considers benevolence a despicable weakness.
Weakness. Okay. So this helps us understand how to deal with the world and
especially international diplomacy. All right, we'll move to the next one. Uh-huh.
How people see. You see, as a psychiatrist and psychoanalyst, when a patient comes
in, it's not his responsibility to understand where I am. It's my
responsibility to understand where he is. And we're walking around the world
saying, you should understand where we are. No, we should understand where they are.
so we know how to communicate with them, see?
So what we think is a lovely idea,
they think is ridiculous, yeah?
So this is just the way the whole thing balances out.
What you see is that although there's very few people
at the top of the pyramid,
their power is so enormous that they counterbalance
the negativity of the rest of the population.
What you need is a few people, you know,
in a very high level of consciousness
to counterbalance all the negativity of an entire country.
So let's move on to the next.
Calibration level 1,000, for instance, of the great avatar,
1,000 will counterbalance all the negativity
of all of mankind.
All you need is one enlightened teacher on the planet
to counterbalance the total negativity of all of mankind
because it's a logarithmic progression,
and 10 times 10 times 10,
a thousand times is a significant amount of power.
So we'll move to the next one.
Uh-huh.
Let's move back to the last one, yeah.
Oh, this is evolution of consciousness over elapsed time.
And you see it was practically at a standstill
for millions of years, and this is the way it's moving now.
So this is why I thought, well, consciousness is going to go up,
and lately it's been going down a few points,
which we'll have to change the graph and put a squiggle in here.
Squiggle.
Okay, well, move to the next one, then.
Yeah, so this is the evolution of consciousness.
You see, to understand the evolution of the ego,
you understand out of the radiance of divinity,
out of the light of divinity shown forth,
its interaction with matter and organic matter spawned life.
So life emerged.
Okay.
Life emerged as a consequence of the presence of the infinite power of divinity
in its interaction with material world.
That's true.
The light of divinity, when it's shown upon matter,
out of that arose organicity, and out of that arose life.
The most primitive forms of life, of course, animal life, protoplasmic life,
does not have within itself a source of energy,
not a source of energy.
Not a single rabbit, not a single protozoa.
They all have to get energy.
You see, vegetative life has chlorophyll,
and if you're a plant, all you've got to do is sit there.
The sun shines on you, and you get all the energy you need.
You don't have to acquire or get.
If you're protoplasmic, however, you won't live very long unless you get energy.
You have no source of energy.
You have to get it.
To get energy, you have to sample what's out there.
If you're a little amoeba, you have to try this, you have to try that.
You know, a little sip of this, and then .
Over the millennia, life then learned that which is favorable to life and that which is unfavorable.
And if you didn't learn that, you didn't exist.
You don't survive.
Therefore, the ego is constantly that quality of life which samples everything experientially
to discern is it pro-life or anti-life.
So, the kinesiologic response then, if it's over 200, the life energy gets that this is pro-life,
and she goes strong.
If it's anti-life, below 200, the little proto, the little amoeba in her senses that and goes weak.
It says, no, don't eat that.
That's automatized over the millennia in the autonomic nervous system
and in the acupuncture system.
So, if I hold something in mind, I don't even have to tell her what it is.
So, I'm going to hold something in mind.
What I'm holding in mind calibrates over 400, 450, 480, 475.
It's a painting by Degas.
And she doesn't know what I was holding in mind.
You can see that.
A painting by Degas of the ballet dancers, you know, a very entrancing impressionistic painting.
Calibrates at 480.
So, you see how life then evolved over time, calibrated level of life overall.
The first signs of life were then bacteria and algae calibrated at one.
And marine invertebrates, cephalopods, and then we go up to the mammalian life.
Calibrated level of evolution, calibrated level of life over the eons.
We'll go to the next next slide.
So, here you see bacteria.
So, we said, what is the lowest level that we can say life emerges as bacteria?
We'll call that one.
And what's the highest it reaches?
And we found that at 1,000, the great avatars, Jesus Christ, Buddha, Krishna,
Zoroaster, all calibrated at 1,000.
Highest energy of life experientially in this world, therefore, are the great avatars at 1,000.
They represent, therefore,
In this range is the absolute.
Now, there's nothing relativist hate worse than the thought of an absolute.
Because their idea of reality is reality is whatever you think it is, and project out there.
They think that perception is reality.
No.
These numbers are all essence.
Perception is not reality.
Essence is reality.
If anything is only what you think it is, then there is no reality.
And if there's no reality, then there's no reality to their statement, that,
There is no reality.
The way to get rid of deconstructionism is you can deconstruct deconstructionism, because
the premise is that all premises are false, that means the premise is that all things
are false is false, so that's the end of relativism.
No, the absolute, some people have reviewed some of my work somewhere, and he warns the
reader, beware, he's an absolutist.
Autism means responsibility, doesn't it, means yes, you are accountable, yeah, means
your karma is what counts, all right.
So here we go, you see protozoa, crustaceans, insects, amphibians, did anybody see the Blue
Planet the other night?
The Blue Planet reruns on TV, if you haven't seen the Blue Planet, be sure to see it, it's
so stunningly beautiful, and people who don't believe in intelligent design, I tell them,
watch the Blue Planet.
And then call me later.
And tell me if you still don't believe in intelligent design, the exquisite beauty and
the absolute perfection of the evolution of all things at the bottom of the sea, mysterious
and entrancing.
You watch these little things down there, they're incredible beauty, and their ingenuity,
this little diddly light gets you to bite and come over and try and eat me, and then,
I got you, smarts.
Unintelligent life is nowhere to be found.
It killed itself off millennia ago.
There's only intelligent.
All right, arachnids, the fish, you see, the octopus, I love the octopus, they're the smartest
thing around, 20, and you see the Komodo dragon, don't go in the cage with them, and if you
do, always wear your shoes, some idiot went in the cage with a Komodo dragon without his
shoes on.
Well, he lived to tell the tale, God bless him.
Snakes and alligators, and all kinds of wiggly, screamy things, dinosaurs, whales, dolphins,
whales, and all these kind of things, aha.
So down here you see dinosaurs.
Do you know that there are a large percentage of people on the planet that are at this level,
that of the reptile, reptile, there are actually people out there.
These serial killers that kill lots of children, they calibrate at 35, less than a reptile, aha.
Now you notice that life in here has to destroy other life in order to survive.
The polar bears got to pounce on a seal and eat it.
All these animals here, wolves and all these, live by killing others.
And then at level about 200, you see the emergence of the herbivores.
And who do not have to kill anything in order to live, they live on vegetation.
And so here you see a shift from carnivorous predators to benign, the grazers, deer and
domestic pigs and elk, dairy cows, the sheep, range cattle, and now we're getting over 200.
That's very interesting.
Now we're very, very interesting.
You can relate to these animals.
And elephants at 235.
All right.
A kitty is at 240, and a family kitty that's loved is 245.
Dogs at 245.
Then we go up through the monkeys, the gorillas.
Alex, the trained African great parrot, is at 400.
Coco, the trained gorilla, is at 405.
Do you realize you are safer in a cage with Coco than 90% of the people on this planet?
Coco's not out to do you any harm.
He's not trying to sell you anything, isn't going to kill you in the name of peace.
Coco says, either be peaceful or I'll kill you.
Now, the most amazing thing, and we still don't have the answer, is a cat's purr calibrates
at 500, which is the level of love, as does a dog's wagging tail.
They have literally the capacity to love.
That's why when I hear a cat's purr, I'm like, wow.
That's great.
I had a practice, and I would have a depressed patient living alone.
I'd say, I'm not going to treat you unless you get her a cat or a dog.
You need something to think about except your own self all the time.
And the cat's purr at 500 and the dog's wagging tail at 500.
Amazing.
Now, kinesiology is very useful.
We use it all the time because you can know the unknowable.
You can know the unknowable.
Right now, we've got a sick kitty at home.
And so I can find out his medication.
Let's check out kitty at home.
We can check out kitty at home right now.
Right now, he's feeling comfortable.
Resist.
He's got pain, but the medication is handling it.
So we should keep the dose of the medication the same.
Give it to him every other day.
He needs antibiotics right now.
Resist.
Okay.
Do we have them on him?
No.
Okay.
Now that saved a big bill at the veterinarian, didn't it?
I think he might be anemic.
Phil, let me check here.
He has clinical anemia, is this?
Yeah, I knew he would get it.
Yeah.
All right, he's got a bleeding lesion, he's got anemia.
So he's a little cat, but we've got the diagnosis on him.
We know everything we need to know about him.
We know whether he operates, if we raise him on medication, his pain.
So I can know the unknowable.
Okay.
So, many things in your life will become unknowable and now you have a way to instantly know the
truth.
You have to have permission to ask the question.
So, I don't always verbalize it in front of an audience because it's on repetition,
but I ask before I ask it, I have permission to ask this question.
Okay.
No, I don't need it.
I have permission to ask this question.
And occasionally, we will get a no, and in fact, we've gotten no in front of large audiences
and we didn't know the reason for the no and we didn't have time to research it out.
There's probably some things that are better not to know.
Got in his wisdom, keeps us ignorant of certain things, yeah.
We'll move on to the next.
Now the thing that's, okay, this is the relationship between the linear and the nonlinear.
All right.
The linear.
The linear is like science.
It's discernible and it operates according to, or it seems to operate according to Newtonian
principles of cause and effect.
It's definable, identifiable, it's a world of science.
It's the world, the Newtonian world of causality.
However, what the Newtonian world of causality ignored until just recently in quantum mechanics
is that it doesn't exist in a vacuum.
It exists in a field.
Infinite field.
Infinite field of infinite power.
So the only reason the linear works is because of the power of the infinite field of the
nonlinear.
So you take a potentiality all by itself, something that's linear, nothing will happen
unless you, you know, you might say electrify it, put it in an infinite field of power,
and now that which is intention becomes an actuality.
So things come about then.
It's sort of a karmic emergence, karmic too, karmic and karmic, the emergence of potentiality
depending on local conditions.
Therefore your own intention has a very powerful effect.
The less selfish the intention, the greater the likelihood that it will manifest.
If you, to want, crave, desire, and gotta have, tends to block it, tends to block it.
To hold it in mind.
Every place I've lived all the last, well, a lot of years now, well over 50 years, every
place that I've lived, I had only envisioned, I just pictured what I thought, you know,
would really love to have, and it would always just magically appear, where I live now, was
the same thing.
I just held in mind that which would be ideal, and the next thing you know, somebody would
call me and say, you know what, there's a property next door to me and it's for sale,
that's how the place I live now came about.
And back east, I just envisioned a place in the woods and a place in the woods came about.
So what you hold in mind then tends to manifest because there's an infinite field, which
is consciousness, divinity, you might say, the omnipotence of divinity.
The proximate field is what you're holding in mind, proximate field.
And then the content is, let's say, you want a house or a car, a pretty maiden, whatever,
whatever.
We'll move on to the next.
The content then, we say, is the ego, it's linear, it's measurable.
The spiritual ego, here's the nonlinear dynamics and the quantum mechanics, the context is
the spirit, which is nonlinear, unlimited, self-existent, we call it spiritual.
It's demonstrable, we demonstrate it using kinesiology.
Okay, what's the next one now?
I forget what number we're on.
Eighteen.
Eighteen, right?
Let's see.
Where's my magnifying glass?
I don't have a magnifying glass.
How am I going to see what's there?
Well, anyway, things get dimmer as you get older, I don't know, it's just that the universe
does that.
The universe gets dimmer.
It has nothing to do with me.
What number are we at?
Eighteen.
Oh, eighteen.
Okay, so, alright.
Also, somebody's got to keep track of the time.
We'll have to take a break at what time?
Five more minutes.
Oh, my god.
Oh, I better hurry up.
Alright.
Quantum mechanics, because it's important to understand quantum mechanics.
You can't become enlightened without quantum mechanics.
The Schrodinger equations denote the current state of the universe.
Through the Heisenberg principle, you make a choice.
And then you collapse the wave function, and you do it via the von Neumann process, and
then by calculating the Dirac, you can calculate.
So, the potentiality then becomes an actuality via the Heisenberg process.
That was the discovery, that you cannot do the same experiment twice, because merely
witnessing and observing an experiment already changes the outcome, the introduction of consciousness.
So, Stapp is the most advanced physicist in my idea of understanding.
So, as we teach, everything is in a state of potentiality awaiting to be collapsed into
an actuality, collapse the wave function from potentiality into actuality.
Therefore, what you hold in mind tends to manifest.
So, you picture yourself in whatever condition you think would be ideal, and let go of one
of the two.
You want it, desire it, or crave it, and you surrender it to God.
Instead of trying to make it happen, you allow it to happen.
So, spiritual work is not yang, it's yin.
I would say every position that I've advanced through this lifetime has been a yin.
To thee, O Lord, do I surrender my will in the matter, instead of yang.
So, the ego is very yang and very linear.
And it is out there on the field.
The yin, now.
The thing is, as you know from the 91st Psalm, in the statement of Krishna, those who call
upon me are mine, and God cannot refuse you.
God is unable to refuse your legitimate appeal or resist.
Huh.
You ever hear that one before?
No.
So, that which supplicates infinity.
If infinity then is almost, well, it's the wrong word, but obligated, you might say,
to respond.
However, you may get a no, because of your own karmic propensity.
So, on the way down from 13,000 feet, you can undo a lot of negative karma.
And at the end, you probably, that got rid of the last of that negative karma.
All the people you killed all over your lifetimes, you look at the history of mankind and think
how many people you probably killed in previous lifetimes.
Killing others was the way life was, wasn't it?
When the Vikings came over, they didn't capture slaves, they slaughtered them all.
Right.
The Visigoths, the history of mankind is you slaughter your enemies.
Consequently, the karmic inheritance of mankind, then, has to do with you.
Again, has to do with the undoing of a good deal of manslaughter.
If you have permission to ask this, resist.
That is true, oh Lord, resist.
Yeah, the undoing of a good deal of negative karma.
Say to yourself as you break your leg or whatever, well, that gets rid of that negative karma.
That gets rid of that negative karma.
Everything serves the purpose of evolution.
This is a perfect world.
Because to gain karmic merit, you have to have the option of making a mistake and refuse the mistake
and this time choose correctly.
Otherwise, there's no karmic merit, right?
Isn't that correct?
So, in your karmic bank account is going up and going down.
And, of course, so this world is a world that is perfect for the evolution of human consciousness
to go from the lower levels, the linear, the animal instincts, to shift from this side of the brain,
you pray to the Lord.
You're asking for the kundalini energy to rise.
The kundalini energy then rises and as it does, it shifts your whole perception of the world.
The world looks differently.
You all look friendly.
Everybody here is friendly.
If there isn't anybody who's not here and is not friendly, I'll beat them up until they're friendly.
Beat them until they are friendly.
Who is that king that would beat his subjects until they loved him?
I'll beat him until he loves me.
So, we attract to ourselves that which we are.
Also, when we leave the body, where do we go?
We go to that which we already are.
That's it. I have permission to ask that.
That is a fact.
You don't have to worry about it after death because you're only going to go to that which you already are.
You can't go to something different.
We're all like little magnetic filings in a great electrostatic field.
So, you automatically go to that which you are.
So, by free choice, by option, you say yes to this option, like a little piece of iron filing.
Your positive end and you got a negative end.
So, as you choose love like this and you choose hate there, you choose love.
So, like a little iron filing, you can see your spirit is constantly moving, shifting in an infinite field of infinite power.
Which we call God.
Therefore, the justice of God is absolute.
Not arbitrary.
Not a cranky old man who gets mad at you.
The justice of God is automatic.
In an infinite electromagnetic field, there is no injustice.
Every single little filing is exactly where it is based on its polarity.
And as you say yes, oh, heck with it, I'll forgive him.
You move to this side.
You say, son of a bitch, I want to kill that bastard.
And you can see where you are is the consequence of that which you are.
Consequently, there's no point to fear an arbitrary God who's like a nasty old crank.
The God of the Old Testament is, you know, an anthropomorphic weirdo, you know.
So, gets all jealous, upset, has his favorites, plays favorite.
You don't need a God for that.
Your next door neighbor is a...
You know, Freud ridiculed that.
And, of course, I agree with Freud about that myself.
The anthropomorphic understandings of God are in predictions of the child-parent relationship from the unconscious.
Freud then made the mistake, if there's no false God, therefore there's no true God.
So, Freud calibrated 499, genius.
But he didn't get to 500.
And the fact that the false depictions of God are false doesn't mean that the true ones are not true.
So, he jumped beyond the level of logic.
And, of course, I myself was psychoanalyzed.
And my analyst...
Freud was really my great-grandfather.
My analyst was Lionel Oversee, whose analyst was analyzed by Freud.
So, Freud's my great-grandfather.
I had a Freudian analysis.
I was very young then.
And then I saw Harry Thiebaud, who was the foremost psychoanalyst in analyzing the ego and the unconscious.
And you just brought in dreams.
And so, I had about three different kinds of psychoanalysis.
And then spent the next 50 years listening to some 25,000 people.
25,000 people from a psychiatric, psychoanalytic, psychological viewpoint and treating that many.
And the way I'm describing things is a composite of that totality of experience.
Psychoanalytic.
I also had experiences, which I've written about in books, which were unusual, starting at age three.
Have I got enough time for that?
Yes or no?
I'll just do a brief one, and then we'll have a quick break.
But this lifetime was unusual.
Statistically, I guess.
Anyway, there was absolute oblivion until age three.
Age three, out of oblivion, out of the oblivion of nothingness, suddenly there occurred, with a terrible shock, the awareness of existence.
From nothingness to existence.
It was a terrible shock.
A severe shock.
I still haven't gotten over it.
Every once in a while, I rediscover that I exist, and it comes back as a shock again.
Because in many lifetimes, I was a Hinayana Buddhist.
I negated the linear, and I would go into the void, and I would leave that lifetime in the void.
So anyway, at age three, suddenly I came into the awareness of existence.
Existence versus nonexistence was the puzzle and the conundrum of this entire lifetime.
I was not pleased to discover I exist.
A three-year-old body.
Not only did you exist, but a body went with it.
A three-year-old body sitting in a wagon.
This is all nonverbal.
Just a stunning awareness of existence as existence.
Then came, as soon as you realize you exist, up comes the fear of nonexistence.
Instantly.
If you identify with existence as a reality, you instantly are stuck with the fear of nonexistence.
So at age three, there I was, stuck with the conundrum of, is the infinite reality existence or nonexistence?
You don't solve that one until consciousness level 850.
It took some 30 years to solve that one.
Anyway.
What was I telling you this for?
I forget.
What was I going to tell him?
Anyway.
I was brought up very, very religious.
Episcopal, high Episcopal.
My great-grandfather was an Episcopal bishop.
We were very religious.
And I was very religious.
In fact, I suffered from scrupulosity.
I worried about having a sin all the time.
. . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .
I thought the soul was like a big blank screen, and if you sinned, it blotched up there,
somebody threw an egg on it, and God would see this sin on your soul.
So I was scared to death of having a sin that God was going to see, you know what I'm saying?
God's looking at your soul, and here you got all these black spots on your soul.
So if I had any kind of a negative thought, I really had a fit about it.
I had to go for counseling about it.
. . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .
I lived in fear of sin.
I was an acolyte in church, you know, and I was an acolyte for the church.
church, you know, and I was an acolyte for the bishop. And I was a boy soprano, an excellent
boy soprano, stunningly good boy soprano. Well, you can say that when you're objective
about yourself. And I sang in the Greek choir, and I was the boy soloist. And when I sang
the soprano obbligato above a full choir, paunus angelicus, with a full choir, a full
orchestra, and a full organ, it was entrancing. It was entrancing to the witness because while
people presume I'm a me, I'm not a me, I'm the witness. And so, I remember witnessing
the voice coming out. It was as though an angelic being sang through the voice. The
audience went into tears, and I don't know how I continued to sing, but I did so. I never
asked this before.
I've got permission to ask this. That was indeed an angelic being. So, yes, an angelic
voice. It's a stunning beauty. Later on, I joined the Great Lakes Naval Choir. In World
War II, I signed up for the Navy. I forget how I became an atheist. Somehow or other.
Yeah.
So, then, about age 13.
In the way out in the sticks of Wisconsin. I had the longest paper route in Wisconsin,
and 18 miles every day, 10 below zero on the bicycle. And in a very high storm one day,
a very high storm. It was 10 below zero. I mean, it was ferocious. All my papers are
blown away, and it's pitch black out. There isn't any light of a farmhouse for miles ahead
yet. And to get out of this cold, I dug a hole in the snow. Well, the banks in the Wisconsin
highways are probably 15 feet high by the end of the day. And I was in the middle of
the snow. I was in the middle of the snow. I was in the middle of the snow. I was in
the winter, around late winter. So, I broke through the crust of the snow, and I made
a little cave, and I climbed into the cave to get out of the wind, get of the wind.
And as soon as I got out of the wind, all of a sudden a state of infinite presence.
Everything became silent beyond all time. That which I am existed before all time, before
all worlds, and will exist beyond all
all worlds. That which I am was before all worlds resist and will be after all worlds
resist. That knowingness of foreverness. And I understood then, not intellectually, but
the experience of timelessness. That which has no beginning has no ending. The sense
of love was overwhelming. It's an infinite presence of the Self with a capital S. People
say, how do I know I'm enlightened? Because the presence wipes out everything. There's
no thought, there's nothing. There's only in that which you are, is that, is not different
than what you are. That moment, all fear of death disappeared forever, which was handy
in World War II, when you're about to get blown up. About to get blown up. Yes?
We'll, we'll quit with the World War II. Yeah. You're about to get blown up any second.
So I can remember, here's this mine right there, and these big things are sticking off
this mine, and it's about to bump against the ship. And this, this guy's supposed to
help me. We're supposed to keep this mine from hitting the ship, because they're all
going to blow up. He says, so, what if it blows up? I said, well, then we die. He said,
oh, you're right. And that was the end of the fear.
Total acceptance of death, then. Now, as if you want to evolve rapidly, handle death
right in the beginning. Don't leave it to the end. You decide I'll wait until I'm 85,
and then I'll face that one. Do it right now. Because underneath all the negative feelings
you see from consciousness level below 200, underneath all of them is death. So if you
start with death, if I'm not successful, then what? Then I'll be poor. And if you're poor,
then what? Then I won't be able to afford what I need. Yes. And then what? And then
I'll be poor. And if you're poor, then what? Then I won't be able to afford what I need.
I will die. You'll find that every one of them ends up, and then I'll die. So start
by dying and get that over with. How many people here have been out of body? Yep, great.
Near death experiences. Yep, very good. All right, so people who have near death experiences
or out of body experiences are better prepared to die because you've experienced that you
are, even though the body's laying there. In fact, it's odd. When you're out of the
body, the body looks totally uninteresting. It looks really stupid, and you have to get
back in it because you're not karmically free to go yet. But I can remember looking at it
and thinking, man, that is really not too attractive. I went back in it upside down,
looked at the floor through the back of my skull, had to pull myself out of the body
and re-dock.
So that's a good place that we're going to take a break. I was telling you my sad tale
of, let's see, where was I? World War II, I think. Anyway, I was very, as I say, spiritually
oriented. And one day, the war was over, one day walking around in the woods thinking of
nothing at all, not thinking of anything. All of a sudden, out of nowhere, came an infinite
knowingness of infinite dimension of the totality of the suffering of all of mankind
since the beginning, since the beginning. The totality of the suffering of all of mankind
was like a presentation, a knowingness that came upon me. It was so overwhelming. I thought,
any God who could allow this, I want nothing to do with, and I became an atheist. From
an intensely religious point of view, I became an atheist. I became an atheist. I became
a person, I became a devoted atheist. Any God who could allow that quantity of suffering
was no God in my book. And I rejected God and I became an atheist. So, that time I was
going to a Jesuit university and I got straight A in everything. I didn't believe a word of
it. I got a straight A in the subject, you know. Why? Because if you're going to argue
against something, you better know a great deal about it. The critics of my own work,
I have that feeling. They don't know anything about it, so what they say is babbling, but
anyway, you've got to understand everything about it. So, I got straight A in all those
things. But there had to be some inner essence of truth, and therefore, I devoted myself
to the search for the essence of truth without God. I studied Buddhism and all kinds of things.
I belonged to the first Zen Institute in New York. Actually, I finally became a consultant
to
all kinds of religious orders, Catholic orders, Protestant, Episcopal Diocese, and the Zen
Monastery upstate New York, because I had, by that time, some rather profound experiences.
And I could discern whether the person was in a catatonic state or a Samadhi. I forgot
how it all went. But in the search for truth then became an obsession. And if the essence
of truth wasn't God, then what was it?
And so, I went to the very core of the source of consciousness itself. The exploration took
me through really Dante's inferno. It eventually took me to the levels of hell. And the levels
of hell are far beyond that which can be imagined, far more dreadful, far more worse. You enter
finally a realm, and Dante understood it. I don't know how Dante knew it. There's a
level of hell that you can't really imagine. You enter a realm, and you have to take it.
There's a level of hell that you can't really imagine. There's a level of hell that you can't
of hell where abandon all hope you enter here because you then enter a state of
timelessness so you were like damned you were cut off into hopelessness and
despair forever and you get what forever means and that is when hell really
starts cut off forever from love from God from salvation in a state of
spiritual agony from which there is no release ever so timelessness just as in
the highest states you're beyond all time in the lowest state you again go
back into timelessness which is beyond all description eternal agony in the
depth of eternal agony
the atheist said if there is a God I ask him for help and then I was hit by like
a bolt of lightning all that it ever had been disappeared and instead what shone
forth was the glory divinity as existence itself the whole world became
radiant with exquisite beauty to which it has remained except you get
used to it because otherwise you can't function and I'm having difficulty
functioning this morning because of the state is very close again so glad you
did there help out a little bit here okay thank you the infinite states are
so past the void which is consciousness level 850 oh I know I was going to say
that the way you get to the
void which I kept going out of previous lifetimes in the void because I follow
the pathway of negation pathway of negation will eventually take you to the
void at level 850 is nothingness as the ultimate reality it is so impressive so
awesome that you are sure that this is the state of enlightenment itself
Huang Po made the same mistake and
but having been in the infinite presence in the snowbank I realized that
nothingness was devoid of something incredibly essential and therefore I
refused the void this time because the infinite reality is the overwhelming
presence of an infinite love so the nothingness of the void you reject its
reality when you get to nothingness
reject the nothingness because divinity is allness infinite love and the owning
of that takes you past the 850 and Huang Po made the same mistake when he
wrote it calibrates at 850 the path to the occlusion. Huang Po after writing that
discovered his error so before he died he went to 960 I'm happy to say for Huang
Po
Anyway, that's neither here nor there, so where were we on the slides?
After that everything, oh yes, after that everything happens autonomously and you realize
the narcissistic, the idea that there's a separate you that's a causal agent is the
delusion that one overcomes to reach enlightenment.
There is no you that is making decisions and causing things to happen.
Everything is happening autonomously of its own.
Everything is continuously.
Potentiality is constantly emerging.
There's no me that decided, oh, I think I'll put my arm up in the air to make that point.
It had already happened before I noticed it was there.
If you get, it's a one ten-thousandth of a second jump that you have to get on the ego.
The experiencer aspect of the ego instantly takes credit.
It says, ah, there was an I that made that decision.
There is no I that makes that decision.
Let's see.
What I just said is the truth, oh Lord, resist.
What I just said is the truth, oh Lord.
I don't swear by the Lord unless it's the absolute truth.
There is no personal self that's making all the decisions over which you agonize.
All of it is happening autonomously, autonomously.
The consequent of that which you are interacts with potentiality.
And out comes the decision.
I can be as free as I want.
I can do what I want.
And if you don't like it, then how do you like that?
Did anybody decide to say that?
No.
Because the states of spiritual awareness, people forget to go through joy, ecstasy.
In fact, they can become paralyzing.
States of extreme ecstasy can become paralyzing.
Mm-hmm.
Paralyzed, you're tireless.
You can dance for hours and hours.
You can dance tirelessly.
You can dance around the clock.
You never go to the bathroom.
You don't need a drink of water, water, nothing.
You just go into a state.
Yep.
Ramakrishna experienced such ecstatic states.
They calibrate around 580, 590, around in there.
So you go into all these states of consciousness, and if you've heard about them before, it's
helpful because you don't feel strange, you don't feel like something is unusual or there's
something wrong.
You say, oh, that's right.
It's okay.
It's okay for that to be what it is.
So we'll go back to the academics.
I thought I'd just make a few personal remarks to break up the monotony here.
As I said, no.
Yeah.
I mean, the Kundalini energy is an actual spiritual energy.
People below 200, you realize, have sort of a group karma.
And it's only from 200 and up that you develop an etheric body, an etheric brain.
That seems unfair.
You only develop an etheric brain when consciousness level 200 exists.
Below 200, people don't have an etheric brain yet.
So you want them to understand spiritual concepts.
When they don't have the equipment, you can't understand that goodwill is more important
than killing and getting even.
It doesn't make any sense until you get to level 200, and then you say, oh yes, that's
obvious, that's obvious.
It's not obvious below 200.
Anybody who gives up their life for another is stupid below 200, you see.
All right, so, below consciousness level 200, left brain dominance, you're living in
a linear world, fight or flight, the alarm reaction, the thymus gland, the acupuncture
meridians, everything is now controlled by the left brain.
You notice in the left brain, animal world, people below 200.
Here's the input.
The relay is very fast to the emotional center, the thalamus, very fast to the emotional
center.
The amygdala, the hippocampus, your memory.
So your memory is of a fearful, frightening, angry, embarrassing.
It's a negative viewpoint of the world.
From 200 down, hate, anger, greed, selfishness, jealousy, envy, dominate.
So this is the world of the animal pack, and if you watch international political maneuverings,
it's no different at all than a wolf pack.
Alpha male, jostling for alpha male, constantly pushing for more territory.
You urinate on all these bushes over here, and once you're there, come over.
And if you do, oh, so you see that primarily the world lives on an animal level.
More and more dominance of more and more territory, so you're the alpha male, and you can have
all the alpha females, and if you're lucky, you can do this for eternity.
Boy, how boring it is.
Imagine that heaven where all you do is fornicate all day.
I mean, century after century, you say, God, how am I going to have to keep fornicating?
I'm tired of beautiful females, so I have to keep doing it.
Well, you wanted to do it, man, so, I mean, you know, hysterical.
Life is one eternal orgasm, isn't that hysterical?
Over 200, you give up eternal orgasm.
It's a fantasy.
What happened to our...
God's either pleased or not pleased, I don't know what it was.
Oh, he's pleased, okay.
The kundalini begins to follow up the chakra system, you see?
Now right brain dominance, now context, the nonlinear domain, meaning and significance.
Your brain puts out endorphins instead of adrenaline, positive emotions, the thymus
gland, increased killer cells, so you're less prone to diseases.
Increased blood pressure.
Increased healing, balancing the acupuncture system.
And the track to the emotions is now slowed down.
So the more enlightened person, 200 and up, you get a fast track through the etheric brain,
which is the capacity to see the essence of a thing, very fast, through the emotional
center, and your memory is of a very wonderful and positive experience.
Yeah?
I experienced this audience, it was very wonderful and positive, you know, period.
Experience.
That's because I see the essence of things.
So obviously, an audience like this calibrates over 200, so I pick up the positive essence
of this audience, and you feel happy and content because you're surrounded by that which is
safety and loving, supportive, you know?
All right, so we'll move on.
I just wanted to point out that there's an actual physiologic difference.
Now, the rates of enlightenment...
Or happiness, let's say.
If we start at the bottom, calibrated at level 20, the number...
The percent of people who are happy at these various consciousness levels.
So happiness is not a consequence of the world and what you have in the world and what you
do in the world.
Happiness is a consequence of that which you have become.
If you have become this, then the likelihood of happiness is close to 70%.
Happiness, then, is not a socio-economic class or political trauma.
It's a consequence of that which you have become.
When you become the fulfillment of your potential, you're happy no matter what.
You're happy no matter what.
So at this low level, these are criminal populations here, criminal populations.
You see, at log 20, only 1% of people are happy.
I'm sorry.
People who live in the world of guilt and penance, you see, at consciousness level 30,
4% are happy.
Sackcloth and ashes was the sort of medieval way to God through Christianity.
Oh, God, forgive me my evil and guilt.
And you kneel and crawl on your knees all the way to the cathedral, beating on yourself.
I mean, you know, that's real narcissism, isn't it?
.
That's real drama.
Oh, God, I am such a sinner.
Give me a break, will you?
Wallowing in guilt and penance is sort of a medieval.
Medieval.
And it's one of the reasons I gave up Christianity when I became an atheist.
I couldn't see wallowing in guilt and penance.
I mean, you know, if man can't tell truth from falsehood, I mean, whatever happened
in the Garden of Eden, I mean, I don't have anything to do with it.
I mean, I don't have anything to do with it.
You know, I don't know.
I don't know.
You know, if man can't tell truth from falsehood, I mean, whatever happened in the
Garden, you know, of Eden, I mean, I don't have anything to do with it.
You know what I'm saying?
My toy, you know what I'm saying?
The serpent took advantage of the fact that the human mind, unaided, is unable to discern
truth from falsehood.
Unaided.
The human mind, by virtue of its structure.
cannot tell appearance from essence. Socrates said it. All men choose only the good. A lot
of times we feel guilty because we find it difficult to forgive somebody. See? Christ
said forgive them all, they know not what they do, etc. The Buddha said the only difficulty
with everyone is ignorance. So you remind yourself of that profound innate ignorance.
That's built into the ego structure as it evolved. The ego is unable to discern appearance
from essence. It's only consciousness level 600, the opening of the third eye of the Buddhic
body, the third body, that one discerns essence rather than appearance. So the value of consciousness
calibration is you can accomplish what the human mind cannot do. The human mind looks
at a thing, it doesn't know whether that's gold or fool's gold. Instantly with kinesiology
you know what it is. So it bypasses. All right.
All right.
Only 5% say they're happy. Those who live in fear, 10%. Those who are angry,
only 12% of those people are happy. And they're probably retarded or something, but anyway.
Pride at least makes sense. Log 175, 22%. That makes sense, you know. At least you're
happy that you're better than other people and all that. Everybody secretly believes
that their view of reality is correct and everybody else's is wrong.
Don't we all?
All in favor of I'm right and everybody else is wrong.
Yay, good.
You can't get rid of the ego unless you own it.
Yes, the narcissistic core of the ego.
It just loves being right.
And it's willing to be right even if it costs you your life.
Yes.
When you get beyond pride.
So we know that pride is where so many things fall.
It's where all the great dictators, if they aren't crazy,
before they get there, they're crazy after they get there.
Because of the pride, the narcissistic ego just goes crazy.
All right, at 200 is the capacity to tell the truth.
That's the first in the 12-step groups.
That's step one.
We admitted we were powerless over something.
What? Admitted you were powerless over?
Wow, what an affront to the ego.
The ego isn't going to admit it's powerless.
It's going to admit it's powerless over anything.
It's going to control it and make it different this time.
At 200, then you enter the world of honesty.
At level 200, 55% of people are happy.
And neutrality, you move beyond courage.
Neutrality is it's okay if it happens this way and it's okay if it happens that way.
If I get the job, it's great.
And if I don't, I'll get another job.
So neutral is very comfortable.
It's fun being with neutral people because they're easygoing.
And 60% of them are happy.
Uh-huh.
The other 40% have bad spouses or something.
I don't know.
There's some defect in this.
Because if you're really at neutral, you'd be happy under any circumstance.
So we'll have to reexamine that.
I've been in neutral and it's okay, you know.
You know, like I say, a bomb is about to go off.
The mine is about to explode.
And it goes off, it goes off.
So if it doesn't, it doesn't.
So what's the big deal?
Either die or you don't.
So willingness is a positive attitude at 310, but 68% of the people,
these are the people that help make the world, they're humanitarians.
They sign up for all kinds of help things, clean up Katrina after Katrina,
all these kind of things.
Acceptance is the beginning of the only owning of your power at 350, 71%.
Reason is the world of the world.
It's the world of the intellect.
We didn't do the great books of the Western world, did we?
Well, we'll have to do them.
Reason now is the beginning of the advances of Western civilization as we understand it,
is the level of the 400s.
The great books of the Western world are at the 400s.
On the slide, see if you can find the great books of the Western world.
And we'll just flick to it later on.
Anyway, it's the intellectual backbone.
It's the intellectual backbone.
It's the intellectual backbone of Western civilization begins with Plato, Aristotle.
To my viewpoint, the highest evolution of human civilization was around 350 BC,
and it's been downhill ever since, frankly.
To forgive everybody is easy if you accept Socrates' wisdom.
Everyone chooses only the good, you know, what they think to be the good.
So, everyone is only choosing what they...
So, you see the innocence that they think that will bring them fame and happiness and,
you know, whatever they do, which is outrageous on television.
But if, you know...
So, anyway, neutrality, it's okay if it goes this way.
Willingness is joining in, and acceptance is even higher.
And reason is the intellect, and this is the bulwark of the Western world.
The 400s then takes you through the great books.
The great books of the Western world.
In all the ones that I studied, it used to be in college,
you studied the great books of the Western world.
That was a liberal education.
Nowadays, they avoid anything that's in the 400s.
They stick to 190 or something.
Yeah, relativism coverage is about 190.
So, where were we on the chart?
Oh, there they are.
Oh, yeah.
So, there's all...
These are all the friends of my childhood.
They were my friends, you know,
because that was a small ectomorph,
and the coach wouldn't allow me on the field.
He said, your bones are going to get all broken.
The doctor wouldn't give an okay.
So, I read, you know.
So, I was skinny with thick glasses
and sat in a big chair and read books.
So, these are all my pals from childhood,
and when I get back on the other side,
I'm looking forward to hanging out with them again.
Socrates and Plato and all the folks.
So, anyway, these are the great books of the rest of the world.
Aristophanes, Aristotle, 498.
Augustine, Marcus Aurelius.
The aphorisms of Marcus Aurelius.
That's what I'm reading as a child,
the aphorisms of Marcus Aurelius.
But then normal childhood, you know,
I kind of think of it, yeah.
Descartes, of course, is brilliant
because he pointed out the difference
between res interna and res externa.
The world as you see it
as compared to the world as you see it,
as compared to the world the way it is.
Yeah.
To go beyond appearance, which is illusion,
to reality, which is essence.
And until we had consciousness calibration,
there was frankly no way to do that.
There was no way you could tell the essence of a thing.
All you had was the appearance.
So, Descartes.
What was it?
I forgot what I put this up for.
These are, and Hegel's, of course,
The Absolute,
which the relatives,
both of us have warned you about,
is 499.
Einstein was 499.
Freud, 499.
Carl Jung was at 520.
Okay, so this is the world Newtonian physics.
Plato at 485.
And you see all the great minds of history.
The great minds of history.
Now the last book,
the last book was on Freud.
The last book,
these were collected by
the University of Chicago.
And there's only two things that stand out.
Karl Marx.
See, they're all about 440, 460.
Karl Marx doesn't belong in here.
He's only, well, he's at 130.
Engels just makes it at 200.
But he's on Marx's coattails.
But all this you can see is wrong,
has been wrong with,
relativism really is a variation of Marxism.
So to drop from 450 to 130,
if you establish Marxism as a,
as a cultural reality,
you end up as Mayo did in China
with 30 million people starving to death.
30 million people starving to death.
In North Korea,
tens of millions starve to death.
So Marxism hasn't worked out.
It leads to the masses starving to death.
But he was important politically.
That's why he's put in
the great books of the Western world.
So we'll go back to the slides
of what we were doing.
Here you see reason,
a reasonable person,
reasonable person,
has an 80% chance.
Love at 500,
only 89% are happy.
I don't know what's the matter with them.
What more than love do you want?
I don't know what's the matter with those people.
We'll have to examine some of these people,
holdbacks here.
They're peculiar.
Maybe they're not all there or something.
I don't know.
At 540,
love becomes unconditional.
The 12-step groups calibrate at 540.
540.
Therefore,
one of the great ways to God
is through the 12-step programs,
of course,
the miracles,
other things,
other than,
because not everybody finds religion,
you know,
acceptable.
So they say,
well,
how can I,
you know,
transcend and get somewhere
without going to church
and being a religionist?
The 12-step groups.
Unconditional love means
forgiving people
no matter what.
And you can't forgive them
if you don't love them.
You can't forgive them
no matter what
unless you accept
Socrates'
understanding
that all people
only choose
what they concern
to be the good.
So now you realize
it's easy to forgive them
because what is ignorance?
Ignorance is just not knowing,
knowing essence
from appearance
for which we forgive people.
Why do we forgive them?
Because we see
from the evolution
of consciousness
that many people
have not evolved
to the capacity
where they could see
the essence of a thing.
Therefore,
you forgive them
because you realize
they haven't evolved
to that point yet.
For the same reason
we don't hate a kid
with a low IQ
because he doesn't
get straight A's.
So love becomes
unconditional
at 540,
at 570,
at sainthood.
570,
all the saints
calibrate at 570.
As I say,
the current pope
is practically
at 570
and the Buddhist fellow,
whatever his name is,
I forget.
Anyway,
I understand him
because he laughs
all the time.
The Dalai Lama.
The Dalai Lama,
yeah.
There's somebody
I was talking to,
some famous person
on the phone
and I was laughing
all the time
and she was annoyed.
Anyway,
she doesn't understand
why I'm laughing
all the time.
I said,
well,
the same reason
the Dalai Lama
laughs all the time
because life
is a constant
hysterical comedy.
Even as the
headsman's coming over,
it's a comedy
because you realize
the whole thing
is an absurd drama.
You're laughing
all the time.
Now,
peace is at 600.
this is the peace
of God.
600 is the
peace of God
and 600
is the beginning
of the levels
of enlightenment.
At 600,
you can't really
function.
You can't really
do anything
at 600
because
it's non-linear,
it's eternal,
it's forever
and from 600
on up,
you can leave
the world
anytime you like
and it's invitational.
At 600,
you realize
that you
are not
that
and the state
of bliss
is
blissful.
It's not necessary
to continue on.
So,
and if these states
hit you,
you can get
an okay
to leave
at any time.
If you're driving
down the highway,
it's sort of
what to do about it.
You know,
well,
should I pull over
or not pull over?
I guess I better pull over.
I'm trying to enjoy
the light of it,
you know.
And there are
very few people
at those higher levels.
The reason is
for,
at 600
you can leave
and
50%
that are
at level 600
will leave.
You have the option
to leave.
Each level,
as you advance,
again,
you have a 50%
chance to leave.
At 850,
you have it,
you can leave,
you can leave
and finally,
there's hardly anyone
left on the planet
Not because it's a rare, but because everyone leaves.
I hate to tell you, but everybody, you realize you don't have to continue on.
Some people, by virtue of some prior commitment and agreement, return to the world and function again.
Usually as teachers, and that's their agreement.
The karmic fulfillment of that potentiality.
To share what you have become with others.
And by sharing that, what you have become with others, they become their own potential.
It's to facilitate other people becoming their own potential.
It's the reason to choose to continue on.
And that makes it all worth it.
Oh, Lord, thank you.
Oh, spiritual practice and daily life.
People say, how can I get more involved?
Goodwill towards all.
All of life, no matter what.
Don't forget, when the headsman comes to you, worry about how he's feeling.
Don't feel guilty.
It's okay.
You're doing your job.
I'm counting on you.
And tip him.
I always tip the headsman.
Goodwill towards all of life.
You see?
All right.
Spiritual practice and daily life.
You don't have to isolate yourself or discontinue.
And don't compartmentalize your life.
Become your own spiritual practice.
You know, when I give sermons someplace, I always say, you know, become the prayer.
Become that.
Don't practice that.
Don't think that.
Don't memorize that.
Be that.
You know?
So the practice is education.
And the choice of teachers.
Calibrate.
Always calibrate the teachers and calibrate the pathway.
In your daily routine, you include contemplation as a way of being in the world.
So when I say turn your life into a prayer,
you become that which is supportive of all of life and can see what the limitations of life are.
And therefore, you tend to uplift life by virtue of that which you have become.
And meditation and contemplation become part of your life as does prayer.
Contemplation to me is a way of being in the world.
You see, meditation has its place.
But, and I spent many years meditating, but meditation tends to take you out of the world.
You can't function in today's world and spend all your time meditating.
I did it when I came out to wherever we are here.
And it didn't do anything.
I just stayed in that beatific state, you know, for, you know, just stayed there.
But you can't function in the world.
So being contemplative then is, I compare it to sort
of Yin position.
Contemplative means, you see, Yang is very this.
God, I got to have this, and I'm going to do that.
And it's very Yang.
A contemplative way of being in the world is a Yin posture.
Psychically you have become that which is open.
And by virtue of that which is open, your Yin side of you summons forth
that which you need.
You go to bed with a question on your mind
and you wake up and the answer is there.
Not through any doingness.
By virtue of that which you become,
your life becomes a supplication.
To thee, O Lord, do I surrender my will in the matter.
And you ask that the Lord reveal to you.
So you're asking so life becomes a continuous revelation
which eventually becomes the continuous miraculous.
Yeah.
All right.
So prayer then.
Dedication.
The other thing you begin to notice
is the incredible beauty and perfection of all that exists.
At first this sort of knocks you out
and it's very difficult to function.
Everywhere you go, the beauty is overwhelming.
I can remember being in an airport
and there's a couple of millions looked at each other
and I,
in the glance, you could see the love.
The presence of the love just knocked me out.
I don't know how I got onto the plane.
I was just, it was just,
you're just blissed out by the incredible beauty
of all that exists.
As you walk through nature, you'll see the perfection.
When you see the incredible beauty of weeds,
they stop being weeds.
When you walk by a weed and you look at it
and you see its incredible perfection,
there it stands there like the most magnificent sculpture.
You begin to see everything is like a magnificent sculpture.
Every weed stands there displaying its incredible perfection and beauty
and now you become conscious and you're witness
to the incredible perfection and beauty of all of creation.
Because creation is God manifest, the Godhead through creation.
So you see that creation is ongoing and forever.
There is no linear God with a beginning and an ending.
And the beginning was so-and-so.
That's a way of writing it up.
That which has no beginning has no ending.
Therefore, it has no cause.
So you live in a universe which is beyond causality.
And you see that everything is unfolding.
Its potentiality is actualizing by virtue of the infinite power of divinity,
which is the ultimate context.
The infinite power of divinity is an all-encompassing field of infinite power.
Out of which potentiality arises into actuality through emergence.
Through emergence.
Therefore, the potentiality of the human spirit,
the eventuality of it is inevitable.
You don't have to worry about spiritual evolution.
It's inevitable.
You have to work hard to avoid it.
Because the potentiality is within you and therefore,
in the infinite presence of divinity,
which is the source of all existence,
that which you can become,
that potentiality begins to manifest as an actuality.
Therefore, you watch the focus on the beauty of all things
and you note the perfection of all that exists.
You watch the unfoldment.
So there's no longer causality.
There's the unfoldment.
The willingness to surrender all these negativities.
The willingness to accept God's will.
The choices, situations, the ego and its problem.
You know, instead of being mad at the ego.
So now we have a new way of seeing the ego.
The ego is the leftover of the evolution of the protoplasm as the mammalian species.
It was necessary for survival.
It was what you owe your survival to.
Without the ego, you wouldn't be here to complain about your ego.
I say, thank you, ego, for getting me to the point that I can transcend, you know.
Get off the bus,
and get on a different kind of a vehicle.
But without the bus, you wouldn't get there.
So God's willing to accept all these assets, the ego and its problems.
So instead of making the ego your enemy,
you own it as though it's a pet.
It's your little pet, left over from prehistoric times.
Of course, you hate other people.
Of course, you want to be dominant.
Of course, you want to be greedy and eat it all up.
Of course, you want to copulate around the clock.
I mean, you know.
Is that your animal side?
You eventually accept God's infinite love and mercy.
And, all right, we'll go to the next one.
I forget which is the last chart.
Got to watch the time.
How much more time we got?
Oh, okay.
All right.
Oh, these are practices to move you ahead in your level of consciousness.
The more, the farther ahead you are in your level of consciousness, the more of what you hold in mind tends to materialize.
You have to be careful what you hold in mind because it's there, right there.
Oh, choose holy company.
That's why, you know, avoid that which is obviously dedicated.
Why?
Because of their energy.
It's really just because of their energy.
Yeah, practice Socrates' view.
See others as being programmed.
They can't help being what they are because they've been programmed.
You know, the media program.
Everybody all the time.
I hate to give you the statistics on it.
I'm working on a book called Spiritual Reality in Modern Man.
It's depressing.
I wish I'd never started that book.
I think when I knew less, I was happier.
I mean, you calibrate the most, you know, popular shows on television.
You finally calibrate 160.
160.
Narcissism, cruelty, sexuality, seduction, 160.
See others as programmed.
You make a commitment, visualize your goal of loving this towards all of life and being grateful for what you have and be satisfied with where you're at.
Now, your mind tends to, the more often you choose a certain thing, the more likely you're going to choose that again.
That's called quantum Zeno effect.
The quantum Zeno effect is out of randomness.
The more often you choose this, the more often you choose that.
Although the next time is potentially random, the more likely you will choose this, the more likely.
That's called the tension set.
So by declaration of spiritual intention and choosing constantly the good as you come to understand it, the likelihood is that you will choose it again.
So free will, of which there's all kinds of sophomoric argumentation, is a dominance of likelihoods, the attractor field that you have assigned to.
There's a greater.
Greater.
Likelihood that you will choose to forgive the person.
So even if you're angry and see them as wrong, you won't be satisfied with that.
You say, you know, he's a SOB.
He deserves what he gets.
Then in the bed, you think, but yeah, but the next day you so you meditate on it and you play with it.
And now you're not satisfied that you hate the guy or you fear the person, et cetera.
You're not satisfied.
Not because you have spiritual goals and you say, so you ask for a miracle.
You say, dear Lord, I'd like to see this differently.
And maybe nothing will happen at all.
Nelson, you're driving down the highway a month later and all of a sudden you got a totally different way of seeing it out of nowhere.
Oh, I can see now differently.
What else could he do?
All he could do is hate you and kill you.
I mean, what else could he do?
And then you forgive people for killing you.
Look how the times you've been killed.
You don't remember all those lifetimes, but even killed a lot, folks.
I can't kill.
Killed is one of the ways we usually ended it.
We got killed.
You end up with benevolence and mindfulness means paying attention to that mindset.
You're willing to surrender narcissism, the wonderful me.
You see how spiritual growth is not concordant with the current media world of you as the wonderful me.
You know, Time Magazine had one.
I thought Time Magazine cover was brilliant.
It was a stroke of genius, the mirror on the front of Time Magazine.
The ultimate, we are the ultimate of the narcissistic, me, self-indulgent.
Let's do it around the clock.
Me, wonderful me.
And my spot, my, you know, the blogs are now 90% of blogs are fallacious, you know, 90%.
All right.
So willing to surrender all the adrenaline.
The victimhood, the hurt feelings, look at the injustice collectors, willing to stop needing to win, and most importantly, to be right.
Now, to be right is one of the addictions that is very hard to get off.
To be right is so important, we're willing to die for it, and we're willing to kill you if you think you're right.
If you think you're right, you've just bought yourself a death sentence.
It's so important.
It's more important to be right.
And, of course, you watch the evening news channel, whatever they are, and you get over seeing yourself as the causal, primary causal agent.
You see yourself as only a part of a process in which your potentiality is actualizing because of the agreement of your own will.
If you decided against it with your will, then you've just shut off those options, but you've also shut off the karmic benefit of those options.
Forgiveness of self and others.
Selfless service, those are the great yogas, and, oh, I didn't tell you how to get off the mind.
We'll do that before we quit.
I know, we've got just time to kill the mind while we're here.
The mind is your biggest aggravation, and the classic spiritual writings are that enlightenment is between two thoughts.
That's a mistranslation of the Buddha, he never said such a thing.
Anyway, the people who listen to him, that's as far as they got it.
It was a ballpark.
No, the infinite is prior to thoughts.
It's below thoughts.
You cannot get between two thoughts.
Thoughts occur in one-tenth-thousandth of a second.
By the time you notice, by the time your perceiver perceives that, that one-tenth-thousandth is already gone.
The minute you begin to notice it, it's over already.
You cannot catch your own tail.
That's why enlightenment is very rare.
You practically never have it.
Never, never.
In a whole century, maybe, one or two.
If you're looking for enlightenment between two thoughts, you'll never find it.
No.
The enlightenment is the nothingness, the potentiality, which is underneath your thoughts.
Your mind is actually still and silent.
Ninety-nine percent of your mind is still and silent.
One percent is busy thinking and talking.
And you pay attention to the one percent and think that's your mind.
I'll tell you right now where to find it.
Go away.
It's right now.
There is an infinite field of silence below your thoughts.
It's not prior.
It's not between.
It's underneath your thoughts.
All the thinkingness and mentalization is coming out of an infinite, silent field.
Then the thought of a little dogginess sort of grabs on.
Then it becomes Rover.
Then it becomes the story about a Rover got run over and oh, we all cried and married him and all.
Sad.
Underneath everybody's thinkingness right now, there's an infinite silence below all the thinkingness of everybody here.
There is nothing going on at all underneath the minds of everyone here.
That's a fact.
Resist.
Your mind is not thinking anything at all.
It's just an infinite, silent potentiality.
Your mind right now is not thinking anything.
There's a hearingness of this voice and its talkingness.
The only reason you can hear that is because your mind is actually silent.
Underneath the hearing of all this talkingness that's going on is an infinite, profound silence with no beginning and no end.
Forever.
An infinite potentiality.
Everybody willing to give up thinking for two seconds?
Let's all quit thinking, okay?
All right.
Now, don't try to stop thinking.
If you try to stop thinking, you'll have to stop.
If you stop thinking, you'll be stuck with trying to stop thinking.
You can't stop thinking.
All right.
Now, we're going to dive below, like into the bottom of the sea.
Infinite silence.
That's where it is, what you're looking for, is the infinite silence.
Out of the infinite silence, potentiality is actualizing into actuality, and that's what we call life.
That's what we call who I am.
That's what we call what the world is.
But you can see that's all just a presentation with no innate reality.
Now you're all free forever.
Thank you, Lord.
And thank you.
God bless you all.
It's been my joy.