Dr. David R. Hawkins.
All right, thank you.
Sir Dr. Dr. David Hawkins,
te riang sung kak to sa.
Thank you.
Well, that is all fun.
Well, we're here today to go over a difficult but simple subject.
And the way to learn the most difficult subject on Earth,
seeing as it's eluded the consciousness of mankind up to this moment,
is to just listen with interest, that's all.
Don't try to use your intellect.
There's nothing that you can intellectually wrap around.
It's a matter of familiarity.
And familiarity, strangely enough, changes one's whole context
and feeling about reality.
And so we're just going to cover what consciousness research has turned up
and what's been unique
in my own work
and what it signifies about life and consciousness and spiritual reality.
The other thing we're going to do is we're going to calibrate
the level of consciousness of the audience before and after.
We have permission.
We have permission to do this. Resist.
Consciousness level of this audience is over 350. Resist.
360. Resist.
370. Resist.
390. Resist.
400. Resist.
420. Resist.
410. 410. Resist.
411. Over 410. Over 411.
Oh, good.
So we have an audience that calibrates at 410.
That's very bright.
We'll see what that means in a minute.
It means you're wide awake and able to comprehend what we're going to talk about.
Oh, what a relief.
And if I calibrate an audience and their mind is 50,
uh-oh, it's going to be a tough day.
All right, so what we're going to be covering today
is the whole field of consciousness.
We're going to recontextualize the entire universe.
Man's place in it.
What mankind is all about from the beginning of time up to the moment.
We're going to cover evolution versus revolution.
Evolution versus creation.
The mind of God.
And that will be enough for the afternoon.
Consciousness itself is probably the most rewarding study
of any subject.
Why?
Because through consciousness, through a simple observation,
hundreds and hundreds of seeming problems instantly dissolve.
And they dissolve by letting go a specific point of observation.
And those of you who are into spiritual work,
there's a good deal of discussion about the ego.
And we have a whole chart of the levels of the ego from 200 down.
Transcend the ego.
The ego really arises from positionality.
Taking an arbitrary point of view.
Once you take an arbitrary point of view,
you have now created a duality.
No duality exists in reality with a capital R.
But in reality with a small r,
in which most of society lives,
they live in a world of constant dualities.
And this is created by the positionality.
Let's take a positionality of good and bad.
The minute you're caught by good and bad,
your life is now somewhat considerably down the tubes
because at every moment you have a conflict between
what seems to be a conflict, a contradiction.
So we'll start with the end.
We'll start with the end.
Let's take as an example the academic argument
which is in the headlines having to do with creation versus evolution.
Supposedly there's a conflict
between creation and evolution.
And this is intensely political
and people get red in the face and argue it.
It's been in the court system.
And the minute you hear something versus something,
you realize right away there's an artificiality here.
No such thing really exists in reality
because in reality there is no conflict.
Any conflict that you see has to be made up by the human mind.
So this is a positionality.
A positionality of either-or-ness, either-or-ness.
Well, let us say that that which is the infinite divinity,
that which is the unmanifest,
beyond the manifest universe,
beyond time, space, locality,
that which is infinite obviously has neither beginning nor end.
Neither beginnings nor end.
Consequently, with a little reflection,
you will see that if there is such a thing as creation,
it is either continuous,
always ongoing and forever,
or it never did occur.
There's nothing in between.
That which is infinite cannot do a thing once.
There would have to be a beginning and a stopping.
Well, beginnings and stoppings are within man's consciousness.
That thing begins when you say it begins
and it ends when you say it ends.
But that's all in your mind.
There's no beginning and no ending out there.
You understand?
Creation, to be comprehensible
for an understanding of the nature of life,
the nature of God,
would have to be forever.
Creation is always continuous.
And the unfolding of creation, then,
the unfolding of creation,
appears as evolution.
Consequently, evolution and creation are one and the same thing.
And evolution is merely
the unfolding of creation to man's perception.
As you see it arise, you think it is happening.
It's only happening to your observation.
So if creation and evolution are one and the same thing,
once you drop two different points of view,
you see there is no conflict.
If creation occurs, then it would...
How would it appear?
From nothingness to allness?
No, because we see, even during recorded time,
things change.
So things in an infinite time duration
can't begin to change and then stop.
They're either ongoing or they never were.
So that would be an example
of how one transcends a seeming paradox,
a seeming conflict,
by merely expanding context.
Now, the other thing we're going to do today is,
everything we say is verifiable.
So we want to start, perhaps,
with an explanation of the technique we have used
to do a lot of this research.
And this brings us to understanding
the nature of consciousness itself.
The universe can be looked at
from the viewpoint of the linear.
That is form.
That is the Newtonian paradigm of reality,
in which this causes this, causes this, causes this.
In that paradigm of reality,
cause exists within the world.
We say, what causes this?
And reality is looked at
like a series of billiard balls.
A hits B, B hits C, that hits D.
And that is called causation.
That's the world that we have delineated
from 200 down.
That's the world of form.
It's the world of science.
It goes up to the level of 400,
which is the level of logic.
And the world of form,
the linear world,
is solvable,
as described by Sir Isaac Newton,
by the differential calculus.
That which is beyond the differential calculus
eludes the understanding of the scientist.
The scientist limits himself
to the mechanical, physical world
and says, unless you can measure it,
it's not real.
This presumes, then,
that there's an objective reality
that exists independent of consciousness.
And if we sent machines out there,
it could measure it and report back to us.
So, the paradigm of science
then ends in the 400s.
The world in which people exist
really goes from the 400s up to 1000.
Human life is lived
in the non-linear domain.
Non-linear, meaning not measurable,
not weighable, not photographable.
Human consciousness is where we all
experience all of life subjectively.
So, reality with a capital R, then,
is purely subjective.
Reality with a small r is objective.
And spiritual reality
is non-measurable.
You can't identify and measure
how much happiness, how much love,
how much peace, how much serenity a person has,
or how much value or meaning
something has to a person.
However, that's the level in which we live.
We live in the invisible domain.
From the invisible domain of consciousness,
we witness, we observe,
we become conscious, we're aware
of a linear world.
But that's really out there.
It's the in here that's aware of the out there.
And it's in the in here that we have our existence.
It's our in here, in here,
that which is the self behind the self.
So, we're going to be talking today
about two different domains.
Self with a small s, which is the world of the ego,
which is the way most people define themselves.
Most people define themselves
as how much money they have, how good looking they are,
all these feelings of shame, guilt, apathy,
that's the ego.
That's the realm of the self with a small s.
That's the realm which people seek to transcend
if they're involved in spiritual work,
if they're in the 12-step program,
if they're trying to advance to higher levels of consciousness.
To transcend the identification of I as body,
I as mind, I as a separate ego,
and realize that behind the word I
is a greater I.
The only reason that I can say I
is because that which is not an individual
gives me consciousness.
So there's that which we witness,
then there's that which witnesses it.
Then there's the observer, the experiencer.
Behind that is awareness, consciousness itself.
Consciousness itself has no form.
It's like the fish.
It's like the water,
and the thoughts are like the fish.
So consciousness is like the water,
it observes the fish going through it.
But consciousness is
unaffected by what goes through it.
The spirit is unaffected by what goes through it.
Well, we got interested in consciousness
and began using a technique called kinesiology.
There's a number of different techniques you can use.
And we became aware that
different levels of consciousness
have different relative levels of power,
and that these could be calibrated
relative to each other, relative to each other.
And we came up with, it suggested itself,
as answers to the questions arose,
a calibrated level of consciousness
that went from one to a thousand.
So a little germ, the minute it appears on the planet,
calibrates at one already.
To get anywhere, you've got to start at one.
Consciousness then moves on up through the animal kingdom
as awareness progresses,
and kinesiology is a simple test,
which I'll also teach you before we leave today.
But there are a number of other ways
of achieving the same numbers.
And we asked, if existence is one,
what's the greatest number of any being
that ever walked the planet?
And the answer we got was one thousand.
So I'll just show you how we did it.
We have permission to do this calibration resist.
Consciousness of mankind goes all the way up to one thousand resist.
People who've walked this earth
have calibrated over a thousand resist.
No.
A thousand is the level of the avatar resist.
Buddha, Christ, Krishna.
Yes, thank you.
All right, so reality then goes from one to a thousand,
which one thousand then is the highest energy field
which protoplasm apparently can handle.
The energy beyond that would be sort of fry.
So a thousand is as high as it goes.
Over a thousand I presume are angelic realms.
Let's just see.
Over a thousand is angelic realms.
You don't get a physical body anymore.
All right, so from one to a thousand.
Very interesting.
Well, we found that at a certain level
there's a difference between truth and falsehood.
And this is probably the most interesting thing we've discovered.
At a certain level, kinesiology can tell the difference
between truth and falsehood.
And we said, what is the number of that level?
And it gave us 200.
So this is the level of truth.
This is the level of 200.
Anything that calibrates above 200 makes your arm go strong.
Anything below 200 is false,
destructive, what the world calls evil,
and will make your arm go weak.
Consequently, this level differentiates two different realms,
two different polarities,
the positive and the negative, the true and the false,
the constructive and the negative,
the constructive and the destructive.
Interestingly enough, it infallibly tells the truth,
tells truth from falsehood.
It infallibly tells truth from falsehood about anything.
Inasmuch as consciousness is beyond time and space
and is universally present everywhere throughout all of time,
anything that has ever happened,
every thought that's ever been thought,
every event that has occurred
is registered forever in the energy field called consciousness.
A nonlinear domain in which the vibration,
the frequency, the signal,
the unique signal of every thought,
every feeling that ever occurred,
anywhere, by anything or anyone,
is registered forever.
Not surprising, scripture says,
not a hair shall be lost,
every sparrow shall be counted.
And we find kinesiologically that is correct.
That at this time and place,
anybody here in this audience,
and we'll do it for relief,
can pick the person next to you,
and we can find out anything about anywhere,
anybody or anything that ever existed,
anywhere in the universe,
anywhere in time or space.
I'm not confined to this planet.
I'm not confined to any domain whatsoever.
It's possible if you realize the nature of nonlinear reality.
Nonlinear means non-dimensional.
It means beyond time, beyond space, beyond form.
Advanced theoretical physics approaches this realm,
and you get below the alpha neutrino.
You come to things that no longer have physical existence.
They exist almost as a potentiality.
They exist as a position,
a possible position of energy, perhaps,
with a certain polarity and a certain charge.
So these energy fields which dominate human consciousness,
then, were calibratable.
We did such things as calibrated
the actual power of a thought.
And this is an interesting thing,
that the power of a loving thought,
let me see if I get this right,
the power of a loving thought
is 2 to the minus 3.5 million microwatts.
The power of a hateful or fearful thought
is 1 to the minus 750 million microwatts.
Well, that was a profound finding.
Why?
Because what it means is
a loving thought is so enormously more powerful
than a negative thought,
which you can think negative thoughts all day,
and as long as you end up feeling the loving courage of your kitty
and love your mother and kiss your wife at night,
you're okay.
A loving thought undoes all the horrid thoughts
that you feel so guilty about.
Well, let's look at the energy level of guilt.
Guilt calibrates at 30.
That's very, very weak.
You can feel guilty for years and years and years,
and other than blowing out your heart rate
and then killing yourself with a heart attack or something,
it doesn't really do much harm on the planet.
Because the lady next door loves her dog,
and her loving vibrations go out
and cancel out all your negativity.
So, this is good to know.
You don't have to be afraid of negativity.
You can have it all you want.
Shame is 20.
Guilt is 30.
Apathy is 50.
Now, the amazing thing we discovered is...
You see, what we discovered is sort of like...
You know, this is about the year 1509,
and the telescope has just been discovered.
We're practically at that same thing.
We suddenly have a new instrument
in which whole new dimensions of the universe
become readily apparent.
And at first they seem mind-boggling,
but as you reflect on them,
suddenly it all fits together, you see.
Oh, now I understand why such a...
So, 85% of mankind,
85% of the people on the planet
calibrate below 200.
Hmm, wow.
So, we've got shame, guilt, and apathy.
That's starvation, grief, despondency,
people being arrested, in jail, prison, fear.
We have war, suicide, desire, addiction,
anger, rage, hatred, pridefulness.
Oh, whoa, what a big one that is.
So, here, below 200,
everybody goes weak, see.
We say, now, what is...
When we do this demonstration,
we're going to test some people
that are obviously
not in great spiritual favor, likely.
You know, Hitler calibrates over 200 resist.
Oops, sorry.
He did calibrate over 200 resist.
Now he's over 300 resist.
Oh, okay.
All right, so things change, anyway.
That which is negative or false,
if I say...
Say my name is Helen.
Her name is Helen.
Resist.
Her name is not Helen.
Say her name is Susan.
Your name is Susan.
Resist.
Her name is Susan, yes.
We've actually calibrated credit card numbers using it.
Somebody sent us one,
and they didn't put the date on it.
We just went through it,
went through the machine, it was fine.
All right, so,
200 delineates
the level of destructive negativity and falsity.
Over 200 is positive, it's true, it's...
So when we go over 200,
which is the level of...
That's the capacity to tell the truth.
The capacity to tell the truth.
The first step in the 12-step programs,
you stop lying and you admit the truth.
You admit the truth that you're powerless
over this, that, and the other thing.
That's the first on the way back,
because it takes you over 200.
250 is the level of trusting and easy-goingness.
People at 250 are very easy to get along with.
I like people at 250.
They say, you know, if I get the job, fine.
If I don't, I'll get another one.
You know what I mean?
They don't panic.
They don't commit suicide.
They don't go into rages and punch you
because they didn't get the job.
They just say, well, you like me, fine.
You don't like me, you don't like me.
They're wonderful people.
Their willingness, of course, is even better.
Willingness at 310.
If you have a waitress at New Challenge,
she says, what do you have today?
And then if you get a waitress at Willingness,
she says, oh, hi, doc.
Are you going to have the regular?
Wow, now she gets a bigger tip, doesn't she?
Willingness makes the greatest employees.
We love people at Willingness
because they're the helpers.
They're the people you need to get things done.
They're the workers of the world.
350 is acceptance.
They would begin hitting such levels as forgiveness.
People are transcending.
About 350, they're transcending good and bad
and beginning to see things more through understanding.
And good and bad is not really so relevant anymore.
It's really sort of immaterial now whether it's good or bad.
It's more important if it works, if it brings peace.
It's in the direction we're working.
Love at 500 is relatively rare.
This level of love is, at 540,
it reaches unconditional love.
The 12-step groups curiously enough calibrated 540.
540 is the level of healing.
Severe diseases cannot be cured with energy levels less than 540.
It takes the level almost miraculous of 540.
Quits is the level of serenity and unconditional love.
I think 0.4% of the world's population reaches that.
Over 500.
We have permission to ask this question.
0.4% of the population ever reaches 500 resist.
Ever reaches 540 resist.
Let's see. Over 500.
0.4% of the world's population resist.
These things change somewhat, so we have to recheck them periodically.
But approximately 0.4% of the world's population
reaches a level you could call unconditional love.
Therefore you see how rare true love really is.
And unconditional means no matter what.
And 600 is the level of peace.
That is an infinite peace.
And on the way there you go through joy and exquisite beauty.
The high 500s are usually spiritual,
well-known spiritual leaders in the world.
The Pope is at about 570.
The fellow out of Tibet, what's his name?
Yeah, those are the high 500s.
That's about 570.
The Pope is about 570.
So they're great world spiritual leaders.
At 600 there's a major transition.
That's the level of enlightenment.
The linear domain disappears as an existent reality.
It's usually experienced as infinite bliss.
And from 700 up you have the high and extremely rare.
Spiritual geniuses you might say.
900 and up is about 4 on the planet.
One being at 1000 totally balances the entire negativity of all of mankind.
So it only takes one avatar to counterbalance the entire negativity of the entire human race.
We found something interesting the other day.
What's the difference between the Buddha and Jesus Christ?
A lot of people say, what is the difference between the two of them?
Obviously two great beings.
And some people switch from one to the other.
They go to Christian for a while, and they go to Buddha for a while, and they go to Christian for a while, and then they go to...
They think, what is the difference?
Is there a difference?
Well, they both calibrate at 1000.
So does Krishna.
So we say, what is the difference if these beings all calibrate at 1000?
And we got the Buddha was a teacher of enlightenment.
The Buddha does not talk about salvation.
Doesn't talk about heaven.
Talks about enlightenment.
However, as the Buddha said, very few people are equipped for that.
And more practically speaking, Christ said, or Christ came to save people below 200.
So we said, Christ's mission was to die for the people who are below 200.
We said, are the people below 200 destined for heaven?
He said, no.
And then Christ's mission was that of salvation.
That of salvation.
That for all those who are below 200 do not have the spiritual energy, insight, or assistance to make it.
And without the help of a very high guru, you might say.
That's in accordance with Eastern religions also.
It's that you cannot reach really a high level without an advanced spiritual teacher.
So they had two different missions, you might say.
I mean, that's what we came up with.
You don't have to believe it.
You don't have to believe anything I'm saying.
But that Buddha was to teach the way to enlightenment.
Christ was the way to salvation.
And there is a branch of Buddhism called New Land Buddhism which takes the same position.
But the likelihood of becoming enlightened on this extremely negative plane here is quite limited.
But if you follow a spiritual pathway, then at the time of death, the Buddha of salvation will take you to the lotus heaven.
From there you can go to enlightenment.
So there's a number of positions then that enlightenment is not possible for the average person.
You'd have to be pretty fixed in one point of the mind and probably considered quite strange by everybody around you.
So now, we wanted to cover the things in the syllabus here.
We wanted to cover the difference between...
We wanted to cover the calibration levels of consciousness and how to do it.
So I thought next...
Any of you would like to learn how to do kinesiology?
Anybody want to learn it?
Okay, we'll just...
We're going to do this.
I'll tell you what we're going to do.
We're going to divide up into ones and twos.
Pick somebody near you.
And I just...
There's just one exercise from that point on.
You can do it yourself.
The person who's tested, we ask them to hold in mind somebody they love.
And we have them resist.
So we'll demonstrate.
You can find out the truth about anything with this, by the way.
You know?
The car that I'm intending to buy is, you know, really good and solid.
We...
Uh-oh.
Okay, so...
The first thing she does is close her eyes so she's not distracted.
You don't have music in the background.
Music will affect it.
She doesn't have any metal across the midline.
She tries to keep her mind blank.
And I ask permission to ask this question.
We have permission to do this demonstration today.
Resist.
Says yes.
We have permission for this audience to do this demonstration.
Hold in mind something or someone you love.
It can be your kitty, your mother, president of your country, spiritual figure.
Resist.
Mother Teresa.
Hold in mind Mother Teresa.
Resist.
Okay.
Okay, now hold in mind that awful person from childhood.
Resist.
I know who it is, too.
Was that the sixth grade teacher?
She had a monster teacher in sixth grade.
All right, so the demonstration is merely love makes you go strong and non-love makes you go weak.
Truth makes you go strong.
Falsity makes you go weak.
It seems like a simple thing.
After we've learned how to do it, I'll tell you what you can do with it, besides becoming an overnight millionaire.
Okay, so let's all just go ones and twos.
One, two.
You want to just choose next to you.
We'll just do it real quickly.
I'll show you through experientially.
You don't have to join this.
This is all voluntary.
Anybody doesn't have to.
Don't bother.
But anyway, if the subject of kinesiology comes up, you can say, yes, I went to electronic.
We tried it, and this and that.
The easiest way is to smile, basically.
Oh, yeah.
Okay, now you decide which one's going to be the doctor, which one's the patient, who's number one, and who's number two.
Okay, number one, you're going to be the doctor.
And you ask, this is your patient here.
Come over here, patient.
Now, just hold your arm out like this patient, please.
And when I press down, I'm going to press with two fingers.
I just want to test out her relative strength.
I'm not trying to break her arm down or win a game or something.
Okay, when I say resist, resist, resist.
See, I'm pushing with one finger.
And I tell her to resist.
When you resist, try to just equalize the pressure that's being pressed on you, you know, so that your arm stays the same.
So when I press down, I push back up equal to the pressure.
Okay.
Now, picture Mother Teresa.
Resist.
Okay?
Okay, so you can all just picture someone you love and ask the person that you're testing to resist.
Have them close their eyes.
Just say to them, resist.
Okay, you all got Mother Teresa.
You all got love.
Hold your kitty in mind, your favorite dog, your favorite school teacher, whoever.
Okay, now we ask the person that we're testing.
Picture somebody you know you don't love, somebody you're afraid of.
Some unfortunate accident.
Picture yourself being run over by a railroad train.
And then ask them to resist.
Something that you know darn well is non-love.
There are some unlovable people on the planet.
Just hold that in mind.
Saddam Hussein was always doing a pinch.
It might.
I doubt it, but it might.
Yeah, across the midnight.
You try to avoid middle across the midnight, mainly glasses.
But you don't have to worry about it unless you see it's interfering.
If you don't get the correct answers, then some of these things you've got to pay more attention to.
All right, does love make everybody go strong?
Does love make anybody go weak?
And non-love makes you go weak.
So all I want you to experience is the energy of love versus the energy of not love.
That's all.
Okay, now we can reverse.
Ones and twos, switch doctor and patient.
Yeah, we'll do that.
Okay.
Ask your patient to picture somebody they love.
Have them close their eyes.
Take off their glasses if it's metal.
Just say, picture somebody you love.
Now resist.
After you picture somebody you love and experience it, it makes you strong.
Picture something fearful.
Disgraceful.
Shameful.
Who's that serial killer?
Your dog being run over by a truck.
Does everybody get that love makes you go strong?
Okay, we can sit down.
What we're experiencing, I want you to understand the nature of what we're experiencing.
Because the major jump in consciousness was the seeing that this response is not local.
It's non-local.
Now I'll explain what that means.
Kinesiology has been used by chiropractors, holistic health practitioners, physicians
all over the world.
I learned it back in the 70s from Dr. John Diamond, who had learned it from George Goodhart,
who was a chiropractor.
Diamond took it to a different level.
He took it to the level of, which I'll demonstrate, a different level.
I forgot to demonstrate.
Anyway, he took it to a different level.
That not only do physical things locally make you strong or weak, but there's certain things
that make you strong or weak.
But there's certain attitudes or designs or figures that make you go as strong or weak.
Let's just, we should have had you do this before you sit down.
You want to all stand up again?
We'll just do it real quick.
I want the patients, okay, let's go back to the ones and the twos that we had the first time.
Okay, patients, I want you to look at this here.
I want the patients to look at the figure going like this.
Look at this picture and then ask the person to test you.
Okay?
Look at that picture and say, doctor, say resist.
Look at that picture, patient, and say resist.
Resist.
Okay?
Okay, patients, now look at this image.
Look at this image over here.
Now ask the patient to resist again while they're looking at that image.
Okay, now we can switch doctor and patient.
Okay, patients, I want you to look at the smile.
Test the patient who's looking at a smile.
And tell him to resist.
And then look at what, there's a negative-looking person's mouth, right?
Okay.
I just wanted to give you some examples because people, I want you to understand that what
we discovered was that the kinesiologic response is the response of consciousness itself.
It is not a local response.
Most people, when they see this, they say, well, the response is going to depend on what
the person you're testing believes.
Now, it has nothing to do with what the person you're testing believes.
In fact, very often, the result is the opposite of what the person you're testing believes.
This is the nature of consciousness itself.
Now, we look at protoplasm.
Protoplasm, its response is impersonal.
You stick it with a needle, it bleeds.
That's impersonal.
That's not George bleeding or Pete bleeding.
That's protoplasm bleeding.
It has nothing to do with your personality.
Consciousness has nothing to do with your personality.
Consciousness responds.
It knows truth from non-truth, and that's all it knows.
The only thing consciousness knows is truth from non-truth.
It instantly knows that.
That's not surprising that the essence of life itself, like an amoeba, would know what's
good for it, and it would move towards that which is life-giving, and that it would draw
from that which is destructive of life.
Consciousness, then, which is everywhere present at all times.
Equally, it only knows one thing.
It knows truth.
That's really all it knows.
It doesn't even know falsehood.
Falsehood is only a way of speaking.
It only knows truth.
It knows whether truth is present or not.
That's all it knows.
Well, we've just said probably the most profound thing in the history of mankind.
Innate within us is the capacity to know truth from falsehood.
Mankind, since the beginning of time, has been completely unable to know truth.
To know truth from falsehood.
Every battle ever lost in the history of this world was due to the loss of not knowing what
the other side was doing.
They're going to go around the Maginot Line, not through it, of course.
They're going to go through the Ardennes Forests.
Every single battle.
We could have said, did he move the 8th Battalion?
Or didn't he?
He did.
Oh, we would have won that war, see?
We've done it.
Take every member of the State Department, every employee of the State Department.
I'll tell you who's a mole and who's not a mole within about one second.
Every mole in the State Department, in the CIA.
Why?
Because you look at their picture and you say, this man is an integrist, this man is
an integrist, this man is an integrist.
Wham.
There you've got the greatest spy there who lived.
I had him years ago.
So, the applications are rather stupendous.
I have at home the Greek Books of the Western World, a very impressive series of documents
put out by the University of Chicago faculty back in the 30s, I think.
A whole shelf of the greatest thinkers of all time.
Greatest, right all the way down as far as before, I think it was the last volume.
Oh, he got in there, I don't know, but he did.
The content of the greatest books that have ever lived, the greatest wines that have ever
lived, has been a discussion, all 50 volumes or whatever, is trying to decide what is truth.
Don't know.
What do you need a jury for?
Because you don't know what's truth.
What do you need witness for?
Why do you have to record it?
Why do you have to videotape it?
Because the human mind, unaided, is unable to know truth from falsehood.
That was Eve's problem.
That's everybody's problem.
The human mind is...
Alright, so we can use this analogy, the human mind, innate consciousness itself is like
the hardware, and the ego is like the software.
The ego is like the software.
The software, the ego, is unable to know truth.
It doesn't know truth from falsehood.
It has no mechanism and no means to know truth from falsehood.
We're told, beware the wolf in sheep's clothing, but you're not told how to tell it.
How do you know the sheep in wolf's clothing?
The church didn't know.
The church was invaded by all kinds of destructive and negative people who carried enemy but
truth.
Even the church itself could not defend itself against the lie.
So, until this time, mankind has had no means of knowing truth from falsehood.
Let's say the research done by Edison, research done by Edison, which took, I forget, 14 years
and $350 million, we can come to the same answer with about five questions in less than
two minutes, thereby saving 14 years and $250 million.
So it's application in research, in science.
It's application in, to me, intelligence, military intelligence.
You can tell that there is a true painting and a false painting in an instant, and I've
got both of them at home.
I've got the real thing, and if you wrap it all up in newspaper and hold it like this,
it makes you go strong.
And I have a very excellent Picasso, and this Picasso makes you go weak.
Sell that one quick and get out of town.
So...
Well, you see, the greatest art galleries in the world, the greatest national, what
do you call it, in Washington, had huge, in the last 10 years, a big major every expert
in the world trying to decide whether a certain painting was legitimate or not.
You're talking about millions of dollars.
If it's legitimate, it's probably worth $50 million.
If it's not, it's probably worth, you know, a couple thousand, because it was a good fake.
All right, so it has many, many applications.
So we have these levels of consciousness, which...
Once you become familiar with the levels of consciousness, it's quite difficult not
to keep growing spiritually.
It's practically impossible.
Once you've even seen the map of consciousness and become aware of it, your mind begins to
automatically seek a higher level.
It just automatically begins to want to go there.
We have in the synopsis on the first page the difference between the linear and the
nonlinear domains, which, by the time you read it, it becomes quite obvious.
So, although this may, to some people, unless it's explained correctly, seem extremely
difficult or complicated, it's really quite simple.
Once it's laid out in front of you, your mind just says, oh, yeah, I always knew that.
In a way, what we're doing today is merely recontextualizing what your mind only knows.
And now its meaning becomes significant.
Its meaning becomes quite clear.
And we have, for instance...
How the mind thinks in a linear way is limited.
It's local.
It depends on force rather than power.
Now, we said that the levels below 200 are levels of force.
The levels above 200 are levels of power.
The name of the book is called Power Versus Force.
Levels from 200 down are force.
Force.
What is force?
Force...
Goes from here to there.
Force goes from here to there.
In so doing, it expends energy.
Therefore, force, you have to constantly feed force.
The army gets bigger, it eats more.
The bigger and more successful it is, the more complicated it becomes.
Force gradually exhausts itself because it uses up energy.
It uses up energy.
Force is therefore limited.
Force...
Force is what people who don't have power resort to as a substitute for power.
Below 200.
Those are the things that people do who lack power.
They have to steal.
They have to fight.
They have to shoot.
They have to lie.
They have to cheat.
To feel good, they have to take drugs and things.
Hmm...
So, force expends itself.
Force is what makes everything else work.
What makes everything else work.
Power, over 200, are levels of power.
The difference between the two is that power does not move from one place to the other at all.
It's stationary.
Power just stands there.
And by nature of its essence, it influences everything within its domain.
So power just stands there and, like gravity, controls everything within it without moving.
It does not expend energy.
Power actually creates energy.
The sun just radiates forth.
Radiates forth and nurtures all that it falls upon.
Power is also not selective.
It doesn't say, well, you're going to get a little grace and a little love and you're going to the other place.
Those are...
Those are imaginations of the ego that such a thing is possible.
Power, then, does not use energy.
It radiates energy.
When we're in the presence of somebody who has great power, we feel good, we feel energized, we feel inspired.
So power, then, is not local.
And the great power, the power of the great spiritual beings that have been here still reside within the field of human consciousness.
They remain to this day, can be calibrated to this day.
It must be class is almost over.
Class is over, folks.
We're going to take a five-minute break.
And we're going to speak for a little while longer.
And then, at the end, we'll ask for questions and any commentaries you wish to make.
Okay?
Thank you.