It's an hour late. I'm going to pass the, I just thought some people might put this together.
It sounds sort of academically. It starts with a syllabus, and then it goes on to a synopsis.
We could pass these out. A syllabus and a synopsis. It tells us what we're going to be talking about today,
which I have the slightest idea, but it looks good on paper.
It features the academic people. Well, I did give a conference a week or two ago,
and a lot of people get continuing education credits, you know.
If any of you need continuing education credits, I have certificates of education here, good, for three credits.
Today will certainly be at least three credits. So anybody who needs any, I have these here.
They're all signed, and we'll just put the date, and the name of the presentation is on the syllabus.
And so those who would like, you know, continuing education academic credits, we officially have them.
Close for five minutes early. I just want to make sure we're close for five minutes early.
And if we run out of them, we'll get some more made.
All right, what we do is, let's see what the name of it would be.
We have Commissioner Ashley's, which is, I feel like it's over 470, 472, 475, 480, 478, 479, okay.
It was 770 before, but I did resist.
All right.
This is a very exciting audience to speak to.
Well, what we always do is calibrate the level of consciousness of the audience before and after the presentation.
And historically, the level of consciousness of the audience usually jumps considerably.
I mean, a group like this will jump considerably.
And the average group will jump probably about 10 points.
And as we said in the book, Power Versus Force,
the consciousness level of the average person increases by five points in a lifetime.
So if you can knock off 10 points in one lecture, that's two lifetimes right there.
That's two times you won't have to come back.
So anyway, I just thought that was good news.
Well, we have most luxurious accommodations here.
And we were greeted in the most impressive airport parking lot I've ever seen.
In my life.
It went on for miles.
We traveled.
She had a compass with us.
It was phenomenal, I thought.
It took great courage, great courage and stamina to, brave that to come and find us and bring us here.
And here we are in California.
Now, you see, we have to set up for transparency and the transparency of course is sitting home on my desk.
Okay.
Thank you.
So, today we will just have to speak from truth and that will have to do it.
And the other thing we'll do that's different in this lecture is we'll stay right now.
We'll stay right now at all times.
And I want you to notice that we will not let the past catch up with us or the future elude us.
Because most people spend all their time trying to catch the past, the future before it escapes them.
and holding off the past so it won't catch up with it.
So the only safe place to be at any time is right now.
And so throughout this lecture we'll say right now.
So everybody will be safe from the past and safe from the future.
And the reason for saying that is because everyone looks to see,
you know, where is enlightenment and when is it going to happen?
And everybody looks into the future.
Or they look into the past.
They say it's either my karma from the past
or it's something that I will evolve into sometime in the future
or some future lifetime.
And the fact is it's found in the immediate moment of now,
in the split second, in the split second between two thoughts,
which is what the Buddha said.
And he was correct.
It was in the same place he said it was.
In fact, it was still there.
It never moved in all these thousands of years.
It's right here right now.
And how to stay on the edge of now is partly what we'll be talking about today.
So the syllabus says that we will be talking about who the speaker is
and various subjects.
We will cover the levels of consciousness and their inference.
We'll be talking about the different situations,
between linear and non-linear.
So to make everything that I say simple,
we'll start out from the most difficult and obscure.
That will make the rest simple.
And that is that we have two ways of experiencing reality.
One is in the linear Newtonian paradigm of reality,
which has to do with form, has to do with structure.
And the linear linearism,
linear reality is discreditable in terms of advanced theoretical math and physics,
and especially of the differential calculus.
But a lot of data falls outside the realm of the predictable mathematically.
It falls outside the expected paradigm of science.
And our society is primarily oriented to the intellect.
Our society in America, the caliber is extremely high,
and indicates that it's the intellect,
that we worship as God.
Science is the, it's taken over the point,
the one that's taken by religion.
So when we look for answers, we look to the intellect,
and we look for science to come up with the answers.
The only difficulty with science is that,
in our level of consciousness, as you can see,
we have our levels of consciousness here,
a map of consciousness where everybody can just refer to it if they want.
But the reason the intellect calibrates in the 400s,
well,
spiritual truth in reality, you know, the reality of spiritual truth really commences formally around 500.
500 is the level of love, 540 is unconditional love.
So the realm of science then takes us up really to 499.
If we calibrate 499, we see Einstein, Freud, Sir Isaac Newton,
all the great scientists.
All the great geniuses of old time calibrate around 499.
500 is the level of the heart, 500 is the opening of love.
500 is the, really the, taking over of the non-linear dimension.
From 500 and up we're talking about qualities that are powerful qualities,
that cannot be measured.
Love, meaning, significance, motivation, all the things that run human beings,
are in the non-linear, non-measurable domain,
and therefore not within the realm of science, not describable, not measurable.
So the radical materialist, reductionist materialism,
states that unless a thing can be weighed or measured,
then it has no reality.
It's only a tautology, that's a popular philosophic system that says you can't measure it.
It's a tautology,
and a philosophic system that says you can't measure it.
It's a tautology, and a philosophic system that says you can't measure it.
it's a tautology, and a philosophic system that says you can't measure it.
It's a tautology, and a philosophical system, but not a reality.
Well, today we're going to say the opposite.
Today we're going to say that the measurable is a perceptual construct,
and that what's real is that which cannot be measured.
Things that make human life human, none of them are measurable.
Although we talk in language, and verbalize, and move about in a physical material world,
human existence is really lived on the level
of the non-linear. From moment to moment, although you may be observing a linear reality
such as tables and chairs or numbers or articles in a grocery store, at every instant you're
really coming out of an invisible space of your own existence which has no form whatsoever.
Even when you decide to vote, you just, out of your right side of your brain, you pick
this one. Then suddenly the left side comes in and says, the reason I picked this one
is this. All that is an afterthought. You didn't pick it for that reason at all. You
don't even know why you picked what you picked because it has to do with 10 million variables
throughout all of time and throughout all of this existence and all the input of this
entire lifetime and all of the subtleties and interactions.
So.
So complex that no computer could possibly calculate it. So our real existence then,
although we deal with form, we deal with form from a space of non-form, the non-linear dimension
of reality. And spiritual work then is concerned with the non-dimensional, the non-dimensional
non-measurable. So of course what we did in the book, what we did in Power vs. Force is
measure the immeasurable.
Well, what was the purpose of that? The purpose of that was to try to make the obvious comprehensible.
Because the people who are in left brain and into the world of science and logic and calibrate,
let's say in the 400s or below, spiritual reality is not a real reality to them. And
the scientific people would like to say this is all fantasy, etc. But it's not. It's not.
It's not. It's not. It's not. It's not. It's not. It's not. It's not. It's not. It's not. It's not. It's not. It's not. It's not.
It's not. It's not. It's not. It is not. It's not. It is not. It's not. So what we needed
was a means of crossing over from Newtonian paradigm of reality, measurable, scientific,
logical, sequential world of existence to the non-linear world of spiritual reality
and a way of making the non-spiritual world comprehensible to the intellect. So the
whole purpose of the map of consciousness, which is on the back of page 1, is to make
the non-life understand the idea of spiritual reality as something that is not absolutely
meaning in topic. So the purpose of the map of consciousness is to make the non-life stream,
transition from the nonlinear to the linear comprehensible so that even the scientific
skeptic can look at it and say huh you mean to tell me there is an actual objective means
you know verifying the existence of a nonlinear domain not only that but calibrating its low
relative energy its relative power so when we did the levels of consciousness we started out
from one to a thousand one to a thousand and then we found this out the scale came about empirically
we said if the existence is one existence is one logarithmic scale what would be the highest number
ever achieved by any living being and instead of thousand I thought well that's pretty neat
one to a thousand that's very cooperative so then we went back and we asked
we found out that that which is true makes you go strong with kinesiology and that which
is false makes you go weak and what was the number of that and we came up with 200 so the
most crucial thing about the map of consciousness is that anything under 200 makes you go weak and
anything over 200 makes you go strong so the exciting thing was that kinesiology differentiated
truth from falsehood that was the most significant finding and when I studied
kinesiology I attended lectures by John Diamond who wrote your body doesn't lie and he's a
wonderful teacher he's a psychiatrist and he's in New York and John Diamond had picked up the
kinesiologic technique from George Goodhart chiropractor I think in Detroit who had worked
on muscle testing and then Diamond took it to a different level he took it to the level where he
demonstrated that he was able to do a lot of things and he was able to do a lot of things
attitudes attitudes and feelings affected the kinetic response and then I just took it some
dimensions further and discovered that one could calibrate all the levels of the fields of
consciousness and that a peculiar thing was happening that the kinesiologic response was
not a local physical response that has had been resumed that was instead a non-specific
impersonal response of the
of consciousness itself, that when we ask somebody a question with kinesiology,
what is answering, is consciousness itself, not the person. So the response
bypasses the personality of both the questioner and the test subject, and
instead you're tapping into some universal, all-present, ever-present
energy field beyond all of time, which we call consciousness. And the discovery was
that anything and everything that had ever happened, anywhere in time or
history, any time in time or space, no matter how small, every single thought,
feeling, movement, every action, by anything or anyone, anywhere in the
universe, was recorded forever. That it is true, as Scripture says, that every hair on
your head should be counted.
Every single thing that occurs then leaves an indelible trace, and
consciousness is beyond time and space, so it's there forever. What Napoleon said,
thought, or felt, every moment of his life can be tracked back again. In the moment,
the day of his death, we can find out what he had for breakfast.
Alright, so this was rather mind-boggling, and I sort of sat on it for about five
years not knowing what to do with this.
We now had something that is
so mind-boggling that it takes practically a lifetime to get used to the
thought, that we now had the means unknown to mankind throughout all of
history to discern truth from falsehood. Well, any student of human history,
even recent and remote, realizes that almost every event in history would have been
different had we given the capacity to know the truth from the falsehood. Jesus
Christ says you don't know the truth from the falsehood.
He said watch out for the wolf in sheep's clothing, but he did not tell you how to tell
the wolf in sheep's clothing. And until this very recent time, man has struggled, and I'm
very, I'm writing a book right now called The Eye of the Eye, and in it I'm sort of
tracking sort of the tragedy almost of the evolution of mankind, and which throughout
the histories has been beset by one plague after another, millions and millions slaughtered,
by disease, millions and millions slaughtered, by war, and even the most battle, recent battles
in history, and you that are World War II buffs, every battle in history could
could have been won if there was a capacity of knowing what the other side
was up to, what the other side was up to. And if Hitler was going to come through
the Ardon forest, which is a big surprise to veterans of World War II, it was
inconceivable.
It was a forest full of trees, and the Panzer tanks couldn't get through them, so the
Allies didn't bother defending where the Germans actually came through. Well, Sutherland
and I could have told them in a second, couldn't we, Sutherland? We could have told them in
a second.
So you see, the significance of being able to know the differences between truth and
falsehood, plus you can tell at any time, any place about anything, is really critical.
It's not necessarily quite mind-boggling. In a way, it really is a fulcrum, on which
the history of mankind can actually make a change. Well, the history of mankind did make
a change in very recent times. Using kinesiology, you can find out for yourself. Everything
we say today you can verify for yourself with kinesiology. The level of consciousness of
mankind throughout the centuries stood at 190. Well, we said 200 is the level that a
of truth 200 is the level of integrity above 200 is that which supports life and below 200 is that
which is destroys life and which is based upon falsity and a lie the consciousness level of
mankind throughout all these centuries has stood at 190 so it's like you lose a little every century
but you make it up in time right you mentioned lost the mankind is so staggering 190 so whether
the scale is slightly this side or slightly this side makes all the difference in the world because
if the if the pointer is being hit by a beam a laser beam that goes off for thousands of light
years the slightest movement is being will it's going to change history throughout time you know
something so being at 190 meant that the future for mankind was not good it was going to start
the same the teachings of Jesus Christ and the Buddha are extremely effective amongst the
listeners to the teachings of Jesus Christ and the Buddha and extremely ineffective amongst those who
cannot hear it and have no interest to it even today 85% of the population of mankind calibrates
below 200 200 is the level of integrity all right 85% of the current population on the planet then
calibrates below 200 below the level of integrity
lives in a world of lies deception greed disaster poverty insecurity fear competition the issue of
mankind then down through the ages when you look at it as though you were coming from some other
planet and looking at mankind and evaluating mankind from a purely objective viewpoint where
what kind of a race is this and where have they come and what do they spend all their time doing
besides killing each other
most of their time killing each other and recovering from killing each other and then starting up a new
generation which then goes up to kill some more people and get killed by other people it's pretty
much what it's been doing actually warfare has killed more people than any other cause throughout
history and then you add on top of that all the plagues and natural disasters so the history of
mankind has been extremely difficult it's really a wonder that he survived at all and you could
look at history and say how in the world did they ever survive that you know the world war
wiping out 70 million people and then that was followed by the flu epidemic of 1918 that knocked
off millions more and of course these were all survivors of the Black Plague which wiped out what
quarter or half of all of Europe after the hundred year war knocked out a good percentage of them you
see yourself on the world event can't even get this far so all right so there it stood at 190
suddenly in 19 about 1986
consciousness level of mankind suddenly jumped to 207 the most significant event in all of man's
history unrecorded and unnoticed by anything or anyone the most profound and significant event in
the history of all of mankind occurred in 1986 or so when the consciousness level of mankind shifted
from 190 which means endless disaster to 207 which means in the success all the difference in the
world
just slightly below the water. Mankind has been struggling with his nose just below the water,
coming up for a little air, and just barely making it. 207 means the universe and the world we live
in now is a completely different energy field. At 190, negativity is socially acceptable. It's okay,
Deutschland über alles. Sacrifice your sons and daughters to the grandeur of Germany,
and we will conquer the world. At 190, that somehow captures people's imagination. At 207,
it sounds a little kooky. You say, yeah, uh huh, right, is this guy okay? 70 million people.
Germans didn't say, is this guy okay? They all saluted. Why? Because the predominant energy
field at 190, negativity appeals to you. Militarism, smart uniforms, killing lower class
people is appealing.
At 207, it sounds pretty stupid.
At 407, where this crowd is, it's absurd. It's absurd. So mankind has not really
had a chance to evolve, despite being at 190 we see the technologic advances in mankind.
Our advances have been technologic, communications, electricity, modern wonders, airplanes and all
those marvelous things. Marvelous 다음.
Marvelous, often known power.
Marvelous, when you see material goods in Ukraine, when you see human capital goods in Korea,
and so on so on.
Marvelous times, hammering into its economic opportunities.
We have seen right forward, the company that our durantewoo, the techn reversal Sung
a lot.
Marvelous but at a restaurant, and the way we have seen mankind, they do so much to its virtue.
Modern cultures don't give you the way you Thantない aids in dealing with Sarah Napol Hitomach .
Marvelous, yes. Well, anyway. Conveniences. Marvelous conveniences.
So we see technologic progress over the centuries, but no real shift in the heart.
No real shift in the heart of mankind.
And suddenly we see a shift now, so that that which was once tolerable is no longer acceptable.
207 is a completely different playing field.
So at 190, North Korea can threaten South Korea with atomic weapons
and scare the bejesus out of them and throw the whole world into a third world war.
We came very close to it.
At 207, it's rather unthinkable.
At 207, everybody looks at the opponents and says,
listen, you better get together to solve this thing.
At 190, they gang up behind this opponent and they gang up behind this opponent
and then they start a war.
At 190, that's acceptable.
At 207, everybody says,
look, why don't you figure out a way? There must be a way out of this.
And so we see out of the Korean situation,
then a resolution of a dilemma that had been there for 50 years.
The way that resolution came about was the awareness.
You see, the awareness that aggression just forms counter-aggression.
You cannot possibly win with aggression
because the harder you push, the harder the other person pushes back.
You just precipitate attack.
It was inevitable.
And realizing that supporting the political position of their opponent,
the opponent would then stop being warlike and welcome support
and that you had an opening for resolution of difficulty,
which is exactly what did happen there.
And now the leader of South Korea will be nominated for the Nobel Prize, etc.
So at 207, we see the resolution of things that would not have been possible in the past.
We saw the dissolution of monolithic communism,
and that, again, was done without a shot.
That was done without a shot.
It was not done by the Western world overpowering communism
and bombing it into oblivion.
It was done by Gorbachev snapping his fingers and the whole thing fell apart.
House of Cards dissolved without a single shot.
Gorbachev didn't shoot anybody, nor did he have any of his...
That was not popular in current communism, in current Russia, rather,
because even a corrupt government has certain benefits to it,
as we'll probably see now in Mexico.
Even a corrupt government has certain benefits to certain parts of the populace.
And when you change it, now everybody is wondering,
where is everything going to come from now?
Because everything now is thrown into a new paradigm of reality.
So we see that change of paradigm of reality shifting now even in politics in Mexico.
That which was corrupt was acceptable for some 70 years.
It's no longer acceptable, even to the people that participated in it.
So we see this general shift of consciousness prevailing throughout the world
and shifting public attitudes towards many things.
Capital punishment, which was a foregone conclusion, has come into question now.
Even the Pope, God bless him,
even the Pope has suddenly become very Christian and said,
but Jesus said,
proudly true, you did not kill your enemies,
even though it sounds justified.
So I have been very happy to see,
you see, even Catholicism has come around to Christianity
and supported Christ's teachings,
which it had not done for many, many centuries.
And under the name of Christ,
you could kill your enemies and execute them and hang them right and left.
Now it doesn't jive.
So we see this immense subtle shift in consciousness
and change in socialization,
attitudes towards many things.
The wisdom of capital punishment itself is now being brought into question.
And in many countries it's illegal and going out of style.
Even the Pope says he thinks it's a poor idea.
And that always puzzled me,
how the Church could hold for capital punishment
considering what Jesus taught about it.
But anyway, those are the ambiguities of human consciousness.
So we see the difference between,
between force and power,
what these things are bringing us to look at.
The name of the book which I wrote was called
Power vs. Force.
And it compares the two different domains.
The lower consciousness levels,
the world of Newtonian logic, etc.
The world of form is the world of force,
which is quite a bit different than the world of power.
It has different rules, different laws,
different ways of expressing itself,
different consequences.
What North and South Korea were looking at was,
only a couple of years ago,
the likelihood of force.
Force vs. force.
If one side used force, the other would use bigger force.
So what if it ended up as an atomic war, frankly,
ballistic missiles and all.
Because force always results in counter force.
This is true within the world of physics.
It's also true within the psychic domain.
But force results in counter force.
Now, the characteristic of force is that
force moves from here to there.
Force moves from here to there.
And because it moves from here to there,
it consumes energy.
Force sooner or later runs out
because it runs out of its source of energy.
You can send only so many troops to the front
and then pretty soon your supply line goes down
and the spirit of the men goes down.
And no matter how victorious your army may be,
it's only a matter of time before the Roman legions
would reach defeat.
They lasted longer than most.
But force is then consuming of energy.
And force exhausts itself because in its expression
it triggers from the universe counter force.
Force requires, triggers counter force.
Therefore it consumes endless energy.
And as we see from our annual income tax,
it has a voracious appetite.
It eats up energy endlessly, endlessly,
trying to overcome obstacles
because it doesn't understand power.
Power, which is non-form,
has completely opposite characteristics.
Power does not consume
any energy at all.
Power instead radiates energy.
So power would be like gravity.
Gravity just stands there.
It just stands there
and it influences everything,
all the time,
more profoundly than any other factor actually.
The sun just shines,
radiates forth energy to the planet.
Not selectively, not onto this plant
and not on that plant,
but onto everything and everyone.
It just radiates forth endless energy.
So power then is more profound.
And because it does not consume energy,
it outlasts force.
When you put power and force together,
eventually power wins out
because it doesn't need any additional supplies.
It just stands there until force runs out of ammunition
and then falls over of itself.
We notice that the energy fields from 200 up then
are the beginning of power.
200 down on our calibrated level there,
you'll see it has to do with force
and it has to do with emotionality
and it leads to exhaustion.
There's only so much fear,
so much grief,
so many tears,
so much pridefulness,
so much aggression
when you finally run out of energy.
Once it's no longer a novelty
and once you've gotten squeezed all the drama you can out of it,
it sort of loses its appeal.
Power on the other hand,
such as the most common example in human experiences,
the power of love,
power emanates and radiates endlessly
and it originates out of the essence of its own nature.
So power then is the radiation of creation expressing itself
in ways that influence all of life
without the expenditure of any energy
and without causing any reaction.
So power doesn't cause a reaction.
So there's no counter,
there's no counter reaction to power
and there's always counter reaction to force.
Anybody got any questions thus far?
Were there circumstances around 1986,
outward circumstances?
Yes, what happened in 1986,
you see you don't know which is cause and which is effect
and which is merely concordance,
which brings us, we'll talk about
creation versus causation and what that brings to that.
What happened at that time was
an evolution of consciousness that reached a point
that was marked historically by the,
what was it, the confluence of the something or others,
what was it in 1986, the confluence of the?
Harmonic convergence, right.
Harmonic convergence was the event that marked that time.
It didn't cause it,
but it was the coalition of all those forces
at that moment did express them
and themselves and people everywhere
joined in prayer for peace
and there was an enormous power of prayer
going on at that time as well.
And a concordance of evolution of consciousness
throughout time, it reached a jumping off place
and crossed over that line unnoticed by anyone,
unnoticed, nobody noticed it,
the most significant event in all of human history
sadly occurred without a single headline.
All of life is different as a result.
It is so profound.
It's like the overall temperature of the globe
going up two degrees, you know,
the children on the street don't notice it,
but the difference in production of vegetation
throughout the planet, you know,
runs into billions of tons of,
you know, the profound implication and effect
on all of life on the planet
by even a couple of degrees shift
which goes, you know, generally unnoticed.
So here we had,
it wasn't just the size of the jump from 190 to 207,
but the fact that it crossed a critical line,
that was what was critical.
So the difference between 31 degrees and 32 degrees
is quite a bit, you see,
because at 31 everything turns to solid or ice
and at 32 it turns to water,
so it's only one degree,
but what a significant degree that,
and the same thing occurs at 212, you know,
211 is water,
212 is steam and turns into gas,
so that crossing over to 207 was very profound
because now the quality, the quality of change,
it wasn't just a quantitative change,
it was a qualitative change.
So we can feel somewhat optimistic
that the future then of mankind
is obviously quite a bit,
going to be quite different,
or is already quite different
than it was or could be.
At 190 it could not improve,
it really couldn't do anything more
than what it did.
At 207 almost anything,
it can go almost anywhere.
And we will see all these changes of,
shifts of consciousness,
now that we're aware that this is taking place,
you can see it in the headlines,
you didn't see it before,
you thought it was just a sequence of current events,
but it's not just a sequence,
you see a shift in the nature, in the tone,
and we hear people talking about the quality of life,
the quality of life,
not only just keeping people alive longer,
but, you know,
ensuring the quality of life,
quality of life.
HMOs are not too interested in the quality of life,
but mankind is, yes.
You mean individuals?
I'm sure even the frogs felt it,
but they didn't express it, you see.
So a lot of people felt the shift,
and they weren't sure what it is,
and so I'm just trying to define it,
and make it rather specific,
so that we know what it is.
I wanted to bring up then,
the difference between creation and causality,
a very significant understanding,
because from 200 down,
the world of form,
the world of force,
you're dealing in what is termed causality.
The world's understanding of what makes things happen
within the visible domain
is that it's like billiard balls,
A hits B hits C,
and you have a sequence of causalities,
and this explains the phenomena
that are witnessed within the world.
When we look at the world from a different viewpoint,
from the non-linear,
we'll see that no such a thing happens at all.
First of all, sequence is only a phenomenon
in human consciousness,
it has no objective reality of its own.
Sequence is a sequence of perception.
You see this, then you see that,
then you see that,
just because you saw them sequentially,
doesn't mean that it's happening sequentially.
The whole idea that there's a happening out there
is an invention within the mind.
The only place a happening occurs
is in your own mind.
In the world there isn't such a thing as a happening or an event.
You can witness anything out there and say,
start now, end now,
so that's an event.
You can make the event this long,
you can make the event this long,
it's when you say it starts,
and it's when you say it stops.
So in the world there is no events.
There is nothing really that requires
an explanation of causality.
Because what you're witnessing
is the sequence of revelation.
What you're really saying is creation.
The common argument,
you know, the creationist versus the evolutionist.
What you're seeing,
what's actually being seen
is the way creation comes about, you see.
Power starts at the top
and then it radiates down sort of
like a series of step-down transitions
and transformers has become the used example.
From the unmanifest,
invisible domain,
in which there is no form,
that which is the onus
out of which all of creation occurs.
Out of the unmanifest comes the manifest.
The power of the unmanifest is infinite.
The power of the unmanifest is innocent.
Even within the domain of advanced theoretical physics
we know that
the amount of potential power
in one cubic inch of space
is equivalent to the entire mass of the universe.
In any cubic inch of invisible space
potential energy, the power,
is greater than the equivalence
of the mass of the entire universe.
That's one cubic inch.
Maybe it's a quarter of an inch.
The understanding of this then is
that the power of the unmanifest,
that which is beyond form,
that out of which form arises,
is infinite.
Infinite.
Unending.
Out of the unmanifest arises the manifest.
We observe that in,
we observe that in meditation
where you notice
if you start
asking yourself what is it that's witnessing,
what is it that's observing,
you go through the various layers of consciousness
until finally you get to awareness
of the self.
The interesting thing is
you go higher and higher in your meditation
is that you'll notice
that the levels are impersonal.
That which is witnessing,
the content of your thinkingness
or your feelingness,
is self-existent.
It is not a personal you at all.
And you find that out of habit
you've called it me,
but when you examine it
you realize it's not really a me
any more than protoplasm is a me.
I mean, you'd say,
theoretically this is me,
and if I pinch it, it feels like me,
but actually it's not me
because if I take it off and throw it away
I haven't lost any me at all.
I'm still the same me, so.
Then,
the argument between
evolution
and creation is a fallacy.
Actually, they're one and the same thing,
you see,
because evolution is nothing
except the way in which
creation manifests itself.
So, if there is creation at all,
then
it is a continuous ongoing event,
a continuous ongoing event.
To understand the nature of God
is to realize that no such thing
is an arbitrary moment somewhere in history.
Did God suddenly roll the dice
and then go off to retire, see?
Which is the common viewpoint, you know.
No, that which is infinite
and that which is forever
and that which is beyond form
is its nature to continuously manifest creation,
and as we see the unfolding of creation
we think that's time
and we think that's evolution.
Evolution then occurs on the level of consciousness
and we see the little animals and
plants and people manifesting
in what we call time
because that's the way
the universe is created.
So, creation is continuous and ongoing,
never ending.
Hmm.
The person says,
how can I know the existence of God?
Well,
God is that
out of which existence arises.
So, the very fact that anything or everyone has existence
is the creation of God,
creation of God
is existence itself.
So, we don't find
happiness in the future,
we don't find it clinging to the past.
We find it by focusing on this instant.
The joy of this instant
is the realization,
the recognition,
the awareness
the feelingness
that it is the presence of God
that is sustaining my existence
this very moment
and the existence of everyone here.
The fact that I am
is proof of the existence of God
and that's all you need.
When I studied theology,
I was an atheist at the time,
but I got a straight A in theology
and,
anyway,
the arguments for God's existence
really blew my mind.
I said,
that wouldn't make an atheist out of anybody.
Based on first cause, please.
So, what they're talking about
is how the mind thinks.
They're not talking about God at all.
To the mind, that would seem
that all causes must have a first cause
and the prime cause would then be God.
But you see how that's really just
poking around in the intellect.
You're circling around in the intellect.
And if you calibrate the energy fuel of that,
I would say it's in the low 400s.
In the low 400s, people are so
enamored of the fact
that they can think now,
that they try to think,
use thinkingness and logic
to answer everything.
We have politically correct answers to everything.
This comes out of the low 400s.
It says, you know,
we think of a corresponding formula,
get everybody behind it,
it'll solve problems,
and we'll pass a law against it.
So,
the way to stop something
is to pass a law against it.
Every day in the paper,
there should be a law against something.
Pass a law against it.
Now you've cured it.
I mean, it's wonderful.
So,
anyway,
the low 400s are enamored
of thinkingness and the intellect
and get carried away with it.
And they write most of our laws,
and they write legislation,
and all these things that sound so erudite.
Except they have a hidden downside,
and then once you put them into operation,
you find the downside is worse than the upside was.
It'll give welfare to all the mothers,
you know,
but the thing is that they put in there,
so long as there's not a man in the house,
well,
what happened as soon as they had welfare?
And if there's no man in the house,
all the men left.
And the inner city,
there wasn't no fathers anywhere.
Why should they be?
If she yee-yanks around,
there's no money.
So,
the unseen downside comes around
to kick out the good of the upside.
And so,
the intellect is limited
in what it can accomplish in society.
So,
we talked about creation
and its contrast with evolution.
So,
creation,
you know,
it's a very complex thing.
It's a very complex thing.
So,
creation comes out of the essence of,
you see,
everything is what it is,
as a perfect expression of its own essence.
Nothing,
there's no need for anything to cause anything else.
Everything in the universe gives forth a radiation,
a vibration,
an energy,
that is characteristic,
individual,
and unique.
Everything in the universe sets forth an energy field
and a vibration.
Throughout all of time,
everything is a vibration.
So,
the calibrated levels of consciousness
are really the levels
at which these vibrational fields
tend to congregate.
They tend to congregate.
And,
using chaos theory,
non-linear dynamics,
says that within what appears to be chaotic,
there is really a hidden inner attractor field.
Within what appears to be a chaotic flight of birds,
for instance,
there is
an energy field,
and you can actually map out that energy field
and draw it as a design,
that the birds,
when you see them moving around,
you see these huge flocks that all feel in unison like this,
or you see them fish underwater.
Millions of fish all turn in unison.
Within the left brain of logic,
there's a presumption that all these fish are somehow looking at each other
and keeping two and a half inches from each other
and staying in line like a bunch of
airplanes out there,
you see,
where the guys are looking at their instruments,
and,
hey,
Joe,
you're getting a quarter of an inch too close to me.
You can hear all these little fish
and little birds and all.
Now,
the minute you look at it,
you realize there's some kind of hidden,
you can actually see,
the hidden energy field
in like an invisible attractor field,
and it's shaped like this,
and each one,
each one singly is following that pattern
within their own mind.
Each one of them
is singly following,
within their mind,
that pattern.
They don't even know what the other one's over there doing,
surprisingly.
Each one is being led by this organization
of this intrinsic energy field,
which in itself is extremely beautiful.
I mean,
you can see the field itself.
You're going to design it and project it,
and in graphics,
you would see the beauty of it.
And not only are dynamics and chaos there,
these are called attractors,
hidden attractor fields.
It was first discovered
by Lorenz who discovered it
when he advanced computers,
allowed Lorenz to examine
the history of weather
over a great expanse of time.
And weather had never been predictable.
It's not within the predictable.
You cannot use a computer
and tell us what the weather's going to be next week.
But he found that
by organizing all this data
over the centuries,
that there was within it
a pattern that revealed
that there was an organizational
hub, you might say,
emanating forth as the changing
weather from century to century.
And he got a computer graphic of it,
and it's called Lorenz's Butterfly,
very, very famous,
Lorenz's Butterfly.
And it looks something like a butterfly.
And that was the organizational field behind
weather over the centuries.
And you can see the same pattern
when you see on TV
these beautiful migrations
of birds wheeling about
or the fish under the sea.
So there you see an energy pattern
hidden from sight,
revealed by their movement,
but it doesn't exist in a measurable domain.
You can't go out there
and with a yardstick
find this invisible pattern
and measure it.
So it decides it didn't really exist,
that there was no organizational pattern.
These calibrated levels of consciousness
then are really,
what we've tuned in on is that
with the energy field of consciousness
to which man is subject
and participates,
there is hidden energy fields
which tend to dominate that field.
Our consciousness tends to be dominated by,
it becomes influenced,
extremely influenced
by the energy fields to which we subscribe.
So once you subscribe
to a certain energy field,
you're really asking
that energy field to come in
and dominate your consciousness.
And you now
will feel a certain allegiance
to these types of attitudes.
So we can calibrate
these various energy fields
and identify them as typical
social attitudes,
vocational proclivities,
even crime rates,
likelihood of various health phenomena.
Because they're characteristic
of certain energy fields
and certainly energy levels.
The most critical one to know about
is over or under 200.
We're going to show you kinesiology
and I'm sure everybody here is familiar with it.
Everybody here has experienced it?
Everybody here experienced kinesiology?
How many have not?
Let's put it that way.
All right.
We will do a very brief exercise
in which we demonstrate the basics of it.
But,
what these energy fields then tell us
is what can be expected.
More significantly,
it tells us what is that level of truth.
So mankind has a great dilemma
throughout all of history.
He doesn't know the difference between truth
and he doesn't know the difference
between truth and falsehood.
And he has no means of discerning it.
The entire legal system
is set upon man's ignorance, is it not?
Why do you need 12 people
to decide what the truth is?
And you can't decide truth
by voting for it.
Yes, I did.
No, I didn't.
I mean, what a ridiculous system, you know?
Oh, wow.
So mankind has had a terrible time
killing each other
and excommunicating people
for old Galileo.
It took the Church almost 500 years
to say,
okay, sorry.
I was very pleased
when Galileo got off the hook.
I was really,
for a while,
I really had a problem
with the Church, you know,
because I thought,
geez, it took you 500 years?
Man, I mean,
what's 450 years?
How did it get off the track,
you know what I'm saying?
Anyway, poor old Galileo
finally got off the hook.
Boy, I felt better.
I was scared to write about
some of the things
I wrote about God.
Look what happened to Galileo.
He was only talking about planets, man.
I mean, here you're talking about
truth throughout all of history.
Oh, you could be right.
So, I'm glad the Church
has given up frying people
so now I can publish the book.
Because it is a sharp razor.
It's a razor's edge.
Truth or falsehood,
first time in mankind's history,
mankind has had to face this.
First time man has ever had to face
that man cannot tell truth from falsehood.
That is so frightening
that very few people
have really picked up
the significance of this book at all.
A group of leaders did
and they invited me to a certain country
where she and I played quite a role
in shifting the whole paradigm.
But mostly people don't get
what it's about.
But you can tell the truth or falsehood
of anything within an instant.
The interesting thing is that
you can tell the level of truth.
Well, I had at home the,
collected the great books
of the Western world.
It was a wonderful find.
I came across them.
It used to cost me 500 bucks.
It's a great book.
And published in 1933,
University of Chicago,
you know, goes through Descartes and Kant
and all the great thinkers
throughout all of time.
And it's a wonderful collection.
The greatest thinkers of the
Western world throughout all of history.
The last one in the series,
I think, is Freud.
And anyway, all of this erudition
and it is fascinating and,
you know, when I was a kid
I was into reading Plato
and stuff while other kids
would go to school
but all the great thinkers
throughout the time
and things, think of all of them. Anyway, being a misfit, I
be sitting home reading Plato and Socrates and stuff. Anyway,
all this dissertation throughout the centuries has all been about
one single thing. How do you tell the truth from falsehood? That's all it's about.
All this collection of the greatest thinking of all the great thinkers of mankind
are all dealing, nor have they even solved, how do you tell
the truth from falsehood? Well, to us it's a snap, of course.
Because we have this wondrous chart here in front of us
which they did not have. And what this chart really says
is truth is what you think it is within certain parameters.
The truth is not that truth is relative, it's that truth is
perceptualized completely differently depending on a level of consciousness.
What is truth? That one level of consciousness is ridiculous
at another. If a person's consciousness is at a
very rudimentary level,
we have to teach them that killing people is wrong.
And if you do it, we will electrocute you.
That didn't make sense, did it? Well, if you do, we will put you in prison forever.
If you don't want to be free, we'll kill you until you want to be free, right?
Bigger, better bombs. Anyway, truth is relative and it depends on context.
That's never been said before.
There's no such thing as truth without delineation of context.
Anything that passes as truth is fallacious if it's missing the context.
And there you have the endless spin put on truth throughout history.
If you don't define context, anybody can say anything and reframe it in some context as truth.
And prove it as truth within that context.
So unless you delineate context then,
uh,
any claim to truth is, uh, fallacious.
So here we have the various levels of truth.
So we say, um, let's just do a few things, uh, for fun.
So, we'll do a few things for fun. Let's see.
We said, first of all, the critical line is 200. 200.
That which is above 200 is concordant with love.
That which is below 200 is not concordant with love.
In fact, people below 200 are repulsed by love.
All the politically correct do-gooders out there.
Oh, we should just love them and they'll get better.
You know that people below 200 are repulsed by love.
It's nauseating.
Please leave us alone.
Disgust.
You guys, the people under 200 are disgusted by loving, understanding, wonderful, compassionate approaches?
They think it's stupid.
They've told me so.
I'm chief of staff at a presidential residence.
Treatment center with 54 teenage girls.
Many of whom are really quite committed to negativity.
We have a wonderful, kind, clean, it's a marvelous place.
It's a dream come true.
I'll say to a kid who just came in from Black Canyon jail.
So, how do you like it here?
She goes,
Thank you. I guess the food wasn't so good.
I mean, the attitude is, you know,
So, you see, that which is negative views love as an enemy.
Oh-ho.
Anything under 200, then, views love as the enemy.
The enemy.
Don't you understand? You're the enemy.
We have a person ask about it.
Well, we just said it's true.
We check ourself all the time.
A lot of times something comes out original and say,
Man, that's wild something.
How so? Okay, good.
Everything,
everything that we study,
everything that we believe in,
every teacher that we follow should be calibrated.
You should know the level of truth in which the person is speaking.
First of all, to make sure that they're legitimate, over 200.
And to give you an idea of what level of reality,
from what level of reality are they speaking,
so that you know what it is you're listening to.
So much of spiritual confusion in the spiritual community
is due to mixing levels.
New mixing levels.
Some gurus said this, and they quoted out of context.
It's because it's out of context,
and you don't know who is,
why it was said to whom, and for what reason,
and in what context of truth you're talking about.
So what we advise everybody to do
is to check out the level of truth of
the writer, the speaker, the course.
Don't accept anything on faith.
Why?
Why should you not accept anything on faith?
Because if mankind was onto the truth,
all these centuries,
our life would be totally different, wouldn't it?
There wouldn't have been any World War II or World War I.
There wouldn't be any plague.
There wouldn't be AIDS all over the place.
There wouldn't have been taxes rising.
All this negativity prevails
because nobody checked out the level of truth of the speaker.
If you checked out Adolf Hitler,
it wouldn't have lasted too long.
Shall we give up our entire life and serve this furor?
You make sure I don't go weak, for God's sake.
Rip you off.
He ripped off the whole country, didn't he?
He ripped off the whole economy,
the whole generation.
Wiped out all the young people.
Corrupted all their morals.
Destroyed their country.
Destroyed everything but beauty.
Brought about the destruction of the Cathedrals of Cologne.
So, let's see.
Picture something or someone you love.
Not picture something you don't love.
So that's the basic demonstration.
People say they've studied this over and over.
They can't get it.
It's only about 18 seconds to get how to look at ideology.
I watched Dr. Diamond do it.
He said, true.
False.
What more is there to know?
You don't have to really know anything more.
It's very simple.
The basic mechanism, however, is not all that simple.
Because Diamond didn't get it,
and neither did anybody,
until we saw that what we're touching into
is not local causality, but non-local.
Consciousness is non-local.
What we're tapping into
is the capacity of non-local consciousness
to recognize truth from falsehood,
to recognize love from non-love.
The Course in Miracles, I think, as I said in the book,
is most of the people here in the Course in Miracles?
Everybody?
Oh, wonderful.
Alright, so,
Course in Miracles itself calibrates at 600.
Let's see if it still does.
Course in Miracles, we have permission to ask, resist.
Calibrates at 600, resist.
Calibrates at 610, resist.
Calibrates precisely at 600.
Very interesting.
Very significant.
See, to know the Course in Miracles calibrates at 600
gives you a whole different orientation
of what the Course in Miracles is,
what it's for,
where it fits into the overall level of truth
as it's been expressed throughout the history of mankind.
600, curiously, is the same level,
same as the level of truth in kinesiology.
Kinesiology, if you ask,
what is the level of reliability of truth in kinesiology,
it says 600.
Hmm.
Course in Miracles is at 600.
Before I did it with Course in Miracles,
in Lewis, enlightenment begins at 600.
And 600, then, is the transition
from form to non-form,
from the linear to the non-linear.
Once a person reaches 600,
in our society, we say they're enlightened.
The chance is one in less than 10 million,
but it does occur.
When it does, it's usually recorded in history
because it's unusual.
However, a lot of people, when they hit 600,
just blitz out and leave.
Nobody rears them.
The whole world wants you to resume this body
and continue on with this pageant here.
And it doesn't seem very attractive to do, you see.
But if you still have something,
if you're not at 1,000, you're only at 600,
you're still vulnerable to love.
And out of love,
you may decide to come back into the body and resume.
And so that's attractive.
You've got to let go of it and get over it.
So we want to calibrate
the level of truth of everything.
In the book Power Versus Force,
we calibrated every chapter.
We calibrated the book as a whole, every chapter.
We went over every page, every paragraph, every sentence.
Examined the entire book using kinesiology.
Is everything on this page correct?
We found we didn't find one error.
We did find one error.
And we said, is there anything out in this chapter?
They said yes.
And then we went page by page.
Is there something on this page?
No, no, no.
We got the page was on.
Is it in the top half of the page?
Bottom of the top half of the page.
Is it this paragraph?
Yes.
Second sentence?
First sentence?
Oh, I got the word.
It was John Lennon.
We took John Lennon out of the sentence,
and then it was perfect.
Let's see.
What's the truth are we talking about now?
All right, so right now we're talking at 750.
In other words, we calibrate what we are saying
from moment to moment.
The kind of material, the consciousness
from which this speech is being expressed, then,
coming at this moment from about 750.
So if we go back to our levels of consciousness then,
I think when I did this we didn't know much
about 700 to 1,000.
No, we didn't.
We stopped at 600 because we didn't have a chance
to check out what goes on from 600 on up.
The levels from 700 to 1,000.
That's what we've been working on more recently.
And the eye of the eye has to do primarily with those levels.
700 to 1,000.
What are those fields of consciousness?
What do they represent?
What is the understanding that arises in them?
The 700s are the levels of Ramana Maharshi,
Nisargadatta Maharaj,
great and famous saints throughout history.
And then Hoang Po.
Hoang Po, the 6th Patriarch.
He said 700 resists.
Over 700 resists.
780 resists.
Over 800 resists.
He said 790 resists.
After that Hoang Po, the transmission of mind.
It is 790.
There are not many people in the upper one
so we didn't spend much time investigating it
until recent times.
The most interesting thing we found about those levels
is that the level of the avatar is 1,000.
The human nervous system cannot tolerate
an energy that calibrates over 1,000.
the calibration of Buddha, Krishna, Jesus Christ, all came out at a thousand.
Their missions were somewhat different, and that's something we sort of asked recently.
The lady who read our work and called up Susan and said she was concerned about the fact
that she felt somewhat guilty as a Catholic, adhering to a lot of Buddhist principles, you know.
Catholicism tends to sort of have a certain rigidity about its own dogma.
So she had felt a certain conflict between Buddhism and Catholicism.
And she and Susie talked about it over the phone, and we thought about it and reflected on it
and checked that ourselves.
But it was just a difference of missions.
You see, they both calibrated at a thousand.
So if Buddha's a thousand and Christ is a thousand, you know,
what is the relationship between their teachings?
And what we got was that the purpose of the Buddha was to teach enlightenment.
Buddha doesn't talk about salvation and the Christian sense of salvation.
The Buddha really presses towards enlightenment.
Jesus doesn't talk about enlightenment.
He talks about salvation.
That used to bother me, too.
I thought, how come Jesus Christ never mentions anything about enlightenment
when he's at a thousand the same as the Buddha?
You know, the Buddha didn't talk about it.
The aim of Buddhism is not to reach a sufficient level that a savior comes and saves you
and takes you to heaven, see.
Except there is pure land Buddhism.
Pure land Buddhism.
Pure land Buddhism is sort of practical, like Jesus Christ is practical.
It sounds to me like Jesus Christ said,
the likelihood of people becoming enlightened in this lifetime is very, very slim.
So instead of teaching people how to become enlightened,
which is not going to be too attractive to them and not appeal to many
and probably not going to happen in one in a hundred million,
let's get practical and talk about what is achievable.
Christian principles are achievable.
And they don't take you into the five hundreds.
And from there, you obviously go to heaven.
And from heaven, you can then go the rest of the way.
So the thinking was, and it still is in many sides of Buddhism,
that the negativity of this planet is so intense
that the likelihood of achieving enlightenment is, you know, so slim
that it's not really a practical way to go for many people.
And so new land Buddhism really says practice spiritual principles
and you will then, the Buddha,
the Buddha of salvation, Amitabha Buddha will then become your savior
and represent you in heaven and from the new land,
which is really one of the levels of heaven,
you can then from there shoot for enlightenment.
So Jesus Christ then sounded to me like a practical person.
He's talking to, you know, the people of his time were very uneducated, et cetera.
And so what he was, you know, what he,
recommended was to avoid sin and follow virtue.
And if you do that, then you will qualify for salvation,
which means starting to go to heaven.
So let's bring it up to date in modern terminology then.
Modern terminology, we'd say,
what Jesus Christ said was avoid everything
that calibrates below 200.
Simple enough, that's really all he said.
Don't hang out below 200.
Those are what he calls sin.
The reason is,
the consequences of sin are very unpleasant.
And Jesus did not recommend that.
If you hang out below 200,
you will not be pleased with the end result, you see.
So he was very practical.
He said, in his own inner self,
he said, enlightenment is for so few.
Why not think of the many?
Much like Mahayana Buddhism is concerned with the many,
and Hinayana is with the few.
Christ was very practical and realized
that only so much was possible.
And then we found out something very interesting.
Let's recapitulate what we found out.
People who calibrate under 200 are able to get to heaven.
That's true or false?
They're able to get to heaven.
Under 200, they're not able to get to heaven.
Under 200, you have subscribed and committed
to that which is false, negative, destructive, evil,
or whatever you want to call it.
Under 200, unaided, one cannot get into heaven.
Amazing.
Therefore, why did Christ die?
He, and this suddenly came to us as an intuition, he said,
he died to save all the people under 200.
Jesus Christ died to save the souls,
or to give the souls of those under 200 to exist.
So Jesus Christ, who died for all of mankind,
died because his energy,
his energy field was so powerful
that it counterbalanced the entire negativity
of everything and everyone under 200,
without whom they would end up in hell.
That's very interesting.
To accept Jesus Christ as one's savior, then,
is crucial if your energy field is under 200.
Over 200, you don't have to be saved by Jesus
to get to heaven.
Let's see if that's so.
You don't have to over 200.
You've got enough spiritual truth within you already
that you'll inevitably, eventually go the whole route.
Under 200, you're like a drowning person.
You cannot save yourself.
So Jesus Christ as savior, then, is a reality,
which we can calibrate the truth of this very day.
He died to save the souls of all those people under 200
because they are so lacking in spiritual truth.
There's no way they can navigate towards the light.
To be able to be attracted by the light,
you would have to be attracted by the light.
And we just said before,
that people under 200 are not attracted by the light.
They are repelled by the light.
Repelled by the light.
So how would those people get this elevation
if they're repelled by spiritual truth and light?
So, anyway, I'm happy now.
Jesus Christ makes much more sense to me.
I agree with him totally.
I think it was a very practical view that he took.
And many branches of Buddhism take the same.
And we've got Hindu, Krishna,
you know, the ancient Vedas also say
that this time the negativity on the planet is so extreme,
the likelihood of becoming enlightened,
it's not too good every 58,000 years.
One revolution of the Zodiac, or whatever it is,
one aeon is in the universe for 58,000 years,
those are the only things.
All right, so,
the thing about studying the nature of consciousness
is you begin to have a context from which
to understand spiritual teachings,
a way to fit them together.
That which was once mysterious, challenging and undecipherable
now becomes quite logical and comprehensible.
So what we want to do by understanding the nature of consciousness
is to make comprehensible the incomprehensible.
It means that certain information that could not be integrated before
can now be integrated.
A lot of information, once you hear it integrated,
the information itself has enormous power.
Once you've heard that, you're going to be a different person.
The information itself propels your consciousness.
The reason the levels of consciousness of people who read Power vs. Force
or hear a lecture like this jump afterwards
is certain information has automatically opened new avenues in their consciousness.
You can see those little synapses just being happy,
bzz, bzz, bzz, bzz, all speaking to each other and saying,
oh, we have to learn from you, we're many a lifetime,
oh, how nice, oh, how nice,
oh, I see, God loves me,
oh, oh, oh, oh.
That's the truth, wow.
Otherwise I wouldn't have existence.
If God had you, you wouldn't have existence.
You'd be squished like a bug.
Just the fact that we're here means that we're okay.
Oh, boy.
I thought you liked to hear that this morning.
I know you were worried about it.
We're all okay.
Well, now that we know we're all okay,
I think we should take a break, don't you?
Exhausted ourselves with all this very interesting stuff.
We'll take a shirt break.
This is the bust of Newark, isn't it?
This is the bust of Newark, you know?
Well, I thought we'll resume as long as we're here.
As long as we're here.
A couple of things I wanted to talk about today.
I want to explain karma because there's no,
see, a lot of what I do, really my thrust in the world is,
to try and make comprehensible that which has not been made comprehensible throughout time,
due to mistranslations, wrong words,
mistranslations from Sanskrit,
through Greek, through Aramaic,
misunderstandings because teachings are heard by people who can tell they're not enlightened,
and therefore they use the wrong word,
they give the wrong inference.
The difference between detached and non-detached,
is profound.
And you'll see most Buddhist literature talks about detached,
and detached is different than non-detached,
two different things.
Or the Buddha has said that there's only one sin,
and that is ignorance.
No, that's a mistranslation.
So we want to correct some of the mistranslations,
misunderstandings, integrate the understanding of karma,
which is one of the crossovers from Buddhism to Christianity
that many people find difficult.
And we'll talk about some of personal thoughts,
experiences,
that led to some of these understandings,
who this person is.
That's what it says on the syllabus here.
Familiarize and explain.
Background and qualifications of the speaker and his research,
well that's neat.
I thought we'd do that a little bit.
Because it'll lead us into some understandings.
That which is speaking is consciousness,
you understand that.
Because in the linear domain,
you presume that this physicality here is the person,
and everybody presumes there's a Dr. Hawkins here
who's speaking and all this, you know.
It's only consciousness that's speaking, you see.
It's only consciousness that's speaking.
And I'm as surprised by what goes on as anyone.
Because I'm misled by I,
I'm telling you from where I speak from,
doesn't know what's going to happen either,
or what we're even going to talk about today,
until it happens.
Because when you live in the instant,
you don't have any,
nothing's telling you what's coming up in the future,
or what just happened in the past,
because neither exists.
So, it's always a surprise.
It's like riding the crest of a wig.
Which is the way to get into the instant present,
is to constantly release and let go of everything as it arises,
like a note of music.
As the note arises,
it's already falling out of its existence, you see.
So you can't stay with the music that just once was,
nor can you live with the music that hasn't arisen yet.
You can only ride the note that's rising at the moment.
And that is a method of meditation,
which you can do throughout the day,
but which sort of takes me out of the world considerably.
So one of my problems this morning is I'm not really in the world too well,
but, so...
I thought to give some organization,
I would just talk about my own personal experiences,
because it says here,
background of the speaker.
Well,
thinking of the background of the speaker,
we'd have to go back some eons.
But before that,
in this lifetime,
the first conscious awareness was
age three.
Before three,
there was nothing but void.
Three in the word,
three was chronological in terms of the world,
the age of the body was three.
All of a sudden, at age three,
what the world says at age three,
out of void, out of nothingness at all,
out of nonexistence,
there was suddenly a profound and stunning
awareness of existence.
I was just suddenly,
suddenly conscious of existence.
Existence as existence,
not as existence as the physicality,
although the physicality seemed to awake
the awareness of existence.
But there was the awareness of existence as existence.
It was very intense,
and it was also nonverbal.
There was no,
three year old doesn't know such words.
Oh, what a three year old notice they have on it.
Anyway,
this consciousness was stunned by
the sudden awareness of existence.
And as soon as there was the awareness
that I exist,
even though I wasn't there yet,
there was no existence as existence,
instantly its alternative came up,
its opposite came up,
of nonexistence.
And instantly I was frightened.
Instantly there was the fear of nonexistence.
So, out of existence arose instantly
the duality of nonexistence.
That was the profound spiritual conundrum,
koan of this lifetime.
Koan.
How do you pronounce it?
C-O-H-E-N.
No, C-O-K-A-O-A.
K-O-A-N.
That was the riddle of this lifetime.
Well,
somebody will have to make some notes.
There's a couple of things we have to talk about.
We have to talk about positionality,
who's going to be the secretary?
Somebody make a note.
Positionality,
we don't want to forget that,
and karma.
Alright, because
what this represented also was
probably, you know, karmically,
where I left off.
Where I left off as a Buddhist monk,
a Hinayana monk.
In some lifetimes,
I would always end up as,
the ultimate reality is void.
Go out of body and experience void.
Because after all,
if you think reality is void
and you leave the body,
what are you into?
You're into void.
From that lifetime to the next,
and then suddenly you're in a new body,
with no connecting in the astral realms.
Because as a Hinayana Buddhist,
you don't believe in all that stuff.
So,
anyway,
I think that's what happened.
Let's see if that happened.
That is what happened.
My guess is right.
Yes.
So, anyway,
out of voidness,
which this,
apparently,
Hinayana Buddhist monk felt
was the ultimate reality,
suddenly there was this
existence.
So,
the first problem was then,
existence versus non-existence.
The reason that's important is
because it represents
the dilemma of positionality.
See, the whole ego arises
out of positionality.
All of duality arises
out of perception,
out of positionality.
All of perception
arises out of positionality.
Of course,
Miracles talks about
the difference between
vision and perception.
Perception arises
out of taking a position.
The minute you take
a position,
you've instantly created
a duality.
You've instantly created
a perceptual,
a way of looking at things
that's going to create
a right and a wrong,
and a good and a bad,
a good and evil.
Positionality creates
a world which mankind
cannot solve.
It's not solvable.
The minute you create
a positionality,
you create
the unsolvable.
There's no way
you can...
There's the Democrats
in their vote.
Once you get a dimple
in reality,
you're screwed.
Tragically,
Pregnant, dimple,
or whatever.
So, positionality
was what I was hit with.
And I didn't realize it
because it was going to
take practically
a whole lifetime
of spiritual evolution
before I returned
to that same
positionality
and had to resolve it.
I had to jump
that paradox,
the paradox
of existence
versus non-existence.
And,
when it did,
the level of
consciousness
took a leap
because that was
the great
block.
The great block
because
it represented
the whole
error
of the ego itself
that it
thinks that
there has to be
an opposite
to truth.
There has to be
an opposite
to truth.
And then you take
a positionality.
So, the ego thinks
that if something
is,
that brings up
the possibility
of is not.
Everything
then brings up
its opposite.
It's profound
because
people
other than myself
frankly don't
understand
that
they think
it represents
true versus
false.
I myself
even thought
so.
In trying to explain
it in terms
of the world
I came up
with the same
fallacy
that the world
does.
If there's
a true
then there must
be a false.
If there's
existence
then there must
be a false.
If there's
an existence
then there must
be a false.
If there's
a truth
then there must
be a false.
If there's
a truth
then there must
be a false.
If there's
an existence
then there must
be a false.
In the past
there were
two kinds
of constructions
that have not
they're not
based on
unreality.
So we said
and it's commonly
taught
that kinesiology
So, when I state truth, then, consciousness recognizes truth, and her arm goes strong.
If I say something that is not true, which is different than false, the absence of truth
is not falsity, it's just the truth.
In the absence of truth, there's no energy to her arm, and her arm goes weak.
So, what we're really getting is not true versus false, but true versus not true.
Well, that's a great addition to a great . . . that is correct.
Oh, wow.
So, what this means then, just as I was presented at age three or four, whatever it was, there's
only that which is, there is only existence, there isn't such thing as nonexistence.
Nonexistence is not a possibility, a possibility would have to be a realizable reality.
Nonexistence by definition is not a realizable reality.
Oh, wow.
Now, there's an epistemologic realization, it would blow your head right off.
All right, the way to understand this then is, reality is what is, what is not is not.
There's no point to fear what is not, because if it has no reality, why fear it, you know?
When we look at, if we run electricity through a wire, we say it's on, and then when there's
no electricity, we don't say, well, now there's offness there.
Truth electricity is either there, or it is not there.
When electricity is not there, it doesn't mean that the opposite of electricity is
now there, something called offness, you understand?
This is very profound, this is the greater understanding that all of mankind has ever
reached.
It thinks.
It's just an offness.
All right.
So, what we discovered then with kinesiology is that truth makes you go strong, and you
go weak merely in the absence of truth, not in the presence of falsehood, because falsehood
does not exist.
Truth is either present or not.
Wow.
Now, suddenly I understood the first page in A Course in Miracles.
Only that truth is true, nothing else exists, therefore there is nothing to fear.
And I finally got it.
Uh-huh.
A long way around.
So, it's presentation that the consciousness was at age three or four, existence versus
non-existence, because in that instant I feared that which is not, I feared non-existence,
scared to death of non-existence.
But if I am, it could have been that.
It could have been that.
It could have been that I would not have been.
You know what I'm saying?
The hypothetical possibility of non-existence arose, and with it, fear.
So, there was the ego reborn in this lifetime, and its fear of non-existence.
So, that took care of me at age three or four, and that was the presentation of the dilemma
of this lifetime.
It took me another, what, seventy years to do that.
All right.
So, anyway.
It was a very profound, it was a presentation, and it was non-verbal, and there was no way
to speak of it to anyone.
And nothing else of any particular interest happened, except that I was not particularly
physical.
Now, I wasn't much into physicality, I like nature, but wrestling and stickball and sticking
greasy fingernails in people's eyes was not my idea of fun.
So, other boys sort of enjoyed this physical adversarial kind of amusement, which I was
always very boring.
But, other than that, I seemed like a normal boy, and I used to say I graduated at the
top of my class in kindergarten.
I got a straight A in crayons.
I made that joke up.
It's stupid.
Anyway, you don't want to sound too serious or anything.
So, anyway, in teenage, I did have a problem in that I'd be sitting in class, and in the
minute if I started to think about who I was, think of I.
Think of I.
The thought of I, the self would begin, that which the world calls the self, would begin
to dissolve.
If there was the self, I would lose track of an individual, discrete entity called I,
which the world addresses David all the time.
I assume that's his name, because that's what they kept calling him then.
And, this would sort of tend to dissolve.
Well, one time I had a paper wrote when I was about 12 or 14.
I wrote about this in the back of the book, Power Versus Self.
There was a note about the author at the end.
Well, they probably wanted to know who he is, so I put it in the back.
And then, later people said, you should put that at the front.
Well, anyway, I put it in the back.
Anyway, about 12 or 14, somewhere in that, I had this paper wrote, and in the middle
of a blizzard, it was very dark and I got lost in this blizzard, it was many miles from
home, and I was free, you know, I actually sort of freed from death, and so I dug into
a big snowbank there in Wisconsin.
In Wisconsin, the snow is very high.
So, I dug into a big snowbank there, a big one.
and the snow was very high on Saturday night, 12 feet high or 15 feet high.
So anyway, I dug through the, into the snow and got into this hole out of the wind.
You know, the wind was fierce.
It was about 20 blow or something.
And I snuggled in there, and very soon, very quickly,
a profound sense of relaxation and peace came on me.
It was really incredible.
It was the infinite, exquisite sensation of gentleness.
It was like exquisite love just took me over in this golden presence.
And to this day, I wish I'd stayed there anyway.
Oh, all time disappeared.
That which, this golden, infinite presence of exquisite love,
melting, just melted away any personal.
So...
There was no self, which dissolved.
There wasn't any personal self.
There was just this infinite presence.
Not different than that which I am.
And I saw that which I am is before all universes
and will exist long after all universes have come and gone.
Beyond all time, beyond all dimension, beyond all universes, beyond all description.
This infinite presence.
So, there I stayed for some eons or so.
And the next thing I knew, my father was shaking my knee to come on our Model A Ford,
29 Model A Ford, and located the body there in the hole and retraced the paper route.
And then, anyway, he was quite shaken by all this.
And so, father reaches in and grabs the knee.
And I really was extremely reluctant to resume this physicality.
But I got that he believes in death.
I could see that he would think that if this body,
if this body didn't start to move again, that it was dead, and that he, that I had died.
And this would bring profound grief.
So, it's the idea that it's absurd, you know.
But anyway, in his state, it seemed like a reality.
In my state, it was an absurdity.
Absurdity.
But I saw that he couldn't see my state.
So, for the sake of love, then, I re-energized this body.
And it was probably a mistake.
So, this happened on several occasions throughout my life.
Anyway, it happened another time under similar conditions.
And I was doing rebirthing, and the breathing stopped.
And the same space, I went back into being that way, which I am.
And there was no necessity to breathe again.
I couldn't see any reason to breathe.
But I didn't seem to need to breathe.
I wasn't interested in breathing.
But the rebirther took quite a concerned interest in whether I breathed or not.
Laughter
He was teaching me this.
He was teaching me this technique, you know.
And anyway, I loved him.
So, telepathically, I'm getting from him, breathe, Dave, you know.
And I got his position.
I was his first patient, his first rebirther.
He was a rebirther.
He had just come back from the place that grew green pig vegetables there by the sea.
I forget where.
Benhorn, yes.
Well, he had taken the course of miracles to Benhorn.
He had taken the course of miracles.
He was now into rebirthing.
Dave, I've got to show you this.
He takes me on this rebirthing trip.
Anyway.
Anyway, there was no desire.
And I could see the same thing happening all over again.
Here I am in this incredible space.
Here's this idiot thinking that I'm going to die if I don't breathe again.
And I see that the whole world is going to believe, believe that he did.
Dave died.
So, and it's going to be on his head.
So, he's looking at me, you know, projecting the position I'm going to leave him if I don't breathe again.
I said, okay.
All right.
So, again, I made the same fatal mistake.
Laughter
And out of love resumed it.
And, but then the more interesting things that happened were perhaps in spiritual work, you know,
I would belong to the first Zen Institute.
And I was a psychiatric consultant to the Zen monastery and the Episcopal Diocese and the Catholic Diocese and the Catholic nuns.
And so my spiritual experience was sort of used in a way to differentiate.
Um, abnormal religious states from legitimate states.
And, uh, that was before we had a kinesiology or any way to test such things.
Anyway, at one time I, um, was in a profound state of illness.
And, uh, I went into this profound state of illness.
Um, one time I went out of body.
I might as well relate all these experiences.
There's a difference between near death and out of body.
And I just want to make that clear.
Near, near death was the golden, uh, exquisite.
When you calibrate the low.
Consciousness of that, uh, uh, field of energy, uh, you get it's quite a high, high field.
And, uh, the person's consciousness is not the same.
Once, a near death experience, you're different.
Uh, you see the fear of death disappears altogether.
I never had the fear of death from age 12 on.
The fear of death disappears and very often their whole life is somewhat transformed.
Out of body is, is different.
Out of body, uh, happened one time when I was very physically sick.
And, uh, suddenly found myself in mid-air, six feet over this physical body, looking down at the bed, and there was Dave in this bed.
Ha, ha, he was a mess, I'll tell ya.
I looked at him, I thought, God, he should be leaving this world soon.
And, uh, but this was totally different.
There was no golden light.
There was no exquisite presence.
But there was, um, weightlessness and, uh, thought, feeling, uh, and, uh, capacity to see and hear went with, uh, spirit body.
Went with the etheric.
Here I am up in space, and I look, here's this body, it's almost exactly like this one, except it's, uh, almost like invisible.
You can see right, right through it, it had no weight.
And a slight thought would move it anywhere in space, it was like weightless.
And I remember looking down and seeing the physical body laying in the bed, and, uh, later that was interesting because I realized that, uh,
the quality of hearing, thinking, feeling, et cetera, goes with the etheric body.
It doesn't go with the physical body.
And the illusion is, uh,
that it's happening through the physical body.
No, you can hear without the body's ears, and you can see without the body's eyes.
Because they were laying there in the bed, and I was up there seeing and hearing.
So, anyway, if you calibrate the level of consciousness of the entity before and after this experience, it's the same.
So the difference between out-of-body is that you're the same person, it's just that your etheric and physical are separated.
And the near-death is quite a different, more profound, transformative experience.
Uh, then, uh,
I just wanted to clarify, because I saw a TV documentary on it,
and it confused the two states,
treated near-death and out-of-body as though they were the same thing.
And they're quite a bit different, quite a bit different.
Let's, let's calibrate, what was the level of, uh, snowbank experience, you know?
Do we have permission to calibrate that resist?
It was over 600 resist.
It was over 700 resist.
It was 750 resist.
It was 800 resist.
It was 900 resist.
It was over 900 resist.
Oh, my God.
Oh, wow.
Anyway, uh,
um,
the Divine Presence was actually the Divine Presence,
and, uh,
I always thought it was God, but didn't want to say anything.
See, you can calibrate where, what was that experience,
that you had or other people had.
I mean, you can go back through history, you know,
the spiritual experiences of saints and various people.
What's real, what's not real.
What was the level of calibration of that?
I mean, you begin to get a feeling for the entire spiritual dimension
of what's real, and where does it fit into the overall reality,
and many supposed dilemmas result in self.
Anyway, at the bottom, uh, then, uh, at a certain age,
I suddenly became, well, I was brought up Episcopal,
and I was very religious, and, uh, I was a boy soprano,
uh, boy soprano with, uh, a choir and a full orchestra
and a cathedral, and I sang the Obligato to Panis Angelicus.
Oh, it brought tears to the eyes of me
and everybody in the room.
Here's a soprano boy, Obligato, with his voice coming out of
I don't know where.
And, uh, this whole floor, I mean, it was really a great moment.
So religion, you know, used to just lift me up,
the sheer aesthetics of it, the sheer beauty of it,
the sheer beauty and joy of the cathedral,
uh, and the entire pageantry of it, you know,
it's an exquisite experience.
Uh, well, anyway, so, then one time,
I was looking at, uh, the suffering of man,
mankind.
Uh, all of a sudden, um, I came into the awareness
of the totality of the suffering of all of mankind,
like I saw all of it.
It was beyond all dimension, all capacity to describe.
The totality of the suffering of mankind throughout all of time
was so profound that in that instant I became an atheist.
I said, um, any God that could allow this possibility
could not be God to me.
I mean, the fire.
I'm a profound atheist.
A dedicated atheist.
Not a fool around atheists.
I was as serious about atheism as I had been about religion, you see.
And I went to a Jesuit university.
Here I am with this profound atheist at a Jesuit university.
I'm getting straight A in theology and Thomas Aquinas
and all this.
And in myself, I'm an atheist, you know.
So, anyway, uh, that was the position I took.
One that a great part of mankind takes.
I understand it because I experienced the very essence of it.
Without understanding karma, without understanding the true nature of God,
anybody with any brain really ought to be an atheist.
If you think God is the cause of all that occurs in this universe, in this world,
and you still believe in him, then you must be pretty depraved.
So, the honest arguments for the existence of God
have made atheists and many an honest man.
And I was one of them.
How could an all-merciful, all-loving, all-beneficial, beneficial God
allow that degree of negativity and suffering of all mankind?
And at that point, I became an atheist.
And I was a very serious atheist, too.
I mean, I really took it seriously.
I loved religious discussions and theological discussions, you know,
and I was really good at it, too.
You know, I could really, like, take a snack, take that.
I was really good at it.
So, anyway, I was out to destroy the false gods.
I didn't realize they were false gods.
But it was the false concept, conceptions of God,
that I had taken issue with.
And as it turned out, certainly so.
Really, the misconceptions of God is what anybody
with any real profound spiritual sense cannot buy,
unless there's profound negative depictions of God.
So, anyway, I was a profound atheist.
And after some years went by,
I then developed some other illnesses.
And at one time, I hit a state of profound spiritual blackness,
profound depth, spiritual depths.
Really, the pits of hell, in a way.
Pits of hell.
Despair and blackness beyond all description.
And in this black despair, it was really sort of the pits of hell.
You know, the upper parts of hell are torture and the devil
and all that kind of stuff.
But those are just the upper realms.
And the bottom realms are those of profound spiritual desolation,
cut off from all light, you might say.
And in that state, here I'm an atheist, a devoted atheist,
I said, and I thought, I'm probably going to die.
I thought, I'm about to die.
And I thought, before I do, I mean, what if I'm wrong?
In a couple of minutes, this could be tacky.
You know, you could be on the other side.
Okay, boy.
A few errors we ought to look into here, you know.
I said, well, if there is a God, I ask him to help me.
And then, I don't remember anything.
I don't remember anything.
And when I came to, when I came to some days later,
or whenever it was, I don't know,
everything had been transformed.
All of existence.
My experience of existence, of my own existence.
Everything was totally transformed.
There's only a brilliant...
The divinity of all things shines forth equally
as the essence of all things being what they are.
The exquisite beauty of the infinite presence is overwhelming.
And the mind, what the world calls the mind, it stopped.
No thought, no thought possible.
The mind still doesn't think.
It doesn't think at all.
This morning it wasn't thinking about anything.
It was wandering around, I don't know what's going on.
Anyway, the mind just came to a stunning stop.
And nor would there be any, even the slightest,
possibility of having a thought in that presence.
The presence is of such infinite power.
Power is so infinite.
It's like the intrinsic power that holds everything together.
Everything that holds this room together.
Power.
And this infinite power is also exquisitely gentle.
And closer, closer than what one thinks of as one's self.
What you think of as yourself.
Is really quite distant from what you are.
And when you, the realization of the self with a capital S
is more profoundly one's home.
The source of one's existence.
Where one really lives.
Than what had been thought of as one's self.
So this infinite presence then,
which took the place of all that had prior existence,
John Dowdall thought.
John Dowdall thought of an individual separate self,
or an I.
The world called data on earth to figure out what they were talking about at the time.
When it first happened.
There was quite a difficulty in pronouns.
And the people were always talking to this body.
And it would mystify me.
Why the hell are they talking to that body?
I'm not even there.
I mean, why are they?
And then I realized that they assumed that this body is me.
Oh wow, I got that.
So it was quite a while, some years in fact,
that I could figure out how to really function within the world again.
Because the world didn't, the world, the mind didn't say anything.
People spoke with things that seemed to have no reality or relevance whatsoever.
And there's a split second of translation.
I see the person's mouth speaking.
The words impinge on the ear, but they don't have any meaning.
And the Holy Spirit translates that into an understanding of what is being said.
Or I'll say to somebody, what are they saying?
And that gives me the moment I need.
To interpret what is happening within the world of form.
So there was some years of trying to live within the world of form.
That's how I left New York City and the big practice I had there and all.
And I went out to a small town.
And for about ten years I had nothing to do with the world.
I just got used to the state and how to regain functioning within it.
So that was quite a remarkable thing.
Then there were various sensations along the way.
In the eye of the eye, I think I wrote about them.
People do a lot of spiritual work.
They really need others to compare their experience with.
Because there isn't all that many people out there to talk to about it.
So I thought, well, maybe a lot of the things I consider irrelevant maybe are not irrelevant.
Maybe I should write about them.
Maybe I should...
There was a period when the kundalini energy was running up my spine.
It was exquisite.
I mean, it wasn't happening to anybody else.
I could run around and say, hey, there's something running up your spine.
It feels exquisite, like a little great orgasm going on.
All the time in your brain.
Whoa, Doc, you really tipped over, huh?
Seen too many crazies, huh?
So anyway, yeah, it was exquisite energy.
You know, I forget what I was doing at the time.
But anyway, some spiritual practice.
It can happen to almost any spiritual practice.
You do the Course in Miracles and you have all kinds of incredible experiences.
Anyway, this energy is running up the spine and up my back.
And it's pouring into my brain.
And it's exquisite, exquisite all the time.
Exquisitely pleasurable.
Just, oh.
And if I would think of the left side of my brain, it would sort of like go into the left side of the brain.
If I think of the right side of the brain, it would go into the right side of the brain.
Oh, wow.
And so this exquisite energy went on for years.
And then it would come down this way and sort of go out through the heart.
And I'd be driving somewhere and all of a sudden this energy would pour out down the road or something.
And a very exquisite sensation.
And I'd say, well, I don't know what.
And this energy would go down the highway some miles ahead of where I was.
And when I turned the bend, there was an accident.
The car is upside down and the wheels are still turning.
And this energy is pouring into the car.
And I got that there was no need to stop physically.
There was no need for physical assistance on my part.
This energy seemed to be handling everything that needed to be handled.
And then as I go down the road, it stopped again.
And I'm going down the highway again.
All of a sudden it started again.
Wow.
It's going around the next bend a couple of miles ahead.
Exquisite.
Just pouring out into this like a radiance.
And I come around the bend and there, my God, there's another accident.
This time the emergency vehicles are on the way.
And the lights are flashing.
They're coming down the highway.
And this energy poured into the car.
And this energy poured into the people in that wreck.
And did the same thing again.
So this peculiar phenomena would occur.
And various paranormal, what the world calls paranormal phenomena would happen.
In the Sanskrit, it's called the various cities.
You know, the S-I-B-D-H-I-S.
And you're warned not to get trapped by them or enamored of them.
First of all, they happen as a result of the presence.
They have nothing to do with you.
This divine presence did all these things.
This presence would answer people's questions.
It would phrase responses that the body would verbalize to the person's question.
And it would be amazing, I think.
I said, wow, that's pretty neat.
And then there was clairvoyance.
There was this envision.
There was, what do you call it, psychometry.
Where you pick up something, you know, whose book this is.
And you can see who that person is.
And you've got everything about that person.
Just from touching it.
And that would occur automatically.
And all those things came and went.
You know, they would last for, oh, four or five years.
Electronic things would fix themselves.
And somebody would come over to repair a 100-amp amplifier.
And I'd look at it and I'd say, I don't know, it looks okay to me.
And instantly the thing would go off.
And the guy looks at it and he says, whoa.
What did you do there?
I said, I didn't do it.
I said, there's some kind of presence that does these things.
I said, it all started from reading The Chorus of Miracles.
He said, gee, I want that book.
I had exactly one copy left, so I gave it to him.
He says, well, thank you.
And he left and tears me to the surface for you.
And he only came over to get The Chorus of Miracles.
That's why, you know, God sent him over.
He came over to get The Chorus of Miracles.
I never saw him again.
But those things were, they lasted for, I don't know, five or six years, you know.
Some years it was, I hadn't even been in the same, that state before.
And people would say, we're running out of gas.
And I'd say, oh, there's a Saccone station a mile or two down the road.
I could see it in my mind.
It's all exactly where it is, you know, around the trees there.
And so this phenomenon would occur.
So, yes, the paranormal does have a certain reality.
Yeah, yeah, it does exist.
And what we notice about Scripture is it's going to exist.
But what we don't notice about Scripture is that Scripture says, it doesn't say the supernatural doesn't exist.
It just says, don't go there.
Don't go there.
Why?
Because you get caught in the astral realms, that's why.
You get caught in the astral realms.
And so much of what people think is spiritual, especially in New Age groups,
that don't have being on the earth, is, you know, endless preoccupation with astral realms.
There are endless astral realms.
There are heavens upon heavens, and there's hierarchies,
and there's masters and gurus,
and followers,
and mystical carryings on,
and people with the colored rays,
and people with the light beams,
and people with the...
Ah, the world's full of them.
So the astral domains is not the same as the spiritual reality.
So I want to make that clear,
because a lot of seekers get pulled into early astral domains.
If you're going to listen to somebody channeling master so-and-so,
you better calibrate the energy of master so-and-so on the other side.
Very, very good.
Because very often master so-and-so is in the control,
in the control,
and calibrates less than 200.
His only desire is to control people out there.
He's got them sitting out there waiting for UFOs to land and save them in the middle of the desert
and all kinds of crazy crap.
And these are just demons that get a kick out of scaring people,
especially if they think they have some kind of...
They're on some spiritual trick, you know.
Well, if you're a demon,
wouldn't you just love to twist people's noses around a spiritual trick
and say,
take that,
sit out in the middle of the desert and starve to death?
They do, you know.
They'll go out in the desert and wait for God to show up.
All kinds of strange things.
So one reason to calibrate things is
it's not that a channeled teaching is necessarily negative.
It may well be positive.
You should know who is it,
you know, what is the level of truth of the consciousness,
because many people go into,
ooh, ah, it's all master.
Baba, ding dong.
And, you know, you go,
what is the energy of Master Ding Dong?
I'm going to think it was very Chinese Baba right now.