Let me first introduce myself a little bit and how we get to know each other, Dr. Hawkins and me.
I'm from Korea. We're a new meditation group trying to settle in Sedona. This is maybe a
third month staying in Sedona, and we happen to know each other by a Korean doctor who wants to
translate David's book, The Power Versus Force. Anyway, through this book, we got to know each
other quite closely, and we admired his effort to do such an enlightening work in a scientific sense.
Now, this book will be soon translated into Korean, maybe at the end of the year.
So after we're publishing his book in Korean version, we want to introduce him more,
because probably lots of people in my country get more curiosity, you know, who this author is about.
There's three million members in Korea? Yeah, yeah. It's kind of very fast-growing meditation.
26 centers? Yes. And now how many centers are in the United States? 13 now. 13?
Already? Yeah. Well, this is not something new. It is really ancient spiritual practice taught or
transmitted from our very, very Asian ancestors, but it had been lost for a while. But now,
over the last decade, we're rediscovering this tradition, and it's getting very popular at home.
I was reading the book that Dr. Lee lent me. Right.
Six thousand years of Korean spiritual tradition. Right.
And the founder of the main religion is about 2500 BC.
What was his name? Dan Young? Dan Young? Dan Goon.
Huh? Dan Goon.
Yeah, that's right. Right. Anyway, so today we originally focused on his
personal journey in terms of spiritual evolution. And in his book, at the last part of his book, he
very briefly...
tells most of his spiritual journey in a very essential form. So what I want to do today is go
through in each stage of his spiritual awakening and go to more details. And also, I have some
questions as a spiritual practitioner, whatever you say. So we're going to follow the basic
format of his writing in the last part of his book. So you're a spiritual student?
I think so.
No, no, no.
But you're a committed full-time student?
Well, what I'm saying, the student is, you know, everybody, in a sense, we are
best spiritual students once you became a human form.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, that's what I meant.
That's a good way to define the human experience.
Why don't, for us, for our potential reader in Korea, why don't you just be describing
where you're born, and what is your, you know, family looks like, and...
Something about my early life, yes. Well, I grew up in the Midwest, in Wisconsin. It was
during the depression, and...
You're born in 19...
27.
And the depression was on, and soon after the depression, there was World War II. And so, I grew
up with that, in a tradition...
Protestant family. I was brought up high Episcopal. I was an altar boy. I was a choir boy.
The family was rather religious. And actually, when I became a teenager, I read Thomas Paine's
Age of Reason and became an atheist. And I was always a hard worker, you know. I had
the longest paper route in the state of Wisconsin, 17 miles every day, and made $50 a month.
And I paid my way through school. And I was born with a reasonably high IQ, so it didn't
take me long to start.
I started to study, so that gave me time to work, so that I could earn the tuition to
go to schools. So I sort of worked my way through school, you know. And then in World
War II, I was on a minesweeper. I was in China, in the East China Sea, Formosa, Nationalist
China now, in the South Pacific. And then after the war, I went to Teachers College
for a couple of years.
And then medical school. And I specialized in psychiatry.
I didn't...in our private conversation, didn't you say you were in Jay Street Theological
College, or over there?
Well, after two years at Teachers College, I transferred to a Roman Catholic university,
Marquette University. And I studied theology. At the time, I was an atheist, you know. At
the time, I studied theology. I was the first man to be an atheist. That's the first thing
that I did. I was the first man to be an atheist, and then at that time, I was teaching this.
Did you follow any Catholic?
No. Did you follow any Catholic?
theology I got a straight A in theology and Catholic ethics and Thomas Aquinas
and all and I used to drive some of my fellow students crazy because they were very
religious and were getting C's and I was atheistic and getting A's that drove me
nuts but I was always intensely interested in religion one way or the
other either pro or again you see did you believe what you wrote in your
papers no I'm just no I didn't know no Thomas Aquinas is proof of the
existence of God and things you know I thought they were interesting and I used
to argue religion all the time you know after class we would go over and drink
beer and argue religion so you basically playing with the theology rather than
studying it well I wanted to know what people believe
I
believe
'm alright if you're gonna disagree with something you better know a lot
about it you know so when you became a psychiatrist I mean when I look back at
it retrospectively now I see what I was doing you know I was what I was really
saying was that the intellect cannot prove the existence of God you know it
can give it a reasonable hypothesis but I didn't know it but later on it is only
the subjective experience of the presence of God
and that blows the intellect out the window
so where they're gone anyway oh I'm sorry I disturbing your life story no I
was just telling you the rough the rough of it and and I was psychoanalyzed
you know I was in psychoanalysis and I did psycho analysis for years and I had
a very large psychiatric practice in New York probably the biggest cooking company hang around there for many years he ended up getting
biggest in the country, I guess. We had 50 employees. We had 2,000 outpatients. I saw
1,000 new patients a year. And then I had a very large hospital practice where I was
chief of psychiatry. And I always had about 40 private patients in the hospital at all
times that I saw three times a week. And I then got into the relationship between nutrition
and brain chemistry and mental and emotional illness. And we did a lot of avant-garde work,
you might say. And patients came from all over. And I wrote about it in a book I did
with Linus Pauling. I was writing a book about this new approach to mental illness. At the
time, it was a Freudian era. And they thought that all mental illness was due to how you
were brought up, you know.
Okay.
And I looked at these
severe psychosis and schizophrenia and bipolar disorder and various addictions. And it was
obvious it was biochemical. So I was writing this book, and Linus Pauling asked if he could
put a chapter in and edit the book. So we published a book in 1973 called Orthomolecular
Psychiatry with Linus Pauling and myself. And I had this very large practice until the
late 70s.
Nice.
And then at that time, I left practice and moved to a small town and pretty much withdrew
from the world for about 12 years.
Now you're in Sedona?
And now I've, after 12 years, which I'll explain later, it took some years to learn how to
function back in the world again. During those 12 years, I pretty much lost track of the
world.
And then there was a...
There was a girls' treatment center that didn't have a psychiatrist, and they asked if I would
come there. And that led to one thing to another, and now I'm back into full-time practice again.
So those are the outlines of my physical life, you know, what the body does in the world.
The body goes about doing all these things, you know, and I'm just the witness of it.
I don't know what it's going to do next. It's always surprising.
Right.
Yeah.
Well, we'll see.
In your book, you start your spiritual journey from at age 3. You wrote, like, there occurring
a sudden full consciousness of existence. So you suddenly felt what is the meaning of
I am, right?
Yes.
So maybe we can start about this.
Well, you know, the first recollection, the birth of, you know, when a person says I,
I, what do they mean by I?
Well...
Yes.
Well, before age 3, there didn't seem to be any I. And then suddenly about age 3, there
was sudden awareness, very intense awareness of existence. Suddenly I realized that I exist.
It was full-blown realization without any thoughts, no language, no words. The realization
that I exist, and almost instantly came the fear, if I exist, hypothetically, I'm going
to exist.
And hypothetically, it could have been that I would not have existed. And so there was
then the fear of nonexistence. So I was confronted with the fact of existence that the minute
you say I am, the minute the ego is born, instantly comes the fear of nonexistence.
So intrinsic to the ego then is I am, and therefore it is possible that I would not
be, you know.
I don't know how many 3- or 4-year-olds worry about that.
I don't know about such things, but I did. And it was a very intense experience, yeah.
Was it like a constant concerning, or just a one-kick experience?
No, it was a sudden onset.
Oh, okay.
So the I was born, you see. People worry about who am I, and when was I born? The physical
body was not the I, you see. The birth of saying that I exist, that I exist, that I
exist.
That was the beginning of I. So that's when I was born. When I was born, the body was
already 3 years old. So it's like I used a body that was already in existence and took
it over and said I, and now I am.
Okay, was there any special accident or anything which created this kind of awareness,
or were you just, you know?
It was just a sudden awareness, yeah.
There's no cause?
There's no correlated accident or special surrounding?
No.
No? Okay.
No. Just, I think in everyone's life, if you look back, there is a moment when you were
born. And that's when you were born. The physical body is irrelevant. You're born when you say
I am. Then suddenly, now you have the fear of nonexistence. The fear of death, you know.
So everybody gets obsessed with the fear of death from that moment on.
Yeah, well, it's what you're describing.
Yeah.
It's an experience. It's quite understandable. But something what surprised me is the age
of 3.
Yeah, 3, 4, somewhere around there.
Because I, you know, I can't really remember what I've been thinking about when I was 3.
It's too early, David, anyway.
The other thing we could do would be calibrate the level of consciousness of these various
experiences for curiosity. You want to do that?
Okay, well, if you want.
I've never done it, but, you know, because in the book we calibrate the level of consciousness
of various things. We could do that now. I've never done that with that experience. You
want to do that?
Okay.
We'll just say what was the level of that experience, just for the fun of it.
Yeah? Okay. Just put your arm on. You don't have to put it down. Just, here, you put out
your arm.
Oh.
Okay. Now, when I say resist, you resist. Resist. Okay.
Okay.
Okay. Picture someone you love. Got it? Resist. Okay. Picture Adolf Hitler. Resist. Okay.
You're okay.
All right. Now, the experience at age 3 or 4, whatever it was, did that calibrate over
400? Resist. Did that calibrate over 500? Resist. Did that calibrate over 600? Resist.
Did that calibrate over 650? Resist. Did that calibrate over 700? Resist. 650, around
650.
Wow.
I never knew that. So, there must have been some karmic predisposition to have an experience
that calibrates at an amazing 650, because the ego stops at 600, so the ego goes up to
600.
Hmm.
Various aspects of the spiritual ego take over from 600, but 600 is really, you know,
600 is really the level of enlightenment already.
Yeah, I think so.
To see oneself. So, what I saw at the time then was the I as existence only, because
I didn't identify with the body.
Right.
It wasn't that I the body am, but that one is, oh, I see, that one has a separate consciousness,
separate from the oneness of God. Wow. Hmm. So, I didn't realize that before, because
I never looked back at that moment, but that moment then was actually a period of enlightenment
at 650 to realize, it must have been more than 650. Let's go, we'll go again.
Okay.
That experience was over 650, resist. That was over 680, over 700, 700.
740, resist. 720, resist. 730, resist. 740, resist. Yes, that would be around 730, see,
to realize that that which I am is existence itself.
Right.
Is already a very advanced state of consciousness.
Mm-hmm.
So, that advanced state of consciousness came on spontaneously, unwittingly, of its own
at age three or four. That's amazing.
Yeah.
Yeah, well, that tells me, again, in terms of spiritual evolution, your physical body,
the age of your physical body, does it really matter? You know, I think what you experienced
at age three, kind of an evidence. We shouldn't so much attaching how these persons are.
Perhaps many years as a Buddhist monk, huh?
You're right.
I think so.
I can tell, you know, you are such a very ancient soul, I think.
So, let's see.
Was that?
I've never asked these questions before.
Was that experience the result of many lifetimes of meditation as a Buddhist monk?
That was as a result of many lifetimes.
Resist.
Oh.
That was from following the Mahayana path.
Resist.
No.
That was following the Hinayana path.
Resist.
Oh, yes.
That was following the Hinayana path, see, because one time when I was surrendering every
aspect of the ego.
I went into the Absolute Void.
The Absolute Void is where you go with Hinayana, you see.
And there, one is beyond existence and nonexistence.
Well, actually it's a mistake, because what you're experiencing almost is nonexistence.
And then you say, well, who would be experiencing nonexistence?
And you see already there's an error.
What can I say?
To say that I am the void, that I don't exist.
That I don't exist as separate, you know, as consciousness, there would have to be
consciousness there to say that.
So, already it's a lie.
So, well, anyway, that's later in the story.
Right.
Yeah.
To switch from Hinayana to Mahayana was one thing I did in this lifetime then.
Okay.
That makes sense now.
I never looked at that before.
Right.
Anyway, then you said you're gone.
You're gone.
And then you even, and then you're living in the world, and you, you're gone through
childhood and all the adolescence, and you still carry all these paradoxical questions
of existence.
So...
I'll tell you how I experienced that...
Okay.
...because see, none of these things occurred in thought.
These things that, they are not things like you would think about.
Uh-hmm.
So, this was not like intellectual ruminations about a philosophical question.
I don't want the viewer to misunderstand that.
The difficulty with the average intelligent, educated person is when they hear what is
a purely subjective spiritual experience, they translate that into the intellect, and
it has nothing to do with the intellect.
But I would be sitting in class in grade school, and that which I had now identified as myself
in the view of the world, this body and the name, would begin to disappear into just the
state of existence itself.
The ego was very fragile, I mean, it was practically nonexistent, it was like it would disappear.
And there was only this, you know, you would disappear into nothingness, into the infinite
void, into infinite awareness.
Awareness itself and the individual self would no longer exist again.
It was constantly threatening to disappear into nonexistence all the time.
And that would scare me, and I would like intensify my identification with this personal
self to bring myself back to being here now, this person named David, you know.
That was a funny experience, it would scare me.
I never told anybody about any of these things, you know, but I mean, what would you say?
So during the...
During your childhood, you constantly had this kind of experience, like a continuous
experience.
Like you have to hang on to this ego or it will slip away from you.
So how, what kind of boy you were, I mean, were you like an introverted and read lots
of books, or you were extroverted?
Well, I had a couple of, I always had a couple of intense close friends, but I was more an
introvert.
I didn't care much for sports and contact sports.
To me it was boring.
Games have always been boring, so it was just another boring game.
And you know, I was busy reading Plato's Republic, or Sophocles, or the aphorisms of some philosopher.
And then I was an avid collector, I was, I studied bugs, I was an etymologist, amateur
etymologist, and chemist.
I did, I studied physics, memorized the periodic table of elements in their atomic weights.
So when other kids were playing stickball, I was doing that, you know.
Well, my question is then, how about, is there anybody, you know, when we're looking back
on our childhood, they're always very influential figures, you know, like for me, my sister,
I had a very intensive, constant conversation.
Oh, yes.
Just as she understands me and the whole family, was there anybody around you like
that?
Well, my father and I were very close.
And I was very close to my grandfathers, I had wonderful grandparents, wonderful parents.
My father was a hard person, you know, a hard person.
And I loved him intensely, and he and I got along extremely well, and I also picked up
all his bad habits.
Like what?
I don't want to mention on television.
So, and my mother supported my intellect, you know, she took me to the science museums
and one side of the family was aristocratic, one side of the family were social, you know,
what you would call the social register.
And my grandmother was a debutante.
So one side of the family were, my great-grandfather was the mayor of Milwaukee, another one was,
Episcopal bishop, and the third one founded Northwestern Mutual Life Insurance Company.
So one side of the family was a very educated and upper class, you might say.
And then the other side was, my father's side was more like creative.
My father was a great musician, great pianist, and he was about to go on a world tour when
his mother...
didn't want her young boy traveling around the world by himself, he was an only son.
So he was more the creative, heart person, and my mother was more like the intellect.
So it was like, through my father's side was the heart, and through my mother's side came
the mind.
And although my other grandfather was also very loving.
So I was very fortunate to have very loving parents and grandparents, you know.
So probably you didn't really get so much great picture of the world during the depression
period.
Well, you know, it was, it partly drove me to enterprise.
I've always been very enterprising, you know, to this very day.
Yesterday I saw a lot of patients and I also sold them five pounds of tomatoes.
I don't know, as a boy I always had to sign up by the side of the road, goat milk for
sale.
Tomatoes for sale, cucumbers for sale, puppies for sale, rabbits for sale.
You know, there was always that drive to be enterprising, and to this day I'm still a
high energy enterprising person, you know.
Well, you know, you said you're an introvert, and that in which doesn't go as well with
this enterprising person.
Well, I got over that.
I got over being an introvert, and now I'm neither an introvert nor an extrovert.
Yeah.
I enjoy being by myself.
I have no need to be with anybody.
I could be alone by myself for years and never see another human being and be perfectly happy.
And on the other hand, I can be around lots of people and do a lot of public speaking
and be in front of millions of people on television.
I was on network television a lot of times.
So I can talk to millions of people and have a good time, and I can be by myself for years
and never see another human being and be very happy.
But I relate to the animals a lot, you know.
I love animals.
So I spent years by myself and feel very close to the animals around me.
What kind of animals are your favorite?
Wild animals.
Oh.
Well, of course, here I have all kinds of domestic animals, too, you know, a few horses
and rabbits and chickens and ducks and a couple of doves and geese and turkeys and cats and
things.
OK.
I don't know where the kitty is today.
Yeah.
Where's the kitty?
I don't know.
She usually likes to get in the television.
Go ahead.
Now, another significant incident you mentioned in your writing, it's in 1939 when you're
a paper boy in rural Wisconsin.
Yes, I was, you know, I told you about I had the longest paper route in the state of Wisconsin.
See?
Yeah.
It was zero and it's pitch dark out and I was a couple of miles from the nearest farmhouse
and the wind was fierce and I took all my papers and blew them across the top of the
snow and I started to cry with frustration and it was freezing cold.
So and my knees were all frozen and, you know, my pants were frozen stiff.
So anyway, what I did was there was the snow plows had been through in Wisconsin, the snowbanks,
by the side of the road are often 15 feet high.
I mean, the plows are higher than this room.
Wow.
The plow, the front of the plow is higher than this room and so the snowbanks are very,
very wide.
By the end of the winter, they're very, so anyway, I broke through the crust of the ice
and I got inside, I made a, I howled it out and I get out of the wind, there's no place
out of the wind.
And so I climbed in and out of the wind, you know.
And the cold, all of a sudden the cold, well not all of a sudden, the cold seemed to disappear.
And instead there was this incredible warmth came over me, it was a feeling of infinite
peace and an exquisite joy on a level I can't even describe.
And there seemed to be like a glow.
There seemed to be a golden light to it.
So I became one with this infinite, it was like the presence of infinite love.
And the individual self again dissolved and this individual love was not, was not different
than what I am.
And before the body, before the world, before planets, before the universe, there's this
kind of, it goes on forever and that went on for some eons of time because you're outside
of time.
There was no form, there was just this infinite presence.
There was no thought about it.
We could ask what, we could ask what was the energy of that.
Let's ask.
These are things I've never asked before.
Okay.
Let's just see.
All right.
Because I want to integrate it also.
That experience is over 500 resist.
That experience is over 550 resist.
That experience is over 580 resist.
That experience is over 590 resist.
That experience is over 600 resist.
700 resist, 800 resist, 760 resist, 770, 780, 770, that's amazing, I didn't realize that.
I thought it was only about 600.
Why such an experience mostly happen when the body is in such a big suffering?
Oh.
It seems to.
Perhaps separate one's identification with the body.
In other words, you stop identifying with the body.
The minute you stop identifying with the body, suddenly you realize who you are.
Right.
And because the separate ego seems to identify so strongly with the physicality.
And once you stop identifying with that, then there's, one time I went out of body spontaneously.
You hear people that go out of body all the time.
Yeah.
They always complain they can't stand their body.
I never had that problem.
But I didn't know, I never heard of such a thing.
But I was very sick with a physical illness.
And I was, yeah, very sick.
And all of a sudden, much to my surprise, I found myself about five feet over the physical
body.
Here I was, in exact, exactly like this body, only like it didn't weigh anything.
And you could almost like see through it.
You know?
Yeah.
You could almost like see through it.
Right.
You know?
And there I was five feet or six feet over the body.
I looked down at the physical body and there's Dave's body laying in the bed.
He looked pretty bad too, I'll tell ya'.
It's a sick looking guy laying in a bed and I'm five feet up in the air.
And, I never heard of out of body experience.
I didn't know what it was.
I was just amazed by the, phenomenon.
Mmm hmm.
In fact I was in psychoanalysis at the time.
And I remember I went back and told my psychoanalyst about it.
I said, there I was, five or six feet over the physical body,
and exact same as this body.
And he said, well, it must have been a toxic psychosis.
And I said, yes, you're right.
I guess we did some kind of a duplication of the body ego image, you know.
So both of us concluded it was some kind of a toxic brain reaction or something.
For many years, I thought that, you know,
it was many years later that I began to read books about, you know, out-of-body experiences.
Nowadays, it's very commonly reported.
But in those days, that was probably back in the early 50s,
nobody heard about such things.
And you didn't talk about them either.
Everybody would think you were pretty cuckoo.
So you even didn't tell the supplement?
No, I told my psychoanalyst about it.
That was it.
And then I discussed it.
Well, so you mentioned that those experiences,
which is very distinctive, you started to become an atheist.
Well, yes, the intellect.
The intellect was pretty advanced, and it was quite sophisticated.
And, you know, many of the proofs for God's existence,
many of the belief systems about God,
and let's say if somebody is basically more spiritually advanced than that,
without even realizing that, they were rejected as false
because they recognized that it's false.
So all the negative gods, you know, the god of retaliation,
the god of punishment, the god who throws you into hell forever
because you're so wicked and he hates you, et cetera,
the god who gets mad at mankind and is prone to jealousy.
I'm a jealous god.
Yeah.
I get very pissed off, and if you get me mad,
I'm going to destroy your village and town and rain pestilence on you and all.
That's some kind of a demon, you see.
That's not God.
That's a demon.
God was what I experienced there in the snowbank,
an infinite presence of infinite love that radiates equally like the sun on all, you see.
It never qualifies itself.
It never limits itself.
It does no judgment.
It just is.
To be God, one could.
To only be, you know, or have the infinite potential to be all that is.
Anything less than that can't be God.
So what I really did when I became an atheist is I rejected the false gods.
And don't forget those false gods have made atheists of many honest men
because if you have an honest, intense intellect
and you look at all the God belief systems that the world holds,
you would automatically...
automatically reject it.
And also I had another interesting experience around 15 or so.
I suddenly became conscious of the totality of the world's suffering.
I suddenly got the totality, the immensity of the world's suffering.
In what way?
I just became aware of its totality.
And in that instant, I couldn't believe in a God that would allow that.
You know, anything that would allow that, I could not call God nor could I worship it.
I was not that sophisticated at the time.
See, what I did was I held God responsible for that which is created by the ego.
What I saw was the extent of the damage of what the ego creates.
And then I thought, because God is the creator, you know, religiously,
religiously wise, he must have created that.
So I rejected that kind of a God.
So all I really did was reject the negative misconceptions about the true nature of God.
Because unless one has experienced an infinite presence,
one doesn't know what one's talking about.
And one is just repeating, mouthing things they've heard from somebody else, you see.
Right.
And like all the so-called Christians,
and when they talk about Christianity,
what they're really saying is,
what they're really quoting is the Old Testament.
Why are you quoting the Old Testament if you're a Christian?
I mean, why was Christ born?
You're not going to pay any attention to what he said.
So an eye for an eye and a tooth for a tooth
did not bring about any wonders in this world.
And Christ was born and said, forget that, forget that.
Instead, he replaced it by forgiveness.
So the law of love was the new law
supplied at the end.
The old law of hatred and getting even,
which is the history of the Middle East,
the history of the Catholics and the Protestants,
the history of prosecution.
And so when somebody talks to me that they're a Christian,
you know, I want to know what they're talking about.
You mean the God of love, the God of forgiveness,
the God of infinite mercy?
And so I was getting a kick out of
Muslims.
You know, because when you read the Koran,
it says, Allah, the All-Merciful.
Every phrase, it says, Allah, the All-Merciful.
But in practice, they're exactly the opposite.
You know, they execute you for all kinds of things
and behead you.
And it is certainly not a merciful country,
a merciful religion.
So it was those gods of negativity that I rejected
when I became an atheist.
So when I look back, I was correct.
Yeah.
I was correct in rejecting it.
I wasn't rejecting God.
I was correcting, I was rejecting the misconceptions of God.
These are all the egos, misinterpretations of God.
I guess what you don't want to follow is such a divinity,
the cold divinity based on the human fear and anxiety.
Yeah.
It's just a projection of human negativity.
Right.
And then calling it God and then living a life in fear of it.
Yeah.
The difficulty with the Christianity has, as I see it,
is so little is recorded of what he actually said and taught.
And don't forget, I calibrated the energy level of Jesus Christ.
It was 1,000.
Okay.
And Christianity in the first century calibrated at about 950.
Mm-hmm.
And then, as you remember, I said in the book,
around the year 476 or something, the Council of Nicaea,
you calibrate what is the energy of Christianity up to the year 400,
and up to the year 950.
to the Council of Nicaea, you see it's still very high, about 900s.
And then after the Council of Nicaea, it drops precipitously to the high 400s.
Some incredibly huge error came into that Council of Nicaea
and blew out a lot of the purity of what Jesus Christ taught.
So we don't really know what he said because it wasn't written down.
And then the difficulty of an enlightened teacher
is the misunderstanding of the listener.
The listener, if he's talking about something as an analogy,
they will take it literally.
Or if he's speaking as a metaphor, they will take it as a literality.
And then because of the negativity of the ego,
they will project negative inferences into something that is actually benign.
When Jesus Christ talks about hell,
he's talking about that which you yourself created,
that which you create for yourself.
He's not talking about some arbitrary, like jail,
cosmic jail you get thrown into.
He's saying if you follow certain kinds of behavior,
you will bring enormous suffering upon yourself.
But that is self-created.
There isn't any sub-punitive God hanging out there
waiting for you to trip over things in the highway
so he can kick you in the butt and throw you into jail,
a cosmic torture chamber, you know.
That's how most people picture God,
a monster who waits for you to trip over the defects of your own humanness.
And now you're guilty of humanness,
and because you're guilty of humanness,
we're going to throw you into this endless torture pit.
So this horrible God sits there waiting for you to screw up,
you know what I mean?
Yeah.
Well, no matter whether you're talking about negativity,
like hell or heaven,
the problem is there is a separation,
Yeah. the problem is there is a separation,
between you as a human being and the divinity out there.
So, I mean, we are not the same exactly,
but somehow we are connected with the divinity.
Yeah.
And we're also the creator of our own inner hell.
Yeah, that's the point, yes.
That one creates it oneself.
Right.
There's no arbitrary, punitive God hanging out waiting for you.
But the thing is, once people are creating such a thing,
then they start to see things as a separate being, you know.
I'm in here.
And there is either hell or heaven.
Which way to go?
So...
Oh, yeah.
So I see.
Therefore, it's the ego that creates all the negative gods.
Right.
The negative gods are self-created.
And so one is always living in the prison created by one's own ego.
So...
Like we often forgot the original creation started from our own inside,
rather than...
So the more purified one becomes,
spiritually, the less any such a god could have any reality,
because it doesn't exist within you anymore
to project out into the world to be afraid of.
Right.
Because your hatred of other people and fear
is now diminished practically to zero.
Only a benevolent god would have any reality to you.
Yeah, I see.
So everyone lives with the very god that they create.
You can neither prove nor disprove the existence of God
through the intellect alone.
Right.
And, of course, if we calibrate,
the energy fields of that,
as we did in the book and other videotapes,
the intellect is in the 400s.
Right.
And the 400s is too much of a limitation.
You couldn't possibly prove the existence of something
that can only be experienced from the 600s and up...
Right.
...by means of a device that is limited to the 400s.
It's like a telescope is too weak to reach the furthest galaxies.