What we have been doing is creating a context in which to hold an understanding of the whole process of addiction.
And by the time we finish today, we'll see why the world has been relatively unsuccessful in handling the whole problem of addiction,
with the exception, of course, of Alcoholics Anonymous, which has been the only successful approach thus far.
The purpose is to create a context, a way of holding, a way of understanding,
because context is the most important thing in our life,
because out of context comes meaning, and out of meaning comes value,
and out of value comes goals, and therefore it really directs our entire life.
This kind of learning, which is not left brain learning,
the right brain learns by familiarity, by circling over the same material.
So?
The person who's listening to it this year is not the same person who listened to it last year.
In fact, to hear the material, you become a different person,
and so nobody will hear the same thing they heard last year.
So we'll recapitulate some of the things we said last year, and then we'll extend it.
We'll extend it.
I apologize for the writing.
It is a typical doctor's writing.
We learned this at medical school.
And if your writing is legible, then you flunk.
So?
You get called into the dean's office.
So this is typical doctor's writing, and therefore I'll explain these terms
so that those of you who can't actually read it will hear it.
In the center is the box, and a lot of my talks, people in DeVille,
a lot of the former residents there refer to the box and where they are in the box.
And so the box is really the ego as understood in psychology.
It's the self with a small s.
It's a lower mind, the common everyday mind with a small m.
The bottom of the box, we always start with the bottom of the box and work our way up.
The bottom of the box is a state, is an energy field.
In the center of the box, these are really energy fields.
And energy fields are impersonal.
An energy field is impersonal.
Those of you who have studied or heard of geomancy realize
that an energy field in nature is impersonal.
And therefore, these energy fields have labels and names,
but that's just the name of that energy field.
To the right of it is the emotion that comes out of that energy field.
And at the far right is the process going on in consciousness.
In the center, then, we have in the box these fields of consciousness.
And beginning at the bottom, we have guilt.
Guilt, which you'll notice,
that is a reversed energy field.
Underneath the names of these various energy fields is an arrow,
which I would hope would be in a different color,
but I forgot my pink chalk today.
You'll notice that there's a direction to the energy field,
and also there's a number which calibrates the relative energy of that energy field.
Starting with death, calibrated at zero.
And this can be repeated by anyone,
and it has been repeated by many people.
It's been proven and verified.
If you start with death at zero,
you will end up with enlightenment at 600,
what the world calls enlightenment.
It depends beyond duality.
If you start with death at zero,
you will end up with 600 as the top of the box,
beyond which identification with the small self,
the personal ego, is transcended.
At the bottom of the box, then, preceding death,
are two states, apathy and guilt.
You'll notice that in the middle,
you'll notice that the energy field goes to the left.
The direction of the energy field indicates something extremely important.
All those energy fields below the level of courage,
which is a crucial level in the understanding of the addictions,
all the energy fields below courage are reversed.
All the levels below courage are reversed,
and they're all levels of victim.
They're all levels of having sold out.
So being close to death,
we see apathy calibrates at 50.
We see guilt calibrates at 30.
These states preceding death, we notice,
are accompanied by an emotional state of hopelessness,
of despondency, of despair, of depression.
And as you slip into guilt itself,
self-hatred, the feeling of sin, worthlessness.
And out of that comes
the destruction due to the loss of energy.
That state of apathy, hopelessness, despondency,
which precedes death,
is a state in which the individual becomes de-energized.
They become de-energized
because the state right above it is dispirited.
The loss of the desire to live,
and because of that,
the loss of energy from the universe,
which the spirit, that which is life,
pulls into us.
So apathy is a state of great importance
in the addictions.
It's a state of great importance in the world.
Probably a third of the world lives in a state of apathy.
Thirty percent, perhaps, of the world lives in a state of apathy,
hopelessness.
Tomorrow will not be any better than today.
The mothers in Ethiopia and Africa,
places like that,
stare, just stare blankly,
watching the children's bellies swell up with starvation.
And you'll notice that the look on their face
is one of just staring off into space.
There is no hope that life is going to get any better tomorrow.
And so, therefore, hopelessness
characterizes the state emotionally.
And in that state, a person is unable to help themself.
Hopelessness means just that.
So a friend of mine was president of the Nassau County Bar Association,
and he died of starvation
all alone in a rooming house.
Starvation on a combination of alcohol and Librium.
Why didn't he call somebody?
He knew thousands of people.
He was very well respected and well loved and well liked.
Why didn't he just call somebody?
Because out of hopelessness, it means just that.
There being no hope, there, of course, would be no purpose to make a phone call.
This is extremely important because when patients come in,
when people come in in a state of hopelessness,
into the villa,
into the hospital,
into the office,
into our groups,
into the influence of our energy field,
because they cannot help themself,
the only thing you can do is pour energy into them.
Because the process over on the right hand side is loss of energy,
then all you can do is pour energy into the person.
Reason and logic has no effect on a person in that state of consciousness.
So the mother who has lost her child,
you know, got a telegram from the State Department,
that your son is missing in action,
suddenly stops speaking, she sits in her rocking chair,
she stares blankly out the window,
rocks back and forth and stops eating,
and doesn't respond to people anymore.
And now, when a telegram comes from the State Department that it was a mistake,
it was another man with a similar name and they say,
mother, mother, it was all a mistake.
You know, it wasn't really Richard at all.
So she just stares blankly out the window and rocks back and forth.
And they say, mother, didn't you hear what we said?
But you see, the state has already changed.
Your state of consciousness has changed.
And in this state, because there is changes in the brain enzymes,
so over on the left we're going to have a column,
we could have a blackboard about 30 feet long,
in which we're going to integrate the entire cosmos and all of man's experience.
But having a blackboard of this length will do it serially.
So obviously you see there are brain enzyme changes,
and at this point,
at the very bottom you have actually the release of a death hormone.
You have the release of a death hormone.
Above that, in a state higher than that,
of course you have the depression of the brain's neurotransmitters,
the so-called catecholamines,
such as serotonin and norepinephrine.
Those brain enzymes, which when they become depleted,
throw a person into depression.
And of course this happens in the addictions,
where first there is an overstimulation of those neurotransmitters,
and then with the withdrawal of the drug,
especially a drug like cocaine,
there is then a severe depression of the neurotransmitters,
and therefore drugs that have an up-effect
will throw a person into a depression when you remove them.
The woman does not respond to the message
that her son was not killed in action,
because she's no longer capable of that.
And so the only thing we can do for a person
in this energy field is to pour energy into them.
Pour energy into them
by our presence, by our caring for them,
by our prayers for them,
by the sheer presence of our own physical energy
and our caringness,
because the person is unable to care for themself,
in an attempt to get them up to the next higher energy field called grief.
Grief, which calibrates at 50,
has a lot more energy than apathy at 50.
Grief at 75 has a lot more energy.
And how is that energy expressed?
Through emotion.
So we know that when the mother
rocking back and forth in the rocking chair
suddenly begins to cry,
we know that she's getting better.
There's an expression of emotion,
and grief has a certain biologic purpose in the universe,
so that it summons forth some kind of a biologic response.
When the infant cries, it summons the mother.
A couple of months ago, I was sitting on my front porch
and I heard this little squeaking sound.
Squeak, squeak, squeak, squeak.
And my cat went over to a flower pot,
you know, was very curious about the flower pot,
and I lifted up the flower pot,
and here's this little toad underneath.
Hop, hop, out.
He'd been trapped there.
So this little toad, you see, in his grief,
his little expression,
summoned forth a great power from the universe,
namely me,
to take the flower pot off him
with the help of the kitty.
So, you see that little squeak,
summoned forth the cat,
and the cat summoned forth me,
and so therefore you see in operation
the power, you see the power,
because we say the energy fields are not personal.
So what the little toad was expressing
was that energy field, you see,
and that energy field summoned the two of us.
So there is power in grief.
In ordinary life, we experience grief,
in ordinary daily life, as regret.
Regret.
So that grief relates to the past,
just as fear, the energy field above it,
relates to the future.
We experience grief in the form of regret,
having to do with loss,
the feeling of loss,
and it leads eventually into depression.
Depression leads then, if it gets worse,
slips into despondency, into hopelessness,
and into the bottom of the box.
What's happened in grief is the person, we say,
has become dispirited.
Dispirited.
All of these are coming about,
all of these are, we say,
are accompanied by random changes,
but all of them are coming about
because everything under the level of courage
is based on the illusion
that happiness is something outside of yourself.
It's something out there.
Consequently, grief is a reaction
then to that illusion that happiness is out there
and that you have lost it somehow in your life
through that person, that relationship,
that money, that position, that title,
the loss of your hair,
your youth, your vigor, whatever,
your potency, your Cadillac.
All the things that people put their stuff on
as being the source of their happiness.
It's always out there.
And so the loss of out there leads to the feeling of regret,
loss, depression, and the dispirited state.
These lower states, grief and apathy,
come from the failure to face the energy field above it,
which is fear.
Fear, again a reversed energy field,
calibrates at 100.
So 100 is a lot of energy.
You think what you can do with the energy
of fear, not with the emotion of fear,
but with the energy of it.
You can run like hell with fear.
You can establish the whole Maginot Line,
which the French did
in preparing for the onset of the Germans in World War II.
Fear motivates, obviously, a huge amount of human behavior
and sells insurance policies
and a good part of our economy,
of course, is based on fear and the defenses.
So there's a lot of energy in fear.
And what we try to teach people to do
is how to use the energy of these fields,
but not the emotion itself.
How to use the energy constructively
coming out of fear.
So all these energy fields have their upside
and their downside.
The upside and the downside.
The upside of fear is how to use that energy constructively
because you can do yourself a great favor
if you know what to be afraid of in this world.
Isn't that so?
To be afraid of the addiction, for instance,
is sensible in as much as it is.
I'll tell you.
In ordinary life,
we experience the energy field of fear
as worry.
Worry, anxiety, panic.
So fear has to do with the future.
It has to do with anticipated consequences.
It has to do with all kinds of projections.
And the process going on over here in consciousness
is one of deflation.
So the animal, when it's afraid,
shrinks and hides
and tries to camouflage itself and be invisible.
And we all remember that in class,
you know, in second grade.
Anybody know how much is so-and-so?
And everybody shrinks behind the person in front of them
and tries to become invisible.
So this is where we like to become invisible
and disappear.
And the whole animal kingdom reflects that
in its magnificent camouflage
in which the insects and the birds and the animals
look like tree bark and various things.
To become invisible and disappear from attack.
And that is the basis, of course,
of the psychological mechanisms
to disappear from the space,
to disappear yourself from the space
through denial and projection
and ways to remove yourself from being there.
Facing this energy field of fear
is what prevents falling into depression and despondency.
So the way out of depression and despondency
for anyone is to face what is the underlying fear.
The reason you're depressed
is because you're unwilling to face
what is the fear underlying the depression.
Fear is much easier to handle
once you understand how to handle fear
than is depression.
Depression really, in a way, can't be handled
except to look at what was not faced
that will pull you out of it.
The minute you look at what the fear is
underlying the depression,
depression now disappears
and instead you feel afraid.
And what is the fear usually?
It usually takes the form of
I have lost my happiness.
The source.
I have lost the source of my happiness forever.
You'll see that under depression
is the thought, the fantasy,
the idea, and the emotion.
So the woman is saying,
without my son, life is now meaningless to me.
He was my life.
I based my life around my son
and what he was in the world.
And now my life has no meaning.
So I have lost the source of meaning
and happiness in my life.
So depression then comes from
what is the fear?
The fear almost always takes the form
I have lost the source of my happiness.
How is fear handled?
Well, we teach people how to handle fear.
It's a very simple thing to handle.
It's surprisingly one of the easiest things to learn.
Handling fear then is merely
handling the fear of the fear.
And the way you handle fear is by disassembling it.
Taking the fear away from the fear.
Once you're no longer afraid of fear,
it's really a nothing.
When you disassemble it
and take it down to what it is,
you know, fear is
a feeling of dryness in the mouth,
maybe palpitations,
maybe some weakness in the legs,
butterflies in the stomach,
gastrointestinal discomfort,
whatever.
If you ask yourself,
you know, could I handle that?
Could I let go resisting that?
So what you do is you let go resisting
what you're actually experiencing
and stop labeling it.
You stop giving it any attention
to what the thoughts are
because what kind of thoughts
do you think fear is going to put out?
Actually, it's going to put out your thoughts.
So instead, what you concentrate on
is the sensations running through your body
and you're asking yourself,
could you let go resisting them?
And you just keep letting go resisting them
and you find that there's nothing to it.
I let fear run one time for two weeks solid
and when it left, I missed it.
I mean, it's like my pal by now.
Just those sensations running through you.
And after the first few minutes
or after the first hour or so,
if you have really a big one that you're handling,
letting run out,
you'll find that you go right on functioning
and that the fearful feelings running through your body
are nothing at all.
You feel fear running through you
as a physical experience
which is quite tolerable
and it's really nothing at all.
It's much easier to handle, frankly, than a headache.
It's easier to handle with nausea.
It's easier to handle with a broken toe.
I mean, all the things that you've handled in your life,
fear is really nothing.
So when you lose your fear of fear
and are willing to handle fear as it comes up,
then the world in a way can really no longer control you
because it's fear, isn't it,
that really runs you
and that you're at the effect of so much in this world.
So losing your fear of fear
and just realizing what it is
that is really a nothing to handle experientially.
Yes?
Yes, because the thoughts are an elaboration
and there's no truth in them.
And the only thing that you're really experiencing
and you force the person to...
It's how you do it with physical symptoms as well
and that's part of self-healing.
And I've done some tapes and things on self-healing
and how I healed many things within myself
was using that technique of stop labeling it,
stop calling it anything
and go into radical truth.
You know, radically, what is it you're experiencing?
Radically speaking, what is it you're experiencing?
You're not experiencing fear.
Any more than you can experience
asthma or allergies or hay fever.
Those are all concepts.
You can't experience hay fever.
You can't experience sinus trouble.
You can't experience any of those things.
You can't experience an ulcer.
You know, radically speaking,
what is it you're experiencing?
Well, you're experiencing a stuffy nose.
Even stuffiness you're not experiencing
any more than with an ulcer.
The person says,
you know, I'm feeling an ulcer.
You're not feeling an ulcer.
What is it you're actually feeling?
You're feeling a sensation.
And of course, all of us who do it,
we just learned that the first day, didn't we,
when we couldn't go to the bathroom.
You had to cancel,
I can't go to the bathroom,
because that's a panicky thought.
And instead, you had to concentrate
on the fact that what are you radically experiencing?
Well, you're experiencing a pressure in the lower abdomen.
Well, can you handle a little pressure in the lower abdomen?
Yeah, you can handle that.
But you cannot handle a thought,
I can't go to the bathroom,
because that's a panicsville.
So, the same, whether you can't handle asthma,
you can't handle any of these labels,
but what you can handle
is the sensation,
and let go resisting the sensation.
In my own personal experience of that,
all of these physical things will disappear
as you keep letting go resisting
the physicality of the sensation of it,
and let go of the thoughts that go with it.
So fear,
and we teach people how to handle fear,
is really a nothing.
And of course, one of the first benefits you get out of it,
out of the willingness to handle the fear,
is the letting go of the depression.
You come out of depression instantly,
out of hopelessness instantly,
the instant you're willing to handle the fear.
But people are not willing to handle fear
unless they feel there's a safe way to hold that fear,
and therefore we're going to be talking about
how to hold some of these experiences.
See, the context out of which you're holding that fear
is now that you are bigger than the fear.
You are the healer of that fear.
You are the one that is holding the field
out of which that fear is now being held.
So you're not at the effect of it.
See, you've summoned it.
You are the master now, see?
It's the difference between whether a dog is barking
against your will,
or whether you invite the dog to bark.
You see?
Are you saying that the best way to begin,
from my point of view...
You move into the physical,
because the mind in panic
is like a computer going wild.
And when you push fear button,
it has enough fear programs
that you could think nothing but fear thoughts
the rest of your time on the planet,
and it would never run out.
In fact, those fear thoughts
would have engendered
whole new banks of fear thoughts.
The collective consciousness,
the number of fear thoughts
in the collective consciousness
is probably infinite, you know?
Self-perpetuating.
Every fearful thought
creates a whole new bank of...
So, trying to handle the fear thoughts,
in my experience,
is not too successful.
If you handle the actual sensation,
for instance,
you'll come out of depression.
The instant you come out of depression,
what you're facing is
what you thought was the source of your happiness
that you think you have lost.
And so, you're now facing...
You're getting right down to the truth.
You're getting much closer to the truth,
which, of course, has a powerful effect.
In the addictions,
we try to get people to do that.
You see, they come in in apathy.
My situation is hopeless.
My case is hopeless.
I mean, my case is different.
And AA is fine for you folks.
And NA is fine for you folks.
And OA is fine for you folks.
All that stuff is okay for you.
My case is different.
And how is it different?
My case is hopeless.
To move them up out of hopelessness into grief.
Because when you begin to see the cost of,
not only addiction,
but any physical illness
or any problem in your life,
the next reaction you get is grief.
Because you see the loss.
You see the cost.
Because grief is really about cost.
You see what the cost has been.
The price.
And you see what you've sold out
and what you've let go of.
And so therefore you move up
into a regret and a grief.
And in the addictive field,
people go into regret and grief
over the loss that has occurred already
in their life about addiction.
Then they move up to fear
because grief having handled the past.
Fear now, they extrapolate
what has happened in the past.
And unless you're somewhat retarded,
you begin to realize
that this is a progressive illness
and that the losses of the past
are nothing compared to
what they are going to be in the future.
So far, you know,
you've lost a part of your stomach.
If you keep on drinking,
you will lose your entire stomach.
That becomes rather clear to people.
And so therefore they go into fear.
You move people up from fear
into wanting something better for themselves.
To move them to the next level,
that of desire.
The energy level of desire,
which calibrates at 125,
has a lot of power in it.
It's obvious to all of us
that desire runs all of Madison Avenue,
the whole marketing,
the whole marketing schemes
of the whole United States,
the basis of the economy.
And desire and the wanting of something
can drive your entire lifetime.
There was a question in the back.
The technique of it
I won't go into today
because it is all part of research
and consciousness,
but I'll tell you a couple of easy ways
and we will do one of them in class.
We ourselves will calibrate the truth
of what we're talking about today in class.
And we'll use a very simple method
that anybody can use.
There are even faster,
simpler ways, of course.
But we ourselves will test out the truth
of everything said today.
And I always say,
never believe anything a speaker says
unless you have yourself
investigated their integrity,
their energy,
their reversity,
and where they're at.
So everything that we say today,
we will test out.
And during the bill of lectures,
we literally do that,
the whole class.
We test out the various propositions
that we have presented during these talks
and prove whether they're so or not so,
especially the most critical ones
because today we'll be talking about
what people are actually addicted to,
which is something that escapes the world thus far.
So fear, then, is a very useful thing
if you use out of the energy of fear,
the fear of the addiction,
driving you into wanting this,
something better for yourself,
to desire something better for yourself.
So desire at 125,000,
that's a lot of power.
And we experience it in ordinary life
as wanting this,
you know, craving this,
the lust,
lust in its generic widest meaning.
And in the addictions,
they eventually become obsession and compulsions.
Obsessions and compulsions,
in which the person is willing to sacrifice
and sell out everything
in the name of that obsession and compulsion,
including life itself,
all that life entails.
And in the end,
the addiction will ask for your body,
and in the end,
you will give it your body.
You see, the fact that even the physical body
is going to go in the end,
you will say,
well, if it goes, it goes, you know,
piecemeal or in toto,
because by then everything else is gone
and the only thing you've got left is the body,
and so that's going to go too.
So the person in the end
is willing then to give up the body.
So we know you can't scare people
out of the addictions.
You can't scare people saying,
if you keep doing this,
you're going to do that.
It doesn't mean anything to the person,
because they are quite willing to do that.
At a certain level of consciousness,
they are willing to do everything
to maintain that which they are seeking.
The energy field of desire then,
to begin to want something better for yourself.
So out of hopelessness,
to move the person into grief,
and grief to face the fear,
the fear I will never be happy again,
because in the addictions, obviously,
the source of your happiness is out here.
So to cut a person off from the addiction,
you then see why they go into grief,
because they have just lost
the source of their happiness.
To move up to fear,
to move up to desire,
for wanting something to crave,
to really want something
that is better for yourself,
and move out of the grief and the fear,
and move up to anger.
If you can move a person up to anger,
anger over what?
Anger over being victim.
Anger over being powerless.
Anger over what the cost has been.
Anger at how you've had to sell yourself out
in order to survive.
Anger at the sheer cost of survival,
the sheer cost that you've had to pay
in order to maintain this.
So we experience anger in ordinary life
as resentment, you know?
In daily life, it's resentment,
and of course that intensifies
to hatred and grudges,
eventually killing and war.
The thing about desire,
the situation with desire,
the desire that addiction itself,
you see the process in consciousness
is one of entrapment.
The person is trapped by the addiction.
They're at the effect of it.
So if Madison Avenue can program you
with a certain want,
a certain desire,
then you are run by that,
and you then will put forth
your money, time, energy, and effort
to get that which you want,
which is usually based on
you won't have what other people have,
or they'll think you have B.O.,
or they won't love you,
or your hair won't swirl in the wind
and make men go crazy,
or whatever the picture program
has gone into your unconscious.
To be at the effect of that,
you have to have that Cadillac
in order to be happy,
otherwise people will not respect you, etc.
So whatever you're entrapped by then
runs you.
So from this level then,
the person is obviously run by that.
And so we get people to see that,
and a lot of times they will go
directly right into anger.
What's the good of anger is that
it has an energy fuel of 150.
The energy of anger,
not the emotion of it,
which leads to destruction,
destructive action,
but the energy of the anger
can now be used for constructive action.
So that anger over the cost,
over what has been,
and move the person up to pride.
Pride at 175 is a lot of energy.
It's enough to run the entire
United States Marine Corps.
Pride runs the whole clothing industry,
the cosmetics industry.
The pride in one's appearance
and leads you to getting all kinds of degrees
and what pride does with us.
I think it's some of the greatest things
I've done out of pride,
especially in adolescence.
I mean, it's really something.
What a girl might think about something,
and then what it led to,
just to erase that from your collar
because she might have seen that.
And of course all night
you never even took your coat off,
so she never would have seen it anyway.
But the pride,
the energy then of it,
is enormous.
If it's used constructively,
it's not a great place to hang out in.
Pride is not a great place to hang out in
because of the defensive nature,
because the process going on in consciousness
is really one of inflation.
And the downside of pride,
you see the upside of pride
is to begin to move into self-care,
to care about yourself,
and to do something about that,
to use that energy of anger
now in a constructive way.
The downside of pride,
and of a great importance to pride,
to us,
in all fields,
but especially addiction,
is denial.
See?
The downside of pride is denial,
and in its other forms,
contempt,
and the defensiveness that goes with that.
So that denial kills a lot of people
in the addictions.
How does it kill them?
It kills them,
it happened in my own family,
in several of my family members,
closest nuclear family in fact,
where people would go to a meeting and say,
well those people need that.
Go to an AA meeting,
they say,
well,
they need that.
Those people.
And it's usually said,
with sort of looking down the nose,
contemptuous,
that those worms there,
they need that.
And a lot of people in our society
who don't understand self-help groups
or spiritually based self-healing
still have that attitude.
Oh, you still need those meetings?
But because you understand what it's all about,
you laugh at it
because you realize that they don't really get it,
but they're projecting this within them.
This within themselves upon that,
you see,
and that's what they see there.
So the whole problem with pride is defensiveness,
to be defensive.
You know that pride is useful then as a transition.
And even the Marine Corps appeals to pride,
but what they really move you up into is courage.
Because prideful people are hard to handle.
So pride is useful as a transition.
The difficulty is that the person's
unconsciousness is inflated.
So we say the person
is too big for their boots,
you know, that they have a swelled head.
The inflation is,
and you see coming,
the state right below that, anger,
is one of expansion.
But this is one of inflation.
In anger, the process is one to become expanded.
So the animal that is in anger,
its hair stands on end and its tail swells
and it looks fierce and it expands itself
to make itself a formidable opponent.
So the person in anger,
their veins swell out and they swell out
and take up a lot of energy space
to try and impose on you and scare you.
Boo.
The anger then is an expanded state.
But pride is an inflated state,
which is somewhat beyond that
and has its own characteristics,
particularly that of denial.
So we hear out of that coming contempt.
And the contempt for that,
exactly what a person needs,
exactly what the person needs
is exactly what they have the contempt for
because they're unable to handle that
because out of pridefulness,
there is the inability to accept one's limitations
and therefore they have to be projected
and ridiculed in others.
So we try to move people in the addictions
through pride to use the upside of pride
to move into constructive action
and really to move the people up
into the level of courage.
Courage is a critical element
to a level.
First of all, we see when we calibrate it
that the energy field has jumped to 200.
200 is a lot of power.
An energy field of 200 is enough
to settle the United States of America
and settle the West,
to create all the industries,
to create all the empires,
to energize all of science.
Curiosity plus courage is enough
to handle the whole thing.
So it's an enormous energy.
Why does it have so much energy?
It has that much energy
because you'll see by the arrows,
whereas these energy fields
were all reversed to the left,
the needle now goes to the middle.
So in the level of courage then,
the energy field has shifted
from destructive to neutral.
The energy field is like an antenna.
So you can picture it
because all things in the universe
give off a vibration, an energy,
at a certain frequency,
which is unique to that individual.
Everything in the universe
gives off an energy and a vibration.
And the track of that energy
and that vibration is there forever.
The energy field here is like an antenna,
so that here it's like the antenna
is set to negative.
This is like a negative antenna.
The negative antenna pulls to it
all that is destructive from the universe.
And so we see at the bottom
the process is one of destruction.
At the very bottom,
destruction has finally succeeded.
This is an impersonal effect
of the energy field.
The person,
electively by his intention,
sets what the energy field is.
But then the energy field itself
becomes impersonal.
What happens is you see a sudden
severe reversal of the energy field.
And now when you come back a year later,
a year later,
and you look at the barn,
or let's say you take aerial photographs,
and you come back a year later,
you will see from the aerial photograph
that the foliage in that canyon has changed.
When you visit the barn,
you will see that there are now holes in the roof,
and there are now packrats living there,
and there are cockroaches there,
and all that is negative
seems to be pulled into this barn,
and a quarter of it has fallen down,
and teenagers have kicked the slats out
and broken the windows,
and you wonder what happened.
I mean, I saw it happen to a little cottage
across the creek from where I live,
in a beautiful, happy little thing,
through abandonment,
and for one thing or another,
its energy got reversed,
and now teenagers were like pulled,
you know, like rats and things,
and they kicked all the sides in,
and they kicked the roof in,
and they kicked the walls in,
and they kicked the windows out,
and they kicked the doors in,
and each time I would visit it,
some more things had been kicked.
So once the thing reverses, you see,
it pulls further destruction to it.
Hmm.
The reason to say that is to get the feeling
of impersonality.
It is the energy field now
which pulls that destructive.
So the antenna then,
if it's tuned to negative,
if it's tuned to reverse,
then pulls into the person's life
all that is destructive,
so that the person below this level then
is experiencing that reversity,
that negativity in the form
of all kinds of adversity.
So it can be a DWI,
it can be parking ticket starts out mild,
parking tickets,
and then it gets a little worse,
DWIs, and then bankruptcies,
and you lost your credit rating,
and the next thing you know,
you find yourself in the county jail,
and your relationships go to hell,
and your family disappears,
and the indebtedness,
and then you lose,
they take away your credit card.
So the destruction and the destitution,
and of course the inner destruction is going on,
and that's what eventually brings people
into seeking help.
The energy field of courage then is crucial
because the antenna,
which was too negative, destructive,
and pulling into the person's life
all that is destructive in the universe,
now goes neutral.
So that process now,
I'd say the person is equally constructive
and destructive,
so that it neutralizes.
The antenna now goes neutral,
and the energy field is no longer reversed.
200 is a lot of energy.
It gives the person the capacity to face,
to cope,
to go into appropriate action.
And the process going on in consciousness
is one of empowerment.
And how does that come about?
It comes about as a result,
how does the energy field reverse itself?
It comes about as a result of telling the truth.
So that, which is below the line,
victim,
is the selling out of the truth about yourself.
The selling out of the truth reverses the energy field
and brings to the person destruction.
The way out, then,
is by stating the truth.
The difficulty is a person down at this level
looks within himself and says,
if I looked at the truth,
I wouldn't be able to handle it.
And you will hear people in the 12-step groups
who will tell you they've been in the program for years.
They've taken the first step,
maybe the second step,
the third step,
they even do 12-step work.
But the fourth step,
which is one of a personal fearless moral inventory,
many of them can't handle.
The reason is because the person looks at all this
and they say,
this person here,
a reversed 100 person that I am,
cannot handle what's going to come up
if I start telling the truth.
Of course, what they don't know is that the minute you do,
you see you're walking off a cliff,
you don't know it,
but when you do walk off the cliff and tell the truth,
what happens is you pull yourself from the universe,
the power to face what comes up
as a result of telling the truth.
But you don't get the power until you do it.
So that's the first step then in the 12-step programs.
Admit it,
we are powerless over some addictive substance
or people do it in their daily life
who are not into the addictions.
The minute you admit the truth about something,
then this reversity stops.
The energy field goes neutral.
You pull to yourself,
the energy field is 200,
which has,
the capacity to face, to cope,
and to handle it with appropriate action.
What has the power?
The energy field has the power.
The energy field is what has the power to handle it.
So you summon to yourself an energy field
that has the power to handle it for you.
And as your own consciousness gets higher,
you realize that it is being done like through you.
It is not your personal self.
Your personal self has summoned it
through its own free will.
It has summoned it forth,
but now it is the field that is handling it.
You move up to the next higher level then,
the courage to face, to cope,
to take appropriate action in the addictions.
In the addictions and to let go the resistance.
To let go the resistance.
And through that empowerment now,
to let go resisting
and move up through an energy field which,
we calibrate out at about 250.
And that's often accompanied by a feeling of detachment.
That this is, it's all okay.
It's okay if this happens.
It's okay if it doesn't happen.
And the process going on in consciousness,
we say is the person has become released.
They've become released in that they've let go,
trying to control it.
They have let go the resistance to however it goes.
So they say,
if I get a new car, that's great.
And if I don't get a new car, that's great.
This company wants to keep me, swell.
And if they want to let me go,
I'll find another job.
So, it's a great field to be in
if you've been down here.
To be up in neutral at least,
you don't have the painful experiences.
You see, in courage, you have the energy
to handle these lower feelings,
but they haven't disappeared.
The person in courage goes to ask the boss for a raise.
His stomach is in a knot.
See, his stomach can be in a knot.
He can be run by this desire.
He can be angry that he's got to go and ask in the first place.
He can be resentful and have all kinds of self-pity down here.
This value to the company wasn't recognized
and he had to go and ask for it, etc.
So he has all these negative feelings.
But the courage, the power of courage at 200
has the power to handle that.
And so he acts appropriately
despite the negative feelings.
As you move up into neutral,
where you become no longer attached to outcome,
then you energize,
you get a feeling of being released about the matter,
and these feelings begin to disappear.
These feelings disappear.
When you're totally released on it, it's great.
The boss gives you the raise, fantastic.
And if he doesn't, you live with it.
So it's a great field to be in
as compared to having your stomach in a knot.
Of course, the person at the bottom wouldn't even ask for a raise
because, in his view, he would be worthless
and the boss would never give him a raise anyway.
So you have to move up higher
to even take appropriate action.
So this allows the person
to become easygoing
and move up into the next energy field called acceptance.
Acceptance is a much higher field.
It calibrates out at 380.
At that level, the person is easygoing
and confident and capable.
And we see that there's the beginning now
of a transformation in consciousness,
a growing awareness.
And what is the growing awareness from?
The growing awareness is coming from
the realization
that the power,
the power to be happy,
the source of happiness in my life is within me.
I'm the one that decides
whether I'm going to be successful or happy
in any situation or relationship or position.
Below the level of courage,
everybody, because they're victim,
thinks that it is out there.
The power is out there.
It's the Cadillac that will do it for me.
It's the position, it's the title, it's the address,
it's the suit of clothes.
It's something out there will do it for me.
It's the relationship,
it's the her in my life or the him in my life.
It's the PhD degree or whatever.
That's what's going to do it for me.
But as you move up to this higher energy field,
there's the realization
that the power to create happiness and success in my life
lies within me and me alone.
And it's arising out of my positions,
it's arising out of my decisions,
it's arising out of my intentions,
my goals, my purposes.
It's arising out of that which I value.
And what I value is arising out of the meaning.
It's arising out of the context.
It's beginning to arise out of that which I am.
So that transformation of that awareness
then gives the person a great deal more power.
They're no longer dependent on the world as the source.
See, down here the world has to amuse you
and there's nothing more panicky than your TV set going out.
Or being all alone by yourself with nothing to do.
See?
You have to sit in a bus station for three hours
with nothing to do.
And the magazine stand is closed
and there's no TV and there's no radio.
And there you are all by yourself in a bus station
in the middle of nowhere
and you've got four hours to kill.
This would be death to these people.
Because there's nothing out there to hang on to.
There's no beauty out there.
There's no aesthetic amusement.
There's no action.
Here a person would say,
fantastic, wow, I've got three and a half hours
and I've got so much stuff to work on myself.
I mean, what a lucky break.
I've got four hours.
I can barely catch up in four hours.
All the stuff I've got to handle in my life.
They would think it's great.
So that power then,
that person in that energy state knows
if you drop them in a desert island someplace
in the middle of the Atlantic or Pacific Ocean
and if you come back a year later
you'll have a coconut factory going.
You'll be teaching the natives French.
You'll have found a cute little native girl.
You'll build a tree house.
That capacity to create for yourself
out of what is around you,
to make a garden there,
to grow things there,
to create an industry,
to create something where the energy flows back to you
with the happiness of that.
So we all know that level in ourself.
What the world calls important
doesn't really mean anything
when you just found the missing nut
that allowed you to fix the fan.
I mean, you know how happy that is?
Or you just found your crochet hook
that you can't finish the thing with.
It's the little things that make your whole day delightful.
And how many times in my life
has it become a delight over some little thing, you know?
Like I just finished a chicken coop
and the chickens are happy.
I mean, what could make you happier, you know?
What the world thinks and all the tiles on it
doesn't mean anything
because what you're experiencing is joy
with the right now,
with the right now of what it all is to you.
The joy of your own existence.
To experience the joy of your own existence
then moves you up
and you're moving up to the next energy level.
That's what we call love.
Love is, in this context then,
calibrates at an energy field of 500.
It is the beginning of happiness.
Happiness, if you calibrate it, comes out at 500.
A very crucial level,
a very crucial level
for us to work in the addictions
because we're moving into the energy field
of the self-help groups.
Alcoholics Anonymous calibrates out at 540.
The energy fields of love
and these are not the sentimental emotionalism of love
that the world talks about
but a powerful, stable, unconditional energy field
that you set by your own intention,
by your own decision,
by that to which you say yes in your life.
The energy field of 500.
As you move into the energy fields of 500 and up,
about 540,
Alcoholics Anonymous really calibrates at 540
which is the energy field of healing.
When you calibrate the energy field of healing,
it is around 540.
That means that the energy field alone of the group,
irrespective of what they talk about,
irrespective of the whole program,
the wording, the phrasing, the languaging of it,
the energy field of that
is in itself healing.
And therefore you hear statements
in which this is intuited.
They will say,
just bring the body,
just bring the body.
We know that people get just as sober
if they're ordered there by the court
as if they go there voluntarily.
And somebody I know
quite well in one of the groups
was just ordered there to the court
because he had three DWIs
and he had a choice between a year in jail
or going to AA.
At the end of a year,
when his sentence was up,
he wouldn't have left it for the world
because his own consciousness
had become transformed.
So this is sort of like,
you might say,
an electromagnetic field.
It's a field phenomenon.
An energy field of 540
heals anything you put in it.
Sick rabbits,
wounded legs,
people in despair,
people addicted to substances,
whatever.
If you picture it like an impersonal
electromagnetic energy field then,
with a certain power,
a power that we calibrate,
let's say you set the dial at 540,
then whatever you set in it,
set in it is going to begin to heal
itself.
The kind of love we're talking about
never dies.
There isn't a such thing
as unconditional love dying.
Why?
Because it is a decision
that you make within yourself
that sets up an energy field
which is stable.
So that which is unconditional love
is unchanging.
Unchanging.
Within the energy field
of unconditional love
to which you've committed yourself,
the negative emotions may come and go.
You may hate the person.
I hate you.
I can't stand you.
That's a passing emotion.
And the person's unconditional love
has not changed their commitment.
It has not changed their commitment at all.
That's a passing emotion,
but it is only passing within
a greater energy field.
And of course they know
they're going to forgive the other person.
that they're going to make up.
And of course they know
they're not going to hang on
to this resentment any longer
than it takes to get rid of it.
So the person in this level then
is characterized in their emotional state
by a caring for,
a nurturing,
a support,
a willingness to forgive,
a willingness to understand.
So what is the question then
in the person's mind
in this energy field
is to understand that,
to understand that.
See, down here the idea is to make it wrong.
Who's right and who's wrong.
Here the intention is right and wrong.
Here the intention is not even interested
in right and wrong.
It's totally irrelevant.
If you get into an argument,
if people in this level
get into an argument,
nobody even cares
if it's right or wrong.
What they want to know
is what's out with us.
What don't we understand?
I mean, where is it coming from?
Is it karma?
You know what I mean?
Is it a past life?
Is it something going on
that I'm not aware of?
What is it that's not healed in me
that's bringing it up?
Because there's the beginning
of a revelation, you see.
The beginning of transformation now
is bringing you
to certain inner revelations.
And you begin to realize
that when things
are not going smoothly,
that it's merely something
to be handled.
It's something that's
not understood.
And then when it's
correctly understood,
because it is now held
from the viewpoint
of understanding,
the understanding itself
heals that.
So that you can't
stay mad at a person
in the field
of unconditional love.
And of course,
we're all aware of that.
That's one of the whole intentions
of the consciousness movement
and all that is called
New Age and etc.
As we know,
that a resentment
is your problem
to handle and get off,
you see.
To get off the resentment
is your problem.
It is not up
to the other problem
to change.
So if you don't like the fact
that he wears a vest
all the time,
that's your problem.
It's not the other fellow's
problem to no longer
wear a vest.
It's your problem.
Why that bothers you.
So that brings us
then into a powerful
energy field
which is coming out
of our intention
to be that kind of person.
So we might say
that we could call
this level here
lovingness.
Lovingness.
We say that a person
like that,
what they're showing
is lovingness.
This quality goes on
with them all the time.
So their relationship
to things
is one of lovingness.
To nurture that beauty
around them.
Their relationship
to animals
is one of lovingness.
Their relationships
to all things
is one of lovingness.
A lovingness towards life
and a lovingness
towards life.
Towards beauty
and the desire
to support that
and understand that.
So relationships
coming out of that
are then unconditional.
Meaning non-judgmental.
There's no interest
in rightness
and wrongness.
So characteristic
of the 12-step group.
So let's say
somebody who's been in AA
would have a slip.
And while they're
on the slip
they shot three people
and ran over four infants
and destroyed a building.
When they come back
to the group
what does everybody say?
George.
It's wonderful
to have you back.
You know what I mean?
It's wonderful
to have you back.
There is no interest
in a moralistic condemnation.
There is only
an interest
in what the person is.
And it's because
they're relating
they're beginning
to relate now
to the person's beingness.
That which they really are.
So the mother
who visits her son
in prison
for 20 years
a murderer
in prison
and when I was
a doctor
in the state hospitals
we had situations
exactly like that.
People
extremely psychotic
and in their
psychotic behavior
they had done
really terrible things
almost a terrible
dimension.
And yet the mothers
the families
would come
and visit them
throughout the rest
of their life.
So the unconditional love
then
overlooks
what the behavior is.
It says
that which is
the behavior
is coming out
of that
which is not understood.
It's coming out
of illness
it's coming out
of unknowingness
of ignorance
and that is not really
something greater than that.
And so
in Outlawics Anonymous
then what the people
relate to
is that which you really are.
And the behavior
is overlooked.
Nobody cares
what you have.
See at the bottom
of the box
people are interested
in what you have.
What you have.
Possessions
and titles
and appearances
and things
all having to do
with have.
In the middle of the box
people are interested
in what you do.
See your titles
what you do
in the world
becomes very important.
But as you move towards
the top of the box
what people are interested in
is what you are.
What you are.
And so
therefore
in recovery
from addictions
in AA
for instance
nobody cares
about what you have.
You can know somebody
for 20 years
and have them
disliked
about what they have
or interest.
You may even
after 20 years
still not really
even know
what they do
despite the fact
that you've talked
to them
on the most intimate level
about the most mind-boggling
thing anybody else
in the world about.
You still at this point
don't even know
what the person does.
What was it
you do again?
I forget what it is
an engineer or something
I don't know.
What the person is
that is what
is all important.
It's because
of what they are
that you honor them
and you protect them
and you support that
and you forgive them
and when they forget
the truth
of that which they are
then you hold that
for them
and remind them
of that.
And how that
powerful energy
feels
then you see
over on the right
we said
a process
a revelation.
So what's going on
within the brain
we sort of lost
track of the brain
here for a while.
The bottom
we had the death
hormone
the death enzyme
and then we had
depression
of neurotransmitters.
Up here we have
a build up
up here we have
of the neurotransmitters
you know high levels
of norepinephrine
and serotonin
etc.
And as we
get up here
we get into
the release
and the release
of the endorphins
having to do
with the activation
of the pituitary gland
and as you get up
near the top
having to do
with the endorphins
with the pineal gland
also
that is of critical
importance
and there's a lot
of research
coming out
in neuroscience
of course
having to do
with endorphins
and the part
that they play
in addiction
and that is a whole
subject in itself
we don't have time
today
to go into that
but that is a whole
subject
in the endorphins
and the treatments
that are based
in the illogic theories
on the presence
or the absence
of the endorphins
the most current
one being that
alcoholics
and others
have a deficiency
of these endorphins
and that the drug
releases an endorphin
and allows the person
to feel
normal
to those endorphins
as you move
up
and then
because of
the
what's happening
out of this revelation
out of the release
of the endorphins
you have awarenesses
now
that move
the person
up into levels
of joyfulness
which calibrate
about 540
up into energy
levels of ecstasy
which calibrate
at about 560
you start moving
into transfiguration
and states
of illumination
and you're moving
out towards
an energy field
which is right
about the level
at least you're in
the ballpark
of an energy field
called bliss
bliss in its most
generic sense
meaning
to feel expanded
it starts all the way
from
around 500
these levels
of bliss
start
and they start
with
I always call
mellow
I used to like mellow
mellow is a great
place to hang out
mellow is
you move
into mellow
from here
you have two martinis
and an empty stomach
or you smoke something
or nowadays
they sniff marvelous
white powder
and things
but anyway
you move
you move right up
into an energy field
called mellow
mellow is about 500
and from mellow
on up to 600
are the states
that you could say
are blissful
this state
at 600
then
as you move
closer to these
energy fields
are states
of inner joy
expansion
feeling
generous
forgiving
ecstatic
those who are
into
meditation
and various
other things
know what
we're talking
about
states in which
the personal self
is transcended
that which is
the small self
with its painful
limitations
is
transcended
and you begin
to experience
that which is
greater than
the personal self
progressive states
of joyfulness
of happiness
of transcendental
experience
and you begin
to experience
exquisite
ecstasies
as the person
gets closer
to an energy field
called bliss
this energy field
which I call
in these lectures
bliss then
is a state
of consciousness
very important
for us to know
about
because from
second to second
that is what a person
experiences
is it not
they experience
their own consciousness
for instance
you can't experience
the physical body
has no
capacity
for self awareness
it's in ascension
it's because
of the mind
you experience
what's going on
in the body
because that
is experienced
in the mind
no mind
no experience
of body
correct
it's only within
the mind
that the body
is experienced
the mind
itself
has no capacity
to experience
itself
a thought
cannot experience
its own thoughtness
that which is
going on
in the mind
its own self
neither does an emotion
it is because
it is taking place
within a fuel
called consciousness
it's because
what's going on
in mind
is registering
in consciousness
otherwise
there would be
no awareness
of what is going on
in mind
that's the whole basis
of anesthesia
remove consciousness
there's no awareness
of what goes on
in mind
or body
consciousness
itself
actually
has something
greater than itself
otherwise
and that is
absolute awareness
itself
that which is
the absolute
which is
unchanging
and ineffable
which has no beginning
and no end
that within which
there is no change
in which all change
takes place
but that which
itself does not change
because without
that which
does not change
there would be
no way of perceiving
that which does change
it is because
of the unchangeable
that the changeable
so that which
is going on
in consciousness
which is changeable
is
unbearable
because of awareness
itself
so all experience
then is going on
within consciousness
itself
so when we ask
people
who take drugs
for instance
to remember
back to the
greatest experience
that they ever had
and locate
where that experience
is
they without
exception
realize
it has nothing
to do with the drug
at all
the drug
is really immaterial
was only
the mechanism
by which
the drug
was created
is not about
an inner state
of consciousness
it was that inner state
that they sought
if drugs
if the drug
doesn't get you
to this state
it doesn't sell
I'll tell you that
these are called
in spiritual language
higher states
of consciousness
are they not
those are higher states
and in street language
we say
the drug
you know
people on drugs
are getting high
it is the inner state
it is that state
of consciousness
and what does it feel like
as you move into it
you move into
let's say
you're down here
into angriness
resentment
self-pity
what happens is
you begin to move into
mellowness
what is mellow
it means
what's a person like in mellow
they're generous
they're forgiving
they had an argument
with the wife
oh well
you call her up
say
sweetie I'm sorry
I was wrong
you know
they buy everybody
at the bar a drink
go get it
there's generosity
there's
all kinds of lovingness
the person who was not
very affectionate
now becomes affectionate
so what's happening then
is
that the drug
now we know
what a drug actually does
is block off
that which you are not
so you get closer
to the experience
of that which you are
to transcend the small self
and experience
that which is
the higher self
let's look at
this
let's say
if we had a drug
if we had a designer drug
that we could design
to block off
all the vibrations
of all these energy fields
all the emotions
all the experiences
if we could block
everything below ecstasy
on down
then what would you experience
you would experience ecstasy
and there just happens
to be such a drug
is there not
very specifically labeled
what the drug does
the designer drug
is
to block off
all that
is below
the energy field
of 560
so what does that do
to block off
all that
is to block off
the energy field
of 560
so what you experience
now
is that vibration
of energy field
of 560
you see
when you remove
the clouds
from the sky
that does not cause
the sun to shine
the sun shines
all the time
and these are
the clouds
and that which you are
is the sun
so that when you
remove the clouds
from the sky
artificially
or by whatever
if you could get
a big thing
that went
out there
and remove them
what you experience
of that which is
there all along
is the state
of consciousness
that the person seeks
by one means
or another
now the energy
that energy field
called bliss
that state
of consciousness
you experience
of that
ballpark
not necessarily
but anything
from 500 up
those experiences
and the higher
you get
the more powerful
they become
are what
is addicting
the energy field
to experience
is the most
addictive
of all human experiences
in my
personal
and professional
experience
to once have
experienced
that state
you will never be
the same again
to know
that it exists
to have ever
experienced it
this has
nothing to do
with drugs
it has nothing
to do with drugs
at all
but people
in the world
who fall into
this state
by virtue
of spiritual
practice
by virtue
of their own
experiences
by virtue
of their own
karma
that has brought
them to a certain
point of awareness
by virtue
of meditation
fall into states
of samadhi
to fall into
that state
to experience
that ultimate
truth
is the most
addicting
of all experiences
in
what do we
mean by
addicting
in this context
that the mind
now seeks
that above
all else
to be
a single drug
who fall into
that state
will very often
go through a whole
transformation
of consciousness
they will often
leave the world
and become totally
different
so we see
in a movie
like revelation
a movie like revelation
which was clinically
pretty accurate
i believe it was based
on a true life story
once she experiences
this state
of consciousness
of course
she couldn't stay
there
because she had
to come back
because of her
children
or whatever
it wasn't time
to leave and stay
in that state
so she had
to come back
from it
but she was
transformed
she was no longer
the same person
having experienced
that
having known
having come into
the power
of that
some of it
stays with you
and so
her life
became transformed
she did a total
turnaround
and became
a healer
and at the villa
i used to give
three lectures
and then on the fourth
thursday night
when i'm not there
they watch
lost horizon
because it
is such a beautiful
description
of what the whole
this whole experience
is about
you remember
that they're lost
in the himalayas
or something
and some of them
survive
and go through
a pass
and as they go
in through a pass
they walk into
what is really
an energy field
that i calibrated
out of it
and shangri-la
then
is a state
of consciousness
of such unconditional
lovingness
and perfection
of the awareness
of the truth
of who you are
that the exquisiteness
of it
is like
the inner
quiet
joy
and ecstasy
and as they
so
once having had
this experience
of course
the hero
of the story
played by ronald
coleman
in the original
version
for those of you
who haven't seen it
yet
in the lower part
of the box
at all
he was already
in a very high
state
i think he was
up for prime minister
i forget what the
aristocratic level
was but
he was a person
who was very
satisfied
in the world
so he goes back
into the world
and he cannot find
satisfaction
in the world
anymore
because the memory
of what is possible
the memory
of that which is
always there
you see
because shangri-la
is always there
this state
of consciousness
like the sun shining
is always there
and you know
that the only thing
that's blocking it
is your own access
to it
it's within you
and so people
who've experienced
that then
go back
to reflecting
to purification
to removing
that which is
in the box
so as to move
back into that
energy field
on a permanent basis
and so in the movie
he goes back
into the world
and he tries
to find satisfaction
within the world
worldly success
money
power
success
sex
all the things
that the world
says
are what you
should want
you see
all those things
they all calibrate
out at about 200
so he goes back
into a solar plexus
world
of about 200
of success
and power
and appearance
and prestige
and status
and all those things
having once experienced
something like 600
an energy field
of 200
is really no longer
appealing
tell the former
person who's
experienced this
you should really
get a new job
and get a hobby
and move to Cincinnati
and quit that girlfriend
and move out
of your mother's house
alright
what we're suggesting
is a 200
solution
to a 600
experience
and that's why
it doesn't work
a 600
energy problem
requires
a 600
energy answer
and so
in Shangri-La
you see
finally
he tries his best
to do what he can
within the world
but the memory
of that
the knowing
inner experience
because in Shangri-La
what you experience
is the truth
of your own
isness
and so
he lets go
of everything
in the world
and he struggles
to go back
into Shangri-La
and in so
doing
he sacrifices
everything
sacrifices
and becomes
like a madman
they say
he's like a madman
as he went
through the villages
and finally
even the Sherpas
desert him
and he's left
all by himself
the lone survivor
who finally
at the point of death
gets back
to Shangri-La
but it's
a very
difficult time
it's different
this time
the struggle
see
the first time
he lands there
by accident
karmically
you might say
the plane lands
within striking distance
and he
gets there
but the second time
it is only
you know
through his own
personal effort
and constant
recommitment
he has to say
yes
every step of the way
when he landed
there by accident
he didn't have to
and say yes to it. He has to say yes to every step of the way to get back to that mountain pass.
And then he returns to Shangri-La, but this time it is different. He is now himself the one who
holds that for Shangri-La. You remember the old leader of the community had died in the interim,
and now he was the one holding that level of consciousness for the group. So the power then
of that experience, the power of that experience. So what happens of course with the drugs is the
drugs don't have any power to create a state of highness. Drugs have no power at all. We will
test this out in the class today and prove it. It's a critical point. It's why the world can't
handle the drug experience. It doesn't know what it is. What the person then is addicted to is the
re-experiencing of this energy field.
Drugs block off the shadows, they block off the
clouds and allow you to experience a vibration
and energy field which is always there. But the drug itself does not have the power to create
that experience. It only has the power to remove the block to that experience,
that experience which would be there all the time for everyone, all the time,
if it weren't for what's-in-the-box blocking our awareness of it.
So all the drugs
does is clear the field for you to experience something that is already
there. It has no power to create that whatsoever. Drug has no power to create
any high at all. It only has the power to block off that which is not the truth
about yourself and get closer to the energy and the feeling and the inner
vibration of that which is. That's why it is so addicting, see, because then the
left brain says, the left brain gets that sequence. It gets to take the drug, move
up in the box, experience that feeling. It must be in the box. It must be in the
drug. It must be in the drug. An aew person thinks it must be in the drug.
People, who in the great days of LSD, took LSD with proper preparation, you see.
Spent a year of meditation and fasting and spiritual study, took it once, walked
out of that which they were and experienced that which was there since
the beginning of time. They walked into that which always was.
. . .
and realized the truth of that, what that was, and never took it again.
People who really took LSD correctly took it maybe once, maximum twice.
Because it was very obvious that it wasn't a drug at all.
All the drug had done was remove your ability to witness that which is.
And the realization of that which is then,
I mean, the people came out of that with an intense spiritual commitment,
and you saw a great rise in spiritual commitment to spiritual values and all,
and then people spent the rest of their lives purifying themselves
to return to a state which only through the LSD experience,
let's say for them perhaps, did they verify the truth of that.
So the person suspected this is so, verified this is so,
and now spends the rest of their life returning to that.
Anybody with any awareness realizes, obviously,
that you cannot experience the truth of that which you are by repeatedly taking LSD.
I mean, that was sort of retarded.
That's not the right way to do it.
Anybody who really took it in the proper context took it once.
Because all it did was verify for you that that is always there,
that it is what it is,
and that you see that which is within you is blocking your awareness of that experience.
The work of removing that which is blocking the experience then
is what the rest of your life is dedicated to.
So that would be how to do it consciously.
Many people say,
well, of course, did not do it consciously,
and instead for the glamour and the sensation of it.
But people who had a transcendental experience,
which happened in the very early days,
because it was then, in those days, considered a sacrament,
it allowed you, as Aldous Huxley said,
it opened the doors of perception,
allowed you to experience that which is.
But the drug does not create that which is.
And of course, that is one of the great problems in the drug experience,
is that the left brain begins to think that it is,
for the person who has never had that experience otherwise,
that the power is in the drug.
The power is in the drug.
The person thinks the power is in the drug.
You see, in the beginning, a person, let's say, is nervous,
and self-conscious, and etc.
And they stop by, and they have two martinis,
and now they go into a mellow,
and they go to this business conference,
and they carry it out successfully.
I mean, nobody is being harmed, right?
There's no scandal being created.
I mean, what's wrong with that?
What's wrong with moving from a negative energy field,
resentment, let's say, and nervousness, and anxiety,
and moving into a lovingness,
where you are concerned about the welfare of humanity,
and love, and generosity?
So what's wrong with that?
Why does it end up in such a disaster?
I mean, how come it ends up in the pits of hell?
How does the energy field get reversed?
I mean, why does it go from a positive,
mellow, happy lovingness,
to a hatefulness?
The father that used to have a drink or two on his way home,
and come home happy, and the kids love to see him,
now as the years go by, comes home nasty,
and selfish, and then becomes physically violent,
and everybody hates him, and fears him,
and finally the family breaks up.
What happened?
He's only doing the same thing he did in the beginning.
In the beginning he stopped for two martinis,
and he came home mellow.
Now he stops for two martinis,
and he comes home violent and nasty.
What has changed?
What has happened?
What has been the critical?
What is going on?
What's going on is that he's given the power to the drugs,
in my own particular research into the question.
What's happened is that the energy field,
we said that the truth puts you above the line.
If truth puts you above the line,
then a lie puts you below the line.
So when he gives the power to the drug,
when he gives the power to the drug,
then what happens is he reverses the energy field,
because the lie, the telling of the untruth,
is what reverses the field.
Now a lie that's told at a minus 50,
let's say you're down in apathy at 50,
your life is one entire lie anyway.
The whole context of your life is a lie.
And all you do is lie all day long anyway,
so one more lie doesn't really have that profound an effect.
But if you're in a very high state,
and you owe the lie,
the effect is disastrous.
A lie with a power of 550 behind it
is quite a different lie
than a thought with an energy field of 50 behind it.
A lie at 550 has,
can totally reverse all your energies
and totally transform your life now into destruction.
So we see,
it's the giving of the power,
the power, the truth of that which you are,
you now deny,
and you say it does not exist within me.
On the contrary, it exists out there.
It is within that.
And the giving away the truth of that which you are
then reverses the energy field.
And if you want, later we can test that out,
test out the truth of that.
But it is the ascribing of the power,
the truth of that which you are,
to something that is outside of you that you are not.
And it is that statement
which is made in a high energy state.
See, it is in the high energy state that you say,
it is that that created this.
You didn't say that in a low energy state,
you said that in a high energy state.
With a lot of power.
550 is a lot of power.
So in a high energy state you said,
the power is in that.
It is that that I worship.
This is what I worship. It has become my idol.
This is the center of my life now.
God has been really replaced by that.
That which I am has been replaced by that.
The giving of the power away then to that
is what reverses the energy field.
So now, that which at one time you got high,
now sends you into destruction.
The very same thing now is the two-faced genus.
Suddenly its face turns around
and you see that the energy field has reversed.
That which once was positive in your life
is now the most destructive thing in your life.
So I thought, well, we'll take a break now
that we've gotten to what the addiction is.
The addiction is to that state of consciousness called bliss.
It really has nothing at all to do with the drug.
And the drug comes in accidentally in our society,
because most people don't meditate themselves
in the states of samadhi.
They experience that state only through drugs.
And therefore it is a phenomenon of our society
of being a materialistic culture.
I said this afternoon we'll test out,
we'll use, for instance, kinesiology
to test out the truth of some of the statements we've made.
Especially, and most importantly,
the one that people who themselves have become addicted
are most impressed by,
is the awareness of what it is they're addicted to.
After saying this for some time, a year or two,
I ran across a writing by Ramana Maharshi.
Ramana Maharshi being one of the great saints of India,
enlightened in the view of the world,
and a very famous person.
But anyway, Ramana Maharshi said,
in one of his books that I ran across,
that the reason the person becomes intoxicated
is to experience the self.
And that once a person learns what it is they are seeking
through the intoxication,
they will then seek that directly.
So I thought it was very interesting,
because Ramana Maharshi never took a drink in his life.
He knew nothing about addiction,
and yet he knew that.
That once the person realizes what it is they are seeking,
that inner experience in consciousness,
once they realize what that is,
they will then begin to seek it directly.
And of course, that's the whole function of 12-step groups.
That's the whole function of Alcoholics Anonymous.
So now we can see,
from a viewpoint of consciousness itself,
we have some greater understanding then,
of how the 12 steps work,
and how the whole field, the energy field, of AA works.
Because we see in the first step,
the first step was we admitted we were powerless.
We admitted we were powerless,
powerless over alcohol or drugs,
as the case may be.
And the minute,
when you come out of denial,
when you come out of this denial,
and the reversed energy field,
which is bringing destruction into the person's life,
the admission that I'm powerless over alcohol or drugs
is the first statement of the truth.
And what it does is reverse the energy field
and bring into the person's life,
through empowerment,
the first reaction you see,
in fact, the external representation of that empowerment,
is that they find themselves now in an energy field of 500 and over.
So they become empowered then.
So the first step of Alcoholics Anonymous then,
because it tells the truth,
reverses the energy field, the admission,
that I'm powerless over drugs and alcohol.
The second step of Alcoholics Anonymous then,
you know, deepens that statement of truth.
The awareness that some power
greater than myself
is necessary to return me to sanity.
Insanity, in that definition,
being anything in these destructive energy states,
those denials of the truth then,
and languaged as insanity.
Something greater than myself is necessary
to turn this whole field around.
Something greater than myself,
and by that they're talking about the small self.
Something outside of,
and more powerful than the ego,
is going to be necessary to conquer the ego.
Something greater than what is in the box.
Something that is outside of the box.
Some lever that has the power
to lift that which is in the box.
Intuitive awareness that I, of my own self,
this self here, unaided,
do then have the power to overcome
the attraction of an energy field of that power.
The attraction to return to that state of consciousness
is so powerful that it requires something
of equal power to neutralize it and to handle it.
That's an admission of the truth.
So the second step then,
furthers and deepens the commitment to the truth
and brings the person face to face with the third step.
The willingness to turn over
my life and my will
to God as I understand him,
to something greater than myself.
The turning over,
the surrender.
So the step of surrender then,
coming out of the pain and the suffering
of the descents into hell,
because these lower states are really
approaching states of hell.
The surrender, the letting go then,
and the turning over of one's life
to something greater than oneself,
that moves one up into this energy field
of the self-help groups of the 500 energy fields.
That surrender, that I myself cannot do it,
is what brings about eventually the salvation
because it opens the space for something
greater than oneself to come in.
It opens the space for the grace of God.
And so people who recover from the addictions
will say that it happened to them
as the grace of God.
It is not something that the ego did
of its own doingness.
That it was something outside
of that which I thought I was
that transformed my life
and the desire to drink disappeared,
which is what exactly happened
to my own personal experience.
Being an atheist at the time,
an atheist for some 20 years,
and a devoted atheist,
a devout atheist,
not a casual cocktail lounge atheist,
but I mean I was an atheist,
because I was committed to the truth.
And we'll get to that when we talk about
the various conceptualizations of God.
My own dedication to the truth told me
that how it was conceived was false.
And so anyway,
that preoccupation with God
has gone on throughout my life.
When I was a child,
I was a devoted religionist.
And then I became a devoted atheist.
And then in a moment
when I myself hit bottom
at a great depth and great despair
and out of utter hopelessness,
I asked God,
if there was such an entity
in the universe to help me.
I didn't hold my breath,
not thinking that there was any such item.
So the denial broke down,
the arrogance of the intellect.
The arrogance of the intellect.
Being a left-brained person,
I didn't conceive that there was anything
other than intelligence.
I thought that intelligence was God,
that man through his intelligence
would solve all his problems,
through his intellect.
And I worshipped the intellect.
I was baptized by the God of the intellect.
Reason, you know, Thomas Paine's age,
reason really hit me when I was like 15 or 16
when I became an atheist.
Reason and the intellect,
the left brain, the intellect,
the IQ, I was born with a good IQ.
So I thought IQ,
intelligence, reason, science,
that was going to solve all man's dilemmas.
Hmm.
Following my best reasoning,
I found myself at death's door,
having been given up as hopeless.
And so, having followed my own best reasoning,
I found myself
at the very bottom of the box,
very close to death.
And suicide, by the way,
calibrates at a minus 50.
Zero, it's below zero,
it's in the lower beginnings of hell.
So I had a reversed energy field of minus 50.
So from that state,
the atheist asked if there was something
greater than himself in the universe
and totally surrendered
and committed himself to that.
Whatever there was.
That emptiness, it seemed to me that nothingness.
And walked off the cliff.
And in that instant,
in that instant,
was an enormous transformation.
And the person that had been
no longer existed.
And instead,
stood in the presence of the infinite,
the infiniteness of the universe.
That which had infinite power.
And it ran me.
It ran whatever this body did
or whatever it said,
what it thought, what went on with it,
was run by that
infinite presence.
So from the very bottom of the box,
you can break out of the box
through that
experience of surrender.
So that's the third step,
which creates the space
for that which by grace
takes the place of that which we were.
Got a question?
What she asks is,
is grace available to anyone who asks for it?
It is only by asking for it
that we create the space.
It is because of the law of free will.
So when we ask for it,
we create the space,
the possibility
for it to happen.
It was only through the surrender
that such an incredible experience
could have occurred.
Bill Wilson said that
AA is the language of the heart.
That heart being.
So when we talk about that chakra,
the energy field of the heart,
see these are the laws
of the lower energy fields,
the lower chakras,
you move up through the solar plexus
and then you move into the heart.
So Bill Wilson said AA
is the language of the heart,
not of the intellect,
not of the head,
not of the mind with a small m,
but that of one's own inner experience.
So the third step then opens
the way for that.
Through that despair,
the arrogance of the ego
finally lets go.
Through the addiction,
there is a total transformation.
The transformation may not be complete
and include the whole personality,
obviously,
because that's the reason for the 12 steps.
But at least in one area
there has been complete and absolute
and total surrender
and its replacement by grace.
The fourth step then says
that we took a fearless moral inventory.
So the fourth step then says
what we did was we looked in the box,
we looked in our box
in our own particular case.
And after looking in the box
to see what's in there in our own particular case,
for one thing we discovered
if we move on to the fifth step
that what's in our box is no different
than what's in everybody else's box,
the ego being the same in everyone.
The ego is really the same
in its design, in its overall
way of being in everyone.
So that whatever we find within our own
personal experience really falls
somewhere within the box.
And therefore the fifth step
says we admitted
to God and to ourselves
and to another human
being the exact
nature of what we discovered
within ourself.
In admitting it to
myself, in admitting it
to God and to another fellow human being
what I've done now is reversed the
energy field on it, taken the charge
off it, removed its
power to corrode and
destroy. When I look
at a thing, when I let go of the deny
when I'm willing to handle whatever
pain comes up in the looking at it,
the willingness to heal it,
to ask that it be healed,
to share it with another human being
is part of the whole process
of healing it.
Because that which is held in mind
and never shared has by
that virtue of that power
to corrode. The minute it's shared
with another human being it's now held
in a different way, it's held in a different
context, it's transformed into a shared
communication and
its capacity to destroy has not
been removed. So the event
in one's life, instead
of lying awake at night
hating in self-hatred, that
self-hatred which comes out the bottom
of the box, maybe
what's left of it is a mild
regret, a mild regret.
So that's what Bill Wilson said.
He said that whatever you've done in your life
at best, the way to hold
it now is with a decent regret.
A decent regret.
To replace that horrible
intense self-hatred and depression
and contempt, self-contempt
which leads to the actual
seeking out of destruction.
You see that the process coming out of the box
is the
willful, lethal satisfaction
out of one's own
destruction. Because an energy
fuel that reverses now seeks
its own destruction. And so
you tell the person that they're killing
themselves with drugs
and you think you're going to scare them out of it
you're merely appealing to this.
You bet I am. Love it.
Love it. Love it.
So you see how you're playing right
into the person's self-destruction.
To say if you keep on drinking
your liver is going to fail.
Fine. The people
got an unconscious satisfaction
out of that
self-destruction. There was a purpose in it
and it was the only way they could see to go.
In this energy field here
self-destruction is obviously
what is appealing to you and attractive.
So, the fifth step
then removes the appeal and the
attractiveness of that which is
destructive. It is no longer
appealing.
That leads us to the sixth through
the ninth steps, you see.
Having looked at what's in the
box and having seen what its
nature is now and admitted
it to ourself and changed the charge
on that through sharing
it and asking God's forgiveness
and help with it. Then what we
do is we move back into the world
into a step of action. We
moved up in the box to appropriate
action and not through action
to try and undo what damage
we can. To repair
whatever fences that we
can repair. To
tell people that we're sorry for how we
were. To
ask for their forgiveness. To
pay up the bills that we didn't pay.
You know, to give
the employer a good day's work.
And we always suggest that people
do that with the help of a sponsor.
Hopefully that their wisdom will keep
people from impetuously
acting out in a self-destructive
way. But the best way
to repay your boss
is not to tell them that you've been
embezzling
out of the cash box the last ten years, which
make it an M.I.
Raider calling the police.
The best way to repay him would be to give him
an honest day's work for a change.
And the best
way to heal and repair
your relationship is to put
the best that you can into it to make that
relationship work. So to try
to undo the damage that came out of
the past then. So that
that inner searching into
what was wrong within then
becomes reflected back in the world
in those steps six through nine.
The tenth step then says
that we began to, we
made a habit of this. In other words,
it became our way of life.
Self-purification.
Because the drugs took us to the bottom of
the box and now through the
spiritual program of the
twelve steps we're moving back up through the
box. So the tenth step said
that this became our way of life.
It is the way we became in
the world. That the best of
our knowledge as we became aware
as we became aware
of that which was wrong within us
we sought to correct it.
And so that commitment to self-correction
to spiritual growth
to becoming more conscious then
becomes part of the way of life
that comes out of this experience.
The eleventh step
is an interesting one. The eleventh
step says, sought through
prayer and meditation
to increase our conscious contact
with God as we understood Him.
That's a very interesting statement
when you look at it. It says
sought through prayer and meditation
to increase
our conscious contact with God.
To increase our contact with
God as we understood Him.
So what that is saying then is
by the time you've gone through
steps one through ten
eleven doesn't say try to
establish contact with some
power greater than myself.
Eleven says increase
that which has already happened.
So that
whole process of surrender
the opening of the energy fuels
the experience of some
inner grace, the spiritual
growth that comes out of that
what happens is you reconnect within yourself
with something that is rock
like. See that which is love
that which is divine
is not different than love.
So
I always tell people
in these programs who
have trouble with the God aspect
of it to forget about the God aspect
of it and instead commit themselves
to this energy fuel called
love and to these states up here
which are called compassion
to commit oneself to truth
to love and to compassion.
Forget about the God aspect
because what happens as time goes
on is you feel that
rock like interconnectedness
and so you'll hear people
who have been sober for some time
will talk about their sobriety
as though it was some very
wonderful and positive
attribute
and they will guard that with their life.
What these people seemed to have
was something that was so great
that they would go to any lengths to guard it
and to protect it. Something of
great significance that they had something
over and beyond that which they had gotten out of
alcohol and drugs in the first place
otherwise they would still be back in alcohol
and drugs. Something of a greater
dimension had come into their life
and it was within them.
The kingdom of God is experienced
within and so that
rock like reconnection with that which
they had sought in the beginning
now was happening. So step 11
then merely said
that there was a desire
now and following through
on how to increase the power of that
connectedness with something that
had come back within the self.
Some re-experiencing of truth
had recurred
and that brought them to the 12th step
and the 12th step then explains
what the whole process
of addiction is about.
Step 12 says
having become conscious as a result
of this total addictive experience
of having become addicted, having
surrendered, having hit bottom
having turned around, having
gone through a process of spiritual purification
and the wording of it
is having had a spiritual
awakening as a result
of this whole experience.
So now we see what the process
of addiction is all about. It is a
movement in consciousness
it is a one way street
a one way commitment because
once your own consciousness
has picked addiction as
the way to becoming conscious
as the way to becoming spiritually aware
there is no backing up
there is no changing of one's mind
you cannot join this pathway
and then leave it and join some other pathway
and commit to some other church
and then go to unity for a while
and then do the course of miracles
move around through one thing and another
you are now committed
to a one way street
walking a razor's edge because
there isn't enough room on it
to turn around and go back.
Addiction is a one way street
it is a total confront with
the absolute necessity
of becoming more conscious
in order to live
so that the price of life now
itself is that
one has to become more conscious
and that is the whole purpose
in consciousness then of
the pathway so it is really
a pathway
a consciousness pathway
the whole purpose of addiction then is
it is a way in which
one is forced
despite oneself to become conscious
to own the truth about oneself
to a much greater degree
or one dies
in the process and therefore
it is a very powerful
commitment it is really in a way
a long shot because
you either make it you either become more conscious
or you go out the bottom of the box
and at the villa they talk about
going out the bottom of the box
and this last week somebody else went out the bottom of the box
because the statistics
are not all that great
out of 10 million alcoholics
there is 500,000 sober
roughly one out of 20
means that it is a long shot
in which maybe one out of 20
will own the truth about themselves
to a sufficient degree
that their life will return to them
so the 12th step
then gives away what the purpose
the whole purpose
the end the goal of addiction
is and that is to become more conscious
see you can't change
your mind once you are an addicted
person you cannot become
unaddicted once you have
experienced this energy state
there is no way to remove
it from ones memory
ones alignment with the returning
to that state the desire to
return to that state
its impossible to replace that state
with anything else because anything else
is of a much lesser degree
a much lesser degree
the desire to return to that state
then becomes that which
runs the person
so we tell people
at the villa that
what it is you sought you don't have to be ashamed of
what you sought
was the same thing that all the saints
and everyone else has sought
to experience that great
state within oneself
the presence within
that which is the truth
what you have to know is that
what's wrong with drugs is
they don't work
it's not because they're wrong
it's not because they're destructive
it's just that they do not work that's all
they work up to a certain point
and then once the energy fuel reverses
they do not work so the reason to give up drugs
and alcohol is frankly
that they no longer work
they don't work
and now that you know what it is you're addicted to
you don't have to change your direction at all
your goal before
what you sought was to experience
this higher energy state
so you don't have to change your direction
you only have to change the means of getting there
you only have to change
the means of getting there
so that now you own it yourself
so that as you return
to that state
it's because of what you are
it is not something out there
it's merely the awareness of what you are
so that
that state now stems and comes from
within yourself
as people go through a confront
you know a confront with the facts
about their addiction they go through these
various experiences
they very often come in
in the bottom state of despondency
and everybody pours
energy into them in which state
often they start to cry
at the grief over their experience
to find yourself committed
to find yourself at the bottom of the box
to find that all that you have valued
has been lost and taken away
the person goes into grief
grief over the realization
that they are addicted
grief over the realization that they have
what seems to them
is an impossible problem
and out of that comes the fear
to help the person through the fear
of what the consequences of this addiction are
and move them up into desiring
something better for themselves
to move themselves
to move them up into anger
to use that anger to move them into pride
to move them into courage
and so the person can be moved
out of the bottom of the box
and we will see later
a social phenomena which demonstrates
these principles extremely well