We're producing this videotape informally out at the ranch.
It's not a studio production.
The purpose is to merely illustrate the main points that we make in the book Power vs. Force.
We want to illustrate the technique of kinesiology, something about theory,
something about its application in a great many different areas of life.
So this first videotape is a broad, general overview of the subject.
And not in-depth on any one particular thing.
Those will be separate videotapes.
So this is the general overview, and as you'll see from the menu, which we'll follow shortly,
we're going to touch briefly on a lot of subjects.
The one we're going to explore most, of course, is consciousness itself,
because that's what the whole book is about.
All right, I thought I'd just show you the basic technique of kinesiology.
We're going to leave.
We're going to take theory to a different section.
And the various subjects we're going to cover section by section.
But first is the basic technique itself.
It's very, very simple.
You ask the person to hold out their arm.
I usually use two fingers.
First, I want to know their relative strength.
Resist.
I always say resist.
All right, now to make sure this is a suitable subject,
I ask the person to picture someone they love.
Close your eyes.
Picture someone you love and resist.
Okay.
Now picture some horrible event in your life or somebody you don't love.
Got it?
Picture Adolf Hitler.
Resist.
All right, a normal subject goes strong with love and goes weak with hate or fear.
Or a normal subject goes, hold, hold it here, I'm licking it in mine.
Resist.
Okay.
Hold Adolf Hitler in mine.
Resist.
All right, a normal subject goes positive with positive stimuli.
And goes weak with negative stimuli.
This is very, very important to first test the subject.
There are 2.4% of the population will give you the opposite effect.
And this is a whole subject in itself.
These are people whose acupuncture system is totally blown out.
Their thymus gland is totally blown out.
Occasionally, a normal person will give you a paradoxical response.
The way you cure that was figured out by Dr. John Diamond.
The negative, the paradoxical response, that is, something positive makes you go weak,
is due to an underactivity of the thymus gland, the immune suppression.
So if you get a normal person who's leading a normal life,
who's not into criminality and negativity and heavy metal rock and drugs and stuff,
and they give you a paradoxical response,
you can use what John Diamond, the Dr. Diamond, called the thymic thump.
You go, thymus gland is right.
here it's the central organ of the immune system so if a person who's
normal gives you a paradoxical response you smile think of someone you love and
you thump over the thymus gland rhythmically three times you like this
ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha now when you retest the person they will go normal
except for 2.4 percent of population who won't go normal anyway all right so
first we make sure we have a normal test subject next we don't have any
extraneous extraneous stimuli in other words it's very important not to have
music in the background it's best to be to get for accurate results you should
be impersonal try not to radiate love and affection and laughter and that kind
of thing because you don't want to get false positives you can have the subject
close their eyes because what they're looking at might have an effect like
anything else
you
just takes a little experimentation when you're learning archery how to run a
video camera or what just takes a little experience it's a very very reliable
technique as we've said elsewhere in these tapes it's been used by tens of
thousands of practitioners for over 20 years all around the globe all kinds of
physicians and our neurologists and nutritionists physicians of all kinds
chiropractors it's extremely accurate
the only difference is the way it's been used up until the research I did was
mainly for material things and strictly physical phenomena and I'm really took
it out to different dimensions so that's the technique and will demonstrate it in
a variety of subjects okay well you're like a little radio and we're gonna get
you to cut in and tell us what's playing in the field of consciousness so let's
see you like these did you have some of those before no this switch is on now
let's see you like these did you have some of those before no this switch is on now
All right. First, we're going to just check this out.
Put your arm out. Now resist.
Now hold somebody you love in, hold your mom in mind.
Resist. Okay.
Hold somebody you don't like in mind.
You got somebody you don't like?
Somebody you're scared of?
Okay. Resist.
She goes weak. She really goes weak.
Okay. You like those, huh?
I know you like them because you're eating them up.
You're eating them up for...
What? Look at the curtain.
The energy of these is positive.
Okay. Resist.
Well, all these will be sort of positive.
The energy of what's in this is positive. Resist.
You're pretty strong when something goes positive.
No, she never does.
You can look at it if you want.
Just look at this guy and hold him in mind.
Now resist.
Hold him. Resist.
Okay. His energy is positive.
That's Mr. Deutsch, who's head of the CIA.
Oh.
That's very good news. Let's see.
Okay. Here's a newspaper. It's got somebody's picture in it.
This man has positive energy. Resist.
This man has a negative energy. Resist.
Here's the positive energy.
This man's energy calibrates over 500.
Over 540.
560.
570.
This man's energy calibrates over 560.
Did you study about him in school?
You know what that is?
Yeah. Abraham Lincoln.
Abraham Lincoln.
Where's those nasty things?
Oh, here they are.
Hold those over your solar plexus.
The energy of this product is positive. Resist.
You think you're going to smoke them?
No.
They make you go weak.
Who wants to smoke something that's going to make you go weak?
Well, here's something interesting.
Did you ever see these before?
No.
All right. Let's just say
the energy of what you...
You can look at it.
The energy of what you're looking at is positive. Resist.
All right.
She went weak but manufactured tobacco.
Look at the kind of thing.
Now, this was grown organically.
What I'm trying to demonstrate here with this tobacco
is that the response is not only the opposite
of what the individual believes.
The response is the opposite of what everybody believes.
Everybody thinks that this causes cancer and yet you went positive.
So, what we are merely demonstrating is
that the answer will be the same no matter what a person's belief system is.
I've tested this a lot of times
and a group of 20 people all convinced
that tobacco causes cancer
and yet when I hold this organic,
hold that over your tummy,
the energy of this is positive. Resist.
The energy of this is negative. Resist.
So, despite the fact that everybody has a very strong,
reinforced belief system,
the answer we got was exactly the opposite.
So, what we're demonstrating then is
the impersonality of this response.
Here's a letter I wrote about some guy.
I don't even know his name.
We came to a meeting.
This man's energy is positive. Resist.
This man's energy is negative. Resist.
All right.
See, we get the same answer.
She doesn't know anything about any of this.
She doesn't know any of the people.
It's just as valid in kids as it is in adults.
And, again, what we're testing
is the capacity of this field
to detect the differences between truth and falsehood.
We'll add something that I wrote about in the book.
To become acquainted with the contents of this book here,
to become familiar with it,
to read that book and sort of get it,
raises a person's level of consciousness. Resist.
It raises it over 20 points. Resist.
30 points. Resist.
35 points. Resist.
37 points. Resist.
Now, the interesting thing is,
anybody who's ever heard the lectures or read the book,
their own level of consciousness jumps 35 points.
Now, in the average lifetime,
the average person on the planet,
during their lifetime,
their level of consciousness advances over 5 points. Resist.
Does not.
It advances over 4 points.
5 points.
6 points.
The average person's level of consciousness
advances exactly 5 points in one lifetime.
And, therefore,
merely to become familiar with the truth about consciousness itself,
seems to jump a person's own level of consciousness 35 points.
So, to read the book,
by the time you finish the book,
you won't be the same person who started the book.
And the second time you read the book,
you will be a person of more advanced consciousness,
and the book will make a lot more sense the second time through.
I thought I'd just take something out of the current news.
We're going to start with archaeology.
Start with archaeology,
because it just so happened that
on TV the other night, I think it was Channel 8,
was a whole program on Atlantis.
Archaeologic research.
You know, Plato, 2300 years ago,
wrote about the lost continent of Atlantis.
Now, he said that Atlantis existed 9,000 years before.
However, we feel,
or the program brought up,
that he's probably off one decimal.
It was probably 900 years before, not 9,000.
Differences of one decimal
occur like in Britain and the United States.
There's a difference of one decimal
as to what constitutes a billion.
All right.
The program brought this up.
Did Atlantis exist 9,000 or 900 years before Plato?
So let's just ask that question.
On the program it asked,
and we'll ask now,
Plato was correct in stating that Atlantis existed 9,000 years
prior to his existence.
More accurately,
there's a difference of a decimal there.
What he meant in our use of numerology
was 900 years before this.
All right.
Now, the program brought up various places Atlantis could be.
Let's ask these questions.
Atlantis is located under Antarctica, resist.
Atlantis is located near Bimini, resist.
Where did they say it was?
They said it was more likely located in the Aegean Sea, resist.
That's interesting.
That's what they said probably.
Near the island of Thera, resist.
Was it the same as the old city of Akroteria?
Akroteria, resist.
Good.
All right.
So this suggests that archaeologically Atlantis existed in the Aegean Sea
because it was outside the streets of Gibraltar.
But it doesn't say from what direction.
Here's another interesting thing here.
This week's newspaper says,
Buddha's birthplace found in Nepal, archaeologists say.
This is a correct location, resist.
This is actually the Buddha's birthplace, resist.
All right.
You'll notice that I don't ask questions.
I make a statement.
So in using the technique,
we always make a statement, a positive statement.
Most of the inaccuracies that people write me
that they're not getting accurate results
are due to the fact that they ask questions.
It's very easy to lapse into asking a question,
like, is this the correct place for the Buddha's birthplace,
instead of just making a statement.
Well, the archaeologic applications, of course, are endless.
And this film has to be of a certain limited length,
so we could spend one entire videotape
just checking out archaeology
and primitive drawings and caves
and the ancient caves
in France.
And we can go back into paleontology
and track down, you know, the various artifacts
and date them as their exact age
of the various skulls
and things that have been found in Africa and elsewhere.
So the archaeologic applications are pretty endless.
Let's go on to art.
And we have some interesting current things
having to do with art.
For instance,
in a recent Time magazine here,
we have a new Cupid.
And is it really a Michelangelo?
Hmm.
So here is a question.
That Cupid is actually a Michelangelo.
Resist.
No, not a Michelangelo.
Here is a piece of original art.
Want to hold that over here so it reflects this?
This is a genuine piece of art.
This is a genuine Salvador Dali resist.
Look at the signature here.
That is actually Dali's signature resist.
That's good to know,
because when you invest in art,
you're often talking about very large amounts of money.
This is a genuine piece of art resist.
No.
This is authentic resist.
Hmm.
What's the name here?
Picasso.
Okay.
Look at that.
That is a genuine autograph resist.
Okay.
We can ask the question now in reverse.
This is actually a very clever fake resist.
Okay.
When you're investing several million dollars,
it's really good to know.
There are three paintings at the National Museum of Washington right now,
the authenticity of which is being disputed.
So using this technique here,
as you can see,
you could arrive at an answer rather quickly.
I thought some applications in business might be useful.
It might be very interesting to just briefly run through.
As you can see,
each one of these could take us all afternoon.
And here's an interesting business application
that is very practical.
Here's a few checks I got in the mail.
Hold that over your solar plexus.
This is a good check, resist.
As you can see,
it was rejected,
lack of sufficient funds.
Hmm.
Here's a proposition asking me
to accept a transfer of $320,000 from Nigeria.
This is a legitimate business proposition, resist.
This is a criminal enterprise, resist.
This is a criminal enterprise.
It just so happened that there was a TV program about this.
In Nigeria,
there's some peculiarity of the corporate
and business laws
that allows them to do this kind of thing,
and they apparently have made a lot of money
on a lot of people.
I thought we would ask something.
Let's just ask,
what is the integrity of this publisher, resist?
Well, that's good to know.
Veritas Publishing.
So before you invest in something,
a stock, a bond,
before you use a certain investment counselor,
you can check out the integrity of that particular enterprise,
that broker,
or that stock.
I bought for the first time
some mutual fund,
some mutual funds.
Let's see, what was the name of them?
Oh, yes.
This is an integrates fund, resist.
That's good to know.
All right, so what I just,
what I want to demonstrate is that the response
doesn't have anything to do with my verbalizing the thing.
It has to do with my holding it within consciousness.
I don't have to tell you the name out loud.
I can keep it in my mind,
and we'll get to the reason for that.
That brings us to the subject of consciousness itself.
Some explanation is necessary.
We said that consciousness,
we calibrated here the levels of consciousness.
We could zoom in on that.
And on page 52 of the book,
this map appears.
I just wanted to show you that we can recapitulate this.
These are actually,
you see, consciousness is like a potential energy field,
and within it are so-called levels,
which we call attractor,
attractor fields.
That comes out of nonlinear dynamics and chaos theory.
We'll get more into that in the section where we talk about theory,
but what chaos theory discovered was
that behind what appears like random data,
that there is actually an organizing pattern.
The most random data I can think of
is the entire field of human consciousness.
If you look at the human dialogue throughout history,
or through the current newspaper,
or the news broadcast,
it looks totally chaotic.
All kinds of bizarre things happen.
There seems to be no rhyme or reason.
Human behavior doesn't really make sense.
Somebody says they're going to be here at 1230.
It's now quarter one, and they aren't here yet.
You know what I mean?
It appears chaotic.
But behind it, there are organizing patterns.
So one of the main things we did in the book was
provide some kind of a map of consciousness,
and we used kinesiology to do it.
The reason we used kinesiology to do it
is because consciousness itself
has no dimension.
Consciousness itself...
You see, in quantum theory,
when you go beyond the smallest particle
and the smallest energy,
you go beyond locality,
and therefore you're beyond space
and you're beyond time.
So anything that happens within consciousness
is, you might say, recorded there forever.
So that means that we could recapitulate these levels.
Let's just do that.
It's on page 52 of the book.
Let's just stand back and let him zoom in a little bit on that.
The critical level is courage at 200.
Okay?
So let's say...
Let's say pride is over 200. Resist.
No.
Pride is over 170. Resist.
Pride is about 175. Resist.
Pride is over 176. Resist.
Alright. Pride is about 175.
Anger is over 125.
140.
145.
150.
We'll do it again.
Anger is over 149.
150.
Anger is about 150.
Let's say fear.
Fear is over 90.
98.
99.
100.
Fear is about 100.
So we can recapitulate all these levels.
Everything below 200 makes you go weak.
Pride, anger, desire, fear,
grief,
apathy,
guilt,
shame.
And all the variations of those things.
Everything from 200 up makes you go strong.
So...
250 is neutral. Let's ask that.
At neutral...
Neutral is...
It's okay if it's this way and it's okay if it's that way. Resist.
See, that's a positive feeling.
Neutral.
If I get the job, it's okay.
And if I don't, I'll get another job. See?
If you're at anger, you're angry because you didn't get the job.
If you're in pride, you're arrogant about it.
If you're in fear, you're too fearful to pass the interview.
If you're in grief, you didn't get the job, so you're going to kill yourself.
Apathy is...
Well, it's hopeless. There's no jobs around.
Shame is, well, I don't have a job, so I'm ashamed to be seen in public, you know?
Alright, neutral is okay.
Willing is something else.
Willing is around 310. Resist.
Reason is around 400. Resist.
Science is about 400. Resist.
Okay.
Oh, we don't have Reason on?
Oh, yeah, we do.
Love starts at 500 and goes on up to 1,000. Resist.
Unconditional love is about 540.
Joy is about 580.
Peace of God is about...
Peace is what? 600.
Enlightenment is 600 to 1,000. Resist.
Alright, let's check on kinesiology itself.
The energy level of kinesiology itself as a technique is approximately 600.
500. Resist.
Yes, it's 600.
The level of truth...
I've never asked this before.
The level of truth of this map of consciousness here calibrates over 500. Resist.
Over 600. Resist.
Over 700. Resist.
Over 800. Resist.
Over 900. Resist.
The arm okay?
Calibrates about 840. Resist.
Huh, that's interesting. That's the level of...
That's the level of the book, I think.
That's the level of the consciousness of this book.
It's over 700, 800, 840, 850.
That's the level of consciousness of the book itself, you know.
Alright, now, the consciousness has no dimension.
It's beyond space and time.
And the reason it works, kinesiology works, is it has to do with causality.
We're going to have to get into causality.
We're going to get into that more later.
What the world thinks is that causality moves from A to B to C.
In this direction, see?
Actually, causality does not move that way at all.
It moves from consciousness into the world as ABC.
So causality does not work horizontally in this direction.
It works in this direction.
Something that's held in consciousness, then it manifests in the visible world.
Let me show you that.
I'm a flower unfolding like that, right?
Okay.
This precedes this and is a necessary condition to reach this.
But this does not cause that.
So what the world thinks when it sees ABC sequence,
what it thinks is causality is not causality, it's a condition.
The condition for B to appear is preceded by A, but it is not caused by A.
So if we have a flower growing, then a bigger flower growing,
and then a bigger flower growing,
the smaller flower does not cause the bigger flower.
And here's the full-grown flower.
These are stages, but it's not causality.
Therefore, the whole theory of evolution is incorrect.
Evolution has to do with A, B, and C.
Evolution occurs in consciousness and then expresses itself downward.
We'll get into causality later.
All right.
So consciousness is everywhere present.
Let's say like a radio wave.
So anybody within that field would give us the same answer.
The question does not go in this direction.
We think the questions and answers go from person to person,
by their telephone, by their computer, or by asking them just like this.
What actually happens is the statement or the image or whatever is held in mind,
and it goes to consciousness.
Consciousness then radiates it back to the other person.
There is no communication across this way at all,
any more than there is causality.
If I hold an image in mind,
I don't have to even tell you what that image is.
I can test you with kinesiology.
Because you're connected to this consciousness,
you will give me the response without even knowing what it is.
Right?
So if I call somebody in a foreign land,
or the other side of the United States,
and I have two people there ready to test each other with kinesiology,
and I say I'm holding something in mind,
what is the energy of that?
They will give me a response because of this,
not because of this.
It can't be because of this,
because they don't know what I'm holding in mind.
So let's try it as an experiment.
I want to just do that right now.
Oh, let's see.
Number six.
These new triangle things, I don't know.
I'm going to hold something in mind,
and I want you to test...
What's that guy that started the...
Oh, yeah, Page. Okay.
A fellow there by the name of Page,
and I'm going to hold something in mind,
and I want you to test out the energy of the image I'm holding in mind.
The image of what I'm holding in mind is positive.
What do you get?
Is that a true statement?
It's positive.
I'm going to hold another image in mind.
I want you to test that image.
What do you get?
Yes.
All right.
Make a statement.
The image that Doc is holding in mind is positive.
Yeah.
And then just tell him to resist.
What do you get?
Let's see.
I'm holding an image in mind.
The image that I'm holding in mind is...
I'm going to say it's positive.
Check out the truth of the statement I just made.
It's not positive.
It's Adolf Hitler, so I'm...
The first image I gave you was Lincoln, positive.
Hitler, negative.
Any questions you want to ask as long as we're on the phone?
I'm holding a substance in front of me.
Yes.
The energy of what I'm holding is positive.
Just make that statement to him,
and then test him.
Just tell him to resist.
Yes, it's positive.
Okay.
The image of what I'm holding in my hand now is positive.
Check that statement.
See if that's a true or false statement.
That is a true statement.
No, not a true statement.
Well, that's interesting.
I'm just explaining on the blackboard here
that consciousness, you know, has no dimension.
And you see, the way it works,
I don't think I've ever explained it to you,
is when I hold an image,
it goes into the field of consciousness.
Then when you test him,
he's connected to the same field of consciousness,
so he tests out.
So, in other words,
it's like my thought goes into the water,
and then he gets the thought out of the water.
But the thought doesn't go between me and him,
you know what I mean?
Anyway, I'll get to explain that later.
Well, thanks a lot for cooperating with this little experiment.
Bye.
All right, that was just a fun thing,
really just to demonstrate
the basic theory, see?
It has to do with causality
and various interesting things.
So, that's a general theory,
a general theory.
I wanted to demonstrate a few of the things that happen
as a consequence.
In the book, I talk about critical factor analysis.
In other words, if we focus in
on a specific project,
we don't necessarily have to do anything in the world
to make it happen.
This is a basic principle, isn't it,
in spiritual teaching.
What you hold in mind tends to materialize,
tends to actualize.
Let's ask that question.
What you hold in mind tends to actualize.
Yeah, right.
So, the people who hold negativity in their minds
tend to experience a life of negativity.
There's a section of a small town
not far from here.
Everybody who lives there
has the same kind of a life story.
Everything goes wrong.
Everything is always breaking down.
They have all kinds of warrants.
They're always in trouble with the law.
Their fences don't hold up.
Their dogs wander off and bite people.
I mean, it's just one endless negativity after another
because in this world, that's what happens,
is negativity.
Other people will tell you that everything happens
by synchronicity.
Just as they think bobby pin, they open the door,
in fact, they're not even thinking it.
The thought comes up, somebody says,
what about a bobby pin?
You open the door and your hand is on a bobby pin.
So, that's synchronicity.
All right.
So, to save time,
to save time,
you see, all you have to do is hold the thing up here
because to actualize it
can be quite a formidable undertaking.
When we talked about causality,
we said things do not operate ABC.
The Empire State Building was held
in mind by the consciousness of its creator.
That then manifested in this direction
and manifested out in the world.
So, let's take a few pet projects I've had over the years
and didn't have time to actually do anything about it.
It always annoyed me when I was setting the VCR
that when you run a TV station,
when you run through the stations,
there's nothing that identifies the station.
So, the only way you could tell what number you're setting it on
would be to look at the TV guide, see?
So, I always thought, wouldn't it be neat
if these stations would put a little logo
in the lower right-hand corner
or the lower left-hand corner?
Why don't they have a little logo going there
no matter what the program is?
24 hours a day, they should have their logo there.
And to make it even better,
they could have the time and the temperature,
you know, little figures under there or something.
So, when I'm going to set my VCR
and I'm looking for Channel 5,
why do I have to look up that there's a cowboy program
and run through all the programs
to find a cowboy program
and hope that's Channel 5?
Why don't they just have 5 in the lower hand?
Well, I never had a chance to do anything about it,
but I held it in mind rather strongly
for a couple of years.
Now, the logo suddenly appeared.
They've never had a logo appear
in the lower corner of any TV station.
You had to wait till the station break,
usually on the hour,
and then a big 5 would appear, see?
They wouldn't even give you the station
on the half hour most of the time.
A very big annoyance.
So, I just held that in mind,
how nice that would be.
And now, in fact,
all the channels have their little logo there.
I'm working to perfect it
by holding the time and the temperature strongly.
Now, let's just ask.
Those logos appearing in the TV stations
would have appeared
even if I didn't hold that in mind.
No, it wouldn't.
My strongly holding it in mind is desirable
and sort of sending it out
is what was responsible for its appearing.
Resist.
Yes.
People deny the strength of their own mind.
We all live in the world of our own creation,
of our own perception.
Now, here is another pet project
I had going on for quite a while.
And again, I didn't have much time to handle it.
But the dominance of gangs of the inner city,
I saw there was only one way,
through critical factor analysis,
which I talk about in the book,
a very complex problem
has within it exactly one point.
And if you put your finger on that one point,
so a giant clock works,
you can stop a giant clock works,
as complex as it looks,
if you know where to put your finger.
So let's take street crime and the gangs.
The most crucial of all the gangs
was the Gangster Disciples of Chicago
because they were politically organizing into PACs
and beginning to elect people to the city council.
Huge incomes of $100 million a day in drugs,
dominating.
So what I saw was that only by using RICO,
conspiracy law,
could you stop the gangs.
So one member of a gang commits a crime,
you then arrest the whole gang for conspiracy
because I've treated a lot of gang members
and I know that everything that that gang is planning
is known by everybody.
So it's really, they're all in consort.
So I sent out a letter
to everybody from Janet Reno
to the federal judiciary,
the state judiciary,
the governors of the states,
prosecutors, district attorneys,
and it turned out to be quite a formidable task.
So I thought, well, I'll just concentrate on Cook County
because that's where the focus,
the fulcrum of all this is the United States
because the Gangster Disciples were spreading
and becoming the largest gang in the United States
and coalescing with the gangs
in all the major cities in the United States.
So I began to image this as critical
that RICO was the way to stop the gangs
and specifically the Chicago Gangster Disciples,
which is run by a very politically brilliant murderer
currently in Joliet prison.
Up to now, nothing has effectively stopped the gangs.
They pretty much rule the big cities,
have taken over the big cities,
destroyed its economy, really.
So I began to image using RICO
all right, this last week,
it suddenly appears in the paper,
two weeks ago, January 29th, 1996,
Arizona Republic.
Trial begins today for a gang
that may be the largest in the U.S.
and what they're being caught on is conspiracy.
All right, let's ask.
Holding in mind that RICO was the critical factor
to stop the gangs
is what brought about today,
was manifested as that headline.
Resist.
And yes, my holding in mind
on the specific point
and zeroing in and sending out letters
to critical people,
almost everybody answered except Janet Reno.
Janet Reno was glad to get my letter.
Resist.
No, Janet Reno was not glad to ever get my letter
because she never replied.
I don't know if anybody else paid any attention,
but that's not even important.
It wasn't the sending out the letters.
Let's ask that.
I never asked that.
Was sending out the letters critical
to this resolution of an impossible problem?
Resist.
No.
I wasted my time sending out the letters.
So sometimes we can, you know,
put some effort into it in manifest world,
but generally speaking,
it's the holding in mind.
There was something else I did years and years ago
when I first noticed this phenomenon.
I was sort of into unicorn cards,
and I looked all over,
and you can hardly ever find a unicorn card anywhere.
So I began to desire and image unicorn cards
and how great it would be if they were everywhere.
Then unicorn cards appeared everywhere.
Did holding that unicorn in mind
make those cards manifest?
Resist.
Yeah, sure did.
The same with Expresso.
Expresso was very hard to find in the United States,
almost anywhere.
So I held in mind how great it would be
if Expresso was everywhere available.
Now you can get it in the fast food stores.
With holding in mind,
Expresso is partially responsible
for its manifesting as widespread availability.
Resist.
Yes.
So, you see, what you hold in mind
tends to manifest if it's for the good of mankind,
and you just keep holding it in mind.
Everybody knows this who's ever done it.
Every place I've ever lived,
including this place,
was imaged first.
It was a small little remote place
next to a creek,
in an arid place like Arizona,
the big place I had back east,
was again imaged in the woods.
So what we hold in mind tends to manifest.
That's a very, very critical thing to know.
We said that 85% of the people on the planet
calibrate below 200.
Let's see if that's so.
85% of the people on the planet calibrate below 200.
Resist.
0.4% of the people calibrate 500 or over.
Now, that would sound quite alarming, wouldn't it?
85% of the people on the planet live here.
As far as 500 and up on additional love,
0.4% of the population.
So why doesn't the world destroy itself?
Because the power of the thought here
is so enormously powerful
that one person holding one loving thought at this level
totally counterbalances maybe 50,000 people
holding negative thoughts in mind.
So most of us think all kinds of negative thoughts
throughout the day.
This little fear, that little fear,
this little resentment or anger.
And it doesn't destroy us
because we also have a loving thought.
We also have a loving thought about our pets,
about our friends or parents or whatever.
So one loving thought from this level up here
is so powerful that it prevents all these negative thoughts
that we have throughout the day from actually destroying us.
Let's get what the consciousness level of mankind is right now.
The consciousness level, let's get it in history.
The consciousness level of mankind in the year 1900
was over 200, resist.
In the year 1800, resist.
The consciousness level of mankind in the year 1700
was 190, resist.
The consciousness level of mankind in the year 1000
The consciousness level of mankind stayed at 190
for all the centuries until 1986, resist.
All right, in 1985, the consciousness level of mankind was over 200 resist.
In 1986, the consciousness level of mankind was 200, over 200 resist.
Before we leave this brief discussion of consciousness as a subject,
I want to say a little bit more about the map of consciousness and about causality
and relate a little bit more closely to the book.
In the book, it's quite obvious that positions from 200 and up are positions of power.
Positions of 200 and down are positions of force.
What makes the difference is, for one thing, motive, intention.
What is your primary goal? What are your highest values?
What is the basic law that you live by when the chips are down?
And these are levels.
The lower levels are really levels of victimhood.
They all come about by virtue of positionality.
As you take a position, you see, you limit your perception.
So these are all levels of perception.
These are very limited levels of perception in which you scope in on a very, very small piece of reality.
And as you live from a higher view of, let's say, identifying with the good of mankind,
you end up towards the top of the calibrated scale.
So let's see what we mean.
Let's say an unfortunate incident happens to you.
Let's say you lose some money or you make a deal and somebody doesn't pay you the money back, etc.
Well, you could adopt any one of these positions, you see, depending on what your priority in life would be.
You can be ashamed of the whole thing.
You can not bring it up.
You can feel hopeless about it.
You can feel guilty and berate yourself.
You can feel apathetic that it's hopeless.
There's nothing to be done about it.
You can go into grief and wail about it.
Ours is a crybaby society.
Everybody likes to go into these victim roles.
You can get angry about it.
You can get indignant.
Everybody talks about rights.
So rights.
It falls in here somewhere, you know, having to do with anger and pride.
This is my right to do something or other.
See, right has is a rather limited perception because you can look at the same event from the position of responsibility.
Responsibility is way up here.
To a person who's responsible, right is just part of the picture and usually sort of an irrelevant part of the picture.
They're not concerned with rights.
Down below, people are preoccupied with right and wrong, with morality, with good and bad, and classifying things in those categories.
Courage, for the first time, is the capacity to look at both sides of the question.
So a person might be, down here, might be indignant.
A person might be into rage, say, let's sue them.
A person might be arrogant about the whole thing or fall into denial.
That courage.
You begin to look at both the upside and the downside.
Everything has a consequence and you may decide either to act or not act.
Neutral is a position of, sort of, it's okay if you take action.
It's okay if you don't.
It's really not all that important.
Willingness is willingness to look at it from a higher and a broader viewpoint.
Acceptance might be that that's the nature of life.
Reason might be taking the intention.
The intelligent view of it.
One's love for one's fellow human being may preclude taking any action.
Let's say somebody takes a piece of your property and wrecks it.
This has happened to me in the not-too-distant future.
A past, rather.
And it was quite a sizable loss.
I could have gone into any one of these positions here, you see.
However, I happen to know that the person has no money whatsoever.
So, frankly, I didn't even see...
I didn't see the point of bringing it up with the person, you see.
Well, you could say it's my right.
I could have taken a position that is hopeless to bring it up.
I could have gotten arrogant about it.
I could have gotten angry about it.
But the real thing is I love that person and I knew that if I brought this up to that person's awareness,
they would have gone into guilt and shame about it.
So, if you really love somebody, if they can't do anything about a situation,
there's really no point to bringing it up.
Because you would be throwing them into the bottom of the box here,
where they're going to feel guilt and shame about something which is already past.
They can't do anything about it.
And they don't have the assets to correct it.
All right.
So, the loving thing to do would be, in this particular instance, just overlook it.
And accepting that that's the way life goes.
You can't drive your car, you know, 10,000, 20,000 miles a year without sooner or later getting a dent in it.
I mean, those are the things, the wear and tear of life.
Taking that position keeps a person sort of in a state of joy.
What is the joy there?
The joy is that one is no longer at the effect of the world.
From 200 down, one is the victim of the world.
Because happiness is out there.
Happiness is out there.
These are levels, let's say, of revenge and getting even, of jealousy, possessiveness.
If you get the job, so and so.
If you get the job, so one's self-esteem, one's level of being is dependent on consequences.
It depends on how a thing turns out.
If you get the job, don't get the job.
You get the money, you don't get the money.
You get the girl, you don't get the girl.
Therefore, one is the victim of consequences in the world.
As we see from causality, as we get, we'll talk a little bit more about that before we leave this subject.
What determines an external event is millions and millions of things.
In fact, it takes the entire universe to bring about a certain consequence.
To be at the effect of that, to be the victim of that, then, is to be like a leaf thrown about in the wind.
And we know lots of people whose emotions, from hour to hour, day to day, week to week, month to month,
are buffeted about by the arrows of fortune and fate.
If things go well, they're up. If things are down, they're not.
So, from 200 and up, you begin to transcend the world.
And from about 350 on up, you begin to re-own your power.
These positions down here are those of powerlessness.
Because what happens to you is what goes on out in the world.
You've projected your own power into the world.
Once you get to about 350, which is acceptance, you begin to own that you yourself are the source of your own happiness.
I gave an example in the book of all these different ways of responding to finding yourself in jail, let's say.
You can hang yourself.
You can become very spiritual.
You can join a 12-step group and become quite enlightened.
You can become very intelligent.
You can go to the law library and earn a degree.
There are all kinds of different ways we can handle the same circumstance,
depending on what your overall motivation towards life is.
So, these are levels.
These are levels of very limited perception.
These are also levels of selfishness and egocentricity.
These are all levels of me, me, me.
These are the beginning of the levels of us.
And these are the levels up here of really the good of all mankind.
What will the impact of my actions be on humanity as a whole?
Some people who have had a hard time in our society,
have had it because they were acting, let's say, from the good of all mankind.
Linus Pauling, who I knew, he and I had done a book together back in the 70s.
He won the Nobel Prize twice.
Once for chemistry and once for peace.
When he stood alone in front of the White House,
it was in the middle of the McCarthy era,
and he stood against nuclear testing
because the nuclear fallout, the radioactive fallout,
had a deleterious effect.
Not all of mankind.
He wasn't interested in any of these lower levels.
I want to go back to consciousness itself a little bit again.
Make sure we understand it.
I want to go back to causality.
We said within the world,
this is the Newtonian paradigm of reality.
You know, Newton defined for us a four-dimensional world,
the world of the computer, of mathematics and science.
It calibrates in the 400s.
Newton himself calibrates at 499, as does Einstein.
That's the level of reason.
It takes you up to this level here.
For some reason, all the greatest scientists who have ever lived calibrate around 499.
And that's the world of science in which A causes B causes C.
Now, when we go beyond that level of awareness,
you see, that's a limited perception.
A limited perception of awareness.
As we get into the higher 400s,
we start becoming aware of chaos theory,
non-linear dynamics, fuzzy logic, set theory.
As we get to the high 400s,
we get to a level such as the advanced theoretical physics,
quantum mechanics as described, let's say, by David Bohm.
So, Bohm, his thinking, etc.,
is right on the level of,
let's say, beyond 499.
He's already into the 500s.
He has become aware of the difference in causality.
How does cause work?
Well, within the visible world,
the manifest material world as we see it,
there is no cause.
That is a shocking shift of paradigm
when you hear it for the first time.
We're so used to thinking that A causes B causes C,
like a set of billiard balls hitting each other.
It takes sort of a jump of paradigm
to realize that none of that is happening.
As I showed you when I was going like this,
to show you an example of how a flower develops,
the cause is not within the manifest world.
Let's say that cause originates in consciousness,
that this sequence ABC
is held as a concept in consciousness.
This ABC, now,
has the power to manifest sequentially
as this series ABC.
Cause proceeds from unlimited high power
to lesser and lesser power into the material world,
like a step-down transformer.
Consciousness and beyond consciousness,
there is that which is called awareness.
We'll get back to this
when we get to the spiritual aspects later in the course.
Awareness, then, is beyond consciousness even.
Consciousness is potentiality.
It has to do with is and is not,
beingness and non-beingness,
existence and non-existence.
Awareness is beyond all of that.
The highest power, then, is that of awareness,
which is infinite, always was, always will be,
to consciousness.
Within consciousness, then,
arises the beginnings of form
on the level of essence.
So, we might say this is more the level of essence.
Essence, when run through the transformer
of the human consciousness,
comes down through desire and tension
and manifests within the visible world.
When we see a sequence of billiard balls,
such as ABC,
what we're seeing is
the causality manifesting
as this,
and these are preconditions.
These are conditions.
The condition of B appearing in this series,
A is a condition to it,
but it is not a cause of it.
So that when we talk about
a flower, let's say,
the flower here,
he's this big a flower,
and now, a month later, he's this big a flower,
and now it's this big a flower,
and,
in the Newtonian concept,
this causes this,
and this causes this,
but from a higher viewpoint,
there's no cause involved.
These are both consequences
of this M field, you might call it,
morphogenetic field.
Evolution, if we check it out with kinesiology,
we'll see this is so.
Evolution takes place on the level of
morphogenetic fields.
That is like a pattern
held within consciousness,
which then manifests out as its physical expression.
Evolution does not take place
within the physical world.
You know, the tiger with the biggest jaws survives
because he can eat more and kill more.
That's the theory.
Actually, that's not how it happens at all.
This is necessary to understand
if you realize that what we hold in consciousness
tends to manifest.
If you're holding something up here,
it's going to tend to manifest,
materialize,
and appear within the physical world.
You can experiment with that
and prove that to yourself.
Pick something that you desire
that would be good for life,
good for mankind,
and just keep picturing it,
holding it in mind,
desiring it,
maybe draw it,
maybe even write letters to people.
Whether you mail them or don't mail them,
apparently makes no difference.
So the best thing to do is,
if you picture
that the way to keep animals from getting lost
is by having some kind of a little radio transmitter,
somebody obviously held that in mind
because now you can buy them in the marketplace.
So if you have a pet project
you would like to work on
for your own sake
because the mind tends to be skeptical
about such things,
put it down in a notebook.
Put it down in a notebook
and then just wait for it to show up
within the visible world.
I wanted to
mention before we leave
the subject of consciousness
that these numbers that are on here
are logarithms.
These are logarithms
and the direction of the arrow indicates
whether this makes you weak
or it makes you strong.
What makes the difference
with these levels
you might call
a person's level of vested interest.
People say,
well what sets my consciousness
or somebody else's consciousness
where it is?
It's what you have a vested interest in.
So if people have a vested interest
let's say at the level of pride
they can blow up innocent women and children
because that's a negative energy
in the name of the IRA, you know.
They can wave the flag
and say it's patriotism
but actually it's just arrogance
because they're placing
their own political viewpoint
above the lives of innocent citizens.
So what it is you're willing to die for,
your vested,
what you have a vested interest in.
These people here have a vested interest
in being right at any cost,
being right.
That's their vested interest.
So they're willing to sacrifice love,
marriages, joy, positions, jobs
for being right, being right.
So that's where you set your power
is what you're willing to go for.
And I wanted to recalibrate
the power of an individual thought
which has never been done
as far as I know ever.
Let's just try it.
And a thought at the energy level of 100,
energy level 100,
because most people have lots and lots
of fearful thoughts.
The power of that thought is between
10 to the minus 700
and 10 to the minus 800 million
microwatts resist.
At the level of 100
a thought is more powerful
than 1 to the minus the log
minus 10 to the minus 700 million resist.
Okay.
Now let's take a thought
at the level of love, 500.
A thought at the level of love
measures 10 to the minus approximately
35 million microwatts resist.
So the difference between
10 to the minus 35 million microwatts
and 10 to the minus
700 million microwatts,
the difference in power is so enormous
it's really beyond comprehension.
But the significance is
that a loving thought is so powerful
that it contradicts thousands
and thousands of negative thoughts.
And if it weren't for that,
then salvation would not be possible.
Well, we've got Lydia here today,
very fortunate.
Hi, David.
And she's been part of a research team
for NBC
that did a very famous documentary
on PBS on the Sphinx
and having to do with
the age of the Sphinx
and various other things.
Why don't you tell us
what you've been up to?
Yeah, I'd be happy to.
In fact, you got that...
the research you did won the Emmy Award,
I understand, for research.
Yes, we did.
Actually, a colleague of ours,
Dr. John West,
spent many, many years
on the hypothesis
that the Sphinx was older
than anything else
on the Giza Plateau.
And he based his assumption
on the fact that
it's weathered by water.
We finally have hard science
available to us in this century
to go and test his theory
and prove it out,
which is something we did in 1993.
When we were at the Giza Plateau,
we happened to have
Dr. DeBecke
from the Colorado School of Mines
use his new infrared photography methods
and his current
sonography methods
to test what was under
the Sphinx in the plateau.
And we found three man-made chambers
under the Sphinx.
Now, what this did for us
was pose the question
for the public at large,
how did they get there?
Who put them there?
How old are they?
How long have they been there?
And if we can get into them,
since no one we know of
in mankind's history
has ever set foot there,
what's there?
Who put it there?
We want to know answers
to all these questions.
Possibly this technique,
Dr. Hawkins can give us
a place to begin.
Wasn't that
Perry Casey's...
Edgar Cayce,
the sleeping prophet
from about 50 years ago,
I suppose,
postulated there was
a man-made chamber
under the Pala of the Sphinx.
This is one of the things
we went looking for.
And now this is
what science has confirmed.
Yeah.
We found not only
that chamber,
two others.
But nobody's been in them yet.
Never.
Mm-hmm.
In fact,
there's been
another chamber
in what we think of
as recorded history.
Yeah.
Never.
This is a first.
We're going to go back.
We have permission.
Great.
So you think you might
go back there shortly?
In March of 96,
we'll begin.
However,
we won't have
the permission
to go two,
three,
400 feet
under the plateau
at this time.
But we do have
specific feelings,
questions.
Let's ask some questions
with kinesiology
and see what's there.
I think that'd be
very valuable for us.
All right.
So the chambers
are there,
correct?
Yes.
Which arm?
Let's try this one.
Okay.
Um,
art science says
there's three chambers
under what?
Under the Sphinx
and under the plateau.
Under the plateau.
That is true.
Resist.
There's more than three.
Nobody's been
in those chambers
in recent recorded history.
Resist.
There is,
uh,
valuables
within those chambers.
Resist.
I see.
There were
valuables
within those chambers.
What do we want to...
What more do you need
to know now?
Well,
I...
What would be useful
then?
I speculate that,
yes,
those chambers
have been entered,
but with your typical
Egyptian grave robbing,
I really believe
the people,
the locals,
know all about
what's immediately
under the surface
in the plateau.
Um,
a lot of psychics
and others
speculate
there's a complex
further below,
another two
or three hundred feet,
a whole tunnel system
I would like to know
who built these tunnels?
Who built
the original temples?
Were they Atlanteans?
Were they Babylonians?
Were they Sumerians?
Were they from
another planet?
Let's ask it.
The original builders
were Atlanteans.
Resist.
The original
builders
were Sumerians.
What will be found
there?
Physical treasure?
Is it there
in a holographic sense?
Is it information
about man's
beginnings
and history?
What's to be found?
In the chambers?
Yes.
No.
The specific chambers
I'm sure are empty.
Oh.
I'm sure they were cleaned
out a long time ago
by grave robbers.
However,
we can test that.
They were cleaned out
a long time ago
by grave robbers.
Resist.
Yeah,
they've been cleaned out.
But is there more
even further below
to be discovered?
Oh.
There's more below
the three chambers
to be discovered.
Resist.
There is a system
of tunnels.
Resist.
I don't think
the locals know
about those tunnels.
Really do.
Seems to me
that somebody
would have sold
that information
a long time
seeing as what
they'll do for money
which is most anything.
Well,
it's pretty common knowledge
that the Egyptians
that have been there forever
have a good
working knowledge
of where things
go to a point
but it's been flooded
by the Nile.
Oh.
And they're,
they're,
they've gone to a point
where they stopped
because the technology
to go further
was never available.
Well,
the most interesting
thing in that film
is the fact
that the Nile
and the Nile
are very close
to each other.
The Sphinx
is over
10,000 years old.
Resist.
That research
reported in that
special documentary
was correct.
Resist.
Was the Sphinx
created
by a civilization
from Mars
who also had
a Sphinx
in a pyramid structure?
We're curious about that.
Civilization from where?
Mars.
Mars?
Okay.
Anybody
build that
from Mars?
Resist.
Okay.
So,
we're gonna
go into
the
cosmos
in
a moment.
But,
the order
we move on
to cosmology,
we don't have
all that much
time on the tape
so I'm not gonna
go into
it very,
very much.
But,
one of the most
famous books
in the world
is Stephen Hawking's
Black Holes
and Baby Universes.
I think it has
sold 7 million
copies worldwide.
this book calibrates over 450 resist over 490 resist 499 resist 500 resist
so this level of consciousness represented by the leading edge of science runs to 499 resist
um quantum theory uh is over 500 resist all scientific theory seems to end at 499
the same level as einstein and newton and david boehm however let's go do david boehm
uh david boehm described the unfolded and the unfolded universe um boehm's uh consciousness
is over 500 resist 510 520 530 540 550 540. all right so once you get over 499
you run
into what i described uh there's the unfolded and the unfolded universe so this would be the
unfolded in other words not into form and this would be the unfolded universe i didn't discover
boehm and all those kind of things until i had to uh well i wanted to write up the research i'd done
so to do what i had i wanted to present it to university so it would pass academic muster so
i got into research and discovered people like boehm and all things
that i had known about to give it sort of a context and make it familiar to the reader
okay we want to talk a little bit about criminology this is a whole
field in itself of course and we can do a whole videotape on criminology
and especially in forensics where you can quickly identify you know footprints blood writing hair
drugs just like we did with artwork you can check out the validity of dna long before it comes back
laboratory fingerprints the time of the crime and things like that
and of course whether a supposed perpetrator actually committed a crime let's um what's the
name of the fellow blew up oklahoma there mcdain oh the perpetrator the oklahoma incident
uh his name mcveigh resistant mcveigh did not do it resist oj did it resist oj did not do it resist
You just get the other. Those are rather the obvious, huh?
So you can check out the validity of testimony.
Any statement is true or false, whether a witness is lying on the stand.
Some very interesting things.
As far as finding evidence and things like that, solving clueless crimes.
For instance, we could ask, let's say, let's ask a question.
There's a weapon hidden in this house, resist.
There is.
This weapon that we're looking for is a rifle, resist.
It's an automatic, resist.
It's a revolver, resist.
It's a regular length barrel, resist.
It's a snub-nosed barrel.
This revolver has been used in a crime, resist.
There's ammunition for this revolver in the house, resist.
The ammunition is, what's the name of various ammunitions?
Winchester.
The ammunition is Winchester, resist.
No.
Some other, what other could it be? I don't know.
That much about ammunitions.
Let's see if we can locate the gun in the house.
Let's verify again.
There is a gun in this house.
The gun is in the bedroom, resist.
The gun is in the kitchen, resist.
It's in the front part of the house, resist.
The gun is in this room, resist.
The gun is more than four feet above the floor, resist.
It's less than three feet from the floor.
All right.
Let's see.
It's in the north part of the room.
It's in full view, resist.
It's in a package, resist.
It's more than six feet away from us, resist.
It's close.
It's closer than five feet away, resist.
All right.
Five feet away from us and within three feet of the floor on the north side of the room
and not in view.
Maybe Delmarie can find it.
Delmarie, let's see if you can find it.
What else do you need to know to find it?
Well, it's on the north side of the room.
We know it's somewhere around two to three feet from the ground and it's not in full view.
Let's find out.
Let's, by asking questions.
I want to find it by asking questions.
That's a good one.
We said it's a snub nose.
It's a revolver, right?
Mm-hmm.
So it's somewhere here.
Let's ask if it's in that section of the room.
It's in that section of the room, resist.
It's in this section of the room, resist.
So it's in that section of the room.
It's within three feet of the wall, resist.
Three feet of the wall.
All right.
So within the three feet of the wall, so we can move the camera and just follow it right over here.
Okay.
Within three feet of the wall and this section of the room and about this high,
and not in public view.
Let's see if we can find the gun.
Right now?
Yeah.
Let's see if we can find it.
It says there's a gun.
Well, here's potato chips.
I don't.
Shall we?
I can do that.
The gun.
All right.
Good.
Actually, you can locate any evidence anywhere.
You can ask if the gun's ever been fired, how many times it's been fired.
We can ask who owns the gun, if it's ever been used in a crime.
In other words, it's value.
And tracking a clueless crime is amazing, because a clueless crime, you haven't got any lead.
So here we can start with the lead.
We'll do that on a different videotape sometime.
We'll really go into crime and evidence and forensics and verifying data and solve the crime.
We can tell who did it, whether they're black and white, whether they're male or female.
We can get the exact time.
We get their intention, their motive.
We can ask where the booty is.
We can ask what weapons were used, whether the guns are loaded or not loaded.
Well, of course, this is very useful to know.
I mean, if I'm a police officer and I have to go in on a suspected drug raid, I certainly want to know whether they've got guns.
If so, are they automatic rifles?
I mean, are they, what kind of, I certainly, if I'm going to wear a bulletproof vest, I want to know, is it the kind of bullet that can go through a bulletproof vest?
In other words, I can, with kinesiology, research a whole crime area.
And go in at no risk to the life of anybody.
You can also figure out the best time to go there.
Are they asleep now?
Do they have guns there?
Do they have drugs on their premises right now?
In other words, it's used in criminal investigation and forensics and criminology and police work is rather, you know, unlimited.
Before we go into health, you know, current events is a place where kinesiology is really the most fun.
You can watch the news.
You can check out on the McNeil-Lehrer Hour whether somebody's telling the truth.
And I just wanted to do the McNeil-Lehrer Hour because it's interesting.
I was once on that program.
McNeil-Lehrer Hour calibrates at 400 resist.
Calibrates over 450 resist.
It calibrates the low 400s.
It drives me crazy with boredom because the thing about the low 400s is intellectualizing.
People can yammer, yammer, yammer, intellectualize endlessly to the point of distraction.
My daughter does it.
She can't stand listening to the McNeil-Lehrer Hour.
She says, Daddy, please.
Don't play that.
Current events is very interesting.
So we can watch the evening news.
Last night I think there was a program on pop bisexuality.
Let's just check the energy of pop bisexuality.
Okay.
Pop bisexuality is a positive thing.
Faddish bisexuality is constructive resistance.
Ugh.
Faddish bisexuality...
Bisexuality is detrimental to the health of society.
Pop bisexuality represents an advance in man's consciousness.
Pop bisexuality represents degeneracy in civilization.
It's a degenerate movement and it's phrased like it's very advanced,
like we're becoming more sophisticated, more hip, more aware.
Actually, I mean, Rome did the same thing in many civilizations.
It got into degeneracy.
It got into health because almost everybody has an interest in health.
And this is where kinesiology has been used the most.
So, Lily, come on over here.
Okay.
The way kinesiology really started back in the 70s,
the way it was used the most was for medications and health foods, things like that.
For instance, we could take this apple, which is a commercial apple.
The energy of this apple is positive.
So this is a commercial apple.
It's full of pesticides, most likely.
Looks pretty.
That's why it's spread that way.
Here we have an organic apple.
Well, no, I shouldn't have said that to you.
I sort of blew it up.
Here we have a different apple.
The energy of this apple is positive.
So that's the relationship between organic and pesticides.
That's what we got here.
We can show it with one premise, you see.
What people don't understand is that
when we...
When we use this test subject for kinesiology,
we're not testing the person.
We don't care what the person thinks.
They're nothing but a conduit,
like a wire,
between consciousness in the invisible world
and the movement of the arm in the visible world.
It bypasses the person.
So what their opinion is, what their thoughts are...
So let's take something and test it against a prevailing human belief system.
Okay.
It's one that I think is very interesting
because it flies in the face of what people believe.
Here we have a substance in this jar.
Please hold that against your solar plexus.
The energy of this substance is positive for this.
This substance is injurious to you.
What is this?
This is organic tobacco.
Here we have commercial tobacco.
This commercial tobacco has a positive energy for this.
All right.
Here we have a commercial tobacco,
but it's an organic tobacco.
Okay.
The energy of this product is positive for this.
Amazing.
All right.
Let's just take this and hold it again.
This product is injurious to your health.
Resist.
Let's do this again.
The energy of tobacco before 1957 was negative for this.
Before 1957, the energy of tobacco was positive for this.
Yes, the Indians have been smoking it for a long, long time.
My grandparents all smoked, and they lived in their late 90s.
Nobody ever heard of cancer of the lung or attributed it to tobacco.
All right.
The injuriousness of tobacco is due to a chemical placed on it,
and it's manufactured.
Resist.
That chemical came into use in 1957.
That chemical is a fertilizer.
That chemical is a pesticide.
Resist.
All right.
So what we get is what's injurious about smoking tobacco
is that a pesticide, which causes cancer, came into use in 1957.
And obviously, if you want to cure cancer of the lung,
instead of trying to get people to stop smoking because they're not going to do that,
you remove the chemical that's injurious.
Amazing.
Well, you see, science has vested interests.
We talked about vested interests.
That limits truth.
The Center for Science in the Public Interest likes to propagate a lot of,
you know, it's propaganda about secondary smoke and all this kind of thing,
because they have an agenda.
So having to do with that,
there was an article in Science magazine a month or two ago
that one gram of vitamin C for the average adult
protects the cells of the body from any injury from smoking.
The Center for Science in the Public Interest didn't even publicize that.
Why?
Because it's against their own political agenda.
So what people think is,
is a search for truth.
Science, you know, is taking the place of religion.
And science, like anything else, is limited,
has a political agenda,
an ax to grind,
and they were really interested in the public health.
They should have widely advertised that all you smokers out there,
you know, should smoke organic tobacco.
They should ask the manufacturing companies to find and remove that insecticide.
Right.
They should advise everybody to take a couple grams a day of vitamin C.
If you're going to smoke, take vitamin C.
You know what I mean?
If you're really interested in public health.
Well, what's interesting is that you have a prevailing belief system
in society today that tobacco will give you cancer,
and yet when I hold this, I mean, you're a member of the prevailing society.
Oh, I definitely have prejudice against it.
Yeah, right.
So, in other words, we've got an answer completely the opposite
of what you believe and the rest of the world believes.
In fact, the only one who knows this, the facts about this, is me.
The world doesn't know about it.
I raised some organic tobacco myself,
and I tested, of course, the kinesiology,
and it's perfectly harmless.
The kind that's raised by the Indians is harmless.
So to further that research, it would be interesting
to check out the incidence of cancer in the long end societies,
probably primitive societies that don't use chemicals.
The thing is, if you don't use chemicals in raising the tobacco,
the grasshoppers eat up about a quarter of your crop.
So, you know, there's a commercial reason for using insecticides.
Well, maybe you can test and find a way to deter the grasshoppers.
Well, I think they should withdraw that chemical, you know,
and focus on truth instead of some political agenda.
Well, Dr. Honkert, that's certainly an amazing thing to discover for us.
Well, here's something that I particularly like.
Oh!
The energy of these cookies is positive. Resist.
Ah, my favorite cookies, and I've got eight boxes of them.
This one looks better.
Here's a horrible little stale cookie from Christmas.
Hold this over your solar plexus.
The energy of this cookie is positive. Resist.
See, so it doesn't have to do...
I mean, this would be sort of a nasty old cookie to eat,
and this would be very, very delicious.
This obviously is made with, you know, chemicals and things like that.
This is obviously homemade with love.
Well, that was homemade. That's a homemade organic cookie.
The power of belief systems, you see, what causes many human diseases
are common belief systems.
I do a lot of examining lots of patients for Social Security disability
and things like that.
There's a whole raft of diseases which are strictly iatrogenic,
that is, initiated by the medical profession,
and given power and strength and human consciousness by the media.
Half the diseases that afflict mankind today are caused by,
created by, the effect of the media.
Let's just see if that's true or not.
Breast cancer was relatively rare when I was an intern, resident.
The widespread publicity given to breast cancer
has increased the incidence of breast cancer. Resist.
It has increased it absolutely.
Not just because more cases are being discovered. Resist.
You see, a thought held in consciousness tends to manifest.
Now, let's take some purely imaginary diseases.
Diseases that I've known forever are purely imaginary.
Allergy is a physical disease. Resist.
All allergies are due to belief systems. Resist.
You know, you can give anybody an allergy by suggesting it to them.
Fill three of your towels around and here's Grandma saying,
oh, everybody in our family is allergic.
These puffy eyes, I don't need to care.
Oh, me too. I had a fever. I was allergic to horses.
I got poison ivy.
Those are all fake diseases.
They're not fake once you got them, but they're initiated by suggestion.
All right, so one thing we can say about human consciousness
is that consciousness itself, the consciousness itself has no form.
It hasn't been programmed yet.
It's like the hardware in a computer.
Then comes the programming in through the software,
the software being school, Mommy and Daddy,
you know, what you overhear in the playground.
The thing about the hardware, the thing about consciousness itself
is that it's innocent.
As you move up the scale of consciousness,
you become aware that intrinsically everybody is innocent.
What happens then is on this innocent consciousness,
these prevailing programs start to impale.
The little toddler, two years old, believes anything it hears.
It believes Mommy and Daddy. It believes Teacher.
It believes what it hears is a church.
And perception becomes progressively limited
as these belief systems begin to take hold.
So everybody is run by their software.
We could say that everybody is intrinsically innocent and naive.
They have no context of higher awareness in which to judge an incoming program.
Just like the Center for Science in the Public Interest
programs us with one disease after another,
once held in consciousness, these now become very powerfully suggestive.
How can you prove this? It's very simple.
You put a patient under hypnosis, you can recreate any of these illnesses.
And when you, in the non-hypnotic state, you can remove them.
So I can say to a person that they have a very bad allergy to roses,
and they will forget about this when they wake up.
And when they wake up, I then walk in with roses,
and that person, their nasal passages will actually swell up.
The body will respond to the belief system.
In multiple personality disorder, we see a very interesting thing.
When one personality is there, the person has an ulcer.
Another personality may be an alcoholic, a drug addict, an infomaniac.
Another personality may be church-going and honest and have no allergies,
can eat anything.
Uh...
These are real things that really happen in the body.
So it finally has come to public awareness,
something I've known for a long time in examining a lot of these patients.
Um...
Silicone breast, you know, silicone implant disease.
Completely fictitious. There is no such animal.
Um...
Environmental disease, chemical disease.
You read...
You see, and these things typically show an epidemic pattern.
Uh...
One or two employees in a factory will complain that they can't breathe
when they got home that day or something.
Pretty soon, six employees can't breathe.
Pretty soon, the company is removing all these things and putting special fillers.
More and more people come down with it.
And what intensifies these things is compen...
You know, if it's compensable, if you can collect from somebody.
So...
Uh...
The propensity of the judiciary to place blame into the world
and back up these kind of things.
So this is, you know, something I've been holding in awareness,
that these things are all fake.
Come on over here.
Okay.
Last week, finally, my thought manifested.
Is that...
You know, in the previous section of this videotape,
if you hold a thought in mind strongly enough,
and if that consciousness is high enough, it'll manifest.
Um...
In the Arizona Republic, we have a whole article that says...
Beware the nocebo.
The nocebo acts like a placebo, only it's a negative thought.
And they use an example, another one called Gulf War Syndrome.
Okay, let's ask about it.
Okay.
Gulf War Syndrome is an actual physical disease.
Resist.
Ah!
Agent Orange is a...
Is an actual physical disease.
Resist.
Silicone implant disease, which...
I've seen patients with silicone implant disease,
and it's heartbreaking when you listen to them.
Their hair is falling out, they have buzzing in their ears,
their eyes gyrate, they can't swallow,
everything makes them throw up, everything gives them constipation or diarrhea,
all their limbs are weak, all their muscles are shot,
all their joints are gone, their cartilages are dissolving.
It's one walking piece of pathology.
There is such a thing physically as silicone implant disease.
There is such a thing psychologically as silicone implant disease.
All right.
Oh, yeah.
So you've got people all over the place, you know, disintegrating,
and these people you see in the health food stores carrying oxygen on their back,
you know, because they're afraid to breathe the air.
What's happened is they have programmed themselves
in with negative belief systems of such complexity that they can hardly move.
There's a community not far from here, the so-called bubble people,
you know, who board themselves up in their houses,
and they have belief systems that the rug will make, you know,
the rug will kill you, the walls will kill you, the air will kill you.
And, of course, we have the belief system that sunlight will kill you.
Even the sun will kill you.
Fresh air, sunshine.
Fresh air and sunshine, the woods come out over here.
Fresh air, fresh air, the sunshine.
These people believe that sunshine is injurious.
Resist.
Fresh air is injurious.
You see, how can you live in a world with a body?
In a bubble.
And, of course, everything you read in the health,
the one thing I got away from health food and health food literature
and a lot of holistic belief systems is because they tend to propagate a lot of this stuff,
that insecticides and all this kind of thing.
All right.
You come out over here.
Now, you test me.
Where's that thing with the pesticides?
Oh, yeah.
There you go.
Okay.
All right.
This, you want me to ask if this is healthy.
Oh, for me?
This, this apple is healthy for Dr. Hopkins.
Yes it is.
Why?
Because I canceled belief systems that pesticides have any power over me.
Nothing out there has any power over me.
I'm subject only to what I hold in mind.
There's nothing in the world that has any power over me.
Not silicone.
Not insecticides.
Not.
not allergies, not danders, not pollens, like moles, all the things.
I was once subject to all those things,
poison ivy, moles, danders, horse dander, dog dander, you know, all those things.
Once you buy into a negative belief system,
the only way you can get out of it is to constantly cancel it.
So in looking at health, you know, let's talk, how does a disease happen?
Hmm, well, you have the prevailing level of consciousness of the person.
That level of consciousness means they're going to be firing off thoughts.
Those thoughts, if they're negative thoughts,
any time you hold a thought in mind that makes you go weak with kinesiology,
what happens is you're blowing the immune system.
You're blowing a whole acupuncture meridian.
You are disturbing the energy of the organ energized by that acupuncture meridian.
So you hold a negative thought in mind.
That affects the emotional body.
The emotional body affects that energy around the physical body called the etheric body
through which the acupuncture system flows.
That subtly alters in a pathologic direction the physiology of the physical body organ.
Consequently, the way people die and get themselves off the planet
is by holding negative belief systems and thoughts.
Hmm.
People recover from every ailment known to mankind
by going back up the other way,
by canceling negative thoughts,
by elevating their level of consciousness,
by holding loving thoughts instead of negative thoughts.
I myself did the same thing.
I got rid of everything.
I used to think athlete's foot, you caught that in showers.
And, of course, then I did.
And dandruff, you got it to barber.
And I had ulcers and diverticulitis and migraine.
I had headaches.
I even had a pyelonylosis, which is something that's supposedly actually surgical.
All kinds of things wrong with the gastrointestinal.
I was so allergic when I was a kid to the belief, allergic to poison ivy,
that I literally landed in the hospital for two weeks with it.
All those things have disappeared spontaneously and gone away.
So that one can cure oneself, I know people with advanced multiple sclerosis,
all kinds of different cancers,
all kinds of diseases that have refused the negative belief system.
You have to say it doesn't apply to me.
I realize everybody out there believes that.
In doing that, for instance, I went out one time
and I dug up a whole plant of poison ivy
and played with it on some TV program I was on.
At one time, that would have put me in the hospital.
So that's probably the value of following some consciousness-raising program,
such as I use the Course in Miracles because it is such a common and easy one to do,
the workbook in the Course in Miracles.
Because when you get up to about Lesson 97,
you'll find that people are no longer subject to going weak with supposedly negative stimuli.
Almost everybody will go weak with fluorescent lights, pesticides, all those kind of things.
But as your own consciousness reaches a certain level,
the realization that you are the source of all these belief systems,
and you're what's empowering them,
you then become immune to it.
Well, we know from holistic health and alternative medicine,
it concerns itself not so much...
It concerns itself, of course, with the physical body,
but it says that around the physical body there are energy fields.
Acupuncture, for one thing, is a method of influencing those fields.
That around the physical body there's an etheric body,
and around the etheric body there's an emotional body,
and around the emotional body there...
is a mental body.
And beyond that there's something called the causal body.
All right, so, consequently, when they're interested in doing healing,
if there's something wrong with the physical body,
there must, of necessity, be something wrong with the etheric body.
So they work with energies trying to correct the error on the level of the etheric body.
Well, the physical body, the etheric body is like a blueprint
in absolute detail, right down to the molecular and submolecular of the physical body.
So, if you can see...
If you can change the etheric body,
the physical body will conform with the etheric body.
So if I could move your ears up in the etheric realm,
as time goes on, your ears will slowly grow up
and you're going to say to occupy that space.
What's behind a good deal of holistic health practices
is influencing energy fields.
Therefore, each thing you see would be of a greater power.
So we would have...
We would say...
Right beyond the physical body is the etheric body.
Let's ask, is that true?
I don't know.
I've never asked this before.
Is beyond and through the physical body,
is there an energy field called the etheric body?
Resist.
Does it have more power than the physical body?
It does.
Beyond that is the emotional body.
Is that so?
I mean, that is so.
Beyond the etheric body is the emotional body.
Resist.
Surrounding and going through it, there is also a body.
There is a body of energy called the emotional body.
Resist.
Is that where the supposed chakras reside in the emotional body?
Chakra system, is that within the etheric body?
That's within the etheric body.
Resist.
Beyond the emotional body is that which is called the mental body.
Beyond that yet is the causal body.
Resist.
Beyond that is the higher spiritual body.
Okay.
Uh-huh.
So, that tells us how the disease process proceeds.
If I hold a negative thought in the mind, can that create a change in the emotional body?
Resist.
Which, in turn, can cause a change in the etheric body?
Which, in turn, can cause a change in the physical body?
Resist.
All right.
So, now you see the whole purpose of spiritual healing and psychotherapy to treat psychosomatic diseases and all.
If what I hold in mind in the mental body is more powerful than any of the bodies below it,
it will influence how I feel.
You know, how I feel is going to influence my etheric body,
and my etheric body is going to manifest as a disease of the physical body.
And you can actually detect that because with kinesiology or with acupuncture,
you can directly measure the consequences of these negative thoughts on the acupuncture system.
And each acupuncture meridian goes to a specific body organ system.
So, what I hold in mind in my...
My emotions about that then are obviously going to influence my physical body.
That would also explain why one's spiritual position is more dominant than anything else.
I remember when I was looking for some volunteers,
I was going to give a lecture on a course in kinesiology.
And this was at the clinic back east,
and there were some friends of mine hanging around, people I knew.
And I said, I have to give this lecture tonight, and I knew they were going to be there.
I said, can I...
Can I use you as a subject?
Yeah.
So, I usually demonstrate the effect of sweet and low and fluorescent lights and pesticides.
So, as I tried each of these things, none of them went weak.
Everybody goes weak.
By that time, I tested thousands of people in large audiences.
Everybody went weak to sweet and low.
And I thought, whoa, what's going on here?
Well, they were all studying the Course in Miracles,
and the Course in Miracles is a workbook.
And it turned out that by the time they got to...
to Lesson 90, they were immune to most of the...
They wouldn't go weak with all the negative things
that anybody in the world goes weak with.
And so, I went back and sort of studied it specifically
because I was sort of blown away by this.
And it turns out around Lesson 76 in the Course in Miracles, in the workbook,
once you pass Lesson 76 or so,
you're no longer subject to anything except what you hold in mind.
And I thought, wow, that's curious.
And I went back and looked at, I think it was 76, and it said,
I'm only subject...
to what I hold in mind.
All we're really talking about over and over again
is the use of kinesiology as a research tool.
Let's say you want to go back in history
and check out the Amelia Earhart story,
or you want to check out the Lindbergh kidnapping,
or you want to check out how did Napoleon feel
before he went into the pyramid,
and how did he feel after he left the pyramid.
You know, it's said that in the pyramid,
he had a vision of his ultimate...
defeat at Waterloo.
Some...
We could ask some questions about humanity in general.
Let's ask a fun question.
Delmer, come on over here.
Okay.
There's a fun question we want to ask,
and this is a fun one.
You can trust the man in a suit and a white...
You can trust the man in a suit and a tie.
Resist.
I've gotten that over and over again.
What's a trustworthy man?
If the man puts on a suit and a tie,
he enters a domain of untrustworthiness.
Resist.
Yeah.
He becomes now the politician.
In other words,
business is ruled by what makes the bottom line,
you know,
vending the truth for the benefit.
So, expediency.
All right.
The law of the suit and the tie is expediency.
Resist.
The law of the man who wears a suit
and a tie is expediency.
Resist.
The law of the suit and the tie is truth.
He's not interested in truth.
The lawyer in court is not interested in truth.
He's interested in winning the case, obviously.
So, it has nothing to do with truth whatsoever.
Exposure to this videotape and reading the book
Power vs. Force
raises one's level of consciousness
over 35 points.
Resist.
40 points.
Average of 36 points.
Resist.
That's interesting,
because we talked the level of mankind
being at 190 over the centuries,
and it jumped in 1986 to 207.
And another interesting question we can ask is
consciousness,
a person is born with a level of consciousness.
Resist.
We'll ask more about that later.
But there's actually a calibrated level of consciousness
the minute you're born.
It's almost as though you enter the body
or you activate the body
from a certain level.
One obvious place that we can use this
is in intelligence,
military,
espionage,
various things like that.
You don't know who this is.
Come on over here a second.
Hold this against your sword, Plexus.
This man is loyal to the United States of America.
Resist.
This man can be trusted.
Here we have a double agent,
the inside story of the CIA's mole.
You have,
we have another one,
you know,
Ames.
Let's just,
I'm looking at him in my mind,
at a picture of Ames.
The energy of this man is positive.
Resist.
All right,
so you see the obvious advantage in intelligence.
One obvious use,
let's say,
for the Secret Service.
Let's say you have the video camera on the crowd.
The president's parade is going by.
We could do this on the JFK assassination.
Let's say,
we're talking about the safety of the United States president.
So we have the video camera.
You know, we just put an X in the middle like this and we say,
there is a man in the crowd who intends to assassinate the president in this quadrant.
No, this quadrant, no, this quadrant, no, this quadrant, yes.
Okay, now we just zoom in.
Again, we do quadrants.
So, we can get right down to the exact man.
We can say this man has a gun in his pocket.
Yes, his left pocket, his right pocket, it's a revolver, it's an automatic.
We can do the same thing we did with the gun before.
This man is psychotic.
This man is paranoid delusional.
Uh,
this man is a political activist, but he's not psychotic.
We can get a profile of the man.
We can zero down.
We can send somebody, a Secret Service agent, into the crowd and say,
get the guy in the yellow sweater,
because in his left hand pocket, he's got a thumb-nose
36 police special.
We can be that accurate.
We could do the same thing with military intelligence.
You know, military intelligence has been really devastatingly bad.
Considering what's possible, when you think of the Bay of Pigs thing, you know,
You know, you're talking about a country that's only 90 miles off the coast of Florida.
How we couldn't know exactly everything that goes on there just boggles my mind.
Houdon, what's his name? Hussein, what's his name?
I don't follow what you're talking about.
The details of the world.
But North Korea, let's ask about North Korea.
North Korea is literally stockpiling nuclear weapons.
Resist. North Korea tends to use them militarily.
Resist. North Korea tends to use them to blackmail other nations.
Resist.
See, so one of the values of having nuclear weapons is not that you intend to blow up somebody,
because if you're North Korea, a little country like that, you're going to get blown off the map in retaliation.
But some little punky country can, you know, get hold of nuclear materials and proceed to make atomic bombs,
you know what I mean, this kind of talk, anyway.
And scare the wits out of everybody.
So what they're really doing is using nuclear material to blackmail concessions from other countries,
financial remuneration.
They're going to threaten us to blow us up, you know.
Usually we run in and rebuild their country.
We're going to run in and rebuild Bosnia and all those places like we did in all these other countries.
Let's ask some interesting questions about the military intelligence of the United States.
Sharing information in this videotape with military intelligence is a safe thing to do.
They don't have a secret.
The CIA is not.
The Indian Army, resolved, can't be trusted.
It says the Pentagon is U.S. intelligence.
The Pentagon, resist.
Army intelligence is integrists.
Navy intelligence is integrists.
Air Force, resist.
The Pentagon, resist.
OK, everyone thinks Pentagon can't be trusted, all the paranoids, you know, don't trust your government, you know.
It says the Pentagon is integrist.
secret service resist pentagon resist all right so the pentagon the military intelligence is uh
integrus doesn't mean they can't make a mistake see there's a difference between mistake and
integrus you can make an honest mistake but it'd be integrity so what i get is the pentagon is
integrus doesn't mean they can't make a mistake military the intelligence the same i get the fbi
is integrus i get secret services integrus and over and over again i've gotten uh atf alcohol
tobacco firearms is non-integrous and the cia is not there let's see if we can find out where
the lack of integrity is in the cia the head of the cia i've got his picture here somewhere
there we go i shouldn't be telling you information on this i should just ask you look at this guy
here okay this man is integrus resist all right that's the head of the cia um
the first level
below the head of the CIA is integrists, resist. The second level below the head of the CIA
is integrists, resist. No, I've gotten over and over again. The second level below the
head of the CIA is non-integrists, cannot be trusted, and how things like Ames come
about is due to that lack of integrity. Very interesting. So, as you can see, you can research
the moves of other military, you can find out about their weapons, you can find out
exactly what weapons they have, you can find out exactly where they're located, you can
find out what their motive is about using them, you can get the movement of their troops,
you can forestall any of the great military tioskos of recent history, which have ended
up as political disasters and military blunders. When you think about it, it is absolutely
idiotic to say that the CIA can't know what the intention of some subgroup in some foreign
country is. I mean, we're talking about countries where most of the military is not
involved, and most of those people cut their mother's throat for 50 bucks. You walk in
with big bucks and walk into the criminal element, and I can get any information you
want on anything without using kinesiology. So there's something out in the integrity.
For a few bucks, I can find out any information about anything. So, kinesiology is extremely
valuable then, and intelligence.