I'm Dr. David Hawkins. I'm a physician. I've been a psychiatrist for 35 years, worked in the field
of psychoanalysis, worked in the field of nutrition, and especially nutrition and its relationship to
brain chemistry. For the last 10 years, I've been doing research into the nature of consciousness
itself, and especially its relationship to that which the world calls spiritual. In today's talk,
we're going to be looking at the subject of health, one which everyone is interested in,
the subject of health which occupies the minds of a large part of our population. And of course,
as a physician, and as a psychiatrist, and as a spiritual researcher, I've been very interested
in the field of health and self-healing. So we'll be talking again about the relationship between
body, mind, and spirit, because we know from our previous talks,
that body has no way of experiencing itself, that body is experienced in mind only.
It's in mind that you experience the body. We know that the body expresses that which is held
in mind. We know that mind itself cannot really experience itself. It has to be experienced from
an even greater energy field, which we call consciousness. So we go from dense form,
ever expanding into ever increasing formlessness. And so we end up with the experiencing of
experience itself, or that field called awareness, which is beyond consciousness itself.
So we're looking today at that relationship between body, mind, and spirit, very important
when we're considering the whole subject of health. We'll be looking at consciousness itself,
because all experience is going on within consciousness itself. And because the power,
the power of the energy fields here, we've discovered that healing comes out of attitudes
and belief systems and that which is held in mind. And therefore, health is also coming
out of expressions of levels of consciousness. And to understand this and make it more understandable,
more comprehensible, especially to people who are very logical in the orientation, which
I was of course, being a skeptical scientist, what we've done is prepared here an integrated
map of consciousness based on a mathematical relationship between the energy fields. And
the energy field that we've done, and myself and my coworker, Glorian Ross, over the last
few years, in which we've calibrated the energy fields of literally tens of thousands of things.
Attitudes, feelings, etc.
And so we've come up with this mathematical model in which the relative power of energy
fields is calibrated so that you see that apathy, which is calibrated at 50, has only
half the power of fear, which is calibrated at 100.
Fear on the other hand has only half the power or the energy of courage, which is calibrated
at 200.
Not only do these energy fields have different relative power to each other, but we see that
the energy fields go in a certain direction.
We see that all the energy fields under courage are directed in a negative, anti-life, that
which is oriented towards destruction.
The energy fields below courage then tend to be anti-life in their effect.
At the level of courage we see that the needle swings to the midline, and we see that as
we go beyond the energy field of 200, up to neutral willingness, acceptance and love,
there isn't much that is going on behind that Iraq and umas.
Okay, all right.
Sewed to the left, I'll have a photo.
Okay, now let's see how this would work .I'll have Buch constructed to 100, okay, this is
that these energy fuels now go to the right, indicating that they nurture and support life,
that they are energy-giving, life-giving, increasing aliveness.
So as we go up the scale, we go into energy fuels of increasing aliveness,
that which supports life and the truth.
And as we get to the bottom of the field, we get to that which does not support life,
which is anti-life, and which does not represent the truth.
You'll notice that death is calibrated at zero.
And if we start with death at zero and calibrate these fields,
we will find that at about the level of 600, we leave the field of duality.
We leave the field of illusion.
We leave the identification with the small self, with that which is the ego, in common parlance.
And we move on into fields of enlightenment, so that the great enlightened beings,
the great spiritual masters, the avatars,
their energy fuels calibrate and begin up in the 700s and go on up into infinity.
So the truth really begins then, where this needle swings to neutral,
leaving falsehood, going into truth,
and the energy fuels now go to the right, indicating that which is supportive.
Supportive of life, supportive of aliveness.
And so in our talk today, where we're talking about health, we're talking about aliveness.
But we're talking about truth.
We're talking about truth.
What we're talking about is the expression of an energy field.
The expression of an energy field.
And we said that the body expresses that which the mind holds.
We're only subject to what we hold in mind.
And therefore, the greater the negativity that is being held in mind,
the greater the negative energy field effect on the body's physical health.
The greater the positive energy being held in mind and consciousness,
the more powerfully positive.
And the more positive will be the energy field of life.
So this gives us a tool now, a way of approaching things to see,
does this support life or does it not support life?
We can substitute the word health, because health is nothing but the expression of life.
These things up here, we will find, are supporting health.
And these things down here are creating illness.
So at the bottom of the box, we have energy fuels that support illness.
And at the top of the box, we have energy fuels that support illness.
And at the bottom of the box, we have energy fuels that support health.
And at the top of the box, we have energy fuels that support life.
Each of these energy fields reflects themselves in an emotion.
So that which is anti-life, as you would expect, has negative emotions.
The emotions of self-hatred, hopelessness, despair, regret, depression, worry, anxiety,
cravingness, resentment, hatred, arrogance.
These negative emotions then accompany ill health.
We see the process going on in consciousness,
We see the process going on in consciousness, coming out of the body,
of these emotional states destruction loss of energy loss of spirit deflation entrapment
over expansion over inflation loss of power we see the kind of a world that a person experiences
out of these negative mental states a world of sin and suffering hopelessness sadness frightening
frustrating competitive a world of status we see the negative conceptualizations of god that come
out of a lower energy field god is the ultimate enemy of man the one who hates them hates him
the destroyer the one who throws you into hell forever or the god who ignores you the
unlovingness the god who's dead the god is punitive the god is retaliatory or the atheistic
or the bigot position so we have an energy field we have its negative direction we can see the
weakness of the power we can see the negative emotion the destructive
and process going on in consciousness the negative view of the world and the negative
view of god all correlate with ill health all correlate with ill health is that accidental
is it causal so we'll be looking at that today we'll be looking at health as the expression of
unopposed aliveness resulting from the removal of its obstacles from the removal of all that is
negative and we'll see that health results from transcending limitation and feelings of separation
that we have the power of refusal we can refuse things that are negative in our life
if our mind can get programmed in a negative direction we can choose to program it in a
positive direction we'll be looking at health as an expression of self-love
just how does one learn learn to love oneself we'll build an understanding of the subject then
based on um our knowledge of these energy fields and their applications in everyday life and how to
apply them to our daily lives this includes our way of thinking how do we live our lives
we take our time to think we get excited about ourselves and do things that we like and we
see that there's a lot of life that we can do and we can do it we've all got healthy states
of body health so even if we do more often we can have better health and also more energy
the same way we can have better physical health we can have better health and when we have more
health we can have better mental health like we can have better cognitive health and so on and so on
catch out of the corner of your eye and not central to your experience at all that means
letting go of identifying oneself as this physicalness and so on the scale of consciousness
here as we get towards the bottom of the box we have an increasing identification of ourselves
as being the body and as we move higher in our consciousness this lessons and lessons until we
finally transcend that identification with the body and in move into the realization of spirit
the relationship between body mind and spirit then is what we'll be looking at today and how
to achieve optimal health we have to look at the relationship between mind and body because that
is of great importance in the field of health and one that is not really clearly understood
perhaps utilizing our map of consciousness we can make it clearer
and there is a
certain
principle and it's demonstrated clinically and we'll get to clinical examples
that we're only subject to what we hold in mind now this is a principle of healing and a principle
of health the health and healing being two different sides of a coin illness being one side
of the coin health the other the opposite sides of the coin of the same understanding the same
understanding that heals brings about health that we're subject to what we're holding in mind good
clinical
example of this as we said in a talk that we gave on healing illness is that of multiple
personalities and another example is of hypnosis under hypnosis we can give a suggestion to a
patient that you are allergic to the roses on the desk and when you wake up you will get hives
and a rash and start sneezing and then we create amnesia for that suggestion
when the person wakes up from the hypnotic trance all of a sudden they start to wheeze
they get hives and develop a rash so the body you see is responding to what the mind believes
and so with hypnosis we can induce the symptoms and i would imagine probably almost any illness
by convincing the patient under hypnosis that our program that we have just programmed him with
is actually true and then creating amnesia for the memory that he was programmed and so we see
the illness then is coming out of a program a belief system
of course the hypnotic patient is this is happening as an experiment in a laboratory
but let's forget let's not forget what happens in everyday life is that we've been hypnotized
thousands and thousands of times we sit in a trance before the television set have no conscious
memory the program went in and we are now subject to that for the rest of our life with no memory of
where that came from because of childhood amnesia many people can't remember what happened before
the age of five and so they're going to have a lot to deal with what's going on in my life right now
Some people even, you know, at a much later age, they have no memory of anything from their entire childhood or very few memories.
Even people with good memories of their childhood, there are vast areas of vacant forgottenness.
And in those areas of vacant forgottenness are the many programs which are now expressing later on in various forms of ill health.
Such catchphrases as heart disease runs in our family, overweight runs in our family, allergies run in our family, etc.
Everybody has hay fever in our family.
These thoughts then become a program and it goes into the mind and we see that it's the same as though the person was hypnotized.
Until that program is made conscious and cancelled, it remains operative within the unconscious.
We see another example of the power of mind over body in so-called cases of multiple personality.
These have been gaining increasing attention within the field of psychiatry
and it is found to be far more common.
It was previously believed that the consciousness of one personality will be adopted and be operative within the person's body for varying periods of time.
It could be minutes, it could be hours, weeks, days, or even years.
While that personality is operative, while that second personality is operative,
the person is subject to all the belief systems held by that personality.
So if that personality happens to believe I have an ulcer,
I have a weight problem, I have allergies, I have diverticulitis, I have colitis, whatever it may believe,
I have back trouble, so while that personality is operative within the body,
those physical abnormalities actually are brought into existence.
The reverse side of it is when that personality leaves and how that comes about is
sometimes intoxication or shifts of emotionality or life circumstances, suddenly the other personality comes into the body.
The other personality which has no such belief, the body promptly heals itself of all those illnesses.
Now why does the mind have such power over the body?
Perhaps we can look at the physics of it a bit.
The physics would make it very easily understandable.
We sit in our calibrated system here where death is zero and guilt is 30, 50, we went all the way up here.
We can get the energy field of anything in the world.
And so we calibrate the energy field of the body,
the physical body itself, and we find that the physical body is not a reversed state like this.
The body is not a negative state, but the energy field of the body is about 100.
In other words, its power, its energy field is about 100.
The energy field of mind begins here around 400.
It runs between 400 and 500.
Those are the energy fields of the intellect, reason, logic, mind,
and beliefs.
And therefore if we hold a thought in mind that says,
seeds like in a strawberry or caraway seeds or any kind of seeds give me diverticulitis,
then the power of that thought, you see coming out of an energy field of between 400 and 500,
the body which only has an energy field of 100 is overpowered by the power of the pattern
of that belief.
And all thoughts have a form.
And so the form, which is there in the collective unconscious,
the collective consciousness, the social consciousness, whatever you want to call it,
is there in great detail.
The pattern of that and the coming about of how the mechanics of that would happen is already there.
So if we buy into that thought, if we go into agreement with it,
it's like we bring it into our own unconscious.
And that then expresses itself within the body.
So the body will do what the mind believes.
So the healing of the body then and the achievement of health
is achieved not by addressing the body directly but by addressing the mind,
moving right into the fields of consciousness itself.
So if the body is expressing that which is held in consciousness,
then what we need to look at is what is being held in consciousness.
Very often what's being held in consciousness
we are not aware of.
In that case we call it being unconscious of that.
By looking at the body we may have no recall of ever having had such a thought.
But the body is telling us what must be held.
It's like an x-ray.
The x-ray is telling us what must be held in mind for this to be presenting itself in the body.
So if the person, let's say, develops clinical diabetes,
and he says,
I don't remember anything in my family.
I don't remember anything in my family ever being said about that.
I don't remember anybody in my family had diabetes.
I don't see where it could have arisen in my mind.
We know that somewhere in the unconscious is the belief in diabetes
and all that goes with diabetes.
If we do individual research with the individual patient
long enough and patiently enough,
we will uncover where the program came from.
But what it tells us is that the program is there.
That the person thinks, I am subject to that.
And therefore the healing has to be of the belief system.
We have to heal where the origin of the illness starts.
And so health comes out of mind.
It comes out of positive mental attitudes.
It comes out of a field of consciousness.
It comes out of a level of consciousness
which expresses itself on the lower plane, the physical plane,
as an expression of health coming out of these fields above neutral.
Out of willingness.
Out of the willingness to be accepting.
Out of lovingness.
Out of inner joyfulness.
And out of an inner state of peace.
That which is mental was in the 400s.
And that love is 500s.
And of course spirit is 600 and above.
Actually spirit begins here once the needle moves to the right.
It becomes increasingly consciously aware that it is spirit.
So therefore the intellect is not man's highest faculty.
Contrary to the age of reason and other learned works.
Or those intellectuals who hold the thing that differentiates man from the animal is his intellect.
The intellect is only in the 400s.
There is something beyond mind, beyond logic, beyond reason,
which jumps and transcends into a whole different paradigm,
a whole different way of being.
It's necessary to know about that.
It's necessary to know then that which heals,
which is here on up.
It's necessary to look at the contribution that is coming into an illness from these various levels.
We find that always with an illness,
if we now understand illness,
then we will understand its reverse,
which is health.
That in illness there is always unconscious guilt.
Never has there been an illness without unconscious guilt in our research.
There is an unconscious guilt and therefore the undoing of unconscious guilt.
We're not talking about conscious guilt now.
We're talking about unconscious guilt.
And therefore there are whole systems of how to let go of unconscious guilt
through the process of the willingness to forgive.
Moving from here then,
meaning the willingness to let go of judgment,
of criticism and judgment,
the willingness to let go of make wrong,
of right wrong as an orientation towards life,
and a willingness to move towards a forgivingness
and the desire to understand life out of compassion.
So moving out of the contribution of guilt
and all the negative emotions,
and we move up to the mind,
we find that illness requires several things.
It requires unconscious guilt
and it requires a mental belief system.
The mind has to believe in a certain belief
for the person to believe that they are subject to that.
It's as though unconscious guilt
looks for something to justify itself.
So it can be any illness out there
and we see that after a certain illness
gets popularized on television,
let's say some celebrity,
shares with us that particular illness
and that's followed by an epidemic of that illness.
It's because of suggestion.
The mind now buys that.
The mind buys the belief system
in the specificity of a particular disease.
Unconscious guilt gives us
and gives it the power.
It's the unconscious guilt
looking for an expression
through the autonomic nervous system
and through the hormonal system
and through all the stress mechanisms within the body
and through the acupuncture energy system.
Which brings us to the subject of kinesiology
which we mentioned in one of our other talks
as a way of checking out for yourself
these calibrations.
All of you who are familiar with kinesiology
know how it works.
Those who aren't,
I can just briefly explain it to you
in about less than a minute.
What you do is you press down
and you have somebody hold out their arm.
You look away from them
and you press down and ask them to resist.
Now you ask them to hold something negative in mind.
Something about in their life
over which they have grief or fear
or somebody they hate, let's say.
And as you press,
now you ask them to resist
and you press down again
and you'll see instantly the whole body goes weak.
The body goes weak
figuratively and symbolically
it goes weak on many levels.
Now if we ask the same person
to forget that and instead
to hold in mind something or someone they love
and we press down again
we'll find that with all our strength
we can't push their arm down.
They are amazingly strong.
The brain hemispheres are synchronized,
the acupuncture energy system is balanced
and the energy flow of health,
the energy of life is flowing correctly
down all the energy channels
and energizing all the organs of the body.
So that we see every time we hold a negative thought
then the energy flow down one of the 12 main meridians
is interrupted.
And if we habitually blow certain acupuncture meridians
then disease comes about in that organ.
So we see that any of these negative emotions
is the direct cause of a disease process.
Unconscious guilt gives it enormous power
and the form that that illness takes
then is coming from mind,
what the mind believes.
So what the mind believes is what the body expresses.
We have to look at how experience is experienced.
We see that the body in and of itself
as we have said in other of these talks,
the body in and of itself is in ascension,
as curious as that may sound.
It has no capacity to experience itself.
The experience, the next level of experience
is coming through sensations
coming from the senses of the body.
So we don't experience the body,
we experience the senses of the body.
Senses themselves have no capacity
to experience themselves.
They're experienced in mind.
It's because of mind,
it's in mind that we experience the senses.
And the senses then report what's going on
within the body.
So we're already several levels removed.
Mind itself isn't able to experience
its own experience.
It has to be in a greater, larger energy field
than itself.
And in this case it is the energy field
of consciousness itself.
It is because of consciousness
that we're aware of what is going on in mind.
Mind then is telling us via the senses
what is going on in body.
So you see that which we are,
when I say I, me,
is already several levels removed
from the physical body.
Consciousness itself requires
something greater than itself
and that we call awareness.
Awareness.
Awareness is what allows us to know
what is going on in consciousness
reporting what is happening within mind,
which in turn is reporting what is happening
via the senses about the body.
That which is essentially myself then
is many levels removed from the physical body.
It's necessary for us to look at it
and get that correctly in mind
because now we see that it's the mind
that has power over the body.
We saw the physics of it,
that the energy fields of the 400s
just by their sheer power
are greater than that of the physical body.
The physical body does
what the mind tells it to do
and therefore if the mind says
I have this disease or that disease
the body complies.
When we look at this we see the importance then
of not buying into
programs
and all of which are really
limitations of the truth.
We see the importance of consciously
cancelling and saying
something which is the truth.
The truth is
I am an infinite being
not subject to that.
So when we hear something
like eggs which are
full of cholesterol and their
cholesterol will give you heart disease.
If you buy into the thought form,
if you buy into that belief system
that eggs, cholesterol
will give me heart disease
raise my blood cholesterol
what happens is that the body
agrees and
when you eat cholesterol
what happens is your blood cholesterol goes up.
You can experiment with this
because I've done it
and at one time I had a very high cholesterol
and I began to cancel the belief system.
I kept saying I'm an infinite being
I'm not subject to that.
I'm only subject to what I hold in mind.
This does not apply to me
and I hereby cancel it and refuse it.
Well if the mind
can empower you with a
negative belief system it can reverse itself
can it not?
And therefore you begin telling yourself
that they have no effect on me
that that's only a belief system
that I don't have to buy into that
I don't have to go into agreement with it.
When I go into agreement with it
I give it the power of the collective
energy of that belief.
When I refuse it
then I release myself from the collective
energy of that belief system.
I count myself out.
So one attitude then
is to not buy into
agreement
with negative belief systems
having to do with your health.
This is very important
when it comes to epidemics
the hysteria.
So you see the programming that comes in
is aided and abetted by
an emotional program.
So now we hear much about AIDS
let's say.
And then we hear about
constant repetition in the media
who play upon what?
Fear.
Fear about this.
Anger about this.
And of course guilt about this.
What better disease to bring up all
man's feelings of sinfulness
and guilt especially about his sexuality
which is so common in our culture
in all cultures.
That which is the highest expression
of love of course
when it takes on a negative
and when it is turned over
becomes the lowest.
And therefore what a better area
in which to create an epidemic
through sheer belief in it.
The unconscious guilt
not to mention the conscious guilt
about one's sexuality.
The sadness about that.
The grief over that.
The fear about the disease etc.
All of this contributing then
and setting the stage.
So you have the mental belief system
coming out of an energy field in the 400's.
You have fear about it
coming out of a negative 100's.
And you have the guilt coming out
of the minus 30's.
And so you have the exact set up for that.
The exact set up
because the mind will choose
that which
it is impressed with.
And will use that
as a form of expression.
In the case of the cholesterol
the experiment I did with that
with my own self
was to cancel the thought
that came up.
And as time went by
in fact it didn't take very long
with that particular thing
the cholesterol level came down
and now I can eat 3 eggs for breakfast
every single morning.
Lots of cheese.
In fact I live on a high cholesterol diet
and yet my cholesterol is low
and sometimes even below normal
for my age.
The body will do exactly
what the mind believes
and that's my belief in that
make it happen within my life.
It's because of the nature
of the unconscious.
It creates the opportunity
for that to happen.
We certainly see that in accidents.
The person is so called accident prone
that's the form that is taken
in that person's mind.
Unconsciously they just manage
to get their body in the right place
at the right time.
Just to get hit by the fender of the car
slip down the stairs, get hit on the head.
The mind will find a way.
People will just slip into
sort of a hypnotic trance
and expose themselves
to the correct opportunities
to make that manifest within their life.
For instance with the cold virus
there's many experiments
where we take 100 subject volunteers
and expose them to a very heavy dose
of cold virus.
We see what happens
is that not everybody gets the cold virus.
Only a certain percentage
will always get it.
In other words if the power
was in the virus rather than
within consciousness
all 100 would get it
because that virus would be so potent.
Actually what happens is
maybe only 65%
will get it.
A third don't believe in it.
There's sufficient doubt within the mind.
There's insufficient unconscious guilt.
It's not acceptable to the person
to express it in that form.
Nothing is universal.
We see the same thing with healings.
Penicillin doesn't cure 100%
of pneumonias.
It only cures a certain percent.
Every medical treatment
has only a certain percentage
of people who will respond.
And what is the difference?
It is because the others
don't have sufficient unconscious guilt.
It's not operative.
This particular illness doesn't fit
any particular thought form
that they have bought into.
And so both sides of it
are the same.
The energy that we put into
a certain belief system.
So we see then that health
is the willingness to let go
of buying into negativity.
Why should a person buy into negativity anyway?
Why is it that some people
are so programmable?
We know people that go into hysteria
every time they open a magazine.
The latest illness sends them into a panic.
And it has to do then
with the amount of fear
and the amount of guilt.
It's as though the person
knows what to be afraid of.
It's as though they're only too aware
that because they have so much of this
for them to even hear about it
and become mentally programmed
is almost enough to make it happen
in their life.
So what does this tell us then
about the steps towards optimal health?
It means the willingness
to adopt mental attitudes
that are positive and constructive.
And this means the willingness
to let go of the negative ones.
The willingness to take an easy going
forgiving attitude towards life.
The unwillingness
to buy into negative programming.
The owning
of the power of mind.
You see, going into denial
going into denial
and blaming it
on out there
is giving your power away.
We see that these energy fields below courage
here are all levels in which the person
has become victim.
What's happened is they've given
their power away
and put it on something outside of themselves.
And these people
in these levels here have said
to themselves unconsciously
the source of my happiness
is outside of myself.
They've put their survival on something
outside of themselves.
As we move into levels of truth
above the levels of courage
and the energy fields are now going positive
we see that the person
is reowning their power.
The person is saying, I and I alone
have the power to create
happiness and opportunity in my life.
It is coming from within me.
And so these people
then own that health
is something that comes
from within.
These people are coming from
I am the victim of disease.
You see, we are not the victim of viruses.
We're not the victim of accidents.
We're not the victim of cholesterol.
We're not the victim of uric acid levels.
We're not the victim of those things.
When we reown our own power
we say, hey, it's my mind
that's been creating that.
My mind believes that eating liver
and kidneys is going to give you
a high uric acid level
and that's going to give you an attack of gout.
My mind is so powerful
that if I believe that
it will literally make it happen.
That's a hard thing for many people to accept
that their mind has that much power.
You mean to tell me that if I believe
that eating sugar and sweets
is going to give me hypoglycemia
that that will give me hypoglycemia?
Indeed it will.
And so we go back to the physics involved
and we remind ourselves
that the body's energy field of 100
is weak compared to the belief systems of 400.
The belief that sugar and sweets
will give me hypoglycemia
or give me diabetes
or give me overweight.
Those belief systems are sufficient to do it.
And all the explanations
that we come upon
the rationalizations
that justify that we are the victim of that
are just that.
They're not the truth.
They're substituting an explanation.
The fact that it's scientific
is still an explanation.
The science of it
is the mechanism.
The description of the mechanism
of how this comes about on the physical plane
is only a description
of the mechanism.
It is not a description of cause.
Cause is on the level of mind.
Effect is on the level of body.
It's not the other way around.
And if we really just merely reverse
that understanding,
we have the whole key to health and healing.
Health then comes out of a positive
mental attitude.
That's a thing we've heard many times, haven't we?
In fact, many people are annoyed by it.
Yes, because that infers if I have a sickness
I don't have a positive mental attitude.
Let's look at mental attitude then.
Let's look at what is meant by that
and the part that that plays in
health and freedom
from sickness and suffering.
We said the one thing that goes on
in the unhealthy person is
this unconscious guilt
and the cure for that
is the willingness to be forgiving,
to actually take courses in forgiveness
if that is necessary,
such as the Course in Miracles,
which is specifically designed
to let go of that tendency of the mind
to criticize, to attack, and to judge.
The willingness then
to let go judgmentalism.
Now the mechanism is unconscious,
so the person may not see
the connection between
the fact that their mind is critical
and judgmental.
If your mind is critical and judgmental
of others, of course it is critical
and judgmental of yourself.
The creation of the unconscious guilt
then builds up a certain energy
which expresses itself through
the autonomic nervous system
and the acupuncture energy system.
So that is the cure of that.
The contribution from mind,
the belief system,
we said is the power of refusal,
to deny it.
It is your power now
that it is the mind and the mind itself
that is the cause of the illness.
The willingness to give up
the position of victim,
the willingness to reown one's own power
is part and parcel of the third thing
that is necessary for health,
and that is one's overall
spiritual growth and development.
The overall moving out of
these negative energy patterns,
the willingness to face truths
within ourself,
and the moving into a positive energy field.
This can be done actually rather rapidly.
How so?
Because willingness,
you see, is the key.
Through the willingness to look at it,
the willingness to say,
well, I don't really believe this,
but it is said that my mind has the power
to create an illness within my body,
and so I am willing to look at that
because I have an open mind.
I have an open mind
and I am willing to agree.
My intention aligns then
and I begin to move into accepting
which I discover.
I begin to find
that moving into lovingness
has a curative and healing power.
And how do we do that?
Our willingness to forgive,
our willingness here moves us
right into the willingness to forgive,
and if we
can quickly move ourself into
the willingness to be compassionate.
What does compassion mean?
Compassion means
the willingness to see the innocence
within all things.
You see, that coincides
with the willingness to forgive.
Out of compassion
comes the power,
the capacity,
coming out of our intention
to really see into the hearts of others.
When we see into the hearts of others,
as we've said in other talks,
what we discover is the innocence
of the child
within each and every one of us
because it is intrinsic to the nature
of consciousness itself,
is that intrinsic innocence
which never dies
no matter how long we live.
The innocence of the child
is what bought the mistake,
which bought the negative program
in the first place.
The being aware,
that that intrinsic innocence of the child
is ever with us.
It's the innocence of the child
that sits there in front of the television set
and buys the negative programming.
Out of its naivete,
out of its lack of discernment,
the innocence of the child
says,
this is a world
that is out to program you
with as much negativity
as you're willing to buy.
In fact, it gets well paid to do that
because advertising is usually based
in playing off of these negative energy fields.
All of our fears,
all of our desires,
all of our pridefulness,
all of it as you see below the line.
The willingness then
to be aware
that within us is our innocence
and that the innocence
needs to be protected.
So we come into what's called self-care.
Self-care,
the capacity to love oneself now,
means taking responsibility
to protect ourselves
from that innocence
and the willingness
to undo the mistakes
that the mind picked up
as a result of its innocence.
We can handle now
looking at ourselves
and healing that which we find within us
if we're coming from the compassion
of the awareness
of the intrinsic innocence
of our consciousness.
We see that it was innocence
that got programmed.
Now we take responsibility for that
and we say, well,
in my innocence I bought all that.
In my innocence I didn't know any better.
In my innocence I thought
that the right thing to do
was to be judgmental,
to condemn people,
to judge them as right and wrong.
I'm going to let it go.
We have amongst our acquaintances
and the people that we've done research
with people
who have had every disease known to mankind,
advanced multiple sclerosis,
cancers of all kinds,
all kinds of advanced illnesses.
And these people
merely were willing
to look into this question.
And when they did,
they went through the processes
that we've described in this talk
and they all came out
of their illnesses
without any residuals whatsoever.
This capacity then
to be forgiving is within us,
the capacity for compassion.
Out of it comes
a general attitude,
a way in which we look at ourself.
So from our bigness,
from our greatness,
we look at our humanness
through forgiving eyes
and we begin to forgive ourself
for all the things
that were limitations
of the truth.
All of these things
with an energy fuel
with the arrows going to the left
are denials of the truth.
All of those with an arrow
going to the right
is the acceptance of that
which is true and positive.
And so health,
because the body is reflecting
what the mind believes
and the mind is reflecting
our spiritual position.
Spirit has the greatest power of all.
It is willing to accept
the power of mind.
Now we have to be attentive
and we have to persevere
and we can't let it get away
with expressing negativity
without stopping it.
So we get to develop
sort of an ear for negativity
and begin to recognize it
for what it is.
We let go of false humility
and we start questioning
such remarks as,
oh, my handwriting is poor
or I gain weight
in the same amount of food
that other people stay thin.
The minute we hear ourselves
saying these limiting,
self-defeating, self-attacking thoughts
they have to be stopped and canceled.
The handwriting is poor
because there's a belief system
that I have poor handwriting
and not vice versa.
So what we're doing then
is reversing the whole programming
of the mind as far as
we're coming back to a principle
which you can demonstrate
through your own experience.
That the physical is the expression
of the mental and not vice versa.
It isn't that we came to the conclusion
our handwriting is poor
because our handwriting is poor.
The handwriting is poor
because the cause was in mind.
The belief system.
Perhaps a remark
picked up in childhood.
Somebody says your handwriting is poor.
From that point on that program
we have to look at the ingenuity
of the unconscious mind.
To really see it
it would be great if you had
some experience in watching
hypnotic experiments.
Because if we tell the person
that when they wake up
their legs will be itching
and then we induce amnesia
for that suggestion.
When we wake the person up
we'll say how do you feel?
Instantly the mind will start
creating the most marvelous
things.
The person doesn't just say
well my legs itch.
The mind always gets in there
in a creative way
and will say and start explaining
well I've got wool pants on
and you know I'm allergic to wool
and the heat in this room
and steam heat always creates that.
It's just marvelous to listen
to the inventiveness of the mind
as it begins to create
the reasons for the symptom
The mind will do the same thing then
and it's helpful to look at ourselves
as though we've been hypnotized
subjects half of our life
and didn't even realize it.
What is hypnosis?
It's suggestibility is it not?
It means to be in an unguarded
suggestible relaxed state.
So anytime you've been
in an unguarded relaxed
suggestible state
you've picked up all the programming
and whether you remember it or not
it is still operative.
Half asleep as you sat in front
of the television set
hour after hour after hour
of programming went into the mind.
These are all now
unconscious
hypnotic programs.
How can we discover what we've been programmed?
With is by watching
to see what comes up.
So the idea oh I'm no good
I'm no good.
I never was very good at playing cards.
If you have the belief system
that you're not very good at playing cards
you're not going to operate in your life
is that you're not going to be very good
at playing cards.
That goes back then to reinforce
the belief system.
And so these belief systems
become self reinforcing.
They become self fulfilling prophecies.
We hold the belief unwittingly
it then manifests in our life
we look at that and we say see
and that justifies the belief system.
So by looking at our life
we can tell what beliefs we are holding
if we can't recall them
therefore our movement
is upward in consciousness
we said health is the automatic
expression of these energy fields up here.
The energy field of 540 and over
which is one of gratitude
and forgiveness.
We see that gratitude is at 540
forgiveness is at 540
and healing
is at 540.
The willingness to be forgiving
and grateful in itself
automatically begins to heal.
Becoming a
loving being.
This energy field of love
and we must talk about what that means.
It doesn't talk about
it's not sentimentality.
What the world calls love
is coming out in an energy field
in here.
It's talking about dependency
it's talking about control
it's talking about sentimentalism
and emotionalism
and emotional sentimental attachment
in which there is
control going back and forth
and the satisfaction of desiringness
on both sides
is called love.
The Hollywood version.
When you hear somebody say
I used to love George but I don't anymore
what it means is that
they never did love George.
What it means is they had a sentimental attachment
sort of a solar plexus
kind of a hanging onto
which the person then
romanticized and glamorized
within their life
and poured a lot of emotional energy
into their life
and when that was broken
up came a lot of negative emotion.
The kind of love we're talking about
is unconditional love.
Unconditional love.
What is unconditional love?
That's an inner decision
that we make within ourself.
See the intention
it's coming out of the intention
and the decision
to be a loving person.
So if I decide to love you
that is my inner decision.
Therefore I'm not the victim
of what goes on in the world
because my decision to love
creates a stable energy field
of unconditionality.
So the other person's behavior
may not please me
may not contribute
to what I desire
but it doesn't change the lovingness.
So the mother
for instance who visits her son in prison
for 20 years
the son who is a murderer
loves the beingness
the is-ness
that which the person really is.
Of course his behavior
does not make her happy
but the love is unconditional
no matter what he does.
So the closest to it
that we see in our world
is the lovingness of the mother
which is unconditional.
The lovingness of 12 step groups
such as Alcoholics Anonymous
which I've used as an example
in other talks.
The unconditionality of that lovingness.
It's not concerned with what you have.
The people at the bottom here
are very concerned with havingness
and rate people back and forth
on what they have.
In the middle of the box
people are preoccupied with doingness
and people are rated
and their status depends on what you do
and all the titles that go
with your doingness.
As you move towards the top of the box
what people are concerned with
is what you are, what you have become
what you are beingness
that which you truly are.
We're concerned there
with a person's status
their value there
is the kind of a person that you are
that which you have become
you have become that kind of a person
and that is what is valued.
The willingness then to become
a forgiving person
who nurtures all of life
non-judgmentally
automatically brings about within yourself
because of the very healing nature
a condition of good health.
The beginning to see
the perfection of all things
how all things work out for the good.
How can illness be
held in that context?
For the person who is oriented
such in the direction in which
we're talking today
then illness merely becomes
something that is coming up
in order to be healed.
We look at the illness then
as bringing up a lesson.
The illness is saying
please heal what I stand for
what I symbolize.
Please heal your guiltiness.
Please heal your self-hatred.
Please heal your limiting thought forms.
Please move up to loving me
so that I can be healed.
And so the illness
is a demand
to grow spiritually.
It's an incessant
gadfly
that tells us
that something is out
something needs to be looked at
to be held in a different way.
You see because it is not
the events of life
but how we hold them
that creates our reaction.
Events in and of themselves
have no power
to affect how we feel
one way or another.
It's what our position is about them.
It's our judgment about them.
It's how we decide to be with them.
It's our attitude.
It's our point of view.
It's the context.
And so we see
we are the creator then
of the meaning
the impact that it has on us.
Stress comes from
that very thing.
Giving it power over our lives
coming from the position of victim
putting the source of happiness
outside of our life
denying the power of our own mind.
The healing then comes about
through the re-owning of the power
the realization that we and we alone
create
the meaning of any
circumstance, event,
place, position or thing
any person in our life.
We are the one that creates the meaning.
Our position, the way we hold it then
that either becomes
a source of healing
or a source of illness.
We are the one that determines that.
It's her little pet.
In other words
we begin to see that the body
is like a little marionette.
You know it sort of happily goes about its way
energy fuels of joyfulness and gladness.
You see it just sort of does
what it does automatically
without much thinking about it.
Healthy means we pay less and less
attention to the body
and that which we do
which the world would call health giving
is out of appreciation
it's an expression of how we are
with that body.
You see we aren't giving away
our power as source.
Being healthy means you've re-owned
your power as source.
You're not giving away the source
of health of the body to the world.
The exercising we do
is out of the joyfulness
in experiencing the body.
So we don't say that swimming
is what causes the body
to be healthy.
We come from the position
that because we enjoy the body
we enjoy its activity
such as swimming.
So those activities which the world
consider healthy
then are coming out of the expression
of one's inner sense of aliveness.
The joy
in allowing the body's
expression in ways
that the world considers healthy.
Not because they're causal
those are the effect.
The healthy enjoyment of the body then
is the effect of the mental attitude.
Looking at it as something pleasurable.
And therefore we come to a
lovingness of the body.
No, not a narcissistic
self-glorification.
Not a muscle man
a picture in the photo magazine.
Not out of desiringness
not out of pridefulness
not out of narcissism
but out of a lovingness
and a gratitude.
We say ah little body
you've served me well
I love you
I appreciate you
I value you
See we know we are not the body.
If you lose your right arm
you'll still say I am me.
If you lose your left arm
if you lose both legs
you'll still be saying I am me.
If we take off the ears
progressively the body diminishes
to practically nothing
and yet the sense of self
is ever with us.
And so the healthy person
begins to develop a sense of self
that is independent of external events
and independent
of being the body itself.
The person is aware
that the body is the body
of events but I am me.
And that which I am
is really untouched by these events.
The self that wakes up every morning
before it even begins to remember
you know name and address
and where you are
and what you're supposed to do today
that self remains unimpaired.
The innocence of consciousness
the hardware of the computer
is unaffected by the software
the events that go through life.
And so a healthy attitude
is one which does not put
the person in transitory.
When we look back at this chart
we'll see.
What's happened here
is that the person has placed
their survival on something
outside of themself.
This something outside of oneself
is always transitory
and changing in nature.
We can say the one thing we know
about the world for certain
is that all things change.
All things change.
Consequently if we put the source
of our survival on that
which is outside of ourself
our job, our possessions
a particular relationship
then we're merely setting ourself up
for the loss
of our health
because what's going to come up
first of all is fear of loss
even though that's not conscious.
You know if the source of your happiness
is your title and your position
and your address and the kind of car
that you have etc.
or even the beauty of the physical body
that you have
then you're vulnerable.
So that vulnerability
is in the unconscious
and it stores up a great deal of fear.
And therefore people's lives become
endlessly to reinforce
and protect themselves from the loss
of those things upon which
they have put their survival.
The healthy person realizes
the true nature of who they really are.
That they are something far beyond that.
That they are the one
that gives those things value.
That they are temporary enjoyment
but their survival doesn't depend on them.
We said that when you move up
into this energy fuel
called acceptance
one has stopped giving one's power
away to the world.
One has begun to accept
that I am the source of my happiness.
That if you put a person like that
on a desert island and come back a year later
you know they'll have a coconut business going
and they'll have found a new relationship
and they'll build a tree house in the tree
and they'll be teaching the children algebra.
That they have the capacity
to recreate for themselves
the source of happiness
comes from the realization
that I myself am the source of that happiness.
I myself am the source of health.
It doesn't depend on epidemics.
It doesn't depend on what is out there in the world.
It doesn't depend on what I eat.
When we really realize that
then we begin to transcend
and no longer be at the effect
of all these false belief systems.
And so what kind of a life
is possible then?
It comes from canceling these belief systems.
The mind says,
uh-oh, you cancel these belief systems
and you're really going to be in trouble.
So you see here is a mind that has placed its security
it's based its security
on the worshipping of fear.
The worshipping of fear.
It is saying, by paying attention
to these fearful thoughts
and complying with them
that's why
I am alive.
A mind like that says
the reason my house hasn't been robbed
is because I lock all my doors.
It doesn't see
that it's the power of the thought.
The mind thinks
if the doors are locked
the house won't be robbed.
It's the power of the mind
that's keeping the house from being robbed.
It isn't the locking of the doors at all.
As anybody knows
an accomplished thief will go through any lock.
There is no lock made that will hold back an accomplished thief.
They'll go through the window.
You've got your doors locked.
Zip, zip, zip, they're in through the window.
Zip, zip, zip, they're through the ceiling.
They're through the roof.
They're through the wall.
Somebody wants in.
Let's not kid ourselves.
They're going to get in.
Even an amateur like myself.
Give me 20 minutes
and a trunk load of tools
and I'm going to be in that house.
It's the power of the thought.
The power of the belief.
It isn't the lock.
It's the power of the belief.
The willingness to undo its mistakes.
The willingness to be
forgiving and compassionate.
The realization through wisdom
that I make myself victim
when I place the source of happiness
outside myself.
And so what happens is
we begin to recontextualize our life.
We begin to say
what is it that gives my life meaning?
What is it that I really value?
What is it that if you removed
from my life
if you took away my job
and you took away my position
what meaning would my life have then?
What would it be worth?
What am I willing to die for?
And so some introspection
and spiritual movement is necessary
to achieve a state of well-being.
The feeling that one's life
is significant.
That we make a difference in the world.
We don't need the attention
that illness brings to us
because our sense of importance
comes about through the realization
and willingness of our real self.
And so general growth
in the whole field
of spiritual development
brings about a condition of health.
And it can do so quite rapidly.
To change your position
to let go a certain limiting belief
doesn't take very long at all.
First is the realization
that you have the power to do that.
And secondly
is the willingness to try it out.
To verify through your own experience.
It isn't necessary
to take the words of others.
The words of others are only an inspiration.
You have enough faith in them
to say, well, it sounds so
and I'm willing to give it a try.
And therefore in my own particular
personal experience
as well as clinical experience
I've seen illnesses go in a matter of
minutes, days, weeks, months
the most a chronic illness
that lasted for 25 years
perhaps took two years
but it was constantly doing the processes
that I've described today.
The willingness to accept the power of mind
the willingness to never allow the mind
to say something negative
without challenging it
and replacing it with a positive thought.
The willingness to let go
being judgmental towards ourselves and others
as a result of the letting go of the negative.
Why is this so?
This is so because
the energy field of that which you are
which gives us
an intense sense of aliveness
when we let go of the obstacles to it
is ever present.
What we call bliss
is the vibration of life itself.
We could call all that is
at the top of this chart
that which is God
that which is spirit
that which is one's higher power
what Krishnamurti calls what is
isness, beingness
the energy of that is the energy of life itself.
Constantly present, ever present.
Like the sun
it is always shining
but because of these clouds here
we don't experience it.
It is not necessary to program ourselves
with the truth.
It is only necessary to remove
that which is false.
The removal of the clouds from the sky
the elimination of the negative
allows one to experience
the energy fields
of that which is positive.
So it is only the removal of the negative
that is necessary.
The willingness to let go
of habits of negative thinking, etc.
The removal
of the obstacles
through the experiencing of this
will result in an increasing sense
of aliveness.
With it, a joy of one's own existence.
As this joy
of one's own existence comes in
first subtly and then stronger and stronger
there is a diminished
awareness even of the presence
of the body.
One's physicalness
as one gets up into higher levels of happiness
there is a joyfulness
the body is looked to as a source of pleasure
it is held as a pleasure
a pleasurable
enjoyable experience.
But as we move towards
the top of the box
the experiencing of the body
begins to diminish altogether.
There is a progressive experiencing
of joy which is diffuse.
There is an inner progressive
state of serenity accompanied by
a peaceful blissfulness.
And at this point
the experience of the body
may disappear altogether
into sort of a sublime
state in which one is
joyful
aliveness.
One is that which is
loving bliss.
At that point the awareness of the body
may be almost nil.
It's as though it's present in the room
but it's no more
important than anything else
in the room.
That loss of identification
with the body.
And we watch the body from that viewpoint
going about its business happily
but we are no more concerned
about it than we are
anything else in the room.
That loss of identification
with the separate limited self.
The loss of identification
with the limited physical.
And with it of course the body
is expressing the absolute truth
the infinite truth
that one is the infinite beingness
of the universe.
And therefore the value
of replacing a negative thought
into the empty
space of that
in the place that we just cancel
we place the statement
I am an infinite being and I am not
subject to that.
I am an infinite being and I am not subject to that.
So everything that we cancel
we replace with the truth.
In place of the negative thought
we put something in that's positive
because we choose to love
ourself instead.
So we can also use the form we can say
I cancel that. I no longer buy that.
I'm not subject to that.
Instead I choose to love myself.
And so we see that
lovingness then
is the great healer.
We have within our capacity
within the power within us
all the powers of self healing.
All we have to do is remove the obstacles.
Perfect health
is an expression then
of spiritual awareness.
The willingness to let go
of the negative
and allowing it to be replaced by that
which is loving.
So the physical expression then
is of this energy field.
Sickness is merely an expression
of this energy field
down here
given form by what is held in mind.
Physical health
is merely an expression
of a positive energy field
reinforced by our
willingness to commit
to compassion and forgiveness.
That which I am
includes the body
not limited to it.
That which I am chooses to love it
to value it
to be appreciative of it
to be grateful for it
to enjoy the sense of aliveness.
We get into
the joy of the experiencing
of experience.
We get more and more into the awareness
of the joy and the thankfulness
for our existence.
The existence of what?
The existence of our consciousness.
The body is then included
within the field of consciousness itself.
We come to the surprising thought
that the body
is within the mind.
Most people
having a limited belief system
will think that the mind
is somewhere up here.
Actually when you experience experience
if you try to localize it
you will see that it is everywhere.
When you experience a thought
it is being experienced everywhere.
The thought that it is occurring
somewhere in here
within your system
it is a thought about thought.
Inner experience will tell you
that the experience of a thought
the experience of the body
is occurring everywhere.
It is occurring in consciousness itself.
You understand that the body
is sitting in the chair
but where is that understanding
being experienced?
That understanding is being experienced
in no specific place.
It is happening within
your consciousness itself.
The health then is really
addressing ourselves
to the nature of consciousness.
The body then is coming out
of our sense of aliveness
which is coming out of our
sense of appreciation
for our own existence.
In this talk we have repeated
certain things over and over
because of the mind's resistance
to accepting the truth of it.
Right brain learning is really
one of becoming familiar
constantly re-exposing ourselves
until it becomes natural.
Why is it difficult when it comes
to healing and health?
It is because we are really reversing
the mind's belief in causality.
We are saying that the physical
is the expression of the mental
and not vice versa.
You see the world would like to say
and that it is the other way around
that cause is within the world.
Cause is within the powers
within the virus.
The power is within the bacteria.
Even medications work because
it is the belief in the power
of the medication.
We certainly see this with scientific research
into the nature of placebos.
Placebos alone will cure 35%
generally of people with any given ailment.
Just the suggestion
that this pill will heal it
35% of the time
is all that is sufficient.
Realizing then
that we are making a major move
in consciousness allows us
to value
all of our knowledge about
consciousness and health
to use it as a springboard
to our own spiritual growth and development.