I'm Dr. David R. Hawkins. I've been a physician for 35 years and a psychiatrist all those years.
I've worked in the fields of psychoanalysis and psychotherapy and group therapy.
I've done a lot of work with psychopharmacology. I've done research into the nature of
psychopharmacology and its relationship to brain chemistry. For years, I worked in the
field of nutrition and its relationship to brain chemistry. For 25 years, I've specialized in the
treatment of the addictions and serious mental disorders. I've been director of psychiatric
research at a very large hospital. I helped found a very large outpatient clinic that had 2,000
outpatients, and I had a very large private practice, a large hospital practice. I lived a
very establishment life, lived on a very large estate in the east, and had an apartment on Fifth
Avenue. And so I've lived a conventional and really quite successful life.
And many years ago, I became interested in studying spiritual dimensions. I became involved
in Zen, and so I spent many years also in spiritual research. And for the last 10 years,
I've been focusing on studying the nature of consciousness itself. Now, today's talk has to
do with death and dying, and we call it saying farewell to the body. Sound lighthearted? Well,
I think that by the end of this talk, you will perhaps view it in a more lighthearted way than
perhaps you've been accustomed. And in this talk, I'm not going to talk down to the audience. I'm
not trying to tailor it to what I expect the listener is going to be able to hear. Instead,
I'm just going to talk about what I've learned in all of my personal experience and clinical
research. I'm going to share with you experiences that I've had, and I'm going to share with you
experiences in a way that perhaps you haven't been shared with before. I've done this with other
audiences, and people have said, well, you can't talk about things like that. These audiences are
not that sophisticated. They're not going to get it, etc. On the contrary, I found that audiences
that people in the consciousness and spiritual were considered naive got it right away. They
didn't have the slightest problem. They all said, oh, yeah, we see it, of course. Everybody felt
higher. Everybody felt glad. No problem. And so I'm going to tell it to you today. I'm going to
tell you just how it really is and how I've experienced it and what has come into my own
awareness. And in doing so, I'm going to refer to a map of consciousness, a field of consciousness
that we have laid out in sort of a mathematical style. It's here on the blackboard, and although
it may look complicated at first when I explain it, you'll see that it's relatively simple.
Because when we're talking about death and dying, we're talking about consciousness.
This is what people really fear. What people really fear are two things.
One is the physical death experience itself, and the other is what they fantasy to be a loss of
awareness, a loss of consciousness, a loss of awareness of existence. By the time we get through
talking about these things, I hope we will have handled those things. And so we're going to refer
to this board, and on this board we have here what's called level of consciousness. This is
what we call the box. This is the human ego, the self with a small s.
What we commonly refer to as me or myself. And at the bottom you'll see we have these calibrated
with death, physical death at zero, and we have at the very top of the scale, enlightenment at 600.
And if we do that, we find in the middle there's a level called courage. And below courage,
the arrows of all these feeling states are in a negative direction. And they're calibrated as to
their relative energy.
And so they're relative power. So you'll see, for instance, that apathy has roughly half the power of
fear, which is calibrated at 100. Fear has roughly the power of courage at 200. Courage has much less
power than love, which is at 500. And so these have relative energies based on, as you can very well
see, these are lower states of consciousness. Guilt, you see, is reversed, and it's only 30.
Apathy,
fear, hopelessness is 50. Regret and grief is 75. Fear and its forms of worry and anxiety is 100.
Cravingness, wantingness, desiringness is 125. Anger goes up to 150. Pride goes up to 175.
And then by virtue of telling the truth, in this case it is the truth about life,
to tell the truth about life, that life comes from life, a very important statement. Sounds banal on
the surface.
But you'll see most of the fears of death are coming out of the failure to get, that life comes from
life.
And once we tell the truth about it, once we tell the truth about it, you'll see that the reverse,
the negative energy field goes neutral. It then begins to go to the right. It goes in a positive
direction. And as we move towards the source of life, the conscious awareness of the source of
life itself, we move into higher states of love and higher states of joy. And then we come up to a
level at about 600.
And at 600, there is a transition into a different paradigm, a different experience of existence, in which
one no longer identifies with a separate individual physical body. The person begins to realize the truth of
who they are. The expansion of consciousness goes beyond the individual small self. And so, to the right of
these levels of consciousness, we see an emotion that goes with it.
We see at the bottom with guilt goes self-hatred. And we see a process going on in consciousness that it is a
destructive direction. We see that apathy is associated with hopelessness and despair. And we see that the
process is loss of energy. We see that grief is associated with regret and loss and despondency. And the
process there is to become dispirited. We see that fear is associated with worry and anxiety.
We see that fear has to do with the future. So, in that, the process is one of deflation. What we are talking about then,
generally, when people think of death is guilt, and they think of grief, and they think of fear. They may even move up to a higher
state called anger, being angry about the whole experience and resent it, be full of hate and grievances about it. As we
move up the energy scale,
we come to a level called pride.
Calibrates at 175.
Pride feels a lot better than these lower states. But, unfortunately, with pride goes denial.
And then talking about death today, we're going to have to overcome some of this denial.
The denial is really coming up because of fear, once what is fear is understood, then denial drops out and one can move up and move up to the level of courage.
Courage,
you see,
energy field goes neutral now, it has a lot more power. The energy field of courage is enough to
settle the United States of America and create the huge industries and sciences. That's the energy
field that takes man to the moon. So it is the capacity then emotionally to face, to cope, to
handle. And once you begin to tell the truth about things, you become empowered. Empowered.
That moves you up to a state of willingness, the willingness to get what is the truth about this.
One thing that happens at this, you see, we've left the denial of the arrogance of pride because
pride is associated with arrogance, thinking I know when in reality you don't know, pretending to
know, coming from beliefs and opinions which are somebody else's thoughts that you have gathered
to yourself and now your ego has taken a position about and you feel you must defend those. To let
go of that arrogance, we can move up then to willingness. We say, yes, I want to know what is
the truth about the matter.
For my own sake. It becomes powerful because now your intention is put into the energy field. You
begin to move up to wanting to know more about a thing and the capacity to accept. You see, down
here you've given your power away. You've said, I don't have the capacity. I don't have the power. I
don't have the ability to get what this is all about. I have to rely on tradition and folklore
and all that kind of thing.
The willingness to look into the matter then gives you an open mind and the open mind then
moves you up to a state called acceptance, which means you've begun to reown your power. These
states from here to down here, you've given your power away. You've given your survival to
something outside of yourself. And as you reown that power, you begin to feel adequate and
confident. And there's the beginning in consciousness of transformation. The awareness
am the source of my own happiness,
that I have the capacity to find out the truth for myself.
And you move up to an energy field of 500 called lovingness.
Lovingness, that capacity, that dedication
to nurturing, supporting life,
the willingness to be forgiving.
And with that begins a certain revelation
about an energy field that we calibrated around 540.
540 is associated with healing,
healing with gratitude.
And you can move up to an energy field called joy.
Joy, and it calibrates here at about 540.
And inner serenity,
and what really characterizes it is compassion.
Compassion, the ability to see into the hearts of others,
the willingness to be love,
nonjudgmental to life itself
and all of its expressions.
At about 560, we come to an energy field,
which I didn't write on the board
because it's too crowded as it is,
called ecstasy.
Not a jumping up and down with,
these are not jumping up and down states,
not jumping up and down with joy,
not jumping up and down with ecstasy,
but an inner state as you're beginning
to approach the truth of existence,
an inner ecstatic state which is quiet
and gradually moves up to a state called peace,
the peace of God.
The emotion going with that is bliss,
and the person is really going into states of illumination.
And many people, as they go into this state,
feel as though a light is,
they're encompassed within a light,
that they are that light.
And then when we go up to 600,
the top of the box here is 600,
at that point, the identification with the personal self stops.
One goes into an ineffable state,
a state that is so exquisite it is difficult to describe.
And what happens with your relationship
at that point with the body?
What actually happens is you forget the body.
You just forget it.
You forget that it is, was, exists, or existed.
There is really no memory of the body anymore
because the body is associated with an identification
with the personal separate self.
That identification limited your consciousness
and your awareness to that identification
with the physical body,
and people then think,
well, how can I go on living in that body?
And as you reach more enlightened states,
as people really approach death,
people who have any preparation for it at all,
instead there is an exquisite expansion of consciousness,
a loss of identification with that body
and the personal self.
And then we go up into the energy fields above the 600s.
Those are states of feeling of oneness and completeness
and wholeness,
and oneness with all of life,
and oneness with God. These levels of consciousness are also associated, as you will see, with
they dominate your view of the world, your view of life, and they dominate your view
of God. And so we will say a little something about them. You will see that the guilty person
sees this as a world of sin and suffering, and therefore the God of that world would
be a destroyer. We see that the person who is coming from hopelessness, apathy, sees
this as a hopeless world and thinks that God must be dead. The person who is coming
from grief, feels neglected and forgotten by God, sees this as a sad world and feels
that God ignores you because you are such a worthless worm. The person who comes from
fear, then, sees this as a frightening world, and therefore God would be the most frightening
of all possible experiences. The person who is coming from craving and desiring sees this
as a frustrating world, and therefore the God of that world would be a destroyer.
The God of anger, I mean the person living out of anger, sees this as a competitive,
angry world of conflict and war. And consequently the God that would be expected from that level
of consciousness is a retaliatory God of revenge. The person in pride sees this world as a world
of status, and because of their arrogance, intellectual arrogance, may end up either
as atheist or bigot, the zealot, who feels that I am right and the world is wrong. All
of this leaves us in very difficult positions. As we move out of pride, we move up to a level
called courage. That is the capacity to face things for the first time. We see the direction
of the arrow went neutral, meaning that that which is negative, that which is a lie, all
of this down here is that which is not true, that the energy field is changing. And when
we do, our view of the world changes dramatically. From a negative view of the world, from a
negative experience of the world, we now see this as a challenging world of excitement
and opportunity. By the time we get through talking about death, we will be at least up
to this. That is the most exciting opportunity you have had thus far.
It is characterized this state then by an open mind. It means I don't really know. Open
mind says question mark.
says for the first time what is the truth please lord let me open my mind and know what is the
truth for my own self know within my own consciousness to know where i know things
we move above neutral then i mean we move out of courage we move up to a level called neutral
here you see the error goes positive our energy field has jumped to 250 and what characterizes
that is detached unattached the person now experiences that they are released released
from all this negativity down here a person at this level sees the world as okay would see all
experiences that would include death as okay and experiences god therefore as freedom you see the
loss of fear of god the loss of guilt the loss of expecting god to be the great avenger and
the person will become generate that thing again and do it with all that from the head the PlayStation
person coming out of jealousy and hate. The god of hatred is down here who hates man and hates
man's humanness. All a paradox in as much as God created us. Anyway, we move up then to what is the
truth, the willingness to look at what is the truth. And here, because of our open mind, our
willingness now to investigate what is the truth of it, we begin to experience life as friendly,
life and the world and all the experiences in the world, including the death experience,
we now expect it to be some kind of a positive experience. And God now becomes promising and
hopeful. It's like we look forward to death as some kind of a great release into a much greater
expansion in consciousness and awareness. As we move out of acceptance, which we do by owning
back our own power to know, we move into a loving state, that which is forgiving,
that which is a strength.
We move back to a loving state where we are one and the same and the result of that recovery is
which is understanding, the beginning of revelation, and now we begin to experience all of life
in a loving way.
We begin to see the love that's present everywhere.
And therefore we move into a God that is merciful, and out of mercy we see unconditional love.
We now expect a God who is unconditionally loving, God and all His representatives, all
His representatives.
The realization of the lovingness that that is the basic reality moves you to an inner
state of joy.
Out of that comes compassion, the transfiguration of consciousness.
We begin to see the perfection of all of creation, the incredible beauty.
We see the oneness of all of life.
And as we move towards the top of the box we move into states which we call bliss.
States of enlightenment.
In
illumination in which we then become conscious and aware of that unity that oneness that beingness
at that point as we said you move out of the ordinary energy fuels of ordinary consciousness
and you move up into energy fuels which we calibrate in the 600s and something there
strange happens there this is a point where many people have amnesia
because they're so habituated to thinking of themselves as an individual physical body that
anything other than that is relegated to amnesia and but as you go beyond that as you go into states
of that the world calls enlightenment which is just really another paradigm another way of
experiencing existence and life at about 615 or so there's the capacity to remember the death
experience to know what it is
to recall all the times that it occurred with a conscious awareness and as we go up to states that
are higher than that in the mid 600s and all we reach more advanced states of awareness and
consciousness and so i'm going to share with you today things that i've learned clinically over
that many years of experience things that i personally experienced myself and we'll talk now
from having a field of reference about what the
death experience really entails and so and going back then i'll be going back to childhood in my
own experience and so i'll start telling you about some things that happened in my life
and then how it fit in with things that happened later on when i was about 14 i was a paper boy in
northern wisconsin and it was about 20 below zero in a weather and the weather was about 20 below
zero and i was practically freezing to death so i mean literally and i what i did was i went to a
school in northern wisconsin and i went to a school in northern wisconsin and i went to a snow bank
and i crawled inside of this cubby hole that i dug and the snow was piled about 20 feet high on the
side of the highways there and i crawled into this little cubby hole and cuddled up in order just to
get out of the wind which was really fierce and terrible and within a few seconds i began to
experience a state of relaxation a state of profound warmth began to overcome me and my body
the body, the state of almost exquisite pleasure. I began to forget about the body. The body just
didn't seem to exist anymore. And instead this incredible state overcame me. It was like
surrounded by light, but the light had a quality of touching you and being with you as though it
was a loving consciousness that was enveloping you and dissolving so that you dissolved and
became this infinite field that had no beginning and no end. It had no dimension. It was outside
of time. The experience could have lasted for seconds or eons in earth time. It made no difference
because once having experienced it, the experience was total. At every instant the experience was
total and complete.
There was nothing missing, nothing lacking, nothing further to be accomplished. And there
was a profound state of peace that is beyond description. At first as it came on there was
this inner feeling of relief, an inner feeling of relief, and then an inner feeling of a quiet joy,
and then the inner feeling of a quiet ecstasy, and then it went beyond ecstasy. It went beyond bliss.
It became an infinite state which
is not within ordinary consciousness. Sometime later, it could have been 15 minutes, half an hour,
I felt someone shaking me and I was like forcibly pulled out of this state. My father was shaking
me and he had a very upset, anxious look on his face. And he said, don't you ever do that again,
don't you know you can freeze to death? I had no context in which to hold this experience,
what its meaning was. It had just been
a profound experience and in the mind of a child there was really nothing to say about it. I might
have mentioned something to it as I think it did perhaps mention something about it to my father,
but he didn't have any way in which to hold it either and besides he was frightened at the time
and so neither of us knew what the experience meant. Neither of us realized what was being
signified. At that time there were no books on the near-death experiences. The movie Resurrection
has only come out in the last 10 years. That movie Resurrection, by the way, was clinically accurate.
Those who have had that kind of experience all verify the truth of what she experienced. You
know, she got killed in an automobile accident. It's a true story of an actual person who was
declared dead on the operating table and she left the body, she experienced the death of her husband,
she experienced that same incredible infinite state. My father and I not knowing of these things
had no context in which to hold this experience, no way of understanding it and so although I
mentioned it briefly to him, he didn't know what to make of it either and besides he was
too frightened at the time and so the experience was never mentioned again and neither did I ever
understand it over the coming years until I got older.
Then I was dying of a very serious and progressive ailment back in my 30s and as I was laying in this
bed in a very moribund condition and in a grave state, I will tell you, all of a sudden, much to
my surprise, there I was about 10 feet over the body, about 8 feet over the physical body. There
I was in a perfect body exactly like this one. It looked exactly the same except that it seemed to
be weightless.
Practically weightless. In fact, it was weightless and I had all my faculties. I could think and
reason and see and hear and I looked down at the physical body that was lying in the bed about 8 or
10 feet below me and you know, he looked like he was about to go and here I was outside the physical
body looking down at it, you see, aware that that which I am is something other than the physical
body. At that time, I'd never heard of out-of-body experiences and it's only in the last five or
10 years that a lot of books, well, there are classics written and almost in Victorian times,
but they were known only to a very limited number of people. But now, there's all kinds of bodies
and surveys now show that something like 65% of the population has had these, consciously
remembers these kind of experiences. And so therefore, what I'm saying today is, you know,
not shocking like it would have been perhaps years ago. But there I was in a grave illness and I found
myself totally out of the body and it was not time for me to leave and so at a later point, I had to
re-enter the body again. Later on, I learned that this was a technique that one could do this at
will. I learned that there's all kinds of people who leave the body at will. There's people who
are born with this gift and there are people who are very right-brained and they sit down to
meditate and as soon as they sit down to meditate, they have this experience. Well, I was a left-brain
scientist, a skeptic, a pragmatist and I became very curious about this phenomena and so I found
that there was a scientifically oriented place that where this is being studied. And so I read
the book out of, you know, Journeys Out of the Body by Robert Monroe and I went to the Monroe
Institute and there I did a 10-day training, 10-day training where they have audio tapes
and the frequency, the difference of the frequency between the two ears creates
a frequency that entrains the brain and within that certain altered state of consciousness,
one can leave the body at will. So I learned that this is a state then that people who aren't born
with this capacity or who don't develop it spontaneously can later learn to do at will.
The purpose of that was merely my own learning that you are something other than the body,
that that which you are is greater than the physical body, that the physical body belongs
to you but that you are not that. So I recovered from that particular episode of the illness and
continued to live and the illness, however, relapsed and it got worse again. This time it
was grave indeed and I was really right at the very door of death itself. I was in a state of
grave, almost a state of hell, a state of absolute and total helplessness, hopelessness, despair,
self-hatred.
I was in a state of complete malice till the bottom of the box and about a couple of them,
really just a few seconds away from what would really be leaving the body again,
I asked, I was an Atheist at the time and had been an Atheist for some twenty years. Despite
these experiences of an infinite beingness, I still in the face of it, you see the character
of pride is arrogance and denial see, denial and arrogance. Despite having had these incredible
experiences, I was something other than hell-like.
than the body, I still didn't have a way in which to hold it. And I was still an
atheist, and here I was dying of this disease, and really in the last few
minutes, and when I suddenly said, you know, if there is a God, I asked him to
help me. And then I went unconscious. I don't remember a thing. And when I became
conscious again, there I was out, you might say, outside the box. I'd gone up to
a field of consciousness, which is up here off the blackboard. And there was no
longer any identification with this personal physical body. It walked around
and it did all the things it's supposed to. But I stood in an energy field that
was so infinite. The power and the dimension of the field was beyond
description. It held me in absolute safety. It was like rock. It was
is at the same time exquisitely soft and gentle.
Its exquisite gentleness and its exquisite softness
held me in its infinite embrace,
and it spoke through me.
The body just did what the infinite will,
how it expressed itself through this personal,
or what was still left of the personal self.
And so I walked around in that state for some months,
for some months, and I still didn't really have a context
in which to hold it.
There was nothing much you could say about it.
I think the only way I expressed it to someone in my life at that time,
I said, when I was at the bottom of the box,
I was like an absolute blackness, totally cut off from God.
And now it's like that which stood between me and God has been removed,
and I'm now standing in that infinite presence.
During that time, I was doing,
in some rather intensive spiritual work,
and really getting involved in the study of the nature of consciousness itself.
And I started having spontaneous recall of previous lives.
And I can remember all my life I couldn't really dance.
You know, it was a terrible ordeal.
And I would, you know, as a kid I took dancing lessons and all that,
but I was terribly awkward and self-conscious.
It was painful.
And as I got older, I really didn't like it.
I didn't like to dance and would avoid the whole experience if possible,
except for a slow waltz or a slow foxtrot.
But slow waltzes and slow foxtrots were no longer in the mid to late 70s.
And one time I was dancing with someone and she said to me,
you know, forget about your feet, you know, and just do what my body's doing.
And all of a sudden, in one instant, I could dance.
Not only could I dance, but I had like unlimited energy to dance.
I went out every night dancing.
I could dance and close up the discos at 2, 3, 4 in the morning,
get up at 7 and go to work all day, and I could dance every night.
It was like an unleashed.
It's like I wanted to dance for a thousand lifetimes,
and finally I could dance again.
Actually, that's what really had happened.
I had really condemned myself to no joy for an infinite number of lifetimes
due to a terrible mistake I had made in one of them.
Well, while I was dancing one time, all of a sudden,
the memory of a previous lifetime as a dancer came back to me.
I won't say how long ago it was because it'll stretch my credibility,
but it was a long, long time ago.
But I spontaneously remembered that whole lifetime.
I remembered being an incredible dancer.
And as I danced, I went into a state of high ecstasy.
I went out the top of the box.
And suddenly everything was suffused with life, with light, with life.
I couldn't breathe.
I felt this incredible joy.
And I remembered exactly what had gone on.
In fact, I was a sacred temple dancer,
and there were certain inner secrets about this style of dancing
that were part of the sacredness of that spiritual tradition.
And as I went back into that and remembered that lifetime,
the instructions came back to me.
The exact instructions, I remembered them.
And as I remembered the instructions, I began to do them.
And the dancing was so much fun.
And the dancing now became effortless.
There is a certain trick and inner style of dancing
in which the body becomes weightless.
And the body seemed to rotate around an invisible center.
And the more you dance, the more energy you have.
So at the end of four or five hours of dancing,
I was higher and had more energy than when I had started.
So here was a spontaneous recall of a lifetime.
And then I became interested in it as a subject,
and of course there are many books and hypnotic techniques
and age regression techniques.
And I learned a very simple one of self-hypnosis
where you simply put yourself down, count from one to ten,
and then you ask to go back,
and you can picture yourself in an elevator
and punch a certain button.
And when you get out, all of a sudden you can re-experience these lifetimes.
And there, one time I did that,
and I was caught in a...
I was caught in a dilemma about a major decision in life.
And I was very hung up on letting go of a certain piece of property
and various things.
And someone had told me, you know,
that if you look back in some previous lifetimes,
you would find why you are so hung up.
And well, I did.
And suddenly I found myself in another body,
somewhere back in time,
I would guess around in the 1600s, 1500s.
Anyway, I found myself, I looked down,
and here I had another body.
I had huge biceps
and a very muscular,
and I had a leather apron on.
And in my hand was a big hammer,
and I realized that I was a blacksmith.
And funny, because in this big house I had built in the East,
I was at the very time
researching 16th century blacksmithing shops,
and I was about to make a huge bellows
and do my own blacksmithing in the house,
curiously enough.
But I developed vibration disease,
and so I couldn't, in my fingertips,
and I couldn't do the hammering,
and so I was figuring out an electromagnetic hammer,
so that I could do blacksmithing, in other words,
without actually having to hit it with a hammer.
So anyway, I found myself in this body,
and there was a portcachere in the house,
a place where you could drive through with a car.
Well, in the reliving of this experience
from a previous lifetime,
this was not gravel,
I mean, this was not cement, but gravel.
And I heard the hooves of some oncoming horses,
and these four horses with a coach suddenly wheeled,
came through the portcachere,
and apparently the lead horse had thrown a shoe,
and the reason they were coming there
was for me to reshoe the horse.
But instead of stopping, the horses began to gait,
and the front horse went up,
and he came down, and just as he came down
to crush my chest, blank, went out of body.
Didn't experience anything.
That's curious, I thought.
It's just like I became space.
And so I became curious now,
and I went back into a lot of lifetimes,
and a lot of the ways, you know,
at the very end it was not so pleasant, you know.
Starving to death or dying of thirst or something.
Captured, I mean, I really had some adventurous lifetimes.
But all was right at the end,
it would suddenly go blank.
And suddenly it dawned on me,
you know, you never experience your own physical death.
You never experience it.
Just as the bullet that's going to be the one that kills you
gets to the heart,
think, out you go.
And then, of course,
there was the recall of lots of friends of mine.
A friend of mine remembers being in the Civil War, you know,
and he was on the side, I think, of the South, right.
And they're charging with their bayonets,
and all of a sudden he's hit by a couple of musket balls,
and he goes right on charging.
And he wonders as he's charging,
you know, how he can be charging
after being hit in the chest with the three musket balls.
And he's charging right ahead,
only nobody seemed to be paying any attention to him.
And he looks back,
and there's his body laying on the ground,
and he realizes he's left it.
That's why nobody's paying any attention to him,
because they don't see him.
And in that lifetime,
he landed in a hospital
where he was nursed by someone that he fell in love with.
He didn't die.
He came back in the body,
found himself in a hospital,
and this lovely nurse,
and he were attracted to each other,
but he had other commitments
and couldn't be with her in that lifetime.
And curiously enough,
he rejoined her
and married her in this lifetime.
At about that time in my life,
I was studying a certain breathing technique,
which although I don't advise it,
I was researching it at the time.
And in this experience,
as one would pass a certain point,
suddenly there was that,
not suddenly, but gently and softly,
there was that same experience
of suddenly leaving the body
and no longer experiencing the body,
and repeatedly I would go back
into the same experience which I had
when I was 14 in the snowbank.
The re-experiencing,
the forgetting about the body,
and as you leave the body,
you forget everything that went with it.
You know, within a couple of seconds,
there's no memory of all that
what went with that lifetime.
You don't remember whether you were married or not married.
You have no idea what you did
or what your name was.
All of that becomes ridiculous.
It all becomes irrelevant.
It has no bearing in mind.
It has no meaning and no significance
and no reality.
And instead you begin to experience
that which is.
And that same experience
of that incredible peace,
that incredible lovingness,
outside of time and outside of space,
just pure consciousness and pure awareness,
just exquisitely aware of existence,
of the existence of an infinite being
that one is at one with.
And this experience, I remember one time,
I had a coach.
You know, there was a coach for this experience,
a rebirther.
And he was actually a friend of mine
and I loved him dearly.
And I was in this infinite state
and I stopped breathing.
I just didn't want to come back in the body.
I'd forgotten the body was there.
And so he would say to me,
Breathe.
But I didn't want to breathe.
I didn't need to breathe.
There was no desire to breathe
because where I was
was so exquisite,
so beyond anything this world has to offer,
that I really had no desire at all to breathe.
And then I heard the incessant appeal in his voice,
Please breathe.
And suddenly I realized, you know,
his presence and my love for him.
And therefore out of my love for him,
I breathed again.
But there I was back in the same experience,
repeatable over and over again,
just as it has been described
by many thousands of people,
you know, throughout man's history,
but now so available in the literature.
That same experience of
not remembering what you have
or what you did, but what you are.
And so that takes us back then to the board.
You see?
That at the beginning, you know,
at the very, not the beginning, excuse me,
but at the bottom of the box,
there is the great concern with havingness.
And status is based on what you have.
And then as you move up into the box,
up into the more powerful centers of courage
and capacity and capability,
there is a great concern with what you do.
And as you move towards the top of the box,
there is only the awareness
and the value of that which you are.
Nobody cares what you have anymore.
Nobody cares what you do.
And so I discovered that when you leave the body,
what you take with you is what you are.
What you experience is that
which you've been willing to know
and to own about yourself.
The truth about yourself, that which you are,
is what you experience.
So all what you had is forgotten.
There is no memory of money, possessions, power, houses.
All that you did is forgotten.
In that state, if you ask a person, you know,
what did you do when you thought you were a body
and moved around in the world,
there'd be no recall.
Nowhere is what you did.
But that which you are is overwhelming.
That which is is overwhelming.
About the same time,
my mother and I were not too connected about that time
because she lived in Florida and I was up in New York.
And I didn't get a chance to visit her very often.
And we had a difference of opinion about a few things.
And so therefore, we weren't like, you know, emotionally close.
You might say we were psychically close,
but not emotionally close.
And one day I was out in the woods
and all of a sudden I got an intuitive knowing
that I'd better run down to Florida.
I got that my mother was dying.
I got like a call, come down, like right away.
So I went back in the house and I called up
and I made a plane reservation for the next morning
or the first one out I could get,
maybe the same night, I forget.
And after I made the plane reservation,
I called up and I was told that she was in the hospital.
You know, but I knew that she was leaving anyway.
So when I got down to Florida,
you know, the heart of Florida, Lakeland,
Lakeland Hospital,
as I got down there,
I got a tremendous feeling of relief from my mother.
I suddenly felt a great tension relief.
And as I walked into the room,
the room was crowded with hospital personnel, you know.
There was a big-name specialist from New York
and this little hospital was going to make sure
that nothing went wrong, that everything was covered.
So the whole staff was practically there.
And there was my mother in an oxygen tank
and all kinds of tubes sticking in her all over the place.
And all kinds of meters and electronic things
to make her heart go and all.
And all of a sudden, you know,
I didn't even get into the room.
They didn't even know who I was yet.
And I entered the room
and I knew that she just left the body.
And I experienced a state of absolute ecstasy.
As she left the body,
she was so glad to get out of there.
It was like an infinite state of joy and ecstasy.
And I was like one with her in this experience.
I felt exactly what she was feeling.
And she was,
she'd waited to leave the body until I got there.
And she like joined me.
Both of our wills joined to know the experience.
She wanted me to experience the experience with her.
And so I experienced that ever-expanding infinite state of ecstasy.
She went into a state of absolute ecstasy.
Nobody was ever happy to get out of that body than my mother.
I mean, for years she was hoping to get out of that body.
When she finally got out, boy, was she happy.
And of course the hospital personnel didn't even know she'd died yet.
So telepathically I sent to the cardiologist,
you know, she's dead.
You can turn the machine off.
So he suddenly got the idea himself and he said,
turn off the machine.
So he turned off the machine
that was creating the heartbeat and all that.
And he put the stethoscope to her chest
and he said, she's dead.
Oh.
So, and then the hospital staff looked at me
as though they expected me to go into unhappiness or something
and I didn't.
You know?
I was in a state of ecstasy.
I was in the same state my mother was.
I was with her.
What was there to grieve about?
My mother was never happier in her life.
And one woman in the, one woman, she was a nurse's assistant,
got it, an LPN.
And she looked at me and she broke into a big grin.
She said, boy, was she ever happy.
And I said, you got it.
She sure was.
So the two of us grinned at each other,
knowing exactly what was going on, you know.
And nobody else really got it.
They probably thought I didn't love my mother, you know,
and was glad to see her go
or I was going to inherit a lot of money or something.
And God knows what their minds thought about it.
But we knew what was happening
and it brought us into that state of joy.
So my own experiences, my own memories, my own recall then
was of leaving the body
and then there seemed to be two different experiences.
The one that my mother experienced
and which I had experienced so many times
of infinite lovingness.
And then there had been those experiences
of going out of body and experiencing nothing.
Well, either way, you don't experience your physical death.
But in the nothing experience,
the next recall would be
I would be back in the body of some other little person,
some other little child.
In this lifetime, it happened at age three.
Suddenly it's like wham, you land in the body
and suddenly anybody who looks back at early childhood
will remember that moment when you suddenly realize
that you are, I am, I exist.
And then I realized that I had a belief system going
for many years, for many lifetimes.
In those lifetimes then,
because I was holding that in mind,
that's what I experienced.
We said that what you hold in mind,
what you hold in mind is what you experience in the world
and that's what you experience that God is.
So the idea that after death there is nothing
and many people hold that in mind,
what happens is you go out of body
and you experience yourself as infinite space.
Next thing you know, there's another body again.
But I had more often that experience
of the infinite presence,
the infinite, almost angelic experience.
And as I was looking at that one day,
came back the memories then
of being on the other side
and being with those who were dying.
It came back first as an experience on battlefields.
And I remember being with the dying person
and I remember looking at their agony
and their fear and their physical pain
and suddenly this infinite lovingness,
which I was,
and at that point formless because,
as I said, in these states of infinite lovingness,
there is no physical body.
This infinite state of being with the person dying
and then before my very eyes
they would become transformed.
They would like leave the physical body there
and all the wounds would heal.
And it was my love,
my love joined with the love of God.
It was as though I'd turned the heart over to God
and now the energy field of those like angelic beings
who are absolute love poured through.
But my consciousness was there
with this dying person.
And the exquisite love
of that energy then,
it like healed all the wounds
and the fear.
You would see the fear
and the person's eyes would open again
and they would look at you
and you could see they were just melting
with the experience.
All the terror dissolved,
all the fear, all the guilt,
all the feeling of being separated.
And they would look at you with a recognition.
And then I saw that they would see
that which to them was significant or divine.
That I myself was formless.
The same experience has happened in this lifetime.
When you go into higher states of consciousness
where you are no longer the physical body
and you see that people see
and they see what they are projecting there.
And so being without form,
actually without any form,
the dying person then like opening their eyes
seeing you as that which would
be most significant to them.
Sometimes you were seen as
the mother or a lover
or a crowd of people
with whom the person was dearly in love.
Sometimes they would see a divine figure.
But this was happening within the phenomena of mind itself.
It was all the phenomena of mind.
The person was experiencing
that which was the most healing
to them.
And so we come upon a way
of overcoming the fear of death.
See?
Overcoming the fear of death
is the willingness to be that
to yourself and to others who are dying.
The way to overcome your own fear of death
is to picture yourself as on the other side.
Like a first aid receiving station.
And you open your heart and you ask
to be connected with those angelic forces.
To become one with them.
And now you picture yourself
going to those who are dying.
You do it now while you are still
in your own physical body.
But you send forth that energy of compassion.
You see?
Consciousness doesn't know about bodies.
Bodies have to do with the ego,
a limited viewpoint.
You send forth this energy field of compassion.
And you picture yourself in your imagination.
You begin it with your imagination now.
With any person because
in any one hour
there are over 5 billion people on the planet.
How many people do you think are dying every hour?
Thousands and thousands.
By the time we finish this talk
easily 15 or 20 thousand people have died.
And what you do is you select somebody
that you feel you could be most loving.
A child in a crib.
A teenage child just hit by a car.
Somebody on a battlefield riddled with bullets.
A mother in childbirth.
A person committing suicide.
Picture the person for whom you have the most compassion
and start with them.
And send yourself forth in your imagination to that person.
And now picture yourself as infinitely loving.
Now in a way you are more alone
and yet more not alone than ever before.
Because you can fully express
all the tenderness and love
that you have suppressed your whole lifetime.
Now is your chance to send it forth
and to be with that person.
And think of the agony and the fear
of so many people.
And what you do is you go to them
and you begin to heal them.
Picture yourself holding them in your arms.
And now the love pours forth through your heart.
It really comes from a higher being
and radiates out through your heart.
It suffuses that person
and you begin to see their fear melt away.
And many people as they die
whatever the apprehension was before
you will notice go into profound states
of serenity.
As though that compassion
coming from the great beings of the world
reaches forth to us
at our moment of greatest need.
And so when the person says
Oh God help me
because this is a world
a universe of free will.
Then they open the door to this compassion
which is being radiated forth by others
and now by you.
And so you are by their side
and in every way possible
you nurture them
and heal them.
You reach out to them
and gently lift them out of their body.
That they are safe.
They are home.
They are cared for.
They are greatly loved by God.
They begin to get the inner experience
of this truth.
You put your personal self aside
because your personal self is not needed here.
There is no need for your personality
with its likes and its dislikes
its aversions and its attractions.
Just be that individual
with the energy which flows forth through the heart.
And what happens is that healing energy now
through your willingness
flows through you
and into the being of the other person.
And you see the transformation before your very eyes.
You literally see it.
You see the fear leave their eyes.
You see the painful tension leave their body.
And you begin to experience
that the pain is leaving their body.
And they go into that same state of infinite peace.
Surrounded by this light.
Surrounded by this love.
Feeling complete and total and healed.
No more fear.
No more separation.
No more guilt.
No more anxiety.
And what happens is the two of you together
are lifted.
Lifted.
The two of you right out of the body.
Together.
I had this very same experience not long ago.
A few months ago.
When I suddenly, accidentally with a saw
chopped off this thumb.
And at first I heard
first there was shock.
But in this shock there was suddenly like a chorus in my mind.
As though I was surrounded
by angelic forces.
And they kept chanting to me
as though I'd forgotten.
You're not a body.
You're totally free.
And this chant kept going all the way to the hospital.
And in the hospital because of various things
I had to have you know an operation now.
And I cannot take any kind of anesthetic or analgesic.
So it had to be done without anesthesia
or without analgesia.
And the surgeon was a little apprehensive about this.
And I told him well I know a way of
handling this.
You just go right ahead.
So
I lay back and friends of mine
and people very close to me were praying for me.
And they had gathered around and
I lay back and I began to just surrender.
See?
All of this is surrender is it not?
The surrender of the personal will
and the asking of God to reveal to you
the truth of that which is.
And as I surrendered
then I had that same profound experience.
As though I was picked up by angelic forces.
Lifted so softly that feathers would seem rough by comparison.
Lifted gently although the body was there
it was like I no longer experienced it.
Instead I went into a state of infinite and profound peace
beyond all description.
An infinite inner joy and happiness
that cannot be described.
And I remember in my mind
I was looking at the thumb
or some representation of that thumb on a different plane
and I felt happy at it being removed
because it symbolized something I wished to be rid of.
Because of the spiritual symbology of it.
And so what could have been an excruciating painful experience
instead was ecstatic.
Not that jumping up and down kind of ecstasy
but an exquisite knowingness
surrounded by infinite peace
infinitely protected by the love of the universe
infinitely protected by God
and the representation of God in my inner experience.
And so now when we look at
what is the dying experience we see?
It's a surrender and it's a letting go.
It's a willingness to open one's heart
to be love to others.
If you're contemplating dying
and if you're doing the things I'm talking about
if in the morning when you get up
you say to God
to those who are dying I send my consciousness
I send my love
my willingness to be one with them
it's like the forces of the universe
then use the power of your consciousness
and literally carry it to the extreme.
It's a great person.
At first it will seem to you like imagination
it will seem like something that you are doing
but after you do this a few times
you realize you will suddenly experience
that you are not doing this anymore
that you're saying yes to it
it is now being done through you.
Because it is being done through you
you yourself go into a state of high joy and ecstasy.
The fact that what the world calls your physical body is leaving
no longer is even important.
And I've been in those states
where I literally felt the energy coming through
and going to people who were in automobile accidents
here in Arizona.
I'm going down I-17
and I feel this profound energy go through me
and it like goes through the heart
and this profound sense of loving power
which bypassed my personal self
and it went down the highway about a mile or so.
And as I got around the bend in the highway
I wondered where this energy was going.
Here was a car upside down
it had just crashed
and its wheels in fact were still spinning.
And inside were people severely injured
and I heard them praying out to God.
It's as though you were a traveling antenna
and God used you as an antenna tower
to radiate this energy.
And curiously enough that same day
about five miles down the highway
it began to happen again.
That same powerful energy came through me.
It's happened over and over again
on the streets of Chicago
and all over the world.
But as I'm driving down I-17
it started again.
And this time it also went down the road ahead of me
and when I came around the bend
there was a second accident.
Another car had just turned over.
This time there was a squad car there.
And as I went past
this energy kept flowing backwards now
to the site of the accident
and it continued on for some miles.
And then it slowly came to a stop
as though the person had now connected
with a more infinite energy field.
And what was my inner state?
What was my feeling about myself and my body?
I forgot that I had a body.
Whether it was living or dying was so irrelevant.
Why?
Because the joy of this experience is overwhelming.
The willingness to be that to others then.
The forgetting about the personal self.
Allow your consciousness and your energy
to be used by those angels.
By those angelic forces.
You see our infinite self is everything.
It's connected with the angelic realms.
We own that angelic condition within us.
That we ourselves have the capacity to join
by our willingness, by our saying yes
to allow ourselves to surrender
to their energy to go to the dead and the dying.
And now we see that there is no such thing
as death or dying.
You see?
And that's why we talked about letting go of the body
and saying farewell to it.
Because life goes to life.
Life never stops.
If it leaves this body you barely notice it
because you're so busy being with others
that you hardly notice that the physical body
that the planet said belonged to it
doesn't even exist anymore.
There's stories of yogis who've been back and forth
on the planet in three different bodies
and never even noticed it.
Beyond the experience of the physical body
an experience which is so difficult to describe
because tears are part of the body.
Are part of the experience of the memory.
It's exquisite beauty.
And so what we prepare ourself then
is for an experience of exquisite beauty.
Because it is the most beautiful of all experiences.