i'm dr dave hawkins i'm a psychiatrist i've been a physician for 35 years i've specialized in the
treatment of addictions for about 30 years i've worked in the fields of psychoanalysis
individual and group psychotherapy and i did a lot of work on the relationship between diet
and nutrition and its relationship to brain chemistry and how these relate to alcoholism
and the brain function and together with bill wilson who was the co-founder of alcoholics
anonymous and in the late 60s early 70s we published some work communication to aaa's
physicians which summarized the work we've done on the relationship between blood sugar and alcoholism
and brain function since in 1979 i've been doing research into the nature of consciousness itself
consciousness
and how it relates to self-healing and understanding of energy fuels and the parts
that they play in consciousness and various disorders including alcoholism and drug addiction
and a lot for the last couple of years i've been giving lectures here in sedona the sedona villa
in which i've been sharing some of the results of our research and so today's talk is going to
be somewhat unique i'm going to share with you things results of our research our understanding
of the nature of drugs and alcohol and addiction and the relationship to heavy metal rock
that sounds like an interesting connection what is the connection between these things
it has to do with energy fields and an understanding of what goes on within
the body's energy and so today we're going to be talking about consciousness and we're going to
create a context in which to understand what is the destructive effect of drug how can we explain
I mean, how can we explain somebody like today's People magazine, which I just picked up on the way here this morning, Confessions of a Coke Addict by David Crosby. What does he say? He says there are four ways it can go. You can go crazy, you can go to prison, you can die, or you can kick all the else's balls.
What is the basis of that? Why is this? What is the effect? And so we'll be looking at today's Time magazine, which features a rock group on the front. We'll be looking at a current heavy metal hall of fame, 87.
We'll be looking at just a cassette album cover. And we'll be talking about kinesiology. And we'll play some of this music. And we'll see what the effect is on energy fields.
And when we get through time, we'll see what happens.
And when we're talking today, you'll have a whole different way of understanding this whole phenomenon. It's going to be unique. It's not going to be something you can read anywhere. It's something that is known and has been known for some time by a small group of people.
But they haven't been able to really say anything about it because there hasn't been a context, a way to get it across to people who don't have a basic understanding. And so today we'll create the basic understanding, and then we'll reveal what we've discovered.
And you can see for yourself what the connection is. I myself recovered some 22 and a half years ago from alcoholism and drugs. I got into being a physician. Of course, I had them all available to me. Every kind of an upper and a downer and every kind of a combination and permutation. All kinds of pills, ups and downs, and alcohol. And they seem to work together. You know, one sort of a tension.
The other. People who have been into drugs, when they turn to alcohol, they say, okay, drugs are illegal. So I'll join the establishment and drink, you know. What happens is they become very rapidly addicted, extremely rapidly, sometimes in a matter of months. And they're now in the same or worse trouble than they were with drugs. Why is that? And it works in reverse. People who get into trouble with alcohol will say, well, you know, I'm having trouble with alcohol, so I'll just smoke some marijuana and do some things that are, you know, not alcohol.
And the next thing you know, they're badly hooked into drugs. What is the explanation for this phenomenon? You know, so far, what the world understands about it is that this is an effect of the drug itself. But that is not the whole story at all. And by the time we get through talking today, I hope you'll have a much better grasp of the whole situation.
I'm never going to tell anybody not to use alcohol or drugs. I've never have in all my many years.
And of course, I'm not going to tell anybody not to use alcohol or drugs.
i've spoken all over the united states and to large varieties of groups i never tell anybody
not to use alcohol and drugs i just explained what the phenomena is what my experience was
and people make up their own mind and so today we're going to be talking about we're going to
be referring to a map of consciousness and we've done other talks on the same subject in the 12
office visits which i've done for the same publisher and we did a one-hour talk on the
nature of alcoholism and drugs and with also the same publisher we have a four-hour workshop in
which i go into this whole thing extensively which i did at the first national conference
on consciousness and addiction but today we're not going to repeat the same material we're going to
recapitulate briefly our map of consciousness to create a context but we're going to talk about
things that we didn't
talk about in those previous talks and so before we go further we are going to refer to this map
of consciousness this is one we've referred to in the other talks and what we do we say
this is the box see this is a box it's referred to in all these talks as the box
box and this is really a map of consciousness in it we have the various levels of consciousness
and what is very important for today's talk is to realize that each of these
levels of consciousness they go from the lowest to the highest you see starting with death at zero
and enlightenment at 600 we come down joy at 540 five love comes out of 500
acceptance 380 neutral 250 a critical level of all courage at 200 and we come down through pride
anger desire fear grief apathy and guilt these are levels of consciousness but the important thing is
that each of these levels of consciousness has a direction of its
energy field all those below courage courage is a level we arrive at by
telling the truth all the levels below courage have an energy field which goes
to the left it's very important to understand what the effect of such an
energy field is above the level of courage all those energy fields go to
the right that which goes to the left is destructive it does not support life it
is unloving those above neutral which go to the right are those which support
life which are in their essence loving so those that go to the left are
destructive those that go to the right are constructive now this is generally
true in nature so that our work correlates and the deal that came out of
the study of geomancy which is the study of energy fields in nature it's a very
ancient science and art in China and all the
cathedrals in England are laid out according to the ley lines in
sophisticated cultures nobody just builds the building and sets it
someplace they call in the geomancer who analyzes out the energy field and they
decide the best and most proper place to put this building because if you put it
in the wrong place its effect on the lives of the people who live there is
very destructive whole towns for instance are we go down the tubes
because the town is
on a certain ley line and let's say they build a dam and they cut the ley line
what happens is the energy field of that ley line now reverses and when it does
the lives of all the people living along that line now go down the tubes you find
a couple years later that there's been suicides and bankruptcies and divorces
murders rapes as though it pulls to itself that which is destructive and
negative from the universe
an extremely
important thing to know as we look at the emotions coming out of these energy
fields it'll become obvious and so we're going to be talking today about things
that you really know is really within your consciousness and I'm really
pointing them out and making you more aware of them so if we start at the
bottom of the box if we calibrate death is zero as we said enlightenment will
come out about 600 so something we've done that together with my friend and
colleague Gorin rot
is we discovered what the levels of these various energy fields are and these
can be confirmed by anybody in their own living room using a simple technique
called kinesiology which we will demonstrate during this talk starting at
the very bottom we have an energy field called guilt which has an energy of 30
above that we have apathy at 50 so what does that mean means that apathy which
calibrates are 50 and roughly half the energy energy that's being used to make a
the energy of fear which calibrates at 100 fear has practically half the power
of courage which is at 200 grief which calibrates at 75 has only half the power
of anger which calibrates at 150 so you can see what we're talking about is the
relative power of these energy fields guilt at 30 is the lowest one it's very
close to death to the right of the energy field is the emotion that comes
out of that energy field you see coming out of guilt the emotion that comes out
of that is self hatred over at the right we have the process going on in
consciousness the process that's going on biologically physiologically so how
is the life of the entity being affected we see coming out of guilt and self
hatred and the process going on in consciousness
is one of destruction the situation above that is called apathy calibrating
at 50 what comes out of that is hopelessness and despair and the process
is the loss of life energy and the way the world looks over on the left is we
have the way the world looks coming out of that energy field is it looks
hopeless life looks hopeless the stage above that called grief at 75 is
characterized by regret loss
the powerful energy of the Caribbean doesn't host fishy emotions the
person we say has become dispirited and life to them scene is very sad stage
above that call fear we're all very familiar with fear in
its forms of worry anxiety and even severe panic the process is the person's
life energy is becoming deflated and life not begins below the world begins to look frightening
the stage above that and the when we have to understand really quite well in talking about not organized self einsigans as opposed to self Snoopy as I said in cohorts when 소냐 dropin
alcoholism and drugs and the effect of certain kinds of music is called desire
energy fields 125 that's the field of wanting this and creating this the field
of addiction and the process going on there is one of entrapment what does
that mean means once we create a desire for something then that begins to run us
we're at the effect of that and we become victims for all the energy fields
below courage all those with an energy field going to the left are states of
victim the importance of this energy field is that in all of science in
chemistry for instance in nature the effect of a substance let's say a
chemical a molecule and depends on the rotation of its molecule so for instance
dextro amphetamine sulfate dextro means to the right the molecule there spins to
the right
the dextro amphetamine sulfate is the well known speed levo amphetamine
sulfate the same molecule but now with a rotation
to the left and has the opposite effect levo amphetamine sulfate has no psychic
effect whatsoever nobody gets high on regard amphetamine
sulfate it's relatively inert so the direction of rotation then is extremely
important we move up to this energy field called anger and energy fields are
energy fields that are the same as the other ones so that's the first reaction
at 150 we experience that as resentment hatred the person we say has become expansive and they
become quite competitive within the world stage above that called pride which energizes at 175
is characterized by denial by a certain arrogance and a certain contempt extremely important in
understanding the effects of drugs the psychic effect of drugs we're going to be talking today
about the psychic effect and its effect on the energy field which surround the human body
you know everything in the universe gives off an energy and a vibration
and that energy of that vibration has a rotation either to the left or to the right it is either
constructive and supports life or is destructive and destroyed life it also can be calibrated as
to its relative energies so the energy field of pride is 175 we see is
destructive it is destructive because and we can see the denial and the arrogance and the contempt
that comes out of it therefore a person who has exposed themselves to this energy field
will be characterized in its personality by contempt if you tell somebody who is in this
state some kind of a fact they will be sarcastic and ridicule it that in which in your mind ridicule
then is coming out of this energy field
and the process going on in consciousness is one of inflation the energy field actually
becomes overinflated you say the person is too big for their boots they have a swell head
and they have a closed mind they have the incapacity to hear anything or to learn
anything and the way you know that's operating in you is when you say yeah i know yeah i know
yeah i know yeah i know yeah i know what yeah i know my own opinion and my opinion is what's right
and what you're telling me I don't want to hear about when we move up to a level
called courage which is the capacity to face the truth you see the emotion
coming out of that is the capacity to face hope and handle what happens to the
person then is they become re-empowered this is a state of power this is a state
of a false feeling of power coming out of angriness and prideful arrogance
gives you a false sense of power you need that you know why you need it
because you don't have any real power that you have to pretend you have it so
this is a pretend sense inner sense of power it's a fuller because coming out
of these lower fields like fear as compared to fear arrogance feels
powerful because you haven't felt real power yet and you think that's power but
when you experience real power you realize that that was the denial of real
power
so what happens when you do tell the truth about something is you become
open-minded you're willing to hear and to learn and that comes about because
you become re-empowered when you move up to the next energy field called neutral
you'll see now the energy field begins to swing to the right it means the
person has stopped resisting life they are now somewhat detached in the process
going on in consciousness is released we say a person like that to get
into a state of its own and so we begin to experience the world is okay so if I'm
talking to somebody about alcohol and drugs let's say and they finally say to
themselves okay I'll admit the truth it's making my life and manageable
frankly within myself it has worried me what happens then is they've opened up
their mind now and they have become re-empowered truly empowered now if we
can move the person up into a little bit of more enthusiasm we move up to the stage called willingness
which they begin to realize that what's being said,
that what's going on in the universe around them is friendly,
that the world is friendly.
See, when you're coming from down here, you feel like you're being attacked.
If you're coming from that position,
then the very information I'm trying to tell you today,
you're experiencing being attacked against your own belief system.
When you realize that I'm only sharing with you from a friendly space,
you know that I am not your enemy at all,
that I support that within you which supports life,
you begin to realize that the information itself is friendly.
You might even begin to say,
yes, I'm willing to join and listen and even agree and align myself
with what I'm hearing today
because now I've introduced something called intention.
You see, the energy field jumps there to 310.
It means you're beginning to really experience real power.
And if you do, you can even move up to a level called acceptance.
The willingness to accept.
That's what you hear because you see it's coming out of friendliness
and it's really harmonious with your life.
And as you do, you start to feel sort of confident.
By the time we get through talking today,
I want you to feel confident that you have a real way to hold this whole thing.
What you do about it is your own decision.
And I certainly have no intention to influence your decision one way or the other.
But I do want you to have the confidence
that at least now you have the knowledge you need
to come from a rational decision about your own life.
And I hope we will.
Thank you.
I've reached this level called transformation.
What is transformation?
It means that here you've begun to reown yourself
as the source of your own power.
That you yourself can create for yourself
a life which you experience as happy and successful.
That you yourself have that power.
The power is not outside of you.
These levels below courage are based on
and the victimhood of it comes out of
the belief that the source of your own power is you.
The belief that the source of your own power is you.
And the belief that the source of your own power is you.
of happiness is outside of yourself then you put your survival on the source of your happiness
on something outside of yourself you instantly put yourself in the position of victim
what it means if the source of happiness is outside of you then something can interfere
with it something can steal it take it away feel it deliver it cut you off from it
that's the whole anxiety about drugs isn't it the thought is if i admit the truth about my drug or
alcohol situation then i'm going to be cut off from the source of my happiness which is outside
of myself that's the reason for the denial well we drop the denial when we realize that you're not
going to be cut off from the source of your happiness because we're by the time we finish
talking today we're going to realize what is the true source of our happiness and realize we cannot
be cut off from that
we move up to an energy field called love which is a plus 500 an extremely powerful field in which
we begin to realize that the world the universe and what's going on around us is actually a
lovingness and that there is a desire on the part of the universe to nurture and support
all that is life and it encourages self-forgiveness and the forgiveness of others and that begins
within our minds a certain process called revelation
revelation
revelation is accompanied by a release within the brain
of endorphins the activation of millions and millions of banks of neurons which until you
reach this energy field have not been operative it moves you up to a state eventually of joy
the feeling of inner compassion and serenity the beginning of transfiguration and when we get up to
a very high state we move into fields called bliss now in the other talks i've done on this subject i
go into this whole thing very extensively so that you arrive at a very thorough understanding
our understanding of the nature of bliss is extremely important
because drugs and alcohol we have to understand what it is we're addicted to
and those tapes we really go into what we're addicted to to do that we really have to realize
the nature of consciousness itself we begin to realize where we experience experience so you cannot
the body has no capacity to experience itself that's a surprising thought isn't it but you
realize your arm cannot experience its own armness what happens is body is experienced within mind
mind has the capacity to experience the body body does not curiously enough mind has no capacity to
experience itself either a thought which is actually an energy form has no capacity to
experience its own existence
it's because mind is experienced by something greater than itself more diffuse more formless
and that is called consciousness consciousness being an energy field where experience of mind
and body takes place beyond that there is an even greater field which has no beginning and no end
called awareness is uh the awareness that we realize what's going on in consciousness
but all experience on an ordinary way is going on in the field of consciousness
itself when we talk about alcohol and drugs we ask ourselves what was the reason we took them
not the social reasons but what was the inner experience that it brought to us what was it we
were seeking as an effect of that after we took it what we did is we waited for a certain inner
experience and what did we experience we experienced within consciousness something having
to do with... In consciousness, we experience a feeling of being conscious of one's own body...
with the whole energy field of bliss that feeling of being expanded of feeling ecstatic of feeling
joyful a feeling on its lower levels mellow two martinis on an empty stomach before lunch you know
creates a feeling called mellow mellow is an energy fuel of about 500. when we get up to states
like 540 560 the energy field of ecstasy calibrates at about 560. we're now in a position to know a
little bit about what the effect of drugs and alcohol are see the illusion is drugs or alcohol
create the state of high no such thing happens what happens is that drugs and alcohol block off
lower energy fields so that we don't experience them and what happens is we experience these
higher energies which are always present between the higher energies and the lower energies
us the energy field of life itself to experience it in its pure form is
ecstatic LSD taken under the best of possible experiences possible
circumstances has allowed many people to experience that exquisite infinite
awareness of the truth of all reality the LSD does not create that it has no
power to do that what it has is the power to block off these energy fields
so it's like the Sun is always shining and you can't experience the Sun because
of the clouds and what the drugs do or block off the clouds so you experience
that which is always shining if we had a drug for instance that could block off
all the energy fields up to five hundred and sixty you said five sixty is the
energy field of ecstasy then you would experience only an inner ecstasy we had
a designer drug that would do that we could call it ecstasy and as a matter
of fact on the street as you're all familiar there is a drug that blocks off
everything up to five sixty and it is called ecstasy now we know what it is
we're addicted to the reason the world has not been too successful in
understanding drugs and alcohol is they don't understand what a person is
addicted to in the first place but you're addicted to is an inner state of
consciousness called bliss ecstasy bliss mellow generous happy giving
expansive delightful sublime you name it we've all experienced it that's what
was sought after the drug doesn't block all these things off and allow you to
experience that you don't bother with it so we have Thorazine for instance which
blocks off people say well you're running away from reality you're
taking drugs and then etc but we have a drug let's say people will say you're
running away from fear and anxiety so we have a drug that does that
marvelously Thorazine you know a big dose of Thorazine
you won't feel nervous till Christmas and yet nobody asked me for a refill of
that you know nobody calls and says it went down the toilet could you send me a
refund why because Thorazine knocked all this off down here but it does not knock
off any enough to access those higher energy fields we have antidepressants
that knock off these lower fields see but this is all they knock off and
therefore nobody's interested in getting high on antidepressants
so at least we know now what we're addicted to we're addicted to an
interstate of consciousness which we've only experienced in our ordinary
experience by something that blocks off the lower levels of consciousness well
many people who have never taken drugs become addicted to the same state of
consciousness people who meditate and go into a state of Samadhi often change
their entire life sacrifice everything and begin an inner exploration an inner
spiritual purification
to raise their consciousness so they can go back into that ecstatic state on a
permanent basis people have had near-death experiences like the movie
resurrection where she's declared dead on the operating table leaves the body
meets her own higher self and goes into this exquisite sublime state when she
comes back into the body her whole life is transformed and of course there's
many books in the literature now this is not available many years ago but it is
now many books
revealing these near-death experiences and in every case once the person is
experienced these sublime states their life is totally transformed the movie
lost horizon you know depicts this extremely well you see the movie lost
horizon you will understand drugs and alcohol because what happens is once that
person has experienced Shangri-La and he tries to go back into the world the
ordinary World calibrates at about 220 the world of competition success money
success and its law sense in the moment but he can't escape the idea of life until 20 years later.
conquest etc once the person has experienced the sublime state the world
of 220 no longer has much appeal and so in that movie you remember he goes back
into the world where he is no longer satisfied and desires to get back to
that state of Shangri-La when I calibrated the energy field of Shangri-La
came out at about 625 a very addicting state of consciousness once having been
experienced so Ronald Coleman who plays that part of the movie remember gives up
everything in the world to go back into that state of consciousness and you
realize the drugs and alcohol that's exactly what you do you will give up
anything in the world in order to get back into that state of consciousness
that's the whole basis of the joke cocaine is nature's way of saying you
have too much money it's going to remove your money it's going to remove your
freedom your car your driver's license it's going to remove your credit card
it's going to remove your freedom your car your driver's license it's going to
to remove your relationship you're going to give up anything and everything you may not get but let
me tell you because i've gone the whole route when it asks for everything you will give it in the end
it's going to ask for your body it's going to say if you want to keep on reaching this state
because you're dying of a whole variety of variety of diseases this state now requires that you risk
and give up your body you know what you're going to do you're going to say yes to it you're going
to say yes to it you're going to give up everything to return to the state of consciousness
all right now we know what we're addicted to huh what goes wrong with that what's the problem here
so we're walking along here feeling worrisome or anxiety and maybe annoyed about something
and we smoke something shoot something sniff something drink something and suddenly we move
up to this energy field here now we're in the mellow high fantastic feeling great feeling
wonderful i mean so whatever the reason why pastor just you look at this Eric excuse me
I actually like so muchbits because he gives so much, I don't like a lot of books about fame and
stuff like that but anybody, basically anything is over the top, so if you're missing all the facts,
wrong with that you know we're not hurting anybody you know i walk down the street drink a couple
things drop a couple pills smoke a little something a snort a little something i mean
who am i hurting right that's the rationalization what goes wrong how does it end up as a story like
this how does it end up as four ways you can go crazy prison die or give it up how out of such
an innocent it looks like an innocent inner pleasure and can such destruction come about
that's why we needed an understanding of these energy fields yeah and so before we go into back
into that i want to discuss a little bit about kinesiology we have a way of testing these energy
fields and diagnosing them you can diagnose the energy field of anything using a simple test called
kinesiology needs kinesiology is based on the integrity of the energy field of the energy field
is the integrity of the acupuncture system the energy field which flow around the human body
see we have energy fields around the heart that's the energy field of the heart
you'll hear those of you eventually go to aa let's say that aa is the language of the heart
and so in esoteric psychology for instance a great deal is talked about these different
energy fields which are traditional and have been referred to as energy fuel chakras so we know that
the base chakra we know there's the spleen there's the solar plexus what does it mean well the solar
plexus and which fits in around here has to do with pride it has to do with challenge competition
it has to do with ambition with getting this with greed with desiring this with wanting this
that's the craving that's that energy that makes us crave and want see so when madison avenue gets
us addicted to something by advertising
connects up and activates one of the archetypes which have a lot of psychic energy
what happens is we become trapped and want that when a person becomes more advanced
in their consciousness their energy fuel moves up into the heart the person now
opens their heart and is capable of loving loving so the energy field where you are sort
of centered your energy determines completely what your life experience is it determines what
emotions you're going to be experiencing it determines what process your life is going to
be in whether it's going to be in destruction transformation empowerment entrapment revelation
or enlightenment it totally determines how you experience the world it's perfect loving harmonious
friendly okay world of opportunity a world of competition or a world of frustration a world
that is frightening sad hopeless or a world of hopeless suffering and of course it totally
determines how you would experience god or destiny within yourself with your life safe or free and
known it absolutely determines how to live in your life or and always be غ pare Tenemos ρgreen
a world that isING a world that
takes a deep breath from everything tomorrow more mindfulness gets Shelley Hart then a squad of
nor deny the presence of god or think that god is dead so knowing about these energy
fields then is crucial what is the effect of drugs and alcohol then what is the energy fuel
that is coming out of them well the first few experiences because they block all this off
access this allow you to experience that now you become addicted to that experience what you're
addicted to is the energy field of bliss the experience of that which you are your oneness
your beingness really your higher self what you're getting is the frequency the vibration
the higher the frequency the greater the power that's the principle of physics you see
what we're talking about today agrees with current research and quantum mechanics
so the higher the frequency the higher the energy field the more the greater its power
so what you've done is put yourself into a field of great power
enormous power to psychically experience that exquisite joy of that intense power
forever programs us thereafter so the first few times we take drugs and alcohol we experience
that now the addiction to that experience what happens is the left brain which doesn't
really understand causality ascribes the power to the drug well once you project your power
outside of yourself which is the denial of the truth that's the denial of the truth
you see what you were experiencing was your own higher self then you denied that you denied that
you lied about it and you projected it and you said the power is in the drug
what happens then is the energy field goes in this direction so the whole energy field of
drugs and the drug experience now has moved in this kind of a direction the next thing you'll
notice is denial and arrogance coming into your life and you'll notice anger about anything that's
happening that interferes with your drug experience you'll notice that you stop going to
part you know you wouldn't even think of going to a party if there were no drugs or alcohol there
in your relationships you wouldn't have a relationship with somebody unless they were
also into drugs and alcohol so you notice that you have become entrapped that what's happening
is it beginning to run your life that you now have a fear of loss of your supply you start
having an anger of an interference with your supply
the thought that this might be removed from your life sends you into depression so people go into
depression when drugs or alcohol are cut off why is that why is there this depression it's not for
the removal of drugs or alcohol they really don't mean a damn thing it's depression because you now
feel that you are cut off from this state of consciousness your excess roots through
experiencing this has been cut off well the energy field of drugs let's look into it a little bit
and let's look into the whole drug scene and see what is the energy field in which this phenomenon
occurs cocaine let's say which is the current drug of choice what is the energy field of it well we
noticed some research that said that amongst you know people who have been badly bent out by coke
and the recovery rate from of these people who've been into rehabilitation centers who continue to
listen to heavy metal rock with this
drug is that the people who no matter how devastated and certainly the story here at
david crosby is about as devastated as you can get and he's arrested at least six times ends
up in prison and loses all his money ends up on probation almost loses his life in an automobile
accident rolls over his cars is that an exceptional story that's the average story all he's telling
here is everybody's story it's not an exceptional story it's everybody's story how does this come
about you see
what happens is we have to look now into what is the effect of a negative energy field and what
characterizes the negative energy field and someone asked a friend of mine who is here today
susan come on up so we can discover a way in which we can test out what is an energy field you see
and we'll use a simple technique called kinesiology which you can do with yourself your
family and your friends in this what we're testing is a person's power a physical energy and so what
i want you to do is
is just look at the wall what you do is you press down with two fingers and you ask the person to
resist resist so we ask her to resist with all her power all her energy is this okay now i want you
to hold in mind something negative something about which you've been or are angry somebody you hate
some of you dislike something you fear it can be from the past something you said about just hold
that in mind okay now resist
become weak as a kitten what's the matter with you
anytime you hold anything below the line you will go weak okay that is destructive then
every time you hold a negative thought or you're in a negative energy field
what happens is it blows your acupuncture meridians it totally blows your power
it desynchronizes the two cerebral hemispheres think of the application of this in sports when
the starting gun goes off a person is thinking in terms of competition
has already lost a split second of power okay now let's ask i want you to hold something
someone in mind that you love you got somebody in mind you know i never did okay
with all my power now i can't put her down for the minute you hold something
that is joyful loving tender kind it could be your dog be your kitty you know i've been tested
you know and i think of my kitty and i say it's drug you know anything you love that which is
loving that which that which you would nurture and support that which you would really care for
instantly makes you go strong so now we have a very simple technique you can test foods you can
test materials you can test friends you can test gurus you think guru with so-and-so is good for
your life a whole guru so-and-so in your mind and test it you find some rather surprising things
about some of the world's kind of food well let's see what the effect of some of these things are
let's say today's this came on the newsstand today let's today take today's time magazine
which has a group i'm not going to give the name of but it's supposedly one of the hottest groups
out right right now so okay we're going to test you again this time i want you to just look at
the picture and i'm going to now read this and really look at the picture makes you go weak
all right now here's a
we're going to play this in a couple seconds now here is merely the cassette
cover here is merely the cover in which there is a graphic on the front
look at it okay now resist the energy field given off by just the cover the graphic
it picks up the energy field and what determines energy field is intention
when the person with what blows it out is intention so here's another user this is called
metal rock hall of fame 87 and if we just have you look at the group in the centerfold
i can turn it page after page because it's all the same issue it's all the same story
you can tell by the names of the group what the energy field is oh my god
what the energy field is that's coming out of these people okay
everything
okay now we have
another word a means now of discerning that which is let's listen to a bit of the music
for a second and see what the effect is we have a strong man you know maybe the audience might say
you know it's just a weak woman here we have a strong man susan you can maybe poke the
music on okay um you look at the wall and this now i said this big and i've done it on thousands
of people you know i've done it on professional wrestlers who stood there like this you know it was
well we what we can do is we're going to do a second one so first we want to
look at the perpetrator we want to look at thepelton's
inaudible
that is so little hollow
because
because he too much of you know porcelain pressure or aeronautics are a big opắm the effect of heavy instruments and
drugs on you is impersonal. See, we're trying to understand what is it about the drugs that
is destructive. Is it the chemical? No, I'd say it's not the chemical. Not the chemical
that's destructive. You can take morphine for 50 years and in autopsy the brain shows
no changes at all, you know. I had a great aunt who became addicted medically after multiple
surgery in Egypt back in 1917. She lived the rest of her life on morphine. It was a delightful
lady, you know. Well, so we know it isn't just the chemical and it isn't just, well,
the brain enzymes. We know that speed and various up drugs, for instance, will deplete
the neurotransmitters. We know that the neurotransmitters get depressed so that when you remove the
drugs there's a depression of neurotransmitters which therefore causes depression. So there
is the brain enzyme and the brain neurotransmitter explanation.
But that's insufficient. We see now what we're addicted to. There's a certain level
of consciousness. In the beginning it begins to work but it then starts a process. A process
in which we begin to go down because despite all of our education we say, no, it is a drug.
That begins to create a negative energy field within us. Within us. The drugs themselves
and the whole scene in which they occur are a negative energy field scene.
And what characterizes a negative energy field? Well, we said pride. So we take one
of these groups and I did it just before we started to do this phase and calibrated what
is the energy field of that group and we found it was a hundred and eighty in a negative
direction. So what kind of a phase would we expect from a person that's a hundred and
eighty reverse attitude? Upped, nerd, arrogant, denial, contemptuous and anti-life. Anti-life
wouldn't you say that this is anti-life wouldn't you say that to encourage
people to ingest that which destroys every aspect of your life is that which
does not support life all right now begin to see what the destruction of the
energy field is so even if I recover from drugs let's say and I sit around
listening to that music we saw with kinesiology that what happens is the
music creates a destructive energy field over on the right you'll see what
comes out of this is destruction the process coming out of the bottom of the
reverse energy field is to seek destruction it begins to create an
unconscious guilt and an unconscious self-hatred because unconsciously you
cannot destroy yourself without creating guilt the peculiar thing about a
negative energy field is that
the person begins to seek and desire destruction therefore to tell somebody
you know who is in this kind of an energy field that if you continue to
drink or use drugs you know you will end up destroyed the person says good
something within the person just loves it I mean it sounds so dramatic you know
I can remember watching Lost Weekend I had a half pint in my bottle you know in
my pocket in the movie and as I'm watching Lost Weekend
you know I'm drinking and I watched this guy's destruction and you know if
you've ever seen Lost Weekend he's got the DTs he goes insane he ends up in a
straitjacket he was telling me my own future anyways I watched it I was like
caught by the glamour of it seemed to me almost glamorous you know there was a
seduction and attraction to going downhill weird sick perverted right what
does the word pervert mean it means that we're going down the hill we're going to
be
driving goods when we know we're going to be back to them and you know which was
healthy and that which was positive that which was innocent and loving has been
twitted somehow even the names of some groups are called twisted you know that
that is exactly clinically correct it does twist from this direction to this
direction what happens when a person goes in this direction is that they
desire that which is destructive I discovered that years ago we saw that
when people listen to this kind of music they spend six or seven days a week
trying to get to the bottom of a bed they don't realize that they're not
sick so they have to stay awake and keep trying and pray until the morning comes
morning after a meal they eat well and eat food they eat and drink and drink that
went all night I'm healthy I'm happy like the President says all the time I'm happy
With kinesiology, if you hold a substance over the solar plexus and test a person's
energy, it will tell whether it is good for you or bad for you.
So I would put things in little brown envelopes.
In a normal state, for instance, let's say pesticides will make you go weak.
Now if I play that kind of music so that the energy field goes in this direction, still
holding the pesticide, that which is poisonous, and I test the person, they will go strong.
Weird.
When I first saw that, it scared me.
It scared me, but then I saw the implications and I got it.
It's like it totally reversed the person in there and now backwards.
The energy field around the body, called the etheric body, the etheric body is like an
energy blueprint of the physical body.
What happens is it turns these fields around.
And now the consciousness of the person is dominated by a desire for destruction, a desire
for destruction.
So what these energy fields created by all these groups and by these drugs and all their
expressions, what it's inviting you to do is to destroy yourself and then to enjoy the
process.
Enjoy the process of destroying yourself.
So we invite you to destroy yourself.
Enjoy yourself.
Does it look like destruction when you're in this kind of an energy field?
No.
It looks attractive.
It looks glamorous.
See, seduction comes right into here.
This is the energy field of seduction.
So what we're talking about now is the utilization of seduction, seduction through pleasurable
sensation, through drama.
So seduction to inculcate, like brainwash the person into becoming the victim of that.
It's like I say, join me.
Join me.
So pleasurable.
Come on.
Oh, it feels so good.
Wow.
Now I got you.
Now you're mine.
That's what's going on.
That's exactly what's going on when you see it.
It's so clear.
Wow.
At least you know what's going on now.
At least you can't say, well, I didn't know.
You know?
I didn't know I was being seduced.
I didn't know that I was being overwhelmed by a very powerful negative energy field,
that it was beginning to dominate my conscious and that I became the victim of that.
That's what happened.
All we experience in our unconsciousness, and the purpose of this is to make you conscious
rather than unconscious.
All we experienced was the destruction.
All we knew was we kept getting high, and somehow our life was falling apart.
We didn't understand how, so we'd say, well, I'm only going to smoke grass after this.
I mean, I'm off the hard stuff, or I'm only going to drink beer.
I'm only going to have a couple of beers before bed, you see?
How is it just a couple of beers before bed ended up as a case a day, the same as it used
to be, and then a quarter a day, and then adding the fills and the ups and the downs
in order to be able to keep the body walking around?
So what's the solution of this?
Well, the solution of it begins with an understanding, with an understanding to just get what I'm
saying today.
I don't care what you do about it.
I have no interest in that.
Once we begin to understand, see, this energy field of love, the purpose, the purpose, the
intention that comes out of the energy field of love is to understand, not to condemn or
to make wrong.
I have no interest in right or wrong.
No interest in condemnation.
Okay?
Compassion, what that has to do with is the ultimate understanding, to understand what
is the process, to look around you, and now that you're more awake, see, what is the process
going on in the lives of the people around you?
It's no longer, once you get de-glamorized, it's no longer glamorous.
You walk into the so-called happy hour, happy, hysterically.
What a joke that is.
You walk in the nearest bar and grill where it says, happy hour, you know?
People zonked out, staring at television, totally unconscious, in their mind, glamorized
by the thought that this is cocktail time, and I'm having a happy hour.
I mean, this is great, being amongst the guys, you see?
Friday night, paycheck time, everybody congregates, and now we get into the glamor of comradhood,
the pseudo-glamor of pseudo-bridegrooming.
Brotherhood.
Pseudo-brotherhood.
How do you know it's pseudo?
Because if you quit drinking and you quit hanging out with those people, and doing what
they're doing, they ain't gonna want to hear from you, all right?
A true brother is somebody who, when they see that you're having a problem with it,
supports to get in office.
A true brother is somebody who really loves you, can see, man, you're throwing up with
that stuff all the time, you've cracked up the car with that stuff all the time, you
know, the wife is starting to walk out on you all the time, because they haven't got
what they need.
You're blowing it all here.
A real friend would help you get out of it.
That's a real friend.
That's somebody who's in an energy field like that.
So seek those people out.
Find those people who have found the way out, see?
People willing to share the truth.
Here's a great guy, you know, I don't know him, but his willingness to share the truth,
his willingness to come out and say, yeah, this is what happened.
What he does is he lends us his energy, the knowledge that he's gained through his own
experience.
So we seek out the people, you know, who have beat it.
Why?
Because those people are all coming out of this energy field of 500.
All these self-help groups, cocaine anonymous, alcohol anonymous, narcotics anonymous, all
those 12-step groups, all based on the same 12 steps of truth, are coming out of an energy
field of 540.
An energy field of 540 is what you've got to be in to beat the drug and alcohol problem.
To hang out in a reversed energy field of 190 then means that your consciousness is
dominated by that field.
We saw with kinesiology, it had nothing to do with her willpower.
It had nothing to do with his willpower.
So the person says, well, I'm going to handle this with willpower.
All right, let's see you resist it with willpower.
I never found a person yet.
Willpower doesn't have the power.
It takes a love power.
That which is truly loving.
That which is willing to truly share the truth with you.
The person is willing to really stand up for you.
Stand up for what aspect of you.
Not join with your wish to destroy yourself, but to join with that which is nurturing and
supporting.
That which is forgiving.
What people will get is they'll make wrong about drugs and alcohol.
Who cares about that?
Make wrong is coming down here from a prideful opinion.
You know, I'm right because I don't use, and you're wrong because you use.
That's not helpful.
You see, if guilt could handle it, if guilt could handle it, then all the millions of
people who drive and die from drugs and alcohol wouldn't be dying because they all feel guilty
about it.
Unconscious guilt is what leads the person to go off the bottom of the box in the first
place.
So feeling guilty about drugs and alcohol isn't going to be the answer.
The unconscious guilt is what leads to the path of suicide.
And so we see all these people like you rolling the tire over a few times.
Ended up in prison.
It's a wonder to him he's still alive.
All the deaths due to overdoses and all are not overdoses at all.
If we check them out, we'll find that the negative energy field leads to the unconscious
wish for death.
The unconscious attraction of that which is destruction.
And so it's not an accidental overdose.
All the famous rock stars.
Are you telling me they're amateurs?
They're experts.
Just like me.
Just like I was.
I managed to physically survive right at the very point of death.
My whole life flipped around.
I went from max here to max up here.
I opened it up and I said, if there's a God, I ask him to help me.
I was an atheist at the time and had been for 20 years.
And suddenly I stood in an infinite presence and it blew out drugs, alcohol, and any desire
from them.
Now and forever.
Nor have they ever arisen in 22 years.
So what happens then is that the effect progressively of the drugs and alcohol on the human body
is to drive us further and further down.
Until finally that attraction of death, that attraction, expresses itself as the overdose.
The accidental overdose.
We were expert psychopharmacologists.
I had to juggle in a day 42 pills.
I averaged 40 pills a day.
Plus a pint to afford a booze.
Plus anything I could smoke, drink, or inject to put in myself in any other way.
Et cetera.
A pair of Gorex and Serpent Hydrate with codeine.
A couple of alcohols.
And then I'd go to bed.
And I'd go to bed.
A couple of ampoules.
You name it.
Whatever I could get.
Throw in a Demerol and a couple of martinis on top.
How could there be an accidental overdose with somebody who knows how to juggle everything
like that?
Nothing such thing is accidental.
So turning over the car, getting mugged, getting robbed.
Robbed.
Got spells.
Got sent in.
skull fractured in a fight that is the coming out of the passive suicide not actively sought
consciously but unconsciously so that is the effect of that energy field that's the whole
energy field that we're talking about today now you have some way of comprehending and understanding
why is it despite this guy's thing his brilliance his creativity his obvious integrity that he
that he once had how did it all get destroyed he himself says it's impersonal and we see today
that that is impersonal you see the effect that we saw there when we tested with kinesiology
that's impersonal that's the effect of an energy field it has nothing to do with willpower your
goodness your badness it has to do with the effect of that powerful field so you might look at then
the field that you put yourself in as a giant a
electromagnetic field you might picture it as a giant electromagnet
now this field can go and the positive and the negative poles can be reversed like this and
you're full of iron filings you know that you know you have magnetite in the body cells you have iron
so in electromagnetic field now you realize the power of that let's say we had an electromagnet
and one pole is as big as a city block and the other one's half a mile away
the other
is as big as the city block and they turn the power on you are going to be at the effect of
that isn't that right even your belt buckles going to pull you one way or the other now we
can switch the polarity of that field we can make this pole negative this pole positive now by
throwing a switch we can reverse it that's exactly what happened we were born and we grew up in a
positive nurturing electromagnetic field in this direction then what happened is something came
into our life and what positive in the negative suddenly so what happens is the person goes in
the opposite direction so here's the guy who's about as successful as you can get in the world
he's on his way up suddenly the polarity in his life reverses suddenly his life is disaster
we are not more powerful than the field it takes the power of 500 and over
to handle the electromagnetic magnetic attraction of the glamour and the seduction
and the positive asset we saw we banished ourselves from the world we went beyond the
it takes the power of 503 number to handle the electromagnetic magnetic attraction of the glamour
and the seduction and the positive asset tension and to gather occupancy and the power of the informations
but how could you manage the completely value of every single instrument in time we wanted to work
of the whole drug and heavy metal rock field out of that understanding now we
can develop a certain compassion instead of making ourselves wrong for this and
having to go into this you know defensive denial defensive denial comes
out of guilt yeah you see there's nothing to feel guilty about this is a
phenomena occurring in nature we can say you know all of us are part of nature
human life we are all expressions of nature we see that this is just a
phenomenon going on within nature you can see what its nature is you can
understand how it works out of that understanding then comes a certain inner
wisdom and a certain in their decision at least we know what the story is we're
not blind anymore we're not naive we're not unconscious the whole purpose of
these talks is to make us more conscious out of that higher consciousness then to
develop a certain compassion a willingness to forgive yourself
you
a compassion for life a compassion for others to whom this has happened it's
not helpful at all to get into condemnation and to make wrong and those
who are willing to help with this problem are all of the same position
coming out of that compassion they see a brother they know what's happened to
that brother because it's happened to them it's so clear to them what's
happening to the other person and the frustration the difficulty of trying to
get the message across to them because they're so deaf
they're so unwilling to hear huh I've tried to open up your ears open up your
mind see the thought that one is forever cut off from that which we thought the
drugs and alcohol is a lot that which we experienced with our own higher inner
self and therefore those who have recovered from drugs and alcohol and
continues back in this direction and this time they own that experience this
time that is what they have become they have become the very energy field that
they want
through drugs and alcohol.