I've been a physician and a psychiatrist for 35 years.
I've worked in the field of psychoanalysis and psychotherapy and group therapy,
psychodynamics of the various schools.
I've done a lot of research on nutrition and its relationship to brain chemistry
and its relationship to mental illness and emotions.
For the last 10 years, I've been doing research into the nature of consciousness itself
and the applications of that knowledge that came out of that research
to an understanding of that field of knowledge which the world calls spiritual.
And so, inherent in what we're talking about today
is that relationship between body, mind, and spirit.
And what does that really mean?
Is that something scientific that we can clinically verify?
Or is that some kind of a New Age fantasy?
Our talk for today will be about the prevention of stress.
Stress.
A subject about which we read so much.
Its implications for health.
Its implications for emotional and psychological health.
Its meaning in industry.
Its meaning in business.
The realization now of wide areas in our culture
of being aware of what stress means,
what's implied in this disorder.
And so today we will need to look closely at what this relationship is
between the body and its response to stress.
The mind and how this relates to spirit.
So we'll be covering today how stress results from a point of view.
It results from what we are holding in mind.
From our attitudes and our beliefs.
So we'll see that the source of stress is within ourselves.
It's really not in the world at all.
There is no such thing as escaping stress
because its source, its cause, is within us.
Its source.
Its source is not within the world.
And so we'll be reversing the way the mind usually looks at things
about cause and effect.
We'll see that cause is not in the world
and effect in mind, but vice versa.
That the level of power, the level of cause,
is held in mind.
And this brings about our experiences of what happens in the world.
Our folklore intuitively knows this
because it says,
one man's meat is another man's poison.
One man's meat is another man's poison.
And in that we have the secret of what we're looking at today.
The power is not in the event.
The power is not something out there.
The power of creating our experience
of all events in life
lie within us.
And it's by reowning our power then
that we can learn how to prevent stress.
So we will be talking about
methods of precluding stress
instead of treating its aftermath.
The so-called stress reduction programs
which are so commonly available in our society today
are really methods of handling
the effects of stress once it's already happened.
The relaxation programs
to relieve the tension within the body.
You might say,
the horse is already out of the barn.
We'll be looking at ways
to offset this
so that the tension never arises in the body.
These various ways of handling stress
in the medical model.
I recently got a brochure, in fact this week.
It says stress and heart disease.
Stress and heart disease.
And right there we have a whole program.
We have a whole program which the mind has bought.
That stress is something out there.
Stress is something inherent in life.
That the result of stress,
is going to affect the heart.
The heart with all its symbolic meaning to us.
The various papers then had to do
really with heart disease.
The consequence of stress.
Coming about through our levels of consciousness
and manifesting within the body.
Because all things are experienced
within consciousness then today,
we'll be looking at that relationship
between body, mind and spirit.
And in this talk, as we have in other talks,
we want to go back
and carefully define
things that you can verify
through your own experience.
And in this talk as well as the other talks
we're going to be talking about
clinical verifiable experience.
Coming from the viewpoint of the skeptical scientist
who believes only what can be clinically repeated
and which he can verify through his own inner experience.
And so we invite you during this talk
to find out within yourself
the truth of all that we are talking about.
To begin with we notice that
the body itself,
a characteristic of the body,
is that it is insentient.
That is, the body has no capacity
to experience itself.
What do we mean by that?
I mean that the arm in and of itself
cannot experience its own existence.
It cannot experience its own armness.
It cannot experience that it is
much less where it is,
or how big it is,
or what it's doing.
How do we know what's going on with the body?
We know because of the senses.
So we don't experience the body,
we experience the senses reporting this of the body.
The senses themselves have no capacity
to experience themselves.
An ear, the vibrations going through the eighth nerve,
vibrating the tympanic membrane, etc.,
has no way to experience itself.
Where does experience of the body
take place?
It takes place in something greater than that,
and that we call mind.
It's because of mind.
So all experience of the body is occurring
in an energy field, in a level,
that we call mind.
Mind itself, very curiously,
has no capacity to experience itself.
An amazing thought until you look into it.
You'll see that a thought,
of and by itself,
has no capacity to experience its own thoughtness.
A memory has no capacity
in and of itself
to experience its own memoryness.
A fantasy about the future
has no capacity.
Our imagination, our emotions,
all that goes on in mind
is only experienced
because of a greater and larger
energy field than mind,
and that is what we call consciousness.
An energy field more diffuse
and formless,
capable of experiencing change,
capable of experiencing
any phenomena.
It is because of consciousness
that we're aware
of what is going on in mind.
It is because of mind
we're aware of what is going on with sensations.
Because of sensations
we're aware of what goes on
with the physical body.
Curiously enough,
even consciousness itself
cannot report what is going on
within itself
except for a field which is infinite
and without dimension
and called the absolute knowingness
or awareness.
It is because of awareness,
it is because of that quality
of awareness which goes with our existence.
It goes with our beingness.
It's because we are,
we're capable of awareness.
Out of awareness then comes
the knowingness of what goes on
within consciousness.
Consciousness reporting to us
what is going on within mind.
Mind reporting what goes on
with sensations about the body.
And so we can see
that that which we are,
when we say I or me
in its highest and greatest sense,
we're talking about the capacity
for awareness.
It is on this energy field,
in this energy field
and level of consciousness
that we'll be talking today.
It is within consciousness itself
that all experience is being experienced.
Thereby to address ourselves directly
to the source and the place
of the experience
will bring us to the capabilities
of precluding the sources of stress.
In doing this we'll be talking about
a map of consciousness
which we've referred to
in these other talks.
It's a mathematical model.
Not purely mathematical
but it is based upon energy fields,
levels of consciousness
and these energy fields
have been calibrated
as to their relative power.
These are the energy fields
here which are labeled
according to common human experience.
Easily understood
and as you look at it
you will find that
it's easily understandable.
At the very bottom for instance
we have guilt
which is in its form of self-hatred,
a destructive negative emotion.
We know that from guilt
the world is seen
as a place of suffering.
Guiltiness has an energy field of 30.
These are states that come close to death.
Death we calibrate at zero.
If we start with death at zero
then to be of a very high consciousness
to become enlightened
calibrates out at 600.
Guilt you'll see in apathy
and grief and fear
and desire and anger and pride.
All these negative energy fields
all have a negative
or a destructive direction.
You'll notice that their calibrations
are low in number.
For instance apathy at 50
has half the power of fear
which calibrates out at 100.
Fear at 100 has half the energy of courage
which calibrates out at 200.
Desire has half the energy
of that state called neutral
or being detached.
So we can calibrate the energy fields
and these can be reduplicated by anybody
using very common techniques
for instance kinesiology.
Anybody in their own home can
verify themselves
the relative energies
and the directions of the field.
These fields which go to the left
if you hold in mind
a thought which is angry
a thought about something you regret
something you are sad about
or something you fear
and if you press down on the person's arm
you will see they instantly go weak.
The cerebral hemispheres become desynchronized
the acupuncture energy system
goes out of kilt
and the person instantly goes to sleep.
The person instantly loses their power
and their energy.
If we go above the level of courage
and you'll see the energy field now
which was in this direction
now goes neutral
the needle swings to the middle.
By telling the truth
by telling the truth about things
by moving towards that which is true
the energy field now swings to the right
into that which is positive.
That which is positive
is that which supports and reinforces life
that energy of aliveness.
It is aligned with the truth.
And so the great beings of great wisdom
who have walked this earth
when we calibrate their energy fields
they run up into the 600s
and the great avatars
the great saviors of mankind
their energy fields
run from the 700s on up into infinity.
So you might say the truth
begins at this energy field of 200
and expands ever upward
into an ever increasing lovingness
alignment with truth
and health follows the same pattern.
The farther we go up in our energy fields
the more automatic becomes the health
until finally there is a joy
in the aliveness
the exquisite pleasure of the body
which automatically becomes healthy
and it automatically heals its own diseases
because at an energy field of about 540
which is the energy field of healing
healing automatically
begins to take place in the body
at an energy field of 540.
So as we talk about stress
it's obvious that we're going to be
looking at these conditions
these pre-existing conditions
within the consciousness of the person
which set the person up
to experience life in a stressful way.
It's obvious that a person
who is identified with this energy field
is going to experience a world
which is going to make them feel constantly guilty.
It's obvious that a person who identifies
on this energy field here
one of hopelessness and despair
is going to experience the world as hopeless
and all of life's experiences
are going to be colored by that expectation.
As we move up to grief
we'll see that the person who is full of regret
and concern with loss in the past
is going to see this as a sad world.
And if there is a God
He would be a God who doesn't love you
who doesn't care for you
and ignores you.
As we move up to the energy field of fear
we see that coming out of the suppressed energy
which has been held throughout life
held unconsciously
of fearfulness
the preoccupation with anxiety about the future
the person who is constantly worrying
the world looks to that person
like a frightening place.
The God of such a world
would then be punitive.
And so therefore
all that person's experience now
is coming forth in the form of fright.
The person who is always wanting
experiences this as a frustrating world.
The angry person
is always running into conflict and war.
The prideful person
is always experiencing challenges
and therefore assumes a defensive posture.
So that's just a brief look at
we'll be coming back to this map of consciousness
in greater detail
and see how it operates
in the automatic setting up
and setting us up for stress.
We begin to suspect now
from that statement
that one man's meat is another man's poison
that the setup for stress then
is coming out of our own values.
It's coming out of our own position about life.
It's coming out of the programs
that we're holding operative
within our own consciousness.
And we begin to look now
for the source of stress
not in the world
but in what is it we are holding in consciousness
that assigns to a given event
the experience of it as stress.
In looking at this
we'll look now at some attitudes
some ways of being with life
that set us up for this kind of an experience.
And we'll cite some examples
which are available to all of us.
I had an in-law
for instance
who used to come out
and visit my house in the country
at the time I lived in the middle
of a hundred acres of woods
thirty miles from New York City.
And there there was only stillness.
In fact the only thing you could hear
was the rustling of the leaves
and the song of the birds.
And she was a somewhat elderly lady
and she'd lived most of her life
in New York City
you know on East 28th Street
around that area.
And she would hate to come out to the house
and when she had to
she would stay as briefly as possible.
In fact two or three days
was all she could stand.
And the peace and the silence
drove her crazy.
And she just couldn't stand it.
And she couldn't wait to get back to the city
where she would sigh with relief.
And her apartment in the city
you know faced the street.
And so from her open window
she could talk to everybody
she could hear the hustle and bustle of the city.
And she felt secure.
So in the midst of
you know it was mugger land
the Lower East Side, etc.
all those areas of the city at that time
were ripe with muggings.
So here she was
you know in a situation
which another person might consider as stressful.
A lot of people might
consider that part of the city scary indeed.
So what she experienced as security
being there in the throngs of people
and the sound of the garbage cans in the morning
and the garbage trucks
making their racket at 5 a.m.
to her was reassurance.
Being safe and secure
in the middle of 100 acres of woods
to her was a threat.
We look at the interesting experience then
of Devil's Island
the French penal colony.
And of course this is well documented
that when the French government
out of protest
coming from the humanism movement
out of social protest
closed this disgraceful colony
what happened was that
they allowed the prisoners
to go loose on the island.
They released them from these animal cages.
Torture cages is what they really were.
And so the prisoners were now allowed
the freedom of the island.
The freedom to walk around at will.
And so what did the prisoners do?
Much to the surprise of the authorities
the prisoners had been in these cells for many years
at night they went back to their prison cells to sleep.
They felt frightened and lonely and insecure
even though for the first time in all these years
they had the freedom which they so ostensibly
had cried for and demanded over the years.
The sense of security then came from
the feeling of being back in the jail cell.
So to some of us a jail cell would be
the maximum threat.
Nothing, no greater horror could befall us.
And what have other people done in a prison cell?
They've written prize winning novels.
They've written staggering pieces
of literature.
Things written in jail cells and prisons
have changed the course and the history of mankind
for better or for worse.
Adolf Hitler after all wrote Mein Kampf
while in prison.
Another interesting example
in contrast to Devil's Island
is exemplified by the movie Lost Horizon.
You'll remember in that movie
which I remember well from childhood
I saw it a number of times
Ronald Coleman.
The other passengers of the plane
you know land in the Himalayas
and they go through a pass
and they come into Shangri-La
which represents a heavenly
almost a heavenly condition.
Its energy field is very high.
Probably up in the 600s.
A place of unconditional love
of unending bliss.
And although Ronald Coleman was ready
for the experience and himself benefited God
greatly and expanded his own consciousness
the other members of the passengers
took it in a different way.
It was interesting to watch of six different people
the six different reactions.
A couple of them weren't quite ready
for the experience.
Experienced it as sort of stress
due to its newness and its strangeness.
They felt stressed for a while
but then adjusted to it and accepted
sort of a heavenly condition in their life.
But several of the people were acutely
disturbed by it.
Remember the person who played
Ronald Coleman's brother in the movie
became almost paranoid and agitated.
Demanded to return to the real world.
And a person who was stranded there
from a previous plane accident
by that time had actually become paranoid
delusional and psychotic.
And so how it was experienced
by these different people then
represented not a reaction to where
they were but a reaction to their own position.
And what they were talking about then
was not what's out there
but their own level of consciousness.
I remember one time I was flying out of Ecuador
and at that time there were only two planes
a week going out of Ecuador.
And so I got there for the Thursday plane
and of course I had reservations
many months in advance.
When I got there the first thing they told me
was that my name wasn't on the list.
And the next thing they said was that
the plane was not leaving on Thursday this week anyway.
It wasn't leaving until Saturday.
Well, for some reason it just seemed to be humorous.
It seemed to be hilarious.
Somehow when you're in Ecuador
at 10,000 feet altitude and above
the fact that the plane is going to be late
in three days just doesn't mean a thing.
Nobody got upset about it.
And the interesting thing about the clock
in the airport which hung in the middle of the ceiling
was that the clock had stopped many years ago
and nobody had even bothered to fix it.
So you see the expectation then
what is stressful coming out of this attitude.
And so we had an easy going social attitude
in which precision within the material world
wasn't considered to be important.
Human values were of greater importance.
And because human values
because of the convenience of the crew, etc.
that was more important.
And so nobody seemed to mind.
If that had happened in a different social setting
LaGuardia airport let's say
that your Thursday plane is not leaving until Saturday
you would have experienced it as stress.
So the set and the setting, the expectation
the cultural attitude that you buy into.
In a different culture we buy a different attitude
and in that culture
this event was not even experienced as stressful.
As a matter of fact
when I got there for the Saturday noon plane
it was due to leave at quarter to twelve.
There was some kind of delay.
It was the only plane on the runway.
And the plane sat there
and then suddenly it was twelve o'clock.
At twelve o'clock they shut down for siesta.
So not only did the Thursday plane not leave until Saturday
it didn't leave at quarter to twelve
it left at three o'clock.
And so the plane sat there
while everybody took a siesta.
When the siesta was over
everybody gathered their stuff
got on the plane and away we went.
Nobody upset.
Everybody sort of totally relaxed at ease
at peace.
How can you be at peace
with a three day delay in your plane?
So within these experiences that we have cited
is the key
the key to the understanding of stress.
Because when we talk about stress
what we're really talking about then
is the experience of what is stressful within consciousness.
To consider the body
as part of a stress response
is a very late reaction.
The body is only responding
to what is held in mind.
The body is only responding to that which is held in mind.
And so by altering what we hold in mind
our expectations, our way of being with life
we can preclude the development of stress.
I didn't have to go to a relaxation program
to handle the stress
of the plane being three days late.
I didn't have to go to some kind of
coronary exercise program
to protect my heart from stress.
There wasn't any stress.
Consequently, the real approach to stress then
is to prevent it in the first place.
To preclude it.
To understand how it arises
and where it arises.
So our first understanding
and I think it's rather obvious by now
from the examples we've given
is that the source of what we experience as stress
is within ourself.
It does not exist in the world.
It doesn't exist in plane schedules.
It doesn't exist in prison cells.
Nowhere does it exist
except within our own consciousness.
And so we need to go back then to this map
to this field of consciousness
and understand it a little bit more closely
and then our awareness of this subject
will advance rather rapidly
because what we're talking about
is really easy to get.
It's something you really know already.
It's just that we're going to bring it into awareness.
We said that these energy fields
on the bottom which are
you might say adverse to life
destructive of life
we would call them stress
just by their own nature
that the energy field indicates a stressful direction.
That we move above it to neutral
we move in a positive direction
to that which is unstressful.
So that Shangri-La would be up here.
All things are experienced
in their beauty and perfection
the oneness of life
the unconditional love
and the lovingness.
So out of these energy fields
out of these energy fields
which are calibrated as to their relative power
to the right of it we see
the emotions that come out of that position
that way of being with life.
We see that those who are prone to guiltiness
for instance
the emotion is one of self-hatred.
The experience of life is that it is destructive
and as we said
what they see is a world of suffering.
They see a world of suffering.
The person who is holding this position
of apathy about life
the emotion is one of hopelessness.
Life is hopeless.
Life is despair.
There is a loss of energy.
The world is seen as hopeless
and the god of such a world is dead.
If we move out of apathy
if we pour enough energy into a person in apathy
we can get them up to grief.
Grief is a state in which you can express emotion.
It has a certain biologic purpose.
The expression of grief
like the crying of the child brings the mother
has a certain biologic purpose.
Those who are in that energy field
are looking to the past
and they see their life
filled with regret and loss.
They become dispirited.
They experience this as a sad world
and the god of that world ignores you.
We said that the person who is coming from
the suppressed energy field of fear
is looking to life
filled with worry and anxiety.
They experience life as frightening.
Now what is life?
This is a view of the world.
The view of life.
What is it?
What is the thing in and of itself?
Is it coming out of the event?
We see then that these fields of energy
are really portholes.
They are ways in which we see the world.
It is the color of the glasses that we put on.
If we put on gray glasses coming out of grief
everything looks sad.
A person walking down the street
who is coming from this energy field
sees everything on the street as hopeless.
He looks at man and man's conditions.
He opens the paper and he sees hopelessness.
Man's condition is hopeless.
As he walks down the street
he looks at the old people
and he sees how hopeless their condition is.
He looks at the children
and he sees how hopeless it is.
They are going to have to grow up
in a world of hopelessness.
The person who is sad
walks down the street
and they literally experience
their perception is one of sadness.
When they open the newspaper
they see all that there is
to be sad about in the world.
As they walk down the street
they see the sadness of man's condition.
They see the trash on the street.
They look at the old people
and they think how sad,
how sad aging is.
They look at the children
and they feel sorry for them.
They think how sad.
They pity the children,
the kind of a world
they are going to have to grow up in.
You know the pain of life.
They are holding so much pain
that the pity expresses itself now.
How sad for these children.
The person who is coming from
the energy field of fear
sees and experiences
and creates in his world
the experience of that which is fearful.
So the person opens the newspaper.
He reads the same newspaper
and he sees how fearful this world is.
Killings and murder
and muggings and war and bombings.
He walks down the street
and he sees how frightening is the world.
He sees the, you know,
the chance for accidents.
He sees people can twist their
ankle on the curb.
There should be warning signs all over.
The person who sees this
as a frightening world
double locks everything.
You know I know people
who double lock their car
within their own double lock garage,
within their own double lock yard
in an area which has never had a robbery.
Anyway, the fear then is coming from within
and it projects onto the world
a frightening appearance.
If you have got fear colored glasses,
everything looks like fear.
And if you search for God,
you would see a fearful God, you know.
The God of a frightening world
is someone to be afraid of.
The person who moves up in the street
into a higher energy field
of desiringness and wantingness,
often this comes about merely by education.
Let's say people at the bottom
into hopelessness through television,
the whole third world,
segments of the lowest socioeconomic groups
in our society in the last 20 years,
or 30 years.
When television came along,
began to see that which other people have.
What came up out of that was desire, desire.
This is felt in the emotional field then,
as wanting and craving.
This expresses itself in its fullest
in the addictions.
The process going on in consciousness
is one of entrapment
because once you desire something,
you begin to want it,
you then experience this world as frustrating.
So the stress then that this person experiences
is the endless frustration
because coming out of that sort of
solar plexus endless wantingness,
it's the person who is never satisfied,
no matter what they get.
They're always wanting something more.
If they get you to concede to their wishes,
they bring up more wishes.
It seems like it's an endless control
that they want over life.
They see this as a very frustrating world
and so as they walk down the street,
they see all the things they want.
They see the cars that they want,
they see the kind of appearance,
they see the appurtenances that they want,
they see the addresses that they want.
As they open the newspaper,
they're seeing all the things that they want.
They want to change the world they want to get.
So this endless addiction to getting this
then creates an endless stress.
This stress, as you see,
is coming from within the self.
There is no refusal on the part of the world
to come to you.
It's your endless desiringness for it.
The person who, out of this frustration then,
moves up to anger,
begins to experience this as an angry world.
They're full of resentment,
they're boiling over with hate and grievance.
What happens with a person like this
is the suppressed energy now of the angriness
is ready to spill forth in any event.
They see this world as competitive.
So to this person,
because of the kind of glasses they're wearing,
they're wearing angry glasses,
when they open the newspaper,
their stomach churns with wrath and indignation
and anger over the events that they're reading about.
As they walk down the street,
they see many things to be angry about.
All the conditions,
the conditions of the street signs,
the conditions of the street,
the newspapers there on the street now make them angry.
They look at the children, that makes them angry.
They look at the old folks.
They think of their conditions and they become angry.
So they live in a world of injustice,
indignation,
a competitive world,
if they have a used car lot,
you know, sell used cars.
If somebody else opens another used car lot down the street,
they consider this competition.
They look at it like lose,
they're going to lose
because these people live in a win-lose world.
Therefore, the stomach is always tense.
They haven't moved up to a higher level of harmony and cooperation.
Consequently, they don't realize
that the more used car lots on the street,
the better for business.
They would see it as competition.
So the world becomes a threatening place.
The god of that kind of a universe
would be the god of war.
So out of this angriness,
these are warlike people ready for combat.
They have a chip on their shoulder.
That anger is ready to burst forth.
The world is very stressful then.
Why?
Because of the suppressed anger.
So somebody should back into their fender in the parking lot.
Up comes the anger.
Up comes the cursing.
Up comes the threat of the lawsuit,
the angriness.
If a person can move up to pride,
and there's a lot of energy in pride,
you see these are all negative destructive emotions.
Pride, although we like to think of it as constructive,
in essence it is really destructive.
Why?
Because pride is denial.
Its expression is really one of arrogance and contempt.
And because the process going on in consciousness
is one of inflation.
The prideful person then becomes very polarized in his positions.
He's prideful like the angry person.
His position is right and they live in a world of right and wrong.
It's a world of win-lose.
Therefore there is always a stress going on within that person
because they see all relationships and interactions and transactions
in terms of win-lose.
And the win-lose is about status.
It has to do with
ownership.
So that person, when he reads the newspaper,
is seeing the status of all that is involved.
The status of the people that is being written about.
When he walks down the street, he sees nothing but symbols of status.
The labels on clothes,
the addresses,
all these things about life now become status.
And they're very interested in who you are
from a status viewpoint.
These are all vulnerable positions as you can see.
They're all positions
of victim really
because all of these positions below the level of truth
project the source of happiness as outside yourself.
It gives your power away.
It says the source of meaning,
the source of happiness,
the source of value is something outside myself.
It's somewhere out there.
It's coming from lack because it's saying if it's out there
it's something I have to get.
If it's something I have to get it means I lack it.
It means something could stand in my way.
And so to live in that kind of a world is to always live in danger.
Always live under threat
because something outside of yourself,
you can be blocked from it.
It can be taken away.
The world of victimhood.
Victimhood because we've given away our power to the world.
We say that the source of happiness is out there.
The source of stress is out there.
There's no hope for relieving stress by changing the world.
Why is that?
Because stress doesn't exist in the world.
Stress is an inexperience within consciousness itself.
There's no way you can change the world to relieve stress.
What can we do?
We can own, begin to own the truth about it,
to have the courage to look at the facts.
The minute we do that we change the energy field.
We see that the needle now goes to neutral.
We're coming out of destructive on our way into positive.
When we're willing to face something,
face the facts,
to face, cope and handle it,
what happens is we become re-empowered.
That means we begin to own back the power to ourself now.
We're coming closer to the truth.
And a prisoner who's on the level of courage,
what kind of a world does that person see?
They see a world of challenge, of growth and of opportunity.
An exciting, fun world.
A place where you're glad to be alive.
And so that same person opens the newspaper
and he sees all the tremendous opportunities
for man to move into and solve and resolve this problem.
And he has all kinds of problems,
you know, solving things in his own mind.
He just wishes he could try.
So it becomes an exciting world then of opportunity and growth,
which he begins to ask,
where can I fit in?
Where can I start expressing myself
and experiencing some of these opportunities?
The kind of a God that he experiences
of this world of opportunity
is a God of open-mindedness.
So the open mind now begins to change,
obviously, that which is stressful.
That which is stressful down here
becomes perhaps an object of curiosity
and an opportunity for growth to a person here.
Moving up to the next energy field we call neutral,
where the energy calibrates out at 250.
Look how much more power we have
than these positions up down below.
Not only more power, but we see that
that power is now being used in a constructive,
positive direction.
It's as though down here our antenna
is tuned to the negative.
Here it's turned to neutral.
Now we're tuning our antenna to the positive.
We begin to experience life in a positive direction
because we are the experiencer.
The experiencer is not out there.
It is within our own consciousness.
That person is willing to let go
a lot of their positions.
A lot of the positions that make this person
and person's life hell,
the sense of being always defensive
due to his pridefulness, his importance,
the sense of always being right,
the position of either the atheist
or the bigot or the zealot
that leads to all the religious wars.
You know, my position is right,
therefore your position is wrong.
The willingness to let that go,
the person becomes somewhat unattached.
They begin to transcend their vulnerability to the world.
The process going on in consciousness
is that they're released.
The world begins to look
okay to them.
The god of such a world now
is the god of freedom.
How is that okayness expressed?
Well, a person on this level,
on the way to a job interview,
would say, you know, if I get this job
it'll be great.
And if I don't, that's okay too
because there's other job opportunities
I would really like to look at.
And so he's not stuck, he hasn't put his
survival on any one particular thing.
Beginning to own
that the power is within myself.
As we move into willingness,
we add something else now
from the process of consciousness.
We add intention.
It means a yes-ness, a joining,
an alignment, an agreement with life.
And such a person
begins to see the world
as friendly.
So when these people walk down the street,
the god of that kind of a world
would become promising and hopeful.
Their experience now
in the newspaper
is they begin to open it up
and they see all the evidences
of man's cooperation,
man's struggle to solve its own problems.
They see what this person sees as destruction
as merely the process,
the working out of the balance of forces.
They begin to see
a friendlier world.
And so when they walk down the street
they see a friendly look.
You see their perception has changed.
They see the friendliness of old people.
Old people who no longer have to make it
in the world, you know, very often
are much more open to be friendly.
Simple to walk up to most older people
and strike up a conversation instantly.
They don't look at you with that paranoid distrust
or size you up and down to see where you stand
in a competitive, prideful world.
They begin to see
the old people as friendly.
They see the friendliness of the young children.
They become conscious of the fact
that children are friendly.
It's easy to strike up a relationship with them.
And so moving up
into acceptance then,
you really begin to accept that one
is the source of one's own experience of life.
As we've said in other talks,
a person who's reached
this level of awareness,
who's owned the power back over his own life,
realizes that no matter where you put him,
he's going to somehow make do.
You put him on a desert island,
you come back a year later,
you know he's carving coconuts,
and he's got a tree house.
You put him in a jail cell,
he'll write a novel,
or he'll sit cross-legged and go into meditation,
or he'll become a jailhouse lawyer
and get a law degree.
The power to create
my experience of life is within me.
The person has re-owned
their own power.
Consequently, such a God,
the God of that kind of a world
and universe of experience,
becomes not only promising and hopeful,
but merciful.
A merciful God no longer to be feared.
That person is adequate and confident.
We want that kind of a person
to go out after the big contract.
So that person is able to accept
the upside and the downside
and the realities of life
and can accept their own limitations.
You see, a person coming out of pride
can't accept that they are limited
and they have to come from a prideful,
macho position.
The person in acceptance,
when the company says,
we'd like you to go to Venezuela
and close such and such a deal,
a person who is adequate and confident
could say, you know,
I don't get along with that company
and I don't get along with that particular man.
You know, I do much better in Belgium.
You know, I can sell twice as much in Belgium.
Why don't you let Jim go down to Venezuela?
The willingness then to accept
how the world works.
They don't get into indignation.
You know, the IRS has its way
of being in the world.
They get out of right and wrong.
They just accept that's how it is in this world
and they go with it.
So, the beginning of transformation
of consciousness then
is the real realization
that I am the source
and therefore the world begins to look
harmonious and merciful.
That empowerment moves a person up then
to the next energy field of love.
What do we mean by love?
We don't mean the sentimental emotionalism
that comes out of the solar plexus attachment
of what Hollywood calls love.
That emotionalism
coming out of a possessive ownership
of the other person
and that back and forth control.
The subtle power struggles
that go on.
That enamored coming out of a song
that if you leave me I'll die kind of thing.
If you leave me I will die.
This is all coming out of an attachment
which has nothing to do with love.
We're talking about here unconditional love.
A way of being with life
that nurtures, supports
which is of its own nature forgiving.
It's the beginning of the revelation
of some of the truth of life
because within the brain
there's the release of endorphins.
Endorphins allow
a certain inner state
to occur, a way of being with oneself
and one's body and the world.
And now the world
starts to appear loving.
So that person walks down the street
feeling somewhat mellow.
They see the lovingness
that really goes on
underneath the apparent trivialities
they really see the lovingness
that holds all of mankind together.
They're moving into a higher energy field.
Seeing life as harmonious
seeing life as loving
you can see how much stress now
this person is vulnerable to
because they are coming
from a forgivingness.
That forgivingness
the coming out of the intention
of that feel which you choose for yourself
we call it lovingness.
We know that the person
coming out of lovingness
is loving towards all things
at all times.
Loving towards mankind.
Loving and nurturing towards oneself.
You see the difference
in how these people would view themselves.
The harshness
of the perfectionist
puts him always at stress
with his own human nature.
The unforgivingness
the capacity to judge and condemn
the self-hatred and guilt
means for that person
to breathe in and out
is to be in a state of stress.
If he gets up late
he blames himself for getting up late.
The stress is there
coming out of the perfectionism
the inflexibility
the capacity for self-condemnation.
And so the stress you see
is internally generated.
The open-minded person
that starts to become more easy with himself
begins to become accepting
of his own humaneness.
And as we move up to forgiveness
we have that mental attitude
of the readiness
to allow the humaneness
and when we do that
we allow our own humaneness.
We move up then
to an even higher energy field
of joyfulness
which is approaching the beginning awareness
of the reality of that
in which you really are.
That you are not the experience
you are the experiencer.
You are not at the effect of the world
you are the one that is determining
the way you experience it.
And so you develop a certain inner serenity
and out of this
passion towards all of life.
The beginning to see the incredible
beauty and perfection.
The experiencing of the oneness
and the unity of all life.
And so that one
so that person opens the newspaper
you see and experiences
the totality of man's lovingness
seeing that despite
his humaneness which is what is making
all the articles appear
in the paper.
The experience of that onward movement
the expression of the onward movement
and evolution of man's consciousness.
And so when that person walks down
the same street
he experiences only
the incredible beauty of it.
Experiencing the beauty of life
in all its magnificent expression.
As though you see
a rose in the middle of its unfoldingness.
See the perfectionist
would look at the half unfolded rose
and say I don't want that
that's an imperfect rose.
The person on this level
sees the perfection of the evolution of life
itself and sees all of life
as that half unfolded rose.
That in one second
there is only a cross section
but projects forward in time
and sees the unfoldingness
and the incredible beauty and precision
and becomes aware
inwardly of the inner sacredness
of all life.
It's obvious then as we talk about
these energy fields
as these levels of consciousness
that they are determining
how we experience life.
They are determining
what kind of a God we think
exists in the universe.
These energy fields are determining
the kind of emotions
which we are expressing.
All of this expressing
a process going on
within consciousness itself.
It certainly is very clear to us now
that there is nothing
out there
that has the power
to create stress.
That we ourselves
are the creators of stress
by the positions
by our attitudes.
It's obvious that the open minded
easy going person
doesn't experience stress
when somebody backs into his fender
in the parking lot.
What happens, you've experienced it yourself
when you're in a good mood.
You see what is stressful in one mood
is not stressful in another.
And so I came out myself
one day to the parking lot
and there was somebody
who was the only offender.
And the person was very upset.
And frankly my only concern
was the upsetness of this person.
And I kept telling them
there's nothing to be upset about.
I mean it's only offender.
We both got insurance.
It's no big deal.
So it's a little nuisance
you've got to take your car
to the body shop and get it fixed.
But it's really no big deal.
So it was the getting
and the desire to heal that upset
that arose in the field
of my own consciousness.
So whether it's something
that sends you into self pity
about what an unjust world this is
that people back into your fender.
Whether you want to punch the guy
in the nose because you've got
so much anger in yourself.
Whether you're concerned
in just handling the facts involved
with no particular feeling.
The detached person would just handle
this with no particular feeling.
They just want to support life
and relieve their anxiety and their fear.
All of that you see is coming out
of who you are.
It doesn't exist in the world.
A dented fender therefore has no power
over your life.
We've just taken its power away.
We've just owned it back within ourself.
And we've just precluded
the sources of stress
by just the realization
about what we've talked about thus far.
A certain state of inner peace then
automatically comes up
of our willingness to give up
certain positions.
Our willingness to give up judging others.
Making them wrong.
Our willingness then to come from
a forgiving understanding position.
You see, right or wrong
doesn't really solve anything, does it?
The willingness to accept people
as they are.
If we come from this position here
making them wrong
we live in a world of win-lose.
The people at the bottom here
are coming from a world
of lose-lose.
This is a world where I lose
and the company loses.
In the middle of the
energy field here
we come from positions
which result in
win-lose.
It means if I win, you lose, etc.
It's stressful
by the context.
It's stressful in the very way
that it's set up.
Because even if you win
you have to go through the anxiety of losing.
So even winning doesn't win.
Even winning doesn't win.
We know that people, for instance,
who say, I want to have a lot of money
what happens to them
when you give them a lot of money?
Well, some interesting research has been done
on people who win
millions of dollars
in big lotteries and all.
We find out that within five years
a five-year follow-up
that the degree of happiness in this group of people
was dismal.
The suicide rate,
the divorce rate,
the sickness rate,
the addiction to drugs
had risen spectacularly in these people
who had gotten ostensibly
the very thing they wanted.
The reason they played the lottery
was to win.
The win-lose game, you see,
because if you structure things as win-lose
then to win in itself
means to defeat others.
To defeat others brings up what?
Brings up guilt.
And so you can't even be happy in winning
or losing.
In the win-lose context,
if I win, then you are defeated
and I have to put up with the guilt of that defeat.
If I win in competition,
I then have to go into fear
because in competition
I then expect retaliation
from my enemy, from my opponent.
So I may have defeated him this time
but now I worry whether his friends
are out to get me.
And so these are really sort of paranoid positions,
depressed, paranoid positions.
At the bottom of the box,
that is a hopeless, sinful world.
In the middle,
we have win-lose with the anxiety,
the stress that automatically comes out of
a win-lose position.
As we move towards the top of the box,
those positions of great success
and power in the world automatically
come to those who think in terms of
win-win.
Because they are coming from that position,
they then set up
within their own mind
a way of being in the world
and a way for others to be in their life
and automatically win-win.
What kind of stress then
does the person experience
who is setting up everything
as win-win?
The person wins if they come over to your house
and they win if they don't.
If they come over to your house,
what you hold is how much
you're going to enjoy their friendship
and their presence.
And at the same time you let them know
if you can't make it, that's great
because I've got a book I'm working on
and I can use the time.
The other person in your life now
wins either way.
If they come for dinner,
you're delighted with their presence.
If they don't come for dinner,
you've given them the free time
to do something that you know
will enhance their life.
So everybody wins.
So to hold all one's positions
in business for instance,
in a situation,
you can imagine how successful it is.
If my position is,
the marketer wins,
the magazine wins,
all of our bank accounts win,
our status wins,
the alliance wins,
if I set it up so that everybody wins
then I have no enemies.
Because I have no enemies,
you see, there is no negative energy
opposing the direction of the positive support of life.
Then that flourishes,
that flows forth.
So all of life then is experienced
as an enhancement of life.
To hold life then from a win-win position.
So one of the things,
one of the good implications
for a well- escuelaed brand
is that there's a lot of
win-win situation all around and one of acknowledged great success way to become
a success is to make your boss a success instead of going into competition with
them you see in which somebody is bound to lose making your boss a success moves
him up the ladder and creates a space for you to move up to come from a
competitive position would mean to defeat the boss that would bring up the
unconscious anxiety distress of the fear of retaliation in a war as you
picture it a war then you've defeated the opponent and of course now his
friends are going to come and get you and so you would have to live ever after
in a position of danger and defensiveness so there's willingness
then to give up the adversary position to become more easygoing you can see the
amount of stress experienced by the easygoing person does easygoing mean
vulnerable
does it mean being stupid not at all the easygoing person see the person up
here on the level of acceptance sort of accepts what new human nature is like
accepts what the world is like and prepares prepares for the alternates to
come up I remember one time in fact several times three times already I was
audited by the IRS so a lot of people go into a terrible state of fear at this
prospect and they go into an adversary position and all kinds of stress comes
up now as we said stress does not exist in the outer world but your attitude
about it hmm I had a different reaction I was sort of excited I'd never been
audited before I don't know why they never audited me but for 30 years when I
was making pretty good money in the world nobody bothered to audit me and
then one year the computer picked it out so I thought well here's a chance to
find out you know how well I've been doing
I sort of looked at it sort of happily I thought here's a chance to find out you
know if I'm doing things correctly and if not what I can do about it and so I
really prepared for this I really spent a couple of weeks I went out and I
bought fancy notebooks in which I had everything prepared for him and I put it
in celluloid pages so that you know the accountant told me what he would be
interested in so then I had labels on the front of it and I had coffee ready
and when he got there it was he was like an honored guest you know and I
escorted him into the library
and gave him you know the best desk and the best coffee and the best cup and
saucer not out of bettering up buttering him up but really respect for his
position because I could see you know how painful it must be to be a tax
auditor you know everybody hates you everybody's frightened of you so my
heart sort of went out to the guy and I really wanted his day to be a good day
so everything was you know ready for him and I really treated him you know like
an honored guest well he was so pleased and as the day went on I
had my way of looking at things he had his way of looking at things and we had
sort of a friendly talk at it and we sort of did a swap and so at the end of
the day he folded his things and he got to leave early he got to leave early
because I didn't have and hand him a box full of receipts which would be
unloving and disrespectful I didn't have him and him a box of stuff you know it's
up to you to find it I prepared it for him you see and so he had a great day
and by making his day a great day I had an enjoyable day and I had a great day
he had an enjoyable day he said you know I really hate to leave three o'clock in
the afternoon he said but you know frankly we're all done now the computer
picked me up again the following year and we went through the same process and
again the auditor and I agreed on everything in both years I got a letter
that accepted the return as filed and it's always been that way with the IRS
I've always experienced them as very friendly very helpful very positive in
their attitude and I suppose it's because that's how
it's being held in consciousness itself to treat everybody who comes into your
life as a guest and to treat them as well as you can to treat them royally if
possible and so to become easygoing then is not to see danger in the world to get
out of the habit of seeing danger but the person says who worships fear and
thinks his fear you know fear is what's kept them alive in this planet what
about the downside of life well we said the easygoing person
the one who is really confident and adequate is able to accept the downside
is able to accept the possibility of the downside of human nature and doesn't
have to deny it and so what is looking at the downside then it's preparing for
what if it's preparing for what if the plane doesn't leave on Thursday it's
preparing for the what-ifs in life for creating an opportunity to handle the
other side the opportunity to handle the other side the opportunity to handle the
opportunities that would arise now the way to find out the source of stress
very easily is to take along a book that you are really into reading or a
magazine article when you're driving to work you know on the parkway and the city
traffic the stress of the endless delays in traffic most people will tell you you
know the terrible stress of driving in New York City the terrible stress of
driving in Phoenix I never experienced it as stressful on the contrary I always
have something next to me that I can't handle and I can't handle and I can't
handle and I can't handle and I can't handle and I'm just dying to read so if
I'm just dying to read so if you want to see how fast time goes in a traffic
you want to see how fast time goes in a traffic delay have something that you're
delay have something that you're reading the minute the light turns red
reading the minute the light turns red you pull it out and you start reading it
you pull it out and you start reading it it's always in no time it seems like
it's always in no time it seems like half a second the darn thing is green
half a second the darn thing is green again it used to be that the red was
again it used to be that the red was stressful now the green is stressful
stressful now the green is stressful isn't that interesting same stoplight is
isn't that interesting same stoplight is the red stressful or is the green
the red stressful or is the green stressful huh that gives us a key on how
to get rid of stress. And there is the secret. When my car was getting fixed, you know, I
had an office in New York City and I lived out on Long Island. And there was a time when
I was putting in a new transmission on a nice old Imperial. I didn't want to junk it. So
anyway, it was up on the rack for weeks. And during that time, I had to stand in the long
queues. I had to take the bus. The bus took you to the subway. The subway took you to
another subway. The other subway took you uptown. Lots of delays and waiting, you know,
the endless queue waiting for the bus. But I always had a pocketbook that I was dying
to read. And so while other people were champing and feeling the terrible stress, the delay
of the bus and all, you know, time just flew by because I was enjoying the novel so much.
And during that two or three weeks, I guess it was close to a month even, I read more
books than I've ever read in my life. I read three books a day. I read a book a week a
day. I read a book a week a week. I read a book a week a week. I read a book a week a
on the way in on the subway in a way a book on the way home on this that way
and another book in the evening and I knocked off about 50 books over there
and I was really sad when they finally fixed the car I felt a loss I thought oh
there goes my opportunity to do all that wonderful reading that I've been looking
forward to all this time and so you see the capacity then within us to create an
enjoyable because I really enjoyed waiting for the bus I really look
forward to it every morning I go out there and now conflict free because
after all there wasn't anything else I could be doing I had a conflict free
area in which I could enjoy myself catch up on things really enjoy life so
instead of feeling stress you know blowing out my acupuncture meridians in a
frustration trying to change the world change life what was created was an
opportunity to experience another aspect of life when we go into a neighborhood
and we see
you know the zoning sign that says no children or pets what does that mean no
children or pets it means that we have adopted within ourself we people who
live in the no children or pets and neighborhood the idea that children and
pets are stressful hmm that's merely a point of view is it not there are other
people who would consider the lack of children and pets stressful to have no
children note the sound of no children around
they have no pets to greet you when you walk in the door at night at night would
be considered stressful people come home to their part to an empty apartment so I
know people say I can't stand coming home to an empty apartment you know
drives me crazy they have to have the TV on the radio on the lights going a lot
of action in their life to another person that would be very stressful some
people like silence you know some people never turn on the television never turn
on the radio that constant noise in the background that's not a good part of your life
to them interferes with their concentration people who are into sort
of contemplative type of lives these distractions would then be experienced
as stressful the presence of small children the playing of the TV would
drive them crazy another source of stress is coming from that which is
unexpected in other words to not look at the alternatives and to provide for them
if we look at what is the downside of a situation what if the contract falls
through what if the person I'm going to meet isn't on the street corner to
provide for the alternatives so to offset this source of stress in the very
beginning so often the unexpected is experienced as stress we didn't expect
that to happen the open-minded person sees the many alternatives of what could
be and provides how to handle
you
, the unexpected before it occurs we were talking about whether music is
experienced as stressful or not and we come upon a law called the law of
initial stimulus the law of initial value correction the law of
initial value states that the power you see is not in the stimulus but has to do
with the setup of the organism the pre-existing condition
of the function of the patient so the response then depends not just on the
intensity of the stimulus but on the position of the organism with which it's
interacting for instance in pharmacology it would be senseless than
to ask you know what is the effect of 25 milligrams of or Tik the effect of 25
milligrams of or team would depend on the pre-existing condition of the patient did the person was somewhat in Apathy and dull.
27 kilograms or 15 milligrams of 21 milligrams of intimacy would야 Sudden body energy.
25 milligrams of Thorazine may put them out and unconscious for three days.
If the person was in a terribly agitated state, 25 milligrams of Thorazine may have no effect.
If the person is in a state of mild anxiety, 25 milligrams of Thorazine might be quite
effective.
So what we're saying then is the preset condition, the amount of suppressed energy that the person
is holding, their attitudes, their belief systems, determine then what the effect will
be of the same stimulus.
Some people say loud music drives me crazy.
Well, we look at teenagers, they put on earphones, they lie down, they turn the volume way up
and they go into a state of delight.
So is loud music stressful or not?
So we come down to a real basic principle then of what is stress.
We don't experience stress when it's what we want.
And we experience it as stress when we don't want it.
Consequently, when you're in the mood for loud music, you're in a high state, you turn
it up and you want to dance around the living room, get all ready for a party, loud music
contributes to your state of joy and aliveness.
If on the other hand you're tired and exhausted and you've had a hard day at the office, the
same loud music would be experienced as stressful.
The fact that you want it, that you desire it, is what determines it.
It determines whether a thing is stressful or not.
So we can repeat that to ourself and start to move beyond the vulnerability to stress.
We can say to ourself, it's really very simple, stress is resisting what I don't want and not
stress is getting what I want.
We move into sort of an easy going attitude then because now we realize that really the
problem is within ourselves to merely shift our attitude.
And one way we can shift it is to move up into this field up here, a certain, the choosing
of a lovingness towards life because around the middle of the 500 energy field at around
550 we have an energy field called humor.
Humor at 550, the capacity to laugh at ourself, to laugh at the nature of life itself, to
love and laugh at the comedy of it all, that's the value of the great humorous.
And the great humorous tend to be long-lived.
The capacity to hold lightly, to see with enjoyment the qualities of life.
So a person coming from that position then opens the newspaper and breaks it into laughter.
I mean the comedy of it all.
The futility with which people are trying to solve certain types of problems because
now that you understand something about the nature of consciousness, you see that all
is being reflected out.
You see that there is an energy field, that they are like Don Quixote, fighting their
own projections in the world.
This is really their own negative viewpoints that they project on the world and they then
spend the rest of their life battling that which they have projected out there.
So the comedy of it all, that's the basis of all humor, you know, laughing at those
qualities of life, holding them from a position which exposes the paradox.
Because humor is seeing the paradox, the funniness of it, the humor of it, to hold lightly.
We don't have to become at the effect then of anything out there whatsoever.
It's we ourselves who determine by our attitudes, by our position, whether life is experienced
as joyful and harmonious, easygoing, or whether we experience it as our enemy.
The willingness to go with it.
Go with it.
We begin to admire people who are capable and easygoing.
You see, the objection comes up, well, the easygoing person, aren't they a pushover,
you know, in business?
The misunderstanding of what easygoingness means.
No, easygoing means acceptance.
It means to be adequate.
If you can see the humor of life, if you feel adequate and solid within yourself, if you
realize that you're the source of how you experience life.
Then you can handle those things which the world considers difficult with ease.
You can be the boss, and if the janitor doesn't show up, it doesn't bother you at all.
When the business closes for the day, you take off your coat, roll up your sleeves, and
you sweep it out.
It doesn't make any difference.
Why?
Because that which I am is unaffected by all that.
The truth is that I am that which experiences experience.
The realization that I am the experiencer of experience.
That that's where I live.
I live within my consciousness.
It doesn't make any difference.
Whether I surround myself with appurtenances that look important, or whether I roll up
my sleeves and I sweep out the office myself, that which I am is totally unaffected.
That which I am is just enjoying the experience of its own existence.
Enjoying one's own inner aliveness.
Stress just doesn't exist in that kind of a position about the world, where we clearly
identify who we really are.
When we stop identifying with the body as being who we are, we pointed out right in the
very beginning, the body is half a dozen times removed from the reality of who we are.
When we stop identifying with the events out there, when we stop giving them power over
our life, then comes an inner serenity.
You know, it's like the solar plexus can relax at last.
We're out of danger.
We've sort of transcended the world.
We've learned what the source of stress is.
Just knowing what the source of stress is already makes us immune to it, already moves
us into a different way of being with life, allows us to see it as our own creation.