I'm Dr. David Hawkins. I've been a psychiatrist for the last 35 years.
I've worked in the field of psychoanalysis, all kinds of psychotherapy,
done research on the relationship between nutrition and brain chemistry
and its relationship to emotions and emotional and mental disorders.
And for the last 10 years, I've been doing research on the nature of consciousness itself
and its extensions into that field of knowledge man calls spiritual.
In our talk today, we'll be talking about how to meet the major crises of life.
Death, divorce, separation, disfigurement, injury, accident, catastrophe.
Those serious things which result in emotional overwhelms.
What techniques can we utilize to handle these experiences?
And in doing that, we'll be referring, as we have in these other talks,
to a map of consciousness.
A map of consciousness, which gives us a point of reference
and allows us a greater understanding of what we'll be talking about today.
And in this map, you'll see it's a mathematical model.
Within the box, this represents the human ego, the self with a small self,
are various levels of consciousness.
And they're named according to common human experience.
Guilt and apathy and grief and fear, desire, anger, pride, courage,
willingness, acceptance.
Love, joy.
As we get towards the top, we reach, we get closer and closer to the truth.
And as we get to the bottom, we get farther and farther from the truth.
And you'll notice that death is calibrated at zero.
Enlightenment at 600.
And so these numbers indicate the relative energies, the power of these energy fields.
So that apathy is, for instance, half as powerful as fear.
Fear has half the energy of courage.
And neutral has half the energy of love.
And so on.
So that we can get a feeling for the relative power of these different positions.
They're really coming out of points of view.
You'll notice that there are arrows.
So that everything below courage, you'll notice all the arrows go to the left.
Indicating that the effect is destructive, that the effect is anti-life,
does not support life, and is in violation of the truth.
Hmm.
And when we pass above the level of truth, which is courage,
we'll notice that the needle swings to the middle.
And as we get beyond that, into areas of lovingness,
we'll notice that the arrows go to the right.
Indicating that these energy fields nurture and support life, and are aligned with the truth.
In the subject for today, acute catastrophic experiences, which are overwhelming,
we'll be referring to these energy fields then,
for a greater understanding.
Because we'll be talking about techniques with which to handle these emotional overwhelms.
In these experiences, life suddenly becomes a nightmare.
When it's suddenly overwhelmed by an emotional storm.
How to handle this acute event.
How to shorten the period, and how to relieve the pain and suffering.
Diminish it to the minimum, will be the techniques we're talking about today.
All of these major life experiences,
have something in common.
They all represent, to the mind, a major loss.
An acute catastrophic loss.
They all indicate a major change.
And they all have in common, the feeling of powerlessness.
Because of their permanency, the mind gets that it cannot do anything about it.
That it is stopped.
And it is this phenomenon of being stopped, the permanence, the fact that one is powerless,
and cannot change.
And cannot change the event, that is partially responsible, for the acute upset.
And how to handle this, will depend on our orientation to the subject.
And our knowledge of the whole field of consciousness.
All of these experiences, unleash a storm of negative feelings.
Shock, disbelief, denial, anger, guilt, attempts at undoing, self-blame, resentment, feelings of abandonment,
rage at God and oneself, self-pity, rage at the world, rage at the family.
All these negative emotions surface and come on at once.
Sometimes in sequence, sometimes in combination.
But in general, there is a massive overwhelm of negative emotions.
That they all share in common.
The acute separation, the acute sense of loss, the acute sense of overwhelm.
And the sequencing of first the shock, then the resentment,
the disbelief, the anger. The sequencing of these varies from experience to experience and person
to person. Their exact sequence is immaterial. What is significant is that they are unleashing
of everything at the bottom of the box. We said that everything in the bottom of the box,
the energy field, is in a negative direction. And when one of these energy fields becomes
strong, it tends to pull the rest with it. So that grief over loss then seems to bring with it
guilt, senses of hopelessness, fear of the future, desire to change the whole thing, anger.
The whole negative energy field is unleashed in one giant emergency, and the emergency really is
one of energy. The problem is really being that of being overwhelmed by a massive unleashing of
energy.
The mind tries to use reason. It tries to think its way out of this dilemma. It tries to find
explanations and reasons. It can't succeed in this because the energy field overwhelm is so massive
that the thoughts become merely a reflection of the negativity of the energy field. And therefore,
the thoughts themselves become negative. So now one is beset by an overwhelm of energy,
an overwhelm of negative energy. And then one is beset by the overwhelming of negative energy.
So one is beset by an overwhelm of negative energy. And now one is beset by an overwhelm of negative energy.
of negative emotion and an overwhelm of negative thoughts. How to meet this crisis is our talk for
today. Another thing that all these experiences share in common is that they are all at the top
of life stress rating scales. You know there are scales that rate numerically from zero to a hundred.
The degree of stress of certain life events and the ones that we're talking about today are all
at the top of the list. Death of a spouse, death of a child, death of a family member, divorce, all of
these rate 100 on the rating scale. The other ones we mentioned rate maybe 95 to 96, 97. So the ones
we're talking about today are the maximal catastrophes which we can face in our whole
experiences of life. How to convert these into acute gains, how to maximize them, how to use them
as a springboard.
For a major leap in consciousness. We need to look then at consciousness itself and as we have in
other talks we'll be talking about the relationship between body, mind and spirit. What is that
relationship? What is its exact nature and how can it be helpful to us in our understanding of today's
topic? And so we'll review again as we have in the other talks the fact that the body is unable to
experience itself. The body has no capacity to experience.
It changes.
It just is. It is actually insentient. How do we know where the body is? Well, because of sensations.
We don't experience the body. We experience sensations of the body. Sensations themselves have no way of
being experienced. They're experienced in something greater than themselves and that is in mind itself.
Our awareness of what is going on in body then is because it's being reported and experienced within mind.
Now, mind itself has no capacity within itself to experience itself. That seems like a shocking thought.
But a memory cannot experience its own memoryness. A thought cannot experience its own thoughtness.
Feelings cannot experience their own feelingness. It's because they are experienced in something greater than mind
and that is consciousness itself. It is because of consciousness that you're aware of what is going on in mind.
Mind then reports what is going on with sensations. Sensations report what is going on with the body.
And so where we are experiencing then is several levels removed from the body itself.
Consciousness itself is unable to actually experience itself. It is because of an absolute energy field beyond that called knowingness.
That which is absolute that we are aware then and know what is going on within consciousness which is reporting
what is going on in mind, which is reporting what is going on in sensations, which is reporting what goes on with the body.
And therefore where we experience, that which we really are, is considerably removed from the physical body itself.
It is because experiencing is going on within consciousness that we can address the solution to human problems
directly within the field of consciousness itself, thereby effectively shortening and relieving the amount
of pain and suffering and bringing about a far more effective result.
We saw the result of this technique and this approach in our talks on the handling of physical pain and sickness and suffering,
of depression, anxiety and fear. And the same technique will work in meeting these acute emotional catastrophic emergencies.
Where you actually live is in the experience of your own experiencing.
A person thinks, well, I live in the world, I'm experiencing the world.
The world is coming in and it's being registered in your experience of your experience of it.
We can handle anything if we address then this exact focus.
If we focus on where we're experiencing experience, we can handle things with precision.
We can in moments and minutes handle things that would take weeks, months, years and in fact lifetimes.
We can handle within an hour a thing that others have been unable to handle in an entire lifetime.
We know people who have had these catastrophic events early in life and we see them in older age and it's still not over with them.
The resentment, the bitterness, the anger, the disillusionment, the rage, the major decisions that come out of those negative feelings
are still with the person 50 years later.
It's as though the event happened yesterday.
It's still unhealed.
It's still undone.
There hasn't been the knowledge present of how to handle this overwhelm.
And so today we're talking about directly how to handle the overwhelm at the level at which it is being experienced.
To look at the experiencing, the field of the experiencing and to be aware where experiencing is happening.
Experiencing is not happening out in the world.
Experience is not happening in your foot.
It's not happening in yourself.
It's not happening in your stomach.
It's happening within consciousness.
And as you examine where you experience experience, you'll find that it's everywhere.
We don't experience things in a focal point.
That's a belief system of the mind.
For instance, if I say to someone who hasn't looked into this, where do you experience your thoughts?
Out of habit, the person points to their head and says here, that's a belief system.
That's your thought about thoughts.
You think your thoughts here, but that's only a thought.
Where do you think that thought, that your thoughts are thought here?
As you really go into it and introspect a little bit with a little contemplation and reflection,
you'll see that experiencing is diffuse, that it's going on everywhere.
If you had to put your finger on where is experiencing happening, you cannot put your finger on any particular place.
It's like everywhere and nowhere simultaneously.
And it is that particular point which we'll be working with today.
In doing this, we'll say something surprising, but something that makes this kind of work precise.
I know because I've worked with it clinically for over 30 years.
I know because I've been through most of the major life crises myself.
In fact, in the last few years, I've been through half a dozen.
And so I will share my own experience of the truth of these things
because all of them can be experienced within yourself.
The only thing that you have to handle in these acute catastrophic events is the emotions themselves.
The energy of the emotion is the only thing you have to handle.
That sounds surprising?
It's a fact.
It's a fact that if we look at the experience, we'll see it's not the event that happened in the world
or that we think has happened in the world that is our problem.
It's the way we feel about it.
Is it not?
Who cares about facts?
Facts don't mean anything in and of themselves.
It's your emotional reaction to the fact.
A fact is only a fact.
It's a nothing.
It's how we feel about that fact.
And so therefore, the only thing we really ever have to handle about the events in life is our feelings.
Our feelings come from our attitudes, our beliefs, our way of being with that,
the way we view ourself and the world.
So that will give a variety to the emotions.
But in an overwhelm, our problem is going to be handling just the emotional energy itself.
We don't even really have to handle the emotions.
All we have to handle is the energy of the emotions.
Yes, you say, but what about the events out there?
What am I going to do now with no money?
What am I going to do with no husband, etc., etc.?
Surprisingly, the events are very easy to handle.
There is no acute catastrophe that the events themselves are merely just handled in a mechanical way.
Once the feelings are aside, you may have reluctance, you may have some resentment, you may have regret.
But these are minor things.
The handling of the actual issues within the phenomenal world, within your daily life, are going to be easy.
They're not the real problem.
The thought that they are a real problem is just coming out of the negative emotions.
The fact that they seem catastrophic and hopeless and unbearable and insurmountable is merely coming out of the energy field of the emotions.
Once you come out on the other side of it, life adjusts itself.
Life adjusts itself.
Something else comes in to fill the vacuum.
Life goes right on.
I go right on doing carpentry work even though I lost the thumb that was essential to doing it all of my life.
The problem is really not how am I going to learn to do carpentry again.
The problem is really not where am I going to start another business again.
How am I going to start earning money again.
Those are simple.
Those are simple once the emotions are out of the way.
Life presents the solutions to all problems.
Necessity is the mother of invention.
So whatever the dilemma is that appears in one's life, it will resolve itself.
You will meet somebody new.
The energy of life resumes.
Life goes right on no matter how major the catastrophe seems at the moment.
So our problem is not handling the event out there, not handling the circumstances of life.
They will handle themselves.
In fact, usually relatives will handle it for you while you are knocked out of the box by the overwhelm.
The problem then is handling the energies which are arising.
We said once one of these major negative energy fields releases itself, starts to unleash itself,
that it tends to drag the rest with it.
Rarely do you experience grief alone.
There is also almost always guilt.
Grief is associated with that.
Blaming yourself.
Why didn't I look, you know, as I went around the turn, why didn't I put chains on?
Why didn't I take her to the doctor sooner?
Maybe we could have cured her cancer.
Why did I bet on that horse?
Sort of a retrospective self-recrimination.
There is also apathy, hopelessness.
Life is hopeless.
Life seems hopeless.
It looks like we will never be happy again, like the source of happiness has left our life.
Of course, the grief is natural to the loss.
And then there are the fears that arise.
How will I live without whatever it is that I have lost?
The constant, incessant desire drives us crazy to try and change it.
What can we do?
The bargaining, the trying to manipulate, the arguing with God, the making bargains with God.
Oh God, if you only let so and so live, I will do this and that.
Then the anger, the rage at life, at the nature of life.
Anger displaced onto the people of life.
It's the doctor's fault.
Let's sue the doctor if the patient died.
The anger at the spouse for having disrupted the marriage and lifestyle.
All of these negative energies usually unleash all at once.
And from moment to moment, one or the other may be dominant.
As we said before, at the same time, the mind is thrashing around wildly,
trying to come up with explanations, trying to figure it out.
We are swamped by the overflow of the mind.
Overflow of energy.
The problem is that the energy is too much for the apparatus to handle.
It goes into disorganization, into biologic overwhelm.
And the acute stress throws the person into acute emergency emotions and an acute emergency state,
especially to work in consciousness itself.
The problems are not best handled on the level at which they seem to be occurring,
but on the next higher energy level.
Higher energy means greater power.
Handle there.
It handles it automatically on the lower levels.
All we have to handle then are the energies of the emotional overwhelm.
Does that sound surprising for a psychiatrist to say that?
Most people would expect that a psychiatrist would begin talking about the psychology.
The psychology, the intricate relationship between the person and these events and what they mean symbolically.
The psychological components.
But we're going to bypass all that.
We're going to talk about the fact that the emotions that are released, whatever the psychology,
it makes no difference.
It makes no difference.
What's happening is a massive release of these negative emotions.
And what is it about the emotions that we're interested in is the energy of the emotions.
And so the technique which we found very, very effective is this.
We ignore the thoughts.
Why?
Because the mind is never going to figure it out.
The mind does not have the capacity to figure it out and handle it.
It is in a massive overwhelm.
The issues are extraordinarily complex.
And to unravel it would take a lifetime if you really wanted to know the full significance
and every contribution from every level of one's psychological self to the total meaning of these experiences.
We don't really have to do that.
And it's a very good thing that we don't.
We only have to go into the feeling itself.
Notice that the feeling is being felt in a general way.
We notice that the feeling has below it an energy.
It's as though consciousness works this way.
It's as though there's a diffuse body of energy which really has no name.
We could call it the energy of emotionalism.
The energy behind feelingness.
Given a moment of time, this diffuse, unnamed energy will begin to take form.
It will begin to take the form, let's say, of grief or anger or rage or indignation, self-pity, whatever, jealousy.
This emotional feel which now has some kind of form.
And we'll see.
At first it's diffuse and formless.
But it now begins to take something of the form of grief.
But there's also some fear in that.
There's also some anger in it.
It's sort of diffuse.
It's sort of, we might call it, the energy of negative emotions in general.
Allow it a split second longer and it will now take a greater form.
Let's say a specific fear.
You know, how will I live now without money or something?
The fear begins to take form.
And then out of the specific emotion, let us say in this case fear, thoughts begin to arise.
So it's like a sequence of events.
It's like an ocean of suppressed energy.
And what we'll be doing today is talking about how to decompress it.
How to decompress it.
If we can cut the fuse, if we can pull the plug, then we've disconnected the whole experience.
And we're left then with an inner state of peace.
So what I'd like you to do today is to accept, to take my word for the fact that you don't have to do anything about the external events.
You don't have to figure it out.
You can't make any progress by looking at the thoughts because they are endless.
You're not really going to get much headway in handling it by looking at the specific emotion.
But you will get a very profound effect if you allow yourself to focus on the energy below the upset.
As you catch the experience earlier and earlier, you will get that this energy is diffuse.
It's almost nameless.
It's like a container of...
...pressurized gas that's seeking release.
And this pressurized emotion, the energy of it, has been accumulating for a lifetime.
It's all the suppressed emotion that has accumulated up to this point in time.
And it now has an out.
So the event that has happened in life has opened the sluices, has opened the gates, has opened the doorway.
And all this container of compressed, suppressed...
...emotional energy is now using this opportunity to escape.
Once the barn door is open, all the animals run out.
How to get out of the way of these running animals?
You can't.
One way to cut through it quickly is to accept the fact that you can't escape this experience.
Trying to escape it only prolongs it.
It would seem the mind will try to figure out ways to escape it as though that will reduce the pain.
Actually, the pain comes from resisting the experience.
The pain comes from resisting it.
And so we'll use somewhat the same technique we did with physical pain.
Where we surrender, we let go resisting this energy field.
We just sit down and let go resisting it and choose to be with it.
The faster we open it up, the faster we let that energy out, the quicker the experience will be over.
Instead of dragging it out endlessly, agonizingly...
...over the hours and the weeks and the days.
And the months and the years.
In fact, the whole lifetime.
The whole thing can be let go of.
Remember we said when somebody had an acute injury to their hand.
Let's say a burn.
If the person stops everything and does this very same practice.
Let's go resisting.
Just opens the door and welcomes in and says, in fact, I want more of it.
Of the energy of that experience and ignores what goes on in mind.
Ignores thoughts.
But allows themselves merely to experience it.
To experience this energy field.
Your mind will say, well I'm experiencing grief.
That's a label.
So we'll say all thoughts are labels and they have no reality.
In reality, none of these things exist.
These are all labels we've put on things.
To say that it is grief and the mind expects if a loved one dies.
Automatically it says, grief.
Grief is a label.
Mind having the power that it does over emotions.
Mind having the capacity to give it form.
The belief that to lose someone is automatically therefore grief.
Gives form to the emotion.
The energy field of the emotions is actually form less.
But we insist that it's grief.
It then takes the form of grief.
If somebody holds a gun to our head.
We're convinced naturally in mind.
That this calls for fear.
And therefore the same energy now assumes a somewhat different form.
Labeled fear.
We want to decrease the form of the energy field.
And stop labeling it anything.
We don't tell people, you know, I'm going through grief.
I'm going through fear.
I'm going through an upset.
Upset is closer to the truth.
Upset is a general term.
Because it's very hard to say what the emotion is in an acute upset.
Initially what is experienced usually is a sense of shock.
A sense of numbness.
A sense of disbelief.
Can't believe that this happened.
That's the moment to begin this practice.
To know about it in advance, you're prepared.
Knowing about it in advance.
I recently, only a few months ago, went through such an experience.
And instantly began letting go, resisting the experience.
Constantly canceling out the thoughts.
Canceling out the thoughts.
The loss, for instance, seems forever.
A lifetime.
That is a thought.
It isn't the loss of a lifetime that is the problem.
It's the energy of the emotion that's coming up about that.
Once the energy of the emotion about that dissipates,
the fact that, let's say, you're never going to grow another thumb again,
is sort of a so what.
I've learned to do things with it.
Shuffle cards.
Count money.
Turn the pages of the book.
That would seem like an impossible loss becomes sort of a so what.
The problem is that acute catastrophic emotionality.
So, all we have to do is be with that.
The technique is to allow yourself to experience it.
In fact, to get it over with in a hurry, just ask for more.
Say to yourself, I want more of it.
I want more of it.
We'll see as we talk later in our discussion about the energy fields here,
that this is a major opportunity.
The cause of all pain and suffering is the accumulation of this compressed energy field.
And life events allow us an excuse.
It opens the gate so that we allow ourselves to feel some of it.
We put some of this on a...
Let's say somebody bumps the fender of your car.
All the suppressed anger that you've accumulated over your lifetime
now has an excuse to pop out.
It gets angry over the dented fender.
It gets annoyed over this.
It goes into self-pity.
It goes into jealousy.
The events in life are the excuses.
Excuses, and what were their excuses?
Because the compressed energy field,
the compressed energy becomes unbearable.
The mind then finds a way for it to discharge that is acceptable to you.
A person who is familiar with this will feel the compressed energy
and begin to release it without waiting for the mind to create an excuse
that justifies the release of this energy.
The more sophisticated mind doesn't need an event out there to release its angriness.
It just knows that it's building up some suppressed angriness,
and it sits down and it says,
I better look at this,
and starts letting go the energy of it
before the mind gets around and has to create something out there
in order to relieve itself.
It's as though the events in our life are almost like safety valves,
release valves,
a way to decompress this energy tank.
And so our technique today is one of decompression.
It's looking at the energy,
looking at it where it's being experienced.
We don't have to handle the thoughts.
We don't have to handle the problems that the mind creates now
around this particular event.
When you look at any life experience,
you'll see you only live within your feelings about that.
The life event itself is really a nothing.
In the morning, it may look catastrophic.
By noon, it might be amusing.
The event hasn't changed at all.
The dented fender at the moment that it happens may be an outrage,
and you're in indignation.
And then as you think about it,
you start to feel guilty.
You know very well you turned a little too sharply yourself.
Maybe an hour later, you're feeling sorry for the other guy.
He now has an insurance problem.
You realize it really wasn't his fault.
Now you have a desire to make it up to him.
Now you're feeling guilty and blaming yourself again.
Then you think about it again, and now you go back into rage.
You see what you're living with.
Are you living with the dented fender?
The fact is you never really live with the dented fender.
You only live with your own inner experience of that.
It's how you are with that that you are experiencing.
We never experience the dented fenders in life.
We only experience our emotions about that.
I hope that simplifies it.
It makes it simple, isn't it?
It's not quite as bad and overwhelmed now when you look at it.
The only thing you're ever going to have to handle is an energy,
that subtle inner feelingness,
letting go, resisting it, surrendering to it,
welcoming it, saying yes to it,
releases the energy of it.
After you do this for a few minutes or maybe an hour,
depends on how adept, some people get it right away,
other people it takes a little practice.
But as you sort of get where it is,
you no longer have to even experience the emotion.
You don't have to handle or experience any of these emotions as such.
That which was fear disappears and is not felt as fear anymore.
Anger is not felt as anger.
Guiltiness is not felt as guilt per se.
It is felt as an overwhelming upcoming flow of a negative energy,
which actually is nameless.
When you stop naming it anything,
when you stop labeling it,
when you stop calling it anything,
when you stop putting constructions of the mind onto it,
when you stop putting interpretations onto it,
when you let go of right and wrong,
let go wanting to make it wrong, the event wrong, yourself wrong,
when you bypass all that and go directly to the energy of the feelingness of it,
you'll see you don't have to handle all that.
You don't have to handle the thoughts about it.
You don't even have to handle the emotions of it.
All you have to do is handle this upcoming energy.
Can you do that? Yes, you can do that.
Because you're doing it all the time anyway.
The ineffective technique of wildly racing around in your mind trying to figure it out,
wildly running around inside your mind trying to handle these catastrophic emotions,
at the same time this letting go of the energy field is happening anyway.
So today all we're trying to do is become conscious of it,
cut through the confusion,
get right to the essential point of that which is effective.
All the dealing with the thoughts,
all the dealing with the events,
all the reasoning and figuring it out,
all the logic,
all the probing into the psychological significance and all that is entertaining,
but it's thoroughly ineffective.
It's a waste of time and energy.
It really delays the recovery.
The healing of an acute burn of the hand,
how long does that take?
It takes a matter of seconds.
How long should it take bleeding to stop once you cut off,
let's say, a thumb?
Actually a matter of seconds.
Going instantly into this technique,
for instance when I cut the thumb off,
the bleeding led exactly eight drops.
The instant releasing of it,
the releasing of the pain,
the letting go,
the resistance of the catastrophic overwhelm,
allowed the thing to stop instantaneously.
And those people who tried this technique have had the same experience,
that on the physical level you can demonstrate the truth of what we're talking about.
You can do it with any emotion.
You go into the emotion,
then you go past the emotion,
you stop calling it anything,
you get in touch with the energy of it that's coming up.
It seems to be coming right up through your solar plexus,
or it seems to be everywhere.
You go right to where experience is being experienced.
You have to use a little discipline with your mind now and refuse,
you can refuse to have your mind fool you.
The person says,
well I'm experiencing the death of that person out there.
You're not experiencing it out there,
you're experiencing it in here.
Where are you experiencing it?
You're experiencing it in here.
The same place that you always experience experience.
It is within your feeling self.
Your problem is only your own feelingness.
The problem is not the death of someone out there,
the problem is not out there at all.
What you're up against is the energy of one's own feelingness,
the overwhelm of the energy of the feelingness.
If we direct our attention there and focus it there with precision,
that which could be a prolonged and very painful experience,
is aborted,
brought to an abrupt end.
What happens if we keep on letting go of this energy?
What happens if we welcome it?
What if we say,
what an opportunity to decompress all this?
What will be the experience then?
It will be relatively brief,
relatively brief as compared to what it would be
with an ordinary state of consciousness.
And what happens then is suddenly this energy field stops.
It's as though the decompression chamber,
the pressure dial reaches a certain point,
and when it reaches that point,
the overflow stops.
And then one has a state of what?
Of peace.
Right out of acute catastrophe come profound states of peace.
And those who have been through it know what I mean.
The agony all of a sudden stops.
Instead there is almost a silence,
an infinite presence,
an infinite state of peace.
Something that may be greater,
greater than any experience you've had in your life before.
When we come out on the other side of it,
we're not the same.
We're lighter,
we're freer,
we're less subject to pain within our own emotional experience henceforth.
Clinically,
usually what happens is the person now sighs with relief.
They realize that life is going to go on,
that they can live with it.
As bad as it seemed,
somehow one can survive.
And the period of peace goes on for a variable period of time,
and then there will be a wave of this emotion
and personality coming back.
It tends to come back in waves with periods of relief in between.
And what we do is when the wave comes,
we welcome it again.
We try to release as much out of this valve as we can
before it shuts off again.
We welcome it as a very valuable opportunity.
One that may not happen too many times in life.
One to be treasured.
The treasuring of it,
the value of it,
only comes when you're really on the other side of the experience
and you can look back on it now
with the wisdom that you've gained.
To say that the mind is not going to really be of any help
in this experience.
It's because the mind is looking in the wrong direction.
The mind is saying to you,
if I could only change the circumstances
or the event out there,
then I would feel all right.
Well, we have some good clinical examples of that.
We've talked in some of these other talks
about a clinical case I had
of a woman who received a telegram
that her son was killed in Vietnam.
And so what happened is she stopped talking
and she sat in a rocking chair near the window
and she just kept rocking back and forth
and staring numbly out the window.
And she was in a state here that we call apathy.
Complete loss of energy.
The world looked hopeless
and to her, God was dead.
She rocked back and forth in this hopeless state
and didn't respond verbally to the family.
Refused to eat.
Barely slept.
Took naps perhaps during the night.
But just stared blankly out the window
in a total state of apathy.
And we said that certain changes had taken place
in her brain chemistry as a result of this
and the neurotransmitters being depleted.
Some, I think it was about a week or ten days later,
the family in the meantime didn't know what to do with this
and was, of course, very disturbed.
And about a week or ten days later,
the family received another telegram from the State Department
saying that it was all a mistake.
That the son had not been killed in action.
It was another serviceman with the same name
and curiously a number that was only one digit off.
Somehow there'd been an error in the computer.
And so they said to her,
mother, mother, he's not dead.
And she went right on rocking,
staring blankly out the window
as though she didn't even hear them.
So changing the circumstances in the outer world
are not necessarily going to change the upset.
Why? Because it has started a process.
It is the process now that has to be handled.
So what has to be accepted at this particular time?
Not the events that have happened out there
because that's just what you can't do.
That's what you can't do is accept the circumstances
that have happened in your life.
What you can accept
is to surrender to the fact
that you've got to bite the bullet.
That right now there are times
when you've got to be with
your leg is caught in the bear trap.
There's no way out.
And so what we surrender to
is this experiencing itself.
The necessity to sit it through,
to face it, to handle with it.
To surrender to the experiencing of the experience.
And to use the techniques that we talked about.
To be effective then,
to pay attention to the mind.
Because the mind really has no solution to this problem.
The mind is saying
if we could only change those external circumstances.
And this is where people's experiences
with prayer often come in.
Not knowing what to pray for.
Later on they may come out of it bitter.
Because they were praying in the wrong direction.
Very often the prayer goes in the direction of
please undo that.
Please bring joy back to life.
Please bring my thumb back.
Please change what is happening out there.
A prayer in that direction
is very unlikely to be effective.
Is it not?
Because the form of the prayer is like
dear God please let me be one foot shorter.
Is the problem God's or is the problem
the lack of comprehension of how to pray?
At this point the prayer which says
please be with me
and show me how to surrender.
Show me how to surrender
and how to handle this experience.
The asking for the conscious awareness
of the presence of God.
The asking God to take on the experiencing for you.
Now curiously enough
as you keep surrendering into this experience
as you let go resisting it
as you let go labeling it
you are progressively surrendering it.
First surrendering that attraction
to pay attention to the thoughts
and to do something out there
to try and change it.
Then the surrendering
the willingness to surrendering the labeling.
The willingness to surrender
causing this emotional energy to take form.
The surrender to the energy itself.
The total surrender to the energy itself
brings you into an inner state
as you keep getting deeper into the surrender
that something is experiencing
something is handling the experiencing
of this experience for you.
It's as though the personal self
now withdraws
and the energy is being handled
and what one can say is that
the energy is being handled.
So those who prayer
those who pray rather
in that direction
to be aware of that which is handling the experience
because as you get deep into the surrender of the experience
you will realize
that it is being handled for you.
It's as though some energy field
some infinite mode of existence
some aspect of beingness
is handling it for you.
And there comes the surprising realization
that one was never handling it
at all to begin with.
That this was some kind of an illusion
that it was projecting oneself into it
giving it form
identifying with it
that was causing the pain.
So the pain is coming from the resistance
the insistence
that the personal self
in all of its aspects has to handle it
that it must do something about the experiences out there
sue somebody or change the house
or move to a different location.
As it surrenders that
and it surrenders its thinkingness
and it surrenders its wanting to control it and change it
and surrenders to the inner experience
and sees that eventually
as a great gift.
How can it be seen as a gift?
Only when we come out the other side of it.
So we'll talk to those who are aligned consciously
in their life with spiritual work.
What does spiritual work look like to you?
You sit back and you ask yourself
what do I think of is spiritual work?
For those of you who don't call it spiritual
you might call it consciousness.
You might call it dealing with your unconscious
or your super consciousness.
Whatever you label it, whatever you call it
what is the nature of that?
What does it look like to you?
I've asked three or four people
who spent many years at it
and I said when you picture spiritual work
what do you see?
And they see a person kneeling down and praying.
They see a person in church.
They see a person at a gathering
with everybody holding hands
and everybody saying Aum
and picturing light in the center of the circle.
They picture themselves sitting with a book
and studying late at night
12, 1 o'clock in the morning.
They picture themselves listening to audio tapes
of well-known spiritual speakers.
They picture themselves at convocations
for body, mind and spirit
and healing services.
And so this is a whole panorama of that
which the mind then encompasses
and says that is spiritual work.
But then when faced with a life crisis
it's as though that is excused.
That is not spiritual work.
Spiritual work is everybody studying this textbook
and looking at a picture of a guru
and singing songs.
And then there's an acute catastrophe
and we like bypass that now
and we resume our spiritual work
after we've sued that son of a bitch
and after we've handled all these various things in our life.
As a friend of mine once said
well let's sue them first and then forgive them later.
It's as though one doesn't really see
the essence of spiritual work.
What one doesn't see is that the spiritual work
has brought up these acute crises
and brought us into them
and that these are the opportunity.
This is where the spiritual work is happening.
The other was preparation.
The other was gathering of information.
The gathering of experience.
The deciding on direction.
The accumulating of spiritual knowledge.
And then comes suddenly the moment of truth.
Then comes the time.
The time to do it.
When we take it out of the intellect.
And so we see people who have been in spiritual work
and around metaphysical circles for years and years
and nothing changes.
Nothing changes.
They have the same illnesses.
They have the same problems.
Their personality is the same.
They haven't had any of these experiences of inner truth
that they hear about.
And what is the problem?
The problem is when life brings to them
the golden opportunity.
This is it.
This is the time to make that
spiritual knowledge real.
This is the time for transformation.
This is the time to take that leap in consciousness.
These are golden moments.
Acute catastrophes are the times
when you make great leaps.
When you face it directly.
When you fixedly say,
I will not veer from this spiritual work.
Because now what we're really confronted with
is real spiritual work.
Not reading some pleasant sounding phrases out of a book.
Not looking at the happy picture
of some guru with his robes and all that.
We're right in the thick of it.
We're right in the teeth of it.
The teeth of spiritual work is when you're confronted
with that which you cannot avoid.
A direct confront that requires a leap in consciousness.
And so these are golden opportunities.
Priceless.
If you see them as priceless,
your willingness to be with them,
your willingness to say, okay.
Your willingness to go with it
no matter how painful it may be.
Then makes a giant leap in consciousness.
A real advance in wisdom,
knowledge and awareness.
That which you read about within the books
then becomes your own inner experience.
There is something below.
The emotionality
that is literally experiencing
this energy out for you.
It's literally being handled
by something far greater
than your own personal self.
Were there only the small personal self there,
it would be totally swamped and obliterated
by the energy released by these experiences.
It is because there is something greater
than the personal self.
Which is more than capable of handling it
that allows you to survive it.
The trick of the mind is not to see that.
The trick of the mind is to
try to change what goes out there.
Trying to figure it out.
Fall back upon the intellect.
And the intellect is not going to resolve
this kind of a problem.
When you've dropped
a big oak log on your foot
and broken all the bones
across the front of your foot,
what's going to be needed at that moment
is your readiness and your willingness
to handle that which life presents.
The having the tools,
the having the willingness
brings about a very rapid healing.
There is the awareness and an acute overwhelm
that you really can't handle it.
See, part of the panic is the realization
that that which you think you are
like your own limited self,
relatively powerless,
is no match for the power of this experience.
You're correct. That's right.
That's precisely what's going on.
The limited individual personal self
cannot handle this overwhelm.
That is the precise spiritual value of it.
What do you really want to change
about the experience?
And you'll see what you want to do
is change how you feel about it.
It's how you really feel
about it and what you can know
is that the feeling will come and go.
The event is not going to bother you
after the feeling state.
So all that one has to experience
through then is the acute upsurge
of this emotion,
the energy of this emotion.
The events are going to take
care of themselves.
The desire, as you see it,
to change that which occurred out there,
the desire to change
how you feel about it
has to be surrendered.
The confront is there
and all we can do is say yes
to experiencing it through.
Death of a loved one, divorce, separation,
acute emergency, catastrophe, injury.
They all bring about
a state of shock
and the shock is the same
no matter what the precipitating event.
The shock is the sudden realization
of one's powerlessness.
The fact that the will
has met a brick wall.
The shock that one is stoppable,
that one has been stopped,
that the personal will
cannot have its way.
Therefore the shock,
the realization of this
is the same in all the experiences.
The fact that it is unchangeable,
that it is permanent.
This is the shock.
It's as though you came up full speed
against a brick wall
and every time in life
when we come full speed up against a brick wall
it releases the same energy field.
If you've been through more than one of these experiences
then look back and you will realize
that this is so.
That each time the state of shock was the same.
The experience, the sequence
was the same.
There was the feeling of sudden numbness,
the state of disbelief
and then
the unleashing of all the negative feelings.
When you look at the negative feelings
precisely,
when you look back at some of the experiences you have
you realize the truth
of what we've been saying.
That what you really experienced
in all of this.
Is that not so?
You experienced the totality
of that negative energy field.
In the morning it would be here.
In the afternoon it would be here.
In fact, within a minute's time
we fluctuate back and forth.
It's like a scintillating energy field
in which the form of the emotionality
is flickering
from anger to resentment
to self-pity to jealousy
to getting even to revenge
to hating God, to hating yourself
to hating your family, to blaming society
blaming the government, blaming the laws.
The mind is wildly racing around
in this negative energy field.
The reason I mention this
is I want you to see
the diffuseness of it.
The formlessness of it.
That it is
like a whole basket of negative
energy
and we only have to handle the basket.
We don't have to handle all the little things
that are flickering around in the basket.
We only have to handle
all of it.
You see, if we see that
it's decompressing the all of it
brings us rapidly through
and out the other side.
That it's an inescapable experience
the willingness to surrender
to the work that has to be done now.
How can we tell
when that work is through?
Because we suddenly come out
into that inner state of peace.
We know people, as we said,
that years later still have resentments
and are still caught in some aspect
of that negative energy field.
It's because it wasn't handled
in the first place.
The person has been unwilling to sit down
and handle it until
it's through, until it's over,
until it's complete.
The reason, of course, that people
are unwilling to do this
is because of the pain involved.
Because they don't know the techniques.
Because every time they go at it
they start again trying to change
the events in the world
and the thoughts, the intellect
and the mind trying to figure it out.
They run into the same impasse.
So not having an effective tool
with which to handle it
the work is left incomplete.
What happens with
the incomplete work then?
What happens with the emotions
that were not released?
That which is left undone
begins to express itself
in emotional attitudes
and begins to express itself
in the body in the form
of emotional illness.
So the unconscious guilt
that was not let go of
over the catastrophe
that happened many years ago
brings forth through the autonomic
nervous system and the acupuncture
energy system and connects up
with something from mind.
We said mind, the energy field
of the intellect, of thinkingness
is here in the 400s.
The energy field of the guilt then
or of the grief, of the fear,
of the anger couples
is some belief system in the mind
about some particular illness
and results then
in a physical illness
which in psychoanalysis
we would say is psychosomatic
in that here the contribution
of the psychological
is on the surface and quite visible.
So the end result
of the unresolved
handling emotionally
of a catastrophic experience
is often an illness
which may recur many years later.
The grief that was undone
at the time over the death
of some family member
20 years later may express itself
as that heart attack.
The way we know then
that the thing has been handled
is when we feel at peace about it.
We feel complete about it.
It no longer recurs.
It no longer brings up pain
when we think about it.
We feel satisfied.
We may regret that we lived through it
that we had to live through that.
We came out on the other side of it
a different kind of a person
and with that knowledge
there comes a certain sense of peace
telling us that that has been handled now.
Catastrophic experiences
is the seed, the very essence
of the ultimate
spiritual experience.
Within it
and following it to its very center core
and walking off
the cliff totally
the total abandonment
the total surrender to the experience
is the seed,
is the very core
of that which the spiritual seeker
has been seeking all along.
What happens in ordinary life
in many catastrophic situations
is an incomplete resolution
of the experience.
The not realizing
the jewel-like quality
the opportunity
the being overwhelmed
by the what-ness of it
looking in the wrong direction.
A lot of times what happens is
drugs are introduced
altered states of consciousness
so the person is taken to the emergency room
and what could be a crucial
spiritual discovery
now becomes covered over
so the band-aids over the experience
the family
trying to distract the person
with watching television
and taking them on trips
the distraction from the spiritual work
the introduction of things
that alter the state of consciousness
so that the person
instead of running into the experience
runs away from the experience.
The essential aspect
of the spiritual benefit
comes from running directly
into the experience.
There is a saying in Zen
to walk straight ahead
no matter what.
So when this catastrophic experience
comes we center ourselves
right into the core of it
we say yes to it
and we begin to experience it through.
Sometimes what happens then
if we refuse to accept
any band-aids
and I've had times in my life
with acute catastrophic experiences
where there were band-aids available
and I refused them
because by then I had learned the value
of experiencing it through directly
because it really prevents
the experiencing through
of what we might call hitting bottom
that whole concept of hitting bottom
which is well known
in handling many serious problems
such as alcoholism
which means to let go
and let go completely.
So we see what happens with the mind
is in an acute catastrophic situation
it tries to cling to that
which is familiar.
It tries escapism
it tries distractions
it tries tranquilizers and drugs
and alcohol
various ways of trying to
ameliorate the situation
rather than facing it
and working it through directly.
The essence of a catastrophic situation
is the discovery of that which is
that which is greater than
one's personal self.
The experiencing through
completely of a catastrophe then
brings one into a connection
that there is something within oneself
that has the power to sustain
no matter how catastrophic
the experience appeared.
So one comes out on the other side
of it as a greater person
the awareness that there is something within
that there is a presence
there is a quality or aspect
of life within oneself
which has the power
to sustain one through
the most seemingly impossible situations.
If the
catastrophic experience
is not worked through completely
then we have certain residuals
if you like half fall off the cliff
you see
some people think they've walked off the cliff
but actually we find that they were secretly
crossing their fingers and hanging on
to some little lifeline.
The abandonment to God was not really total
and so there is left a doubt
and out of that doubt then
there is the residual
let's say the residual of grief
the residual of fear of the experience
if there wasn't the experiencing
of something greater than the
personal self there
then we may have an
end up with a limitation
a certain crippling
a certain inability to go
beyond a certain point
the willingness to participate
becomes limited.
I would rather lead a limited life
than face that kind of experience again
I would rather never love again
than to love and lose
the saying is
it is better to have loved and lost
than never to have loved at all
because the experience
of loving this
puts us in touch with our greater self
that which is greater than our own limited
small self
the complete resolution then
brings us into a conscious
contact with something
greater than our self
of the hundreds of thousands of people
who have tried that
and left the record
they all attest to the fact
that when they surrendered the small self
to something greater than themself
they came into contact with that
which they considered to be real
one's own inner experience
of the spiritual reality
then takes it from book learning
to a profound inner conviction
this inner conviction then
out of that
comes a willingness
to re-enter into life again
to participate
to take the risk
to take the chances
what is the inner experience
of getting bottom
it's coming out of
this feeling of hopelessness
and despair
and what is really happening
is the personal small self
is saying
I of my own self
cannot handle this
it is out of the hopelessness
then comes the willingness
to let go
to surrender to something
greater than oneself
at the very bottom
in the pits
one realizes the truth
and accepts the truth
that I of myself
of my own individual
personal self
my own ego self
am unable to handle this
am unable to resolve it
then the victory
and the success arises
the phoenix arises
out of the ashes
of the despair and hopelessness
it isn't the despair
and the hopelessness
that's of the value
it's the letting go
and the realization
of the limitation of the small self
in the middle of the catastrophe
the person says
I give up
the law of free will
and the nature of consciousness
being what it is
it is said
that the great beings
that are willing to help all of us
wait for our saying yes
and so it is the sudden turning then
from the bottom of the box
to the willingness
to the acceptance
that there is something greater than oneself
that one can turn to
and when the person says
no
one can turn to
and he becomes not just a free will
but a person is
he has already turned
from the beginning
into the nature of the purpose
of the purpose
and he is now
given a new form
a new form of faith
a new form of healing
and he gains
a new form of life
moment came a great transformative experience, the spiritual power of which is evident from
the millions of lives that have been affected by the energy that flowed out into the world
by this man sharing his spiritual experience. So letting go and hitting bottom then are
crucial. It is out of the awareness that one cannot change it, that one is limited, that
one is powerless. So the powerlessness then is the very source of the discovery of that
which does have the power in the universe. That power comes in and handles the experience.
We know when that happens because of the profound state of peace. Where there was agony, now
there is a state of infinite peace and the ineffable awareness of an infinite presence.
Historically,
it has been a special case out of which a realization of the truth has arisen, but it
is not at all necessary. It is only one type of experience. Actually, spiritual work is
of this nature all the time. The person who is involved in spiritual work is always looking
at what is coming up in life, seeing what is coming up in life as the teacher, the grist
for the millstone.
It is what is happening that represents that which is being worked on. So an acute catastrophe
then would just be a continuation of the process that is going on anyway. So the person
who is intensely involved in spiritual work, then it would be seen as a golden opportunity,
painful and regretful perhaps, and yet one of great benefit. So the essential nature
of spiritual work is remaining the same.
To remain focused on that which is rising from instant to instant, always looking at
experiencing, what is experiencing, where is it being experienced, what is experiencing
it.
There's a meditative technique then which is one that is used. The same result comes
about.
The constantly letting go, wanting to control. The experiencing the quality of experiencing
itself.
cham
And then the sudden coming into the state of attainment.
colon
the experience that it is being handled by some infinite aspect of oneself, hitherto
fore suspected perhaps, but not actually realized. The realization of the presence after that
becomes more and more frequent.
Out of this experience then comes an ever-grating willingness to rely on that inner presence.
Less and less of a reliance on the smaller self. Less and less does the person look to
this small self to handle life's problems. There's a progressive willingness to surrender
to one's higher self, the progressive loss of identification, and the increasing identification
with that presence. The willingness then to surrender life in all of its aspects to the
will of God becomes the very present.
The acute catastrophic experience then is a key learning experience, a key learning
experience in that we learn to go to the very core, to the very essence of the experience
to see what it is and handle it right at the level of experiencing, right within the energy
field of consciousness itself. The willingness to surrender, to let go, wanting to change
what happened out there. The letting go of wanting to change the thinking about it,
trying to handle it with the intellect. The letting go of trying to handle it with the
emotions. The willingness to surrender to the essence of the experience without calling
it anything, without labeling it, without putting names on it. The willingness to handle
the energy field of it, to go directly to the inner experience. And the surrender to
the inner experience.
And is the open doorway to the experience of something greater than the small personal
self.
Each catastrophe then is a repeat, the re-presentation of another opportunity for this great spiritual
learning experience. And therefore we hear people who have been through great catastrophic
experiences express their gratitude. We will hear people say, although I wouldn't want
to live through it again, I'm very grateful for that experience.
We refer back to Alcoholics Anonymous again, we will hear people say that they're grateful
that they're an alcoholic. How could a person be grateful for that which the world considers
a terrible catastrophe, and a terrible progressive illness? It's because what they learn out
of this catastrophe was of such a great dimension that the price was worth it. So if we handle
this experience correctly, we will later look back on it and will say that the price was
worth it.
Time for Dr. Dain Heer's Remote View of Transition and True Consciousness.
Dr. Dain Heer's Remote View of Transition and True Consciousness. NTW.com.au.
the reconnection with the essential core of our beingness,
the realization of truth, made whatever the price was worth, worth it.
As we grow spiritually and as we become spiritually educated,
it takes less and less to bring about the willingness to face this inner experience.
We might say that a person's bottom gets progressively raised.
A person doesn't have to go through agonizing pain
before they are willing to let go and surrender.
More and more, there arises the willingness to do it on a daily basis
so that it becomes part and parcel of one's life.
The constant looking at how I'm trying to control things,
how I'm trying to change God's will about how I'm going to try and change God and control God.
The willingness to totally surrender at great depth.
And so we see surrender occurs at different depths.
In ordinary life,
we surrender a little bit.
Under greater pressure, we're willing to surrender more.
We realize that we don't have to put ourself under catastrophic pressure
in order to be willing to surrender at great depth.
The transformation of personality,
the whole shift in one's spiritual position,
traditionally comes from surrendering at great depth.
And so we become interested in what does that mean, surrendering at great depth.
How can we surrender at great depth?
Without having to put ourself through a terrible emotional catastrophe
to accomplish the same spiritual work.
By seeing the essential nature of the process, then,
we become educated.
Our position shifts and we are different in the way that we are.
And we're willing to be with life in all of its expressions.
That willingness, then, is experienced as an inner state of aliveness.
Coming out of that willingness to take the chance.
Because we now know that we are accompanied by something greater than that personal self.
It isn't the personal self that has to handle what comes up in life.
That there is always with us that infinite presence,
more powerful than the human will and ego.