I'm Dr. David Hawkins. I've been a psychiatrist for 35 years, psychoanalyst, researcher into the
nature of nutrition and brain chemistry. I've been doing work for the last eight years on the
nature of consciousness itself and its relationship to what the world calls spiritual. In this series
of talks, we're exploring the utilization of the knowledge that arises out of studying the
nature of consciousness itself and its application to man's problems and especially his areas of
suffering. So today's talk has to do with the nature of illness itself, the letting go of
illness. And in it, I'll also bring in my own personal experiences as well as my clinical
observations. We won't be talking about philosophy. We won't be talking about theory. We'll be talking
about what you and I can clinically verify in our own personal experience.
That which is true because we can verify it, which is really the basis of all of science. The ability
to repeat, to reduplicate, to verify an observation and within your own personal experience and apply
it to your own individual problems and see if it works. So essentially, we're coming from sort of a
radical pragmatism. We're going to believe that which we can prove to be true through our own
experience.
Mmm in doing this we're going to be talking about the relationship between body, mind, and spirit. Is that just a catchphrase?
Is that
mmm
a wishful-thinking motto
or is it something real?
What is the nature of spirit anyway?
Is that a metaphysical abstraction,
a philosophic position,
um, religious shibboleth? What is the exact nature
of body, mind & spirit?
In order to bring about self-healing, because that's what we're talking about today, self-healing,
it's essential that we understand the relationship between the body and the mind and the spirit.
To start with, we're going to say something we've said in our other talks,
and it has to be repeated over and over again before we finally get the truth of it,
that the body has no capacity to experience itself.
The arm cannot experience its armness.
The leg cannot experience its legness.
The body has no way in which to experience itself.
The body itself is in sentient.
Instead, what we experience are the sensations, sensations of the body.
So, it's the sensations of where the body is in space that we're experiencing.
Sensations themselves, curiously enough, have no capacity to experience themselves.
Sensations have to be experienced in something that is greater than that, and that is mind itself.
It's within mind that the experience of the sensations and what they report about the body is experienced.
If we ablate part of mind, then that opposite side of the body, let's say, is no longer experienced.
It's necessary for mind then to be there to experience the sensations which then report the body.
Surprising as it may sound also, mind cannot experience itself.
A thought cannot experience its thoughtness.
A feeling cannot experience its own feelingness.
Memory cannot experience its own memoryness.
It has to be experienced in something greater than that.
You see, our principle is that each thing is experienced from an energy field
which is less restricted, which is less limited.
It is always experienced in something that is greater.
So that mind itself then is experienced because of the energy field of consciousness itself.
Consciousness, that which is formless, that which is infinite.
The movie screen upon which we experience the moving of the movie.
It is because of consciousness then that we experience what is in mind.
That's the whole basis of anesthesia, remove consciousness and there's no experience of either mind or body.
Consciousness itself is experienced in something greater than that.
And that is the infinite energy field called awareness itself.
It is because of awareness that we know what is going on in consciousness.
It is because of consciousness that we know what is going on in mind.
It is because of mind that we know what the senses are reporting about the body.
And so we can see that that which we are,
that which we are really is several levels removed from the body.
It makes it rather clear that we are not the body, we are that which is aware,
that which is conscious and within that consciousness, the mind.
These are very important things to realize and you can sit down in a very short meditation,
verify the truth of this for yourself.
That you are that.
Hmm.
Which is aware of all these lesser levels of reality.
We'll go back to what we're going to be talking about today specifically.
The actual techniques of self-healing, how they're brought about, how they're applied,
what the basic principles are and we'll be looking at topics such as
the source of all illness is unconscious guilt plus a specific belief system
aggravated by suppressed emotions.
I'll describe how I myself utilizing these techniques and these understandings
and these basic principles I healed myself of about 20 chronic intractable illnesses
which had been totally refractory to traditional medical treatment
including how I let go of wearing glasses after 40 years of wearing glasses.
We'll go through it step by step.
We'll see how illness is also a result of buying into the collective consciousness
and how not to buy into it.
How illness comes about as a result of family belief systems.
We'll look at the fact that all illnesses are recoverable.
There is no order of difficulty no matter how severe they may sound to anyone.
How to energize that self-healer which is present in everyone.
And we'll look at a curious thing which demonstrates the truths of many of the things
we'll be saying today and that is the phenomena of multiple personality.
Those people who some of whom become patients of course
and which science and psychiatry is looking at with increasing interest
because they explain so many different phenomena.
Where more than one personality expresses itself through the body usually alternately.
And we'll look at the curious clinical fact that one personality may have multiple illnesses
may have ulcers let's say and asthma
and allergies and gout and a whole variety of illnesses.
And that personality leaves and the other personality comes in.
That other personality may well have none of those illnesses whatsoever.
That personality may say I don't believe in any of those things.
I'm not subject to them.
And therefore we'll be looking at the power of mind.
The power of mind over body.
We'll be looking at a basic principle of self-healing that I am only subject to what I hold in mind.
And to make this understandable then.
So that we can make sense rather than sounding mystical or puzzling in our expressions.
We'll be referring as we have in all of these talks to this chart.
To this map of consciousness.
A mathematical model.
A useful construct.
In which we have the various energy fields.
And we have them calibrated as to their relative power.
And we have the energy fields calibrated
as to the direction of the field.
Whether it is a negative energy field with a destructive influence.
Or a positive energy field.
It'll be necessary to know a few of these things.
In order to feel confident that we're operating out of something that is reasonable and understandable.
Rather than just taking my word for it.
I'll be sharing my personal experience because that personal experience
is merely the demonstration of the basic truths we'll be talking about today.
Merely a demonstration of things that you know unconsciously.
But today we're going to merely make it conscious so that you can use it as a therapeutic tool.
How to not buy into programs.
And we'll be looking at what it means to be programmed.
To buy into a thought system because the mind is so powerful.
That what it believes tends to manifest.
We have in fact a very interesting study that we'll refer to in a recent issue of Brain Mind Journal.
Brain Mind Bulletin. January 1987.
As a prelude to what we'll be talking about later.
Here's a very interesting study. The title is Expectancy.
What you see is what they give you.
It says at Princeton University research has shown
the self-fulfilling prophecy is just that.
It says what we actively believe tends to manifest in our behavior
and in the behavior of others.
This is what they call a created social reality.
A serious issue that affects everything from stock prices to the arms race.
Not to mention everyday interactions.
And I might add all the details of one's personal health.
The basic premise from which we'll be operating is
that all phenomena are experienced in consciousness.
If all phenomena are experienced in consciousness.
If it is in consciousness that the experience of man is going on.
Then we will address ourself to the level of consciousness itself.
And its expression in mind.
We'll go to the level of cause instead of the level of effect.
The body then is the effect of what is held in mind.
If we want to know what we're holding in mind.
All we have to do is look at what is going on in the body.
And its behavior.
And that'll tell us what we believe.
If we look back into our memory.
We often will not be able to recall that we had any such belief system.
Or that we thought that it applied to us.
But the very fact that it is in our life tells us it must have been there somewhere in the unconscious.
The most common example I see of this is in people who are allergic.
And people will say well I didn't have any belief in allergies.
I didn't bring this into my life consciously.
And yet if we go back into their childhood almost invariably.
We will find that the belief system in allergies occurred very early in life.
Very often ages two or three.
The little child picks up a remark by someone in the family.
Such as allergies run in our family.
The minute the child's mind buys this, hears it, of course believes it.
This now becomes an operative program.
And so a lot of the phenomena that we're going to see.
Expressing itself in the body.
In the adult.
Was picked up very early in life by a chance remark.
Something heard on television.
Something misunderstood in a book.
A remark that a teacher made.
And these things will become conscious as we begin to work on them.
We're only subject to what we hold in mind.
So what must we be holding in mind?
What is the nature of illness itself?
We see that the nature of illness is first of all pain and suffering.
Consequently it's clear and obvious and merely common sense.
That illness is an expression of pain and suffering.
And if we look at our chart over here.
Where is pain and suffering?
Pain and suffering is down here.
At the lowest energy level.
And we'll see that the energy field of that is in a negative direction.
Meaning that it has a negative effect on our life.
So we have to look into the nature of guilt.
Of unconscious guilt.
And how it expresses itself.
And we'll see that the thought patterns in the mind.
Our belief systems.
Which unconscious guilt has grabbed onto.
To express this energy field of guilt.
And where does the guilt come from?
The guilt comes from judgmentalism.
From all the negative opinions and judgments.
All these negative energy fields collectively.
You'll notice that all these negative feelings tend to go together.
Everything below the level of courage.
Where the energy field suddenly swings to the positive.
All have arrows going in this direction.
So all these negative feelings then contribute to illness.
Pride.
Anger.
Desire.
Fear.
Grief.
Apathy.
Guilt.
We know with kinesiology where you test a person's muscle strength.
That if they hold in mind anything below the energy of courage here.
If they hold a prideful thought.
An angry thought.
A wantingness.
A cravingness.
A fearful thought.
Some grief.
Apathy.
Guilt.
A guilty thought.
Any of these kinds of expressions.
These feelings over here.
Regret.
Uselessness.
Despair.
Self-hatred.
Worry.
Anxiety.
Grievances.
Any kind of arrogance or contempt.
We know that with kinesiology the person instantly goes weak.
And what does that represent?
That represents a desynchronization of the cerebral hemispheres.
An instant weakening of the body's energy field.
It represents something that is deleterious to life.
And so we know.
And it can be tested and proven to anyone.
That any negative thought or feeling itself desynchronizes the body's acupuncture energy system.
That energy system which is even more rapid than the central nervous system.
And far more rapid than the autonomic sympathetic nervous system.
That the body's acupuncture energy system which are the energies flowing down the acupuncture meridians.
The 12 main meridians of the body.
Instantly responds to anything that is negative.
Anything that is not the truth.
Because all these energy fields below the level of courage here represent that which is not the truth.
That which is not the truth then brings in the whole energy field of being victim.
And as a sick person we view ourselves as a victim of the disease.
So it's important then to realize that there is the illness.
And then there is the person.
The person who has the illness.
How to be with that illness.
And we realize that the person who is with that illness has to change in order for the illness to disappear.
Today we'll be talking about the specifics of healing a specific illness.
How to handle the actual event on the physical, psychological, emotional, mental level.
And how one must become as a being so that healing becomes automatic.
We see from this chart that all the negative emotions create illness.
And that all the positive emotions heal illness.
We see that once we get above the level of courage.
A level that we cross by telling the truth about things.
We become detached.
That opens a space for us to become willing.
To be an accepting person.
To become a loving person.
And love as an energy field on this calibrated scale where death is zero.
Love comes out at 500.
And healing comes out about 540.
What kind of lovingness then brings about an almost automatic healing within the body?
We see that it's unconditional love.
Unconditional love.
That which is non-judgmental.
That which is forgiving.
That which is aligned with understanding and compassion.
That which nurtures and supports all of life and honors its sacredness.
That which sees the sacredness of life, supports and honors it, of itself creates a healing energy field.
An energy field which we calibrate on our mathematical model at 540.
How to become that.
The kind of a person in whom healing begins to occur automatically because of the level and the general nature of our consciousness.
At the same time, how to bring about a healing of a specific illness.
In healing the specifics of an illness, which we'll address first, because we'll be talking about sort of the mechanics of consciousness,
we'll be utilizing some techniques that we've talked about in other talks in this series.
We have to begin by letting go, resisting the sensations that we're experiencing and stop labeling them.
As we said, you cannot experience a duodenal ulcer.
You cannot experience asthma.
Those are all mental constructs.
Those are all elaborate programs and belief systems.
You cannot experience asthma.
What do you experience?
And this is where our technique of radical truth comes up.
We go into the inner experience of the exact sensations.
We let go, resisting them.
We, in effect, will eventually disappear them by aligning ourselves with them,
by welcoming these inner experiences of the sensations.
And at the same time, within mind, we cancel any labels.
We stop calling it ulcer.
And instead, we go into what is the inner sensation.
The inner sensation is of a pressure, or a burning, let us say.
Burning and pressure, I want you to get, are also labels and names.
We cancel those, and we again go into what is the core,
the absolute essential of what it is we're experiencing.
And we let go, resisting that experience.
So the actual healing of the physicality of the illness
is letting go, resisting,
the inner experience of it, without any mental label.
At the same time, in fact, we begin to cancel that mental label,
and we cancel it, and replace it with the truth.
Cancel. We say, I no longer believe in that.
I am an infinite being, and I am not subject to that.
What does that mean, I'm an infinite being, and I'm not subject to that?
It means I'm only limited to my belief systems,
and if I let my belief systems go, what takes its place?
If I remove form from consciousness, what is left?
What is left is the formless.
Formless, by its definition, by the inner experience of it,
is infinite, without boundaries, without beginning, without end.
That which is the essential nature of consciousness itself is unlimited.
If we place a limitation, if we interject form,
then what happens is we subject ourself
to what we are holding in mind.
And so, to replace it, what we do is we consciously cancel it.
We say, I cancel any belief in duodenal ulcers, asthma,
whatever the illness might be,
and I say, I am only subject to what I hold in mind.
I'm an infinite being, and in truth, I am not subject to that.
And that is a fact.
If we test that with kinesiology, we will see that is a fact.
If we test a person and we say, cancel, I am not subject to that,
I am an infinite being, I am only subject to what I hold in mind,
we will see they instantly go strong,
indicating that this is a statement of the truth.
Consequently, we replace that which is false by that which is true.
We replace the lie by the truth.
Now, what is the effect then on our energy, fuels, and consciousness?
The lie, by its nature, puts us below the line
and throws us into a negative energy field,
which in and of itself brings about illness.
The minute we tell the truth, the energy field,
as you see here at the level of courage,
courage meaning the courage to tell the truth,
that you are an infinite being
and you are only subject to what you hold in mind,
instantly puts you above the line. See?
The willingness to accept this truth puts you up here.
The acceptance of this truth puts you up as far as here.
And then we are now in a position to choose
that position called lovingness.
Lovingness.
The lovingness of the body instead of the make wrong of the body.
The lovingness of our life instead of the make wrong of our life.
The lovingness of the being that we are instead of the criticism of it.
And so we find that we have to let go of criticism.
We have to let go of attack thoughts,
critical thoughts, judgmental thoughts.
We have to let go of putting ourselves in the position
of being right and other people wrong.
Why is that so?
Because the level of right and wrong is about an energy field of 180
and we see that 180 is a negative thought form.
In other words, it has a deleterious effect on our health,
on our life energy.
The willingness to let that go.
So if I am willing to let go of my illness,
then I have to be willing to let go of the attitudes
that brought that illness about.
Because disease is an expression then of attitudes,
of habitual ways of looking at things.
And so the specifics of healing a particular illness then
is letting go resisting the experience of it
and stop labeling it, stop putting names on it.
And to use no words at all.
To let go experiencing what you are experiencing
in a very radical way.
At the same time to cancel the thought form,
to cancel the belief system.
Why is this so?
We said that the energy field of love itself heals.
To put yourself in an energy field of 540
is automatically to heal yourself.
A loving thought then heals
and a negative thought creates illness.
To choose to become a loving person then.
To choose to become a loving person
actually within the brain begins to release endorphins.
And these endorphins have a profound effect
on the body's health and happiness.
We know that health and happiness go together.
Happiness then arises from this
and the willingness to let go of that which is negative.
Because what replaces it in consciousness
is love itself.
Because the essential nature of consciousness
unless it's been impaired
is a lovingness.
We see this in the child.
We see it in the young child whose innocence and lovingness
is the expression of the essence of human nature.
It's like it hasn't been programmed yet
to go into fear, to go into doubt, to go into limitation.
And so that essential expression of lovingness
which we need to recapture
to heal any illness within ourself is critical.
The letting go of the negativity of the belief system.
How do we pick up these belief systems?
We have to cancel specific belief systems.
We pick it up through television.
We pick it up through well-intentioned people who want to
and their intention is to prevent these illnesses in us
by educating us about them.
Instead what we find is that the mind now is programmed
to believe in a specific belief system.
Then unconscious guilt comes up
and utilizes this.
And through the acupuncture energy system
and its interference with the energy fields
running down through the 12 meridians
we find an impairment of energy
flowing into a specific body system.
So let us say every time I go below the line
we're calling this level here of courage the line.
Any time we go below the line
if we test somebody we find that their energy system just blows out.
If the energy system blows out
characteristically most people will blow one meridian
rather than another.
So let us say a person habitually every time
they have one of these negative thoughts or feelings
coming out of their negative belief systems
every time they have a thought
they blow the heart meridian.
As the years go by every time they have a resentment
every time they go into self-pity
any time they criticize someone else
every second that they do that
it blows the energy flow down the heart meridian.
Well that meridian is flowing the life energy
the energy of life itself into the heart
and therefore the impairment of the flow
of the energy of life itself.
To the heart in subtle very delicate ways
begins to alter the physiology
begins to express itself through irregularities
in the autonomic nervous system
that nervous system which operates
in the functioning of body organs.
And so we begin to have an impairment
of the physiology of the heart itself
of the lining of the arteries.
And so as the years go by
the habitual blowing of the heart meridian then
brings an impairment on the physical level.
So that we now see
the expression on the physical level
of that which was held in mind.
That is our basic premise, is it not?
That the body expresses what is held in mind
not vice versa.
The body is now expressing
the person's habit of thinking in a negative way.
The mechanics of that are to blow the acupuncture system
blow the autonomic system
blow the sensitive
electrical and chemical things
which are going on in the cells
and you begin to get
the development of pathologic changes
within the anatomy and dysfunction.
And this dysfunction then results let's say
in a coronary or heart disease
or heart failure.
So the heart failure then came about
as a result of the mental attitudes.
The mind would like to blame it on cholesterol
or blame it on stress.
Blame it on one style of life.
Blame it on genetics.
Blame it on what goes on in our family, etc.
We see that those are all merely explanations.
Those are only excuses and rationalizations.
Trying to make intelligible
that which is not clearly defined.
When we look at the exact mechanics we see that
exactly what we said in the beginning
is exactly what's happening.
What we hold in mind begins to manifest
on the physical plane.
You see it is mind that has the power.
It's mind that has the power.
When you think of it one thought
let's say you have a thought
I think I'll go to Hawaii.
That one thought now energizes your finances.
It determines what you're going to do
over the next six months getting ready for this trip.
You see the thought held in mind now determines
what you do with your money, your whole behavior,
the packing, the getting ready for the trip.
It moves your body thousands of miles through the air.
The one thought energized the next six months of your life.
You see how powerful mind is.
And one of the difficulties to be overcome in self-healing
is the acceptance, the willingness to accept
the great power of mind.
You cannot let a negative thought go unchallenged.
You cannot say I have diabetes
and let that go unchallenged.
That is a belief system.
That belief system is so powerful
that the belief system I have diabetes
alone is sufficient to create diabetes.
Instead you have to cancel it and say
I'm a person who once thought that.
But I am only subject to what I hold in mind.
I'm an infinite being and I'm not subject to that.
And instead you release on any symptoms.
You cancel them.
You replace them
with the truth.
And in doing that you move above the line
in the specifics of a given illness.
And when I get to an account of how I use this
in getting rid of 15 or 20 illnesses within myself,
perhaps these principles will become more apparent.
Because I myself had such a list of illnesses
that frankly I have to write them all down
in order to remember them
because half of them have been forgotten.
And yet all of them lasted for many, many years.
I had a duodenal ulcer.
It was intractable.
I was on all the traditional medical treatments
and had psychoanalysis and a whole variety of things
that began in medical school.
And 20 years later I still had the ulcer.
And not only that but it was a different ulcer.
It was making holes in other parts of my duodenum
and it was threatening to perforate
and it was threatening to hemorrhage.
And it was bringing about recurrent attacks of diverticulitis.
I mean, I'm sorry, pancreatitis.
At the same time I also had colitis.
And at the same time I also had diverticulitis.
In fact, I had diverticulitis so bad
that I landed in the hospital with it several times
and had to have transfusions.
I mean, I almost hemorrhaged to death with it.
I also had migraine headaches which were intractable.
And psychoanalysis had helped it to some degree.
And I had seen neurologists and very famous world experts.
But there was really no help for the migraine
and the migraine was associated with many allergies.
I was sensitive to inhalants, things in the atmosphere.
I couldn't walk into a place that had been exterminated
within the last couple of weeks.
I could detect one part in a million
and I would react with a migraine headache.
The prostate was enlarged
and I had all those problems that go on physically
in the general GU tract of middle-aged men.
I had Raynaud's disease, a vibration disease
that was impairing the blood flow into the extremities.
So I had threatening gangrene of the fingertips
and circulatory impairment of the hands and feet.
And I was cold all the time.
On top of that I had gout and a high uric acid level.
And of course I was on a diet for that.
And I had gouty arthritis.
And I carried a cane in the back of my car.
Imagine carrying a cane in the back of your car
because when gout comes on it comes out very suddenly.
And it's very, very paralyzing.
And so I carried a cane in the back of the car for many years.
At the same time I had severe hypoglycemia.
I couldn't eat sugar or sweets or starches or anything like that.
So on top of all the allergies and the ulcer and the diverticulitis
and the other gastrointestinal problems I had
and the pancreatitis and the occasional gallbladder attack, etc.
there were frankly very few things I could eat.
I would go to a restaurant sometimes
and the only thing I could eat was the lettuce and the salad.
I couldn't eat the tomatoes, of course, because of the seeds.
It might aggravate the diverticulitis.
And I was also 50 pounds overweight.
And I described, of course, how I handled the weight problem
in the talk that I gave on weight.
So here we had things wrong with the gastrointestinal tract
from one end to the other.
Things wrong with the circulatory system from one end to the other.
Things wrong with the digestive system, the circulatory system,
the hormonal balance, the blood chemistries.
I had elevated blood cholesterol, elevated blood uric acid,
impairments in the self-regulatory mechanisms,
migraine headaches and things indicating stress and pressure
within the central nervous system
and its impairment of the autonomic nervous system.
So that's enough to start with.
On top of that I had a cystic tumor which would require surgery.
It's not a thing that spontaneously disappears.
And so that's about where I was at age 50
when I really got serious about researching the nature of consciousness
and its application to spiritual principles.
Systems now had to be questioned and looked at.
What was going on?
Because it's obvious that a person who has that many illnesses
can hardly be said to love themself.
And so I began with perfectionism.
I began to see how this perfectionistic tendency,
which allowed me to forgive others but did not allow me to forgive myself,
was creating an intolerance of my own humanness.
And so, as you see, to be intolerant, to condemn,
to attack all these things within yourself
is coming out of this kind of guilt.
The feeling of guilt about one's own humanness.
And so I had to move to a willingness to accept
and to love, to love and to forgive my own humanness,
all this basket of negativity,
that it was only human to have these kind of feelings,
to let go attacking myself for being human.
And so I had to look into the essence then
of seeing what is the essential, what is the inner core,
the essence of one's humanness.
And this brought me to the awareness
of the intrinsic innocence within consciousness itself.
I had to look then at the nature of consciousness.
How does the child, in its innocence,
in its lack of negativity,
end up with so many programs
within mind as to create all these illnesses?
And we look at the nature then of innocence.
And we can see it if we track what happens to it in the child.
You see, the child's innocence,
the child might even be compared to the hardware of a computer.
The hardware of a computer is innocent.
And it's the software that goes through the hardware
that creates the output.
The hardware of the computer, however,
is not affected by the software.
We look at the child and we see the innocence of its consciousness.
How does all the negative programming come into the innocent child?
It comes in because of its innocence.
It's because the child is innocent
that it believes anything it is told.
It's out of its lovingness and its trust
of its parents and its teacher
and of the world and of television
and of commercials and of society
then that it becomes programmed.
And so the innocence of the child is no longer so observable
because now what we're observing are all the programs
that the innocent child has picked up.
Out of its innocence, it believes
the prejudices of its parents and its playmates.
The little sly remarks that, you know,
we don't play with certain kinds of people, etc.
What bought that program?
What bought that negative program?
The innocence of the child.
And so that innocence remains
within our consciousness throughout our life.
It's always going on.
It's out of the innocence that we buy error.
But the innocence itself is unsullied.
And we have to go back into the recognition
of that inner innocence
in order to forgive ourselves
and to forgive others.
It's that inner innocence that allows us to
learn anything new, you see.
That innocence of the child never changes.
In fact, it is the innocence of the child within you
that is listening to my voice this very second.
It has never changed.
It is that same trusting, believing,
hoping to hear the truth,
open to it,
that same trusting innocence that goes on.
Even if you don't believe what you're hearing
or you don't believe
what you're hearing now,
you're doing it because of some
opposite program within your mind
that says, let's say,
don't trust.
And what bought that program,
don't trust?
Your innocence.
It's because you're innocent
you bought that program.
Don't trust anybody.
So even the untrusting person
is doing it out of trust.
He's trusting the truth of that statement,
isn't he?
Maybe one day,
you know, his father says,
don't trust anybody out there, you see.
And it was innocence that bought the distrust.
So innocence itself is unsullied, untouched.
It never changes.
It is the nature of consciousness itself.
It's the hardware of the computer.
No matter how many negative software programs
and floppy disks you play through it,
the hardware is untouched, unsullied.
It remains the same, pristine and pure.
That inner pristine purity then
is still within all of us.
And so that brings us then to compassion.
Compassion.
We see then
how we picked up programs as we grew up.
Out of pride, let's say, in adolescence.
Or the young boy that I was, let's say.
Out of pride.
You don't want to admit that you have fear,
that you have desire,
that you have feelings of loss
and regret and hopelessness.
These are not manly.
The self-hatred that then accumulates,
the guilt that accumulates,
out of the constant rejection of your own humanness.
And so we have to move to a way of being with ourself
which is a healing way of being with ourself.
And what I'm talking about is easy to do.
It's merely choosing to be compassionate.
Choosing to be forgiving.
Now the decision comes
to be that way about myself.
To be that way about others.
Because if I am that way
about others,
then automatically I am that way about myself.
If I am that way about myself,
I automatically become that way about others.
See, that which I forgive in others,
I automatically am forgiving in myself.
Because all I'm seeing out there
is myself projected into the world.
If I forgive it in myself,
then I also forgive it in the world.
And so what happens then
is the beginning of the undoing
of all this negativity.
The replacement of all these negative low energies
by a positive plus 500 or 540 energy.
As we do this,
we begin to experience the world and ourself differently.
Our relationship to life differently.
And we begin to experience an inner joy.
An inner joyfulness.
When we begin to see the results
of our willingness to let go our condemnations
of ourself and others.
What happens is we begin to make this a habit.
It's the way we are in the world.
It's a decision that we make.
That that's the kind of a person
that we are choosing to be.
A powerful decision.
A powerful intention.
That intention to be
a source of healing to yourself and to others
then sets up a context.
Context.
What does context mean?
Intention sets up context.
Our intention to be this kind of a person then,
sets up the whole energy of our consciousness
and aligns it so that we begin to see things that way.
In other words, there is an actual alteration of perception.
We literally begin to see the world
through forgiving eyes.
Through healing eyes.
Through compassionate eyes.
Not sympathy.
We're not talking about sympathy.
Which is down in the lower energy fields.
We're talking about a lovingness as an inner decision
to be that kind of a human being
towards our self and towards others.
The willingness, the willingness
to let go of our criticalness,
our moralistic right and wrong,
polarizing our self with others by saying
my position is right and your position is wrong.
Because the body expresses what the mind believes,
the mind, this decision then,
begins to affect the body.
And we track down the mechanics of that with kinesiology.
We said that when you hold a loving thought in mind,
if you picture somebody,
you can have anybody in your family test you.
You hold out your arm and you resist
and you hold a loving thought in mind.
When you do that, you'll see you're strong.
Now you hold an unloving thought in mind
and you'll see you instantly go weak.
The body is instantly reflecting what the mind believes.
As we move into this decision then
to be forgiving and compassionate,
to be that which supports life
and nurtures it instead of condemns it
or moralistically puts it down
and gets into a make wrong,
our willingness to let go of make wrongs.
We let go attacking ourself for being ill.
And some people who get into spiritual work
or metaphysical studies, etc.
will compound it by making themself wrong
because they have a physical illness.
Our willingness to accept whatever is being expressed
on the physical level
and our willingness to look within our own consciousness
to see what is bringing about
is what is being brought to our attention.
So that everything that's happening in our life
is happening in order to come up to be healed.
So instead of being ashamed
that we're a spiritual seeker, let's say,
and that we have a physical illness,
instead we become thankful
see, gratitude, and we say,
aha, something is coming up
in order to be healed.
See, once you have that capacity,
once you've activated that which is healing within yourself,
what happens is it brings up the various things to be healed.
So it's a sign of progress,
not a sign of falling back at all.
We can be happy that we have a chance
to heal these things.
So an illness then is merely
our consciousness
calling attention to something that needs to be looked at.
There's something in which we're feeling guilty.
There's some belief system we're holding
that has to be let go of and cancelled.
There's something that has to be forgiven.
There's something within us that has to be loved.
So we thank it then for bringing it to our awareness.
We say, thank you, ulcer.
I see you forced me to look at the way
in which I was condemning myself
and not loving myself.
Thank you, hypoglycemia,
for showing me how much I've been living in fear.
You thank all your illnesses then
because they have brought you to that willingness,
to that acceptance,
to move into that field of lovingness
and the joy of realizing now
out of compassion
that this is how the body brings about self-healing.
The pain then serves a purpose.
We hold it now in a different way.
We're going to make lemonade out of it.
Instead of going into self-pity about my sickness.
See, self-pity is down in here.
Instead of poor me,
instead of being victim, why me?
We say, what is that trying to tell me?
What is it I'm supposed to learn?
And we get interested in learning
about the nature of consciousness.
We become interested in finding out
what is underlying this
and so that we can heal it
through a greater understanding.
So the first tool that we need then is willingness.
An open mind.
The willingness to say
the mind is doing something that's being asked to be looked at
so that it can be healed.
See, the healing of the body comes about automatically
with the healing of the mind.
All the physical illnesses which I eventually let go of
and which healed of their own nature spontaneously
all came about as a result of healing the thought forms in mind.
One of the healings came about is
the willingness to let go of self-condemnation
and the condemnation of others.
Criticalness, self-pity, resentment,
all the things that we see in the box,
regret, worry, anxiety,
grievances,
self-contempt, self-hatred.
It was the letting go of those things then
that shifted the energy field.
And the energy field is what brought about the healing.
And of course, I worked with it.
I kept canceling the belief systems,
hypoglycemia, gout.
As each one would come up, I would cancel it
and say, I no longer believe in that.
I no longer believe in that.
I'm no longer subject to that.
That's the result of a belief system
and I have the power of canceling it.
And so we begin to own that we have the power of denial.
Not denial in meaning being unconscious of,
but the power to refuse.
I have the power to refuse that.
And I don't have to buy into that.
Now because these belief systems are so prevalent in our culture,
we naively think, well, they must have a certain reality
or everybody wouldn't believe it.
The only reality they have is on the level of a thought form.
The fact that there's agreement about a certain thought form
doesn't give it a reality.
It only means that there's agreement about it.
So I can refuse to buy into the collective belief systems
about all these various diseases
and I watch it as those programs come in.
I refuse to believe in cancer.
I refuse to believe in AIDS.
I refuse to believe in all the well-intentioned educational programs
about all these diseases, hyperglycemia and gout
and heart disease and cholesterol.
You see, each one as you buy it, you become subject to it.
You're only subject to what you believe in mind.
You see, if you think eating eggs
is going to raise your cholesterol
and raising your cholesterol is going to give you heart trouble,
then what happens is eating eggs raises your cholesterol
and the cholesterol gives you heart trouble
because of the power of mind. See?
Mind is so powerful.
It creates the thought form.
The thought form then manifests on the physical plane
and becomes a physical reality.
And so you see, self-healing then really depends
on the reversal of the usual belief system of causality.
What you hold in mind manifests on the physical
and it's not the other way around.
It isn't eating the cholesterol that gave you the heart problem.
It's the belief that eating a lot of cholesterol
gives you the heart trouble.
That's a very critical point to get.
The power of the belief system is sufficient
to give you the entire disease picture.
In the beginning, we mentioned multiple personalities.
And here you see it demonstrated clearly.
The one personality that comes into the body,
let's say Dick, and is there for several months,
believes in allergies, believes in cholesterol,
believes in all these things.
And when he's there, the person has attacks of gout,
the person has migraine headaches,
the person has any of a whole great variety of illnesses.
His cholesterol goes up from eating eggs
and he believes in all the fearfulness
and all the fearful programs of the world.
But when the other personality is present in the body,
none of that occurs.
You see, the belief system,
the mind of the other personality,
now the body manifests what that mind believes.
And so the person doesn't get hay fever.
The person doesn't get asthma.
He can eat all the eggs he wants, his cholesterol never goes up.
And if you ask him what he believes about this,
he'll tell you it's all nonsense.
He doesn't believe a word of it.
If you don't believe a word of it,
it disappears from your body.
It disappears from your body if at the same time
you're letting go of the sources of unconscious guilt
and you stop reinforcing the illness by labeling it
and propagating it
and bringing about a fulfillment of your own self-prophecies.
We cannot allow the mind to come up with a belief system
without challenging it.
You see, if the mind unconsciously has been working against us,
if we have been unaware of how much power it has,
well, now we can turn around and use that power in our own behalf.
That same power which undid us can now work for us,
and so we consciously utilize the power of mind now.
So when the thought comes up,
I have hypoglycemia, I stop it, I cancel it,
I say the truth.
I am no longer subject to that.
I'm an infinite being. I'm no longer subject to that.
Now, hypoglycemia is a good example
because it took me a considerable amount of time to undo that one.
After all, I'd given lectures on it for many years.
It was operative clinically as an actual physical reality,
and when I did a lot of work on nutrition,
especially its relationship to the addictions and alcoholism in particular,
it was a very important issue.
I myself was a firm believer in it,
and then I came to the understanding
and the realization that my firm belief in it
was then operating within my body,
which was expressing my mind's belief in hypoglycemia.
And so I had to keep canceling it and keep canceling it,
and stating the truth.
And eventually, severe hypoglycemia disappeared.
The abnormal blood sugars corrected themselves.
And so for many years then,
this was maybe 15 or more years ago,
that I finally let go of the belief system in hypoglycemia
and recovered from it.
It took some time, though.
It took about a year or two.
These various illnesses disappear in different periods of time.
Some of these illnesses disappeared in a matter of days.
Some even disappeared in hours.
Some took months.
This one took longer than almost any of them,
other than a block eustachian tube.
That one also took two years.
I forgot to mention that one in my list of ailments.
But for some 15 years,
I ate all the sugar and sweets I want.
And for the reasons which I explained in my weight tape,
I never gained weight from it.
I didn't have any hypoglycemic symptoms.
Hypoglycemia just no longer existed in my life.
And so I ate hot fudge sundaes and pecan pie and enjoyed myself.
And then I started giving some lectures locally.
They asked me to give some lectures on hypoglycemia.
So I was sort of going back in time,
you know, to sort of a different level of consciousness,
to the physical level again.
And so I started giving little short talks
on hypoglycemia.
And I would explain how the blood sugar goes up
and how the blood sugar goes down and all.
And after giving these talks a few times a month,
after about three months,
I started getting symptoms of hypoglycemia back again.
I would eat sugar and sweets and I would get the shakes
and get feeling anxious and start feeling depressed
and emotionally unstable.
And I thought, after all these years,
how could I be getting hypoglycemia back again?
And I realized giving these talks on hypoglycemia
had reactivated the belief system within my mind.
And so I had to stop them.
I had to cancel it.
I can't fool myself.
I can't, on the one hand, not believe it.
I thought I could split my mind,
in which I could, you know, say,
for you folks who still believe in this, this is true,
and at the same time split myself and say,
but I am exempt from that
because I no longer believe in that.
But I found that that old memory track got reactivated.
The belief system in hypoglycemia returned.
And so I had to re-cancel it.
And so using these talks,
self-healing systems, this may occur.
You may suddenly get the recurrence of something
and you have to check out what are you doing
that you should be canceling.
And so I began to re-cancel the belief in hypoglycemia
and restate the truth.
I am an infinite being.
I am not subject to that.
And within a month or two,
the symptoms of hypoglycemia disappeared again
and have not returned.
So that demonstrates the principle of watchfulness.
If the mind is that powerful,
we can't let it get away with
that belief system even once.
Every time that comes up,
I am allergic.
Every time the thought system comes up,
I am allergic,
it has to be instantly challenged and canceled.
One powerful thought, you see,
is sufficient to create it on the physical plane.
And so we can't be sloppy about this work.
We have to watch it carefully within ourself.
There is really no order of difficulty
in the curing, in the healing of these various illnesses.
And what do we mean by that?
It means that what the world considers a severe illness
is just as easy to let go of as a minor one.
It is just as easy to believe,
you know, to cancel your belief system in coals
as it is in cancer.
And amongst my friends and acquaintances and co-workers
and the people that I have worked with
as Director of the Institute for Spiritual Research in Sedona,
there is a group of people here
who have recovered from every illness known to mankind,
all forms of cancer,
and multiple sclerosis,
and myasthenia gravis,
severe intractable paralyzing illnesses,
complete and total recovery.
Given up as hopeless, given up as almost dead,
and yet those people who have become friends of mine
are extremely alive, extremely well,
have no traces at all of these illnesses.
So it doesn't make any difference.
Why is that so?
Because the truth is the truth,
and that which is false is false.
It doesn't depend on the form of the falsehood.
All that is false is false,
just as all that is true is true.
If your mind can create it,
well, then your mind can cancel it.
So if you begin to use the power of the mind
in your own behalf,
hmm, what about the use of medical measures?
What about the use of traditional medical measures
while we go about our process of self-healing?
See, our process of self-healing at this point now
is being handled on the level of the specific
by letting go our resistance to experiencing it
and canceling it, canceling the thought forms.
The healing is going on in a general,
more powerful way by our willingness
to let go of all criticism and attack
and the beginning to love the humanness
in ourself and others,
and the reawakening of our awareness of its innocence.
What about the third level,
that is, traditional medical treatment?
What part do they play in this kind of self-healing?
Traditional medical treatments now, surprisingly,
become very effective.
We'll find that as we let go of our guiltiness,
which came about through our lack of compassion
for our own humanness,
that medical measures that once were fruitless
now begin to be effective.
In other words, all the illnesses I had,
I was in traditional medical treatment for,
for 20 years or more,
migraine headaches and ulcers and diverticulitis.
I mean, I was on the diets and I was on the medications
and the antispasmodics and the antacids,
and I did all the traditional medical things,
but they weren't working.
What you could say is they perhaps kept things
from getting worse.
After all, I didn't have my stomach taken out, right?
I didn't have to have the colon removed.
So they were working,
but they were working against all this negative programming
going on within the mind.
What happens as you let go of all the negative programming
is that all these formerly relatively ineffective
medical treatments now become very effective.
They become very, very effective.
So that the antispasmodic that once barely
held the symptoms under control
now totally relieves the symptoms.
A healing comes about.
The antispasmodic, the antacids,
and whatever diet was considered necessary
now brings about a healing of the ulcer.
The medications are very powerfully effective.
The medications to relieve the allergies
now work wondrously well.
And we find that the need for the medication
then dwindles off.
The need for all these ameliorative measures
finally disappear.
And so we can resume a normal diet.
You can imagine with an elevated cholesterol,
hypoglycemia, diverticulitis, an active ulcer,
migraine, and multiple allergies,
what kind of a diet I must have lived on.
I literally remember walking into a restaurant,
looking at the menu,
and the only thing I could eat on the menu
was the salad and the spinach.
Because there were seeds and things
which would aggravate the diverticulitis.
There was acids which would aggravate the ulcer.
I couldn't eat tomatoes or anything of that nature.
Of course, nothing with sugar in it or white bread,
so all the pasta, all the bakery,
all the desserts had to go out the window.
And the meat, of course, I had to watch out
because of the guilt, I mean the guilt, you see,
that was it, the guilt of the gout.
The unconscious gives you away.
Because of the gout, you see.
So I couldn't eat all that meat
because it would elevate my uric acid level.
And so frankly, folks, there was very few
things left on this planet to eat.
But as those things relieved themselves,
then I found that diet was also a belief system.
You know, and that's the downside of holistic health,
is the belief system that all these things
are injurious to you.
They're injurious to you because
you're holding in mind that they're injurious to you.
No such thing exists in the world of the real.
And so I am now on a high-sugar, high-cholesterol,
high-fat diet.
My cholesterol, my blood sugar are normal.
I'm on a high-purine diet,
and I never get a gout attack, you see.
Those all turned out to be corollaries to the belief system.
If you have a belief system about gout,
then you will have all that goes with it
and all the various meats that supposedly bring it on,
you know, pickled herring, which I loved, etc.
I used to have it so severe that, you know,
I just took a little liver pate and put it on a cracker.
Literally, one night full of liver pate
would bring on a gout attack.
Now I can eat a pound of it,
and one day I actually did eat a pound of it,
and liver and kidneys,
and I always tell the story of how I one day
cooked a frying pan full of liver and kidneys for my kitty,
and I thought she loved them,
and instead she stuck her nose up at them.
Well, you sort of, as you heal from these illnesses
using these techniques we've described today in this talk,
you sort of sometimes just know when you've recovered from something.
So Kitty wouldn't eat the kidneys and the liver,
and it was a big pan of them, you know,
and it smelled delicious as I was cooking with onions in it
and a little bit of bacon, etc.
I even put some catnip in it,
and Kitty just wasn't interested.
So all of a sudden I just saw
that my whole dietary limitation
was just a crazy belief system I was holding in mind.
And I said, I'm an infinite being.
I'm not subject to this.
I mean, this is absurd.
So I sat down and, you know,
I ate a whole pan of kidney and liver,
and, needless to say,
I didn't have a gout attack,
nor have I ever had one since.
You just cancel it.
It's a belief system.
It's a joke.
It's a sad joke, but it's still a joke.
It's a joke that we're only subject to what we hold in mind.
You see, when we re-own the source of our power,
when we stop giving it away to the world,
the cause of God is not in kidneys and liver.
It is not in stress.
It is not in uric acid levels.
It has nothing to do with purine metabolism.
It has to do with what I hold in mind.
When I re-own,
when I stop denying the power of my own mind,
when I begin to realize that I am the source,
I am the source,
and by I, what do I mean?
I mean my consciousness,
my infinite being,
my infinite being.
Let's look over at the chart then
and look at the physics
of how this works.
What are the intrinsic physics?
What are the energy fuels and what are the levels?
You see, instead of owning myself down here,
instead of putting the power out into the world,
which is a lie,
which is below this energy field here,
therefore the energy field goes that way,
I begin to re-own the truth about myself.
My willingness to look into this
brings about the experience of the truth of it.
It's by the doingness of this
that you realize the truth of it.
That is the scientific purity
of what I'm talking about today.
What I'm talking about today is pure science,
that you yourself can re-duplicate
the truth of what I'm saying through your own experimentation,
through your own individual case.
As I re-own myself then as the source,
as I move up in my own level of consciousness,
I begin to realize
I'm not subject to anything except that which I hold in mind,
that it has been my belief systems,
my thought forms,
that which I've brought into,
that have been the cause of what I've been experiencing.
The source, the cause of my own experience
is what I hold in mind.
The world has no power to create any such thing.
Does a piece of kidney have power in it?
Of course it doesn't.
Does my mind have the power?
To create that as a source of disease,
you bet it does.
And so, we begin to undo the syndrome of the bubble person.
What happens to the bubble person?
The bubble person's innocent childlike mind
buys with enthusiasm this whole idea, let's say,
of holistic health, nutrition.
It begins to read all the literature.
Well, let me tell you,
if you continue reading that literature long enough,
you will find that everything in your world
and everything in your experience,
everything in this universe
and everything in your environment will kill you.
I mean, that is the message you will get.
Magnesium will kill you. Calcium will kill you.
The energy is given off by the rugs and the paints,
everything that's in the air.
You see, if you walk by somebody who's smoking a cigarette,
ah, I'm going to get cancer of the lung.
All these powerfully negative, you know, thought systems,
you begin to buy into them
and pretty soon you begin to cancel them one by one.
I did it.
I began to remove one thing after another from my diet.
I had a friend that says,
eggs will kill you. Goodbye eggs.
Cholesterol will kill you. Goodbye cholesterol.
Butter will kill you. Dairy products will kill you.
Meat will kill you.
Well, eat fruit. Okay.
Fruit's full of pesticides. Holy smoke.
I was into fruit.
Fruit didn't last long at all
because the minute you get the pesticide story, goodbye fruit.
Then I went to vegetables.
Uh-oh, vegetables are full of it too.
They spray all those fields in California.
You become increasingly paranoid, folks.
You don't become increasingly healthy.
You become increasingly paranoid.
And my brown bag friends are all dead.
Brown bag friends.
Those are people that used to belong to one of the medical societies
that really got going on this.
And a brown bag person is one
who has bought so much of this in the world now
that he can only eat one or two grains.
There's only a few things left on the planet he can eat,
which he himself, I presume,
has picked somewhere in the fields of Afghanistan or something
where they don't use pesticides.
And this is carried around in a brown bag.
So when he goes to an event
where everybody else is eating the banquet, etc.,
full of what he considers to be nothing but poison, you see,
killing himself with the steak and the pesticides on the peas
and the pesticides on the fruit
and the pesticides on the lettuce,
while in his view they are killing themselves,
he eats out of his brown bag.
You see, he sits in the back corner.
And this is actually a scene at a big banquet.
And there's a whole table full of brown bag people.
And, of course, he fasts a lot
and he does a lot of running
and all this kind of stuff.
And, of course, he's dead now.
Why is he dead?
A man who did this running every day
and lived this out...
Because he became a bubble person
in which the paranoid view of the world now
begins to close in on you.
You can't breathe the air with trust.
You can't believe anything you hear.
You can't, you see, even enjoy these rugs here
because they're probably giving off something to which you're allergic.
The paints are emanating fumes.
The insulation is emanating fumes.
Little fiber particles are choking you up.
Somebody might have smoked in here
and there's a smoke particle that's going to give you cancer.
And so your life becomes smaller and smaller and smaller
because what's happening is you're progressively denying the truth about yourself.
You're progressively giving away the power of your being,
the power of causality to the world,
to that which is inanimate.
What is happening is you're reversing the truth.
You're progressively reversing the truth
in which you become increasingly vulnerable and victim.
You end up with the total paranoia of the bubble person
who can only live within a protective bubble of purified purification.
This is all going on in consciousness.
This is all going on in mind.
It's not going on anywhere in reality.
It's buying back what is true,
buying back the truth of the power of our own decision
that we can cancel that.
We are not subject to that.
I am an infinite being.
I am only subject to what I hold in mind.
I have the power of canceling.
I have the power of refusing to buy into that commercial.
I have the power of saying no
instead of buying into the collective unconscious.
I have the power of saying no to family belief systems.
Allergies may run in my family, and they did.
My grandmother was allergic. My mother was allergic.
My sister was allergic.
And I can say, but that does not apply to me.
The truth is, I am only subject to what I hold in mind.
And with that thought, we heal ourself.
Amen.