I'm Dr. David Hawkins. I've been a psychiatrist for the last 35 years.
I've worked in the fields of psychoanalysis, psychopharmacology, psychotherapy, group therapy.
I did a lot of research in the nature of relationship between nutrition and brain chemistry.
And for the last 10 years, I've been working in the research into the nature of consciousness itself
and its relationship to that field of knowledge referred to by the world as spiritual.
And today's talk will be on giving up being old, letting go of the aging process,
how to identify with that aspect of yourself which is real,
and let go of those identifications with that which is unreal.
And so we'll be talking about the relationship between body, mind, and spirit.
What is the true relationship, and how does that relate to our topic for today?
We'll be looking at where is it that man experiences experience,
because if we address the results of our research to that area where man really experiences his experience,
we find that we are not subject to many things that the world holds to be inevitable.
We see that aging is a series of identifications.
It's buying into a whole series of programs, stereotypes, behavior patterns.
It's buying life scripts.
That which really experiences life has no age.
And it is not subject to aging.
And we have to ask ourselves, are we that which we are experiencing, or are we the experiencer?
We'll look into the middle-aged myth, the health patterns, sexual patterns,
so weight problems that supposedly occur in middle age.
We'll look into the statement that the body does what the mind believes,
and we'll look into the physics of that.
We'll look into the fact that the body is really the effect and not the cause,
that it's not the cause.
subject to what we hold in mind.
We'll look at the fact that we have freedom of choice to elect these various patterns.
We'll look at the adopting of family patterns
and the influence that they have had on our thoughts and beliefs about longevity
and what that looks like.
The importance of feeling that your life is a contribution, a sharing,
that it makes a difference, that it is of value.
We'll look at some experiments from hypnosis.
We'll look at some odd things that have occurred in science
that have occurred in our lives.
We'll look at a clinical example called progeria and what that means to us.
We'll look at aging as a class phenomenon.
We'll look at sex and age.
And so today we'll cover this whole field which preoccupies everyone as he grows older,
the facts, the fantasies.
How can this be handled coming from our knowledge of the nature of consciousness itself?
And so we'll be referring, as we have in these other talks,
to a map of consciousness, something we have found,
and extremely useful.
It gives us an orientation to the whole subject of human behavior and who am I.
And here we have really a mathematical model
in which we have worked out the relative energy fields,
the directions of the energy fields of these levels of consciousness,
and we've worked out numerically their relative power,
starting with death at zero and enlightenment at 600, for instance.
We find that,
apathy at 50 has half the power of fear,
and fear calibrates at 100.
We find that fear has half the energy of courage.
So we find that neutral, where everything is just okay with you,
has half the energy of love.
We notice that below this level of courage,
which is the capacity to tell the truth,
that all the energy fields are reversed and in a negative direction.
And we notice critically,
above this level that all the energy fields go to the right.
In other words, those plus positive energy fields
are those which nurture, support, and value life and hold it as sacred.
These energy fields below are those which are opposed to life,
do not support life,
and in fact, at the very bottom, become destruction.
Loss of energy, loss of spirit, deflation, entrapment, inflation and expansion
are all negative processes.
And they lead to viewing the world in a negative way.
They lead to seeing God in a very negative way.
And so, in our talk today, we'll be going back to this chart,
to this map of consciousness,
and so that we have a way of orienting our knowledge of this whole field.
It's necessary to restate then the relationship between body, mind and spirit,
to see what this really means, because it is very important
in looking at our subject for today.
It's necessary to know and to realize through your own inner reflection and contemplation
that the body is unable to experience itself.
We've said this in all of our talks, but it cannot bear repeating too often.
The body has no capacity to experience itself.
Our knowledge about the body, of what's going on with the body,
is coming from its sensations.
The sensations themselves, in and of themselves,
have no capacity to experience themselves.
That experience has to go on in something that is greater than the body and its sensations,
its sensory mechanisms, and that is mind itself.
It's because of mind that you're aware of what is going on within the sensations,
and the sensations are telling you what is happening within the body.
Mind itself, as curious as it may seem, has no capacity to experience itself.
A thought cannot experience its own thoughtness.
A feeling cannot experience its own feelingness.
A memory cannot experience its own memoryness.
Mind itself, in order to be experienced,
has to be experienced by something that is greater than itself,
and that is the energy field of consciousness itself.
Consciousness itself being greater than mind and more inclusive.
Consciousness itself, how do we know what we are conscious of?
Is coming from an infinite field with no limitations whatsoever called awareness.
It's because of awareness that we know what is going on in consciousness.
It is because of consciousness that we know what is going on in mind.
It is because of mind that we're aware of what's going on with sensations.
It's because of sensations we're aware of what's going on with the body.
Consequently, that which we are, that which is aware,
that which we really mean by the ultimate I, the infinite self,
that which is aware and conscious,
is far removed, many levels removed, as you can see, from the body.
The interesting thing is that the body, one law of consciousness is,
is that the body does what the mind holds.
We're only subject to what the mind is holding.
In other words, the body, being like a puppet, is controlled by mind.
It is controlled both consciously and unconsciously.
Few people realize the power of mind over body.
When we look back at our field of consciousness,
when we look at this map,
we'll see that the physical body has a relative energy of about 100.
Mind itself is up here in the 400s,
although we don't have it on the blackboard because we only have limited space.
All the levels of mind are energy fields in the 400s.
The energy field of the body is neutral.
It is neither positive or negative.
A thought then held in mind, if we just look at the physics of it,
held from an energy of 400 then dominates the body,
which only has an energy field of 100.
Consequently, the beliefs, the ideas, the thoughts, the configurations,
the patterns, the scripts that we hold in mind are adopted by the body
and begin to reflect in the body's physical appearance.
And we certainly have covered this in our talks on health,
in our talks on illness,
and in our talks on giving up the various diseases,
in which I shared a lot of my personal experience as well as research.
So this principle will be very important for us to look at today.
And we'll demonstrate it with clinical examples,
and we'll give you ways to verify it for yourself.
How to undo the middle age myth,
the whole idea of decrepit old age,
the idea of failing health,
the belief system that all these things are inevitable,
that they must be part and parcel of the body process itself,
little realizing that they are actually coming from mind.
And so we come across the principle of where is the source,
that mind is the creator and that the physical body is the effect.
Mind is where causation occurs and the physical body is in effect.
The fact that the material world then is at the effect
is the result of what is held in mind.
And we can demonstrate this with very simple clinical examples such as hypnosis.
We see in hypnosis, for instance, we can take an old person who is quite feeble.
He walks in the office and he says,
Would you like me to sit here?
Could I sit in this chair here?
And he sits down as though he barely has the strength and the power to sit in the chair.
And we put him under hypnosis and we tell him he's 35 years old.
And then we induce amnesia.
So he doesn't remember what the suggestion was.
And then we wake him up from his hypnotic state.
And we say, Would you like a glass of water?
And he says, Oh yes, I'd like a glass of water.
And he walks over to the bubbler and he takes a glass and he fills it and he sits down.
And the feeble old man is gone.
Where is all the shaking? Where is all the trembling?
Where is all the weakness? Where is all that decrepitness?
What has happened to the feeble old man? He seems to have disappeared.
We can see with the clinical example then, through the hypnotic state,
that the mind is reflecting exactly what the mind believes.
The body is reflecting exactly what the mind believes.
The way it stands. The way it holds itself.
The attitude towards the body.
The old person is looking at the body as though it's frail.
You know, they're preoccupied. They might fall and break their hip.
And thereby holding that in mind and bringing it into their life experience.
So with hypnosis we see a very good example then.
And we've used also the example in other talks of the multiple personality.
Where one of the personalities has totally different views about health and life and aging
than the second personality.
And when the one personality is in the body, the body reflects what that personality believes.
So if one personality believes in asthma, while that personality is in the body,
the person literally has asthma.
But when that personality is replaced by a more pleasant personality
that doesn't have a belief in these psychosomatic illnesses,
then we see the asthma is not present.
And that person has no allergies.
Consequently, the physical body is reflecting exactly what our belief systems are.
We'll look at how did these belief systems arise.
First of all, that we have an option.
You see, the mind concludes, I don't have any options.
The naive mind thinks I'm at the effect of the body.
I'm at the effect of the ongoingness of time.
In this case, the mind is giving away its power to the calendar.
It says, it pictures as the years go by, the body must of necessity get older.
Well, we see a very interesting clinical example in a scientific condition called progeria.
In which the person progressively ages and becomes an extremely old, old person by the age of 5, 6, 7, 8, 9
and often dead by age 10 of old age.
Literal old age, decrepit old age by age 10.
And so we see an interesting example.
How can old age and actually death from old age occur in a span of only 10 calendar years?
If calendar years were cause and physical body was at the effect of the calendar, no such thing could occur.
The only reason to bring these up is to
begin to open the mind to see that we have options.
To see that that which we believe, that which we buy into,
that which we allow ourselves to be programmed by,
now becomes the source. It becomes the program.
It becomes the script.
And this script begins to express itself on the physical level.
When we see it occurring on the physical level,
the mind, because of its naivete, concludes that causation,
is happening on the physical level.
So the naive mind sees causality as A causes B causes C
within the physical realm.
The turning of the calendar, the turning of the seasons,
is causing, on the physical level then, the aging process of the body.
It sees causality on the physical level as A causes B causes C.
And closer to reality,
the truth is that something from a higher level is causing,
sequentially, both A, B and C.
Cause is on this level, effect is on this level.
If I hold a concept in mind that goes A, B, C,
then within the physical world what we see is first A, then B, then C.
The left brain, because it thinks linearly
and projects its concepts onto the phenomena of the world,
holds, therefore,
that A must cause B cause C,
never suspecting that causality of A, B, C
is coming from a different level altogether.
So the level of cause, where the power is,
is the level of mind.
The world of the physical is the world of effect.
It creates A, B, C.
So if I hold a pattern in mind of what aging looks like,
what I think it must be and what must happen,
I create on the physical level A, B, C.
The decrepit, feeble old man,
because in his childhood that's what old people looked like.
He was convinced.
That's what you look like when you're 80.
And so when he was 80, that's exactly what he looked like.
So if we could look back into his mind,
go into his mind and see his pictures
of what does an old man look like,
we would see exactly what an old man looks like
because he's standing there right in front of us.
That was his picture of what it looks like to get old.
The body demonstrating what the mind believes
is an experiment done with the menstrual periods in women
in which they were given an injection.
They were told that this injection would result
in their skipping their next menstrual period.
And so what happened was they were given an injection of a placebo.
And of those people given the injection of a placebo,
all of them experienced either skipping the menstrual period
or a delay.
I think 85% skipped the next menstrual period
and 15% experienced a great delay.
So these examples are not exceptions.
These are...
What we're interested in is the basic principle.
The basic principle is that this is going on all the time.
The mind is continuously reflecting
the patterns and the beliefs of what is being held in mind.
These clinical examples from hypnosis
and research experiments are merely isolated examples
where you can see it clearly.
But you can see then if under hypnosis
the body will do exactly what the mind believes.
For instance, you can put a patient under
and tell him he's allergic to roses.
And when he wakes up, his nose will stuff up.
He'll go into hay fever and have an asthma attack
right there within the office.
It's been done many times and it's historically recorded
in the annals of psychoanalysis.
This is always going on.
And so now you begin to get a feel
for what we're talking about.
That the constant programming is coming in.
The expectations of middle age and old age
and what this is supposed to mean
are now bought by the mind out of its naivete.
And as we've said in other talks,
one of the basic principles of consciousness itself
is its intrinsic innocence.
It's because the mind is innocent
that we have to carefully begin to watch it and guard it.
We have to become like its mother.
Our mind is like an innocent kid
who goes out in the world
and believes everything it hears.
It believes every billboard.
It believes every commercial.
It believes every remark that people make.
It believes what it sees.
It has no way to evaluate it.
It has no sense of discrimination.
And so we have to begin to sort of take responsibility
and say, I can see that my mind
and its intrinsic innocence
because the innocence of the mind of the child
is still with us throughout life.
And I'd better start looking into what it's been buying.
And so we look at the lives of many people
that are very creative.
And we see that, characteristically,
they live well into their 90s.
And frequently they get married at 85
and start having children at 90.
And Dr. John Diamond, a physician,
has written a couple of books about that
in his books about behavioral kinesiology
and the energy of life
in which he does a whole chapter on that.
He made a study of the life patterns
of those who are into classical music,
conductors and composers and performers.
And he found that, characteristically,
they all live to a very old age
and remain productive.
We think nothing of an 86-year-old conductor
leading a whole symphony orchestra,
having a 34-year-old wife
and a young baby at home.
We all just sort of know
that that goes with that lifestyle.
Writers who live to a very advanced age.
People into research and physics
who live to a very ripe old age.
Performers.
We think of George Burns, Fred Astaire.
Age means nothing at all, then, as such.
In other words, the numerical, chronological age
has no power within it.
But our beliefs about that,
how we hold that,
how we genuflect to all the belief systems
that go with that,
that we've bought throughout the years,
that does have power.
How is it that some people are dancing
and performing at 90,
and other people at 59
are ready for the grave?
I have a friend who, at age 59,
looks like he's about 75.
It's like life is all over.
He's already had a couple of coronary bypass operations.
The way he holds himself,
the weakness and the whole body stance,
tells you what he believes old age must entail.
So the first thing we have to see
is that we have options.
We have options.
We can choose to be different.
We can choose to let go of the belief systems in our family.
We can begin to see now and look back
where did these belief systems about
what middle age and the aging process,
where did they come from?
What constitutes them?
We look at our own childhood now
and look at our grandparents.
And what was our relationship with our grandparents?
And at that time, our parents were middle aged.
So when we look at our middle aged parents,
remember the pattern,
we see that like a photograph,
the negative.
It means what? A beer belly?
It means sitting home,
feeling tired and discouraged
and watching the television set
and complaining about life.
Does it mean overhearing remarks?
Well, I don't have the energy for that anymore.
Getting the thought that well,
you're over the hill
and the men start to wink at each other.
Hey George, what are you,
a little over the hill there?
Meaning middle age,
forget about sex life.
All these programs are going into the impressionable mind
of the naive child.
He's creating a picture
what mother looks like,
tired and bedraggled.
She no longer cares for her appearance,
doesn't bother going to the beautician anymore
because middle age to her now means
sort of retiring from life, you see.
And we see the people looking forward to retirement
and what their views of that are.
The confusion of retiring from the job
with retiring from life.
How many people do you know at age 65
retired not just from jobs,
but they retired from life itself?
The whole attitude is,
we'll go to sunset hills now
and slowly wait for the sun to set.
We'll join the old people's
fade out club
and we get progressively weaker
and watch each other go.
That's an option.
George Burns didn't buy that option.
Fred Astaire didn't buy that option.
The great composers and writers,
think of all the politicians
and the powers that run this world
well into their 60s, 70s and 80s.
As they got older,
their power, their wisdom,
their ability in the world
grew ever stronger, not weaker.
Look at all the thought systems and beliefs
about what is supposed to happen to the body.
All the thoughts of what we think
aging must entail.
When I was young,
I heard about the prostate trouble
of all the grandfathers and men in my family.
All the men from age 45 or 50 on
had prostate trouble.
And they complained about this.
And women's complaints about their
GU system and GI system,
all these things that supposedly go with old age.
And when I got to be 50,
I didn't realize it,
but I was holding all those thoughts
in my mind too.
And at age 50,
suddenly I became a very middle-aged,
aging person.
At age 50,
suddenly my hands and my feet
were cold all the time.
I was exhausted all the time.
I was tired.
Libido went out the window.
The prostate became enlarged.
All kinds of physical diseases began to happen.
All the things that fit my picture
of middle age,
discouragement and depression.
At middle age, the picture was
you're very tired out by the world.
You're exhausted.
You lay on the couch and you can barely get up.
You complain about your prostate.
And you infer by various jokes and innuendos
that sex is, you know, a thing of the past now
because older people don't have that.
You see?
Like nuns don't go to the bathroom.
All those childhood beliefs, you see?
How is it that all this came to pass then?
It came to pass because that was my picture
of what it meant to be middle-aged.
And so, to begin with then,
we have to look at what are our pictures?
What was our relationship with our parents?
Did we love them?
Interesting enough that love can be
the very reason for that identification.
It's because we love them
that we pattern ourself after them.
If you admire your father
and then he develops this middle-age pattern,
of your admiration and love for him
and family loyalty,
you identify with it and you pick up this pattern,
not for negative reasons,
but out of innocence and out of love.
The same with your relationship with your grandparents.
You get an idea of what old age looks like.
Now, I had a relatively negative view of middle age.
But I had a relatively positive view
of old age.
And therefore, I've always looked forward to old age.
At 76, my grandfather was up on the roof
putting on a new roof.
My other grandfather was dignified and elegant.
And so, I looked forward to old age.
That's the time when you can put on your spots
and your spats and your best hat
and dress up and wear your best clothes
and live a really aristocratic, enjoyable life.
For once, you can really just be who you really are.
It's going to be over before long
and therefore, you don't have to cater to anybody anymore.
You can really be elegant
and a very loving and wonderful person.
So, old age, to me,
was not something of a faltering decrepitude.
It has been for other people, however.
And so, we see that we have an option.
It's who you loved and who you identified with.
It's all the programming that we've gotten from television,
you know, the movies, the image of what aging means
and all this kind of thing.
The television commercials,
all those things that are designed
to appeal to those fears of aging.
And of course, what we fear, we hold in mind
and what we hold in mind tends to manifest.
So, our fears of old age,
the very things we begin to fear,
are the very things that begin to manifest.
We have to go back to the realization
that we have an option.
We don't have to buy any of these pictures.
Whatever picture we buy
is what is going to manifest in our life.
And therefore, we have to be careful.
About what we buy into.
And so, therefore, we sort of become
the guardian of our mind.
We look at it and see,
what does it believe?
We forgive it for what it picked up over the years.
It didn't know of its own innocence.
And therefore, it picked up all these programs
and stories and scripts.
And unwittingly, we found that we were beginning
to act them out.
Now, if we want to know what life scripts we bought,
all we have to do is look at our life
and look at our physical self
and the physical self then,
being a reflection of what we have bought,
tells us what we've bought.
See, we may not be able to remember it.
Many of these things, we have amnesia.
Remarks overheard throughout childhood.
People look into their memory and say,
I don't remember ever believing such a thing.
We're unconscious and don't remember most of our life.
You realize that you have amnesia really for most of your life.
Because of the millions and millions of things
that you can remember,
what you don't realize is,
in one day, look at how many seconds there are.
Do you remember what happened each second in each day?
You're lucky if you can remember
what you had for breakfast yesterday, right?
Therefore, a great deal of what went on in your life
is forgotten, not totally, not actually forgotten,
but you might say operationally forgotten
and that it's not available for immediate recall.
If we look at the body then,
we'll see what the programs were that it picked up,
what its belief systems were,
what it thought was valuable,
maybe that which it actually loved,
or its reverse, that which it feared
and brought about into manifestation
because the fear was holding it in mind.
We see that the patterns of aging
also follow a certain class phenomena.
And we see a changing picture of age and aging.
We see increasing longevity,
it is now very common for people to live longer
and even though they live longer,
to be energetic and very much alive
into very advanced age.
We see this is characteristic of the upper classes.
We see it as characteristic of those who are aristocratic.
When I said I had grandfathers
who were very lively and spry in their old age
and were very elegant in their style and their dress,
that's a certain lifestyle
which we classify as aristocratic.
It means holding the value of one's life now
and seeing old age as one of increasing stature and value.
We contrast this with a different class view
where the class where your power and value in the world
comes out of your physical strength.
And there we see the more rapid aging patterns.
We see, for instance,
in sports figures where at age 32 they're already old
and at 40, forget it,
they're an old man in that sports field.
We see certain classes of laboring people
where at age 65 when you retire it's pretty much over.
And from 65 on this pattern then
of moving into Sunset Hills and the beer belly
and you see indolence
and the loss of energy, the loss of interest,
the loss of aliveness.
The giving up of life,
as though retiring from the job means retiring from life.
As though the job was the only thing that gave meaning and value to life.
And now that one is not classified anymore as a worker in quotes,
one no longer has value in the world.
The failure there to look at oneself in a more holistic total way,
to see value as something other than productivity in the workforce,
to see the value of one's life as something other than
the capacity to bring home a paycheck every Friday,
to see oneself as something other than just provider
or just mother of the children.
And so we see the pattern in women
in which the aging process doesn't really start
until the children grow up and leave home.
And then suddenly she joins her husband
in this retiring from life.
He retires from the job.
She's now retired from the job.
His mother.
Both of them are now unemployed with no value in their own eyes.
And although they make a few sporadic jabs
at being of some use in society,
they don't really believe it.
And therefore the aging then becomes progressive and rapid.
And many of them die, of course,
within one year of retirement.
The coronary heart attack within one year of retirement
is much higher than any other bracket
amongst a certain class of workers.
And so we have to look earlier in life
and we have to constantly challenge these belief systems
to discover something about our life that is of such value
that whether we work, whether we bring home a paycheck,
whether we're raising children,
whether we're following a traditional,
solid, middle-class American way of life or not,
that our life still has value.
That we see that we're making a difference in the world.
That our life is significant.
The willingness to share our life with others
to be a source of enthusiasm,
to contribute to the life of those around us.
We have to reevaluate now the value of our life
and recontextualize it.
Come from a different way of being with it.
How to look at it differently
so as to give it a different value in our own eyes.
How to raise our own energy pattern
by coming from a different way of looking at it.
We said that one is not really subject
to anything but what is held in mind.
That we can identify these belief systems and patterns,
that we have the option to change them.
The choice is up to us.
We can be very active and vigorous into old age,
have a very significant and valuable life,
highly enjoyable.
Our physical health can continue right to the very end.
When we say this, some people automatically get a resentment.
And what is the resentment coming from?
It's coming from the fact that they were looking forward
to these disabilities of old age.
They were looking forward to the secondary gains and benefits
that they would get out of that.
They picture themselves as somewhat feeble and old
and now people start looking out for them.
So they're going to get a lot of attention.
People will hold open doors,
put the packages in the car for you,
give you 10% off on your groceries.
There'll be all kinds of credits and things
and aids that come to you now
because of your disability.
And so when you see the secondary gain,
we have to look at that and say,
what was I hoping to get out of, you know,
being somewhat debilitated with old age
and somewhat decrepit?
Being excused from the obligations of life.
I really, you know, don't have to contribute anymore.
And please let me out, I'm too old.
You know, you folks, you young folks have all the energy.
What were we looking to excuse ourselves from?
What responsibilities were we going to use old age as a cop-out?
So let's just look at those things and be honest with ourselves.
They're all part of humanness.
Everybody has those fantasies.
Everybody looks at the advantages of any of these life scripts
and that's one of the reasons they choose them.
We have to look at whether we're willing to let those things go
for the gain and for the benefit that we would get.
Would we rather be vigorous
or would we love to have that attention
of having a Boy Scout at our elbow as we cross the street?
Would you like to stride across confidently
or would you like some young man to say,
here sir, may I help you across the street?
It's fun, it's nice, just think of all that attention.
Boy Scouts everywhere helping you across the street.
If it's worth it,
then let the Boy Scouts help you across the street.
If it's not, stride across with a vigorous gait.
Our life, the body, what goes on in our life,
is then a projection of what we have been holding in our own mind.
All we're experiencing then
is the projection into the physical world
of our own belief systems.
What we're holding in mind is manifesting.
And we have a choice when we see this pattern.
We can begin to realize
if all I'm experiencing is that which I've been holding in mind,
then I can change that which I experience
by changing that which I hold in mind.
And that's exactly what we did,
and that's exactly what I've done in my own personal life.
And I shared that with you in my talks on giving up illness.
And I'll just use two of the examples from that talk,
or one of the examples plus one I didn't talk about.
For instance, the prostate trouble
that is supposed to come with middle age.
And it's a standing joke amongst men in the men's rooms, you see.
And men are standing there,
and one will say to the other one,
well, you must be over 50, you know what I mean?
It's like a prejudged thing that this is inevitable
and it's part and parcel of middle age.
And so when that began to happen to me,
I was already into the study of the nature of consciousness itself
and healing techniques, and I began to cancel it.
I said that's a belief system, and it has no basis in reality.
Its only reality is that I'm holding it in mind.
The truth is I'm an infinite being, and I'm not subject to that.
The truth is I'm an infinite being,
and I'm only subject to what I hold in mind.
And as I kept canceling it, every time this belief came up,
and kept insisting on the truth,
so I insisted on the truth,
and what I did is I reprogrammed the mind.
I began to see this belief, you know, as nonsense.
It's nonsense, but the collective consciousness,
you know, the energy field of the world,
its belief in that is something I have to constantly counter,
because the world tries to reprogram you again with it.
And so it leaves, and then it may momentarily come back,
because you chance to overhear a remark.
Some other middle-aged man talks about his prostate trouble, let's say.
And temporarily you find that you've fallen back into believing again.
So it requires vigilance, then,
to begin to undo all these belief systems within the mind.
The same thing happened with vision and with glasses.
And I always wore glasses my whole life.
I wore glasses for 50 years.
I wore glasses since I was a child.
And, of course, the belief system
in our society is that middle age brings about,
you know, changes in your vision.
And many people put on reading glasses at middle age.
So, middle age reading spectacles.
When we think of a middle-aged person,
when we look at the Retired People's Magazine,
they almost always have glasses on.
It's just presumed that by middle age you're going to need glasses.
Well, I had glasses already,
because I had the image in my mind of the intellectual bookworm,
which I was, who always wears glasses.
So part of my image of what I was
as an adolescent young man was, of course, wearing glasses.
Of course, if you already wear glasses,
by middle age it's presumed your vision's going to get worse
and you're going to need bifocals.
And by late middle age, certainly trifocals.
So it was at the trifocal stage,
after having worn glasses all my life,
that I was involved in this kind of research and study.
And one day someone and I was sharing with my class
all the physical illnesses that I'd let go of
following these consciousness techniques.
And probably a list of 15, 20 different diseases.
And when somebody said,
well, then how come you're still wearing glasses?
And so I said, you know, I never thought of that.
I never thought of, you know, the fact that the eyeball itself,
your capacity to see, a vision, the whole mechanism of vision,
would just again be a manifestation of my belief systems about it.
And so I looked at the belief systems and I began to cancel them.
You know, I said, I'm an infinite being.
I'm not really subject to any limitation.
Such as the belief that I need glasses.
And it took six weeks.
For six weeks I couldn't see anything.
I never put the glasses back on again.
And during that six weeks when my motility was somewhat limited
by the inability to see anything more than a couple of feet in front of me,
and I also was myopic as well as farsighted,
and I also had astigmatism.
And so I couldn't read anything, nor could I see anything distant.
After about six weeks of constantly letting this go
and canceling it, and consistent work,
I finally just surrendered to it.
And I said, well, because that's part of the technique also,
is to let go resisting what the belief system was.
And so I said, well, God, I said, if I'm never going to see again,
I guess I'm just never going to see again.
And I just totally let it go.
I just totally surrendered it to a higher power.
And I said, whatever your will is for me, I will agree to that.
Well, what is the will of God for us?
The will of God for us is complete and total happiness,
complete wholeness and oneness.
Anyway, in surrendering to God's will, all of a sudden,
in one instant, the vision came back absolutely perfect,
after a lifetime of wearing glasses.
So it doesn't matter how long we've had this belief system.
There was a belief system that was there throughout my entire life,
literally limiting vision.
That was a good more than ten years ago now.
And I have a driver's license that says no glasses required.
And every time I go for a vision test, the vision is perfect.
So those are just clinical examples, just demonstrations,
and I share them because of the principle involved.
The principle being that we experience experience
in the level of consciousness itself.
Body is only a reflection of that which we believe.
And so if we address ourself directly to those belief systems,
to the mind itself and to where it is being experienced,
we can undo these belief systems.
We have that freedom. We have that option.
So let's go back to some of the commonly held belief systems
about middle age and aging and old age
and see how we can be with that.
You see, because there are two things going on.
There are the belief systems about what all that entails,
and then there is our position about that, the way we feel about it.
Because in truth, it's not the events in life that have any importance at all.
Facts don't mean a thing.
The importance of a fact or an event is how we feel about it.
How we feel about it. Isn't that so?
How we feel about it then creates a context.
It creates a way of being,
and it decides in advance how we're going to feel about that event,
feel about that decision, feel about that fact.
So let's see how we can be with this whole problem in mind of old age and aging,
middle age, all that goes with that.
And we'll go back to our map of consciousness,
where we see we have various energy fields, various levels of conscious.
At the bottom, this would be the most unconscious,
the farthest from the truth, the closest to death itself.
At the top, we have, because of increasing truth,
an alignment with life, with truth, and with a sense of aliveness.
So we might say at the top is God, the closeness to God,
at the bottom is the greatest distance.
And out of these energy fields then come certain emotions.
Certain emotions reflect the energy field which is coming out of our position.
And out of our position comes a certain view of the world,
and then the God of that world would have to be a certain kind of God.
So how could we look at old age and let's look around us in the world
and you'll see instantly how the world and what you hold this
and how you have bought into it.
We can identify at which level did we buy into it and about what.
At the bottom with the lowest energy, one leading almost to pass of suicide,
and many deaths from old age are not due to old age at all.
They're all forms of passive suicide.
They're the result of having given up out of hopelessness.
So we see a guiltiness as though old age and the decrepitudes,
the illnesses are somehow punishment for one's sins.
One failures in life, you now deserve all this.
Out of self-hatred then, the person chooses destruction.
They see their life and the world, you know, as the experience of sin and suffering,
and they really fear dying because out of their guilt,
they picture that God is very likely going to destroy their soul
and throw them into hell forever.
And so there is a fear of old age and dying, of course,
viewing it as a destructive process, looking at age then as destruction.
And we see the destruction then that comes from this belief system in their life,
all the aspects of their life which they let fall into the detriment
of this destructive viewpoint.
An energy field somewhat above that, but still very close to passive suicide,
just allowing yourself to die over not caring about yourself enough to care for yourself,
is a field called apathy, with a calibrated energy field of 50.
You see it is again a negative attitude,
and this is the one of hopelessness and despair,
in which there is loss of energy.
In this view of old age,
we consider that the whole situation is hopeless,
that the grim reaper,
you know, the skeleton on the horse with the scythe,
has the power over us,
that old age then is hopeless.
All these conditions are hopeless.
All the physical elements are hopeless.
There is no point in doing anything about them.
You might as well let the teeth rot out and the body go into decay.
There is no point because there is a loss of energy coming out of this world view.
The loss of energy means,
now out of that hopelessness and despair,
you don't have the energy to handle it,
and therefore you see your life
and life in the world as hopeless,
and God is really dead,
a very uncaring view of God.
The next higher energy level,
the way of looking at old age or middle age,
is one of grief.
This is very common.
The sadness over middle age,
picturing the loss of youth as a great and terrible loss,
the loss of the vigor,
the loss of one's sex life,
loss of one's physical attractiveness
and sexual seductive abilities,
loss of mental acuity,
position and power in the world,
physical attractiveness,
the endless grief over this,
ending up in the emotions as regret,
looking at middle age and advancing age as loss,
becoming dispirited about life,
about one's own life and life in general,
and the sadness of middle age,
looking at one's own life as sad,
looking at the future as sad,
looking at the progressive aging as sad,
looking at God as that which really ignores you,
doesn't really care about this process.
If we get to a higher energy field than that,
we move into fear,
and today we'll say that the energy of fear
can be utilized in a positive way.
What we need to fear is the consequences
of these negative belief systems,
not old age.
The danger is not in the age itself.
The threat to us is really out of
these negative belief systems that we've been holding.
That's what is to be feared.
But the ordinary person fears old age itself.
They're full of worry and anxiety.
You see, grief has to do with the past,
and fear has to do with the future.
And so the mind which is looking at it out of fear
is holding worry and anxiety about the future.
Therefore, the world, the whole aging process,
looks frightening.
And there doesn't seem to be any God
that one can rely upon,
because that God could be punitive.
It doesn't seem to love you very much.
Next comes the desire.
Coming from desire is the intense craving,
the wanting to change all this.
And one aspect of that, you see,
is becoming addicted to being young.
The whole thought that life is where youth is.
And so you see the youth cult,
the fear of old age then,
expressing itself in a frantic desire
to hang on to youth.
And the inappropriateness then of some people
failing to age gracefully,
meaning that inability to let go of the desire for youth.
And so, you know, at 75 you buy yourself
a sports car and start smoking joints
and running around the discos
and get an 18-year-old girlfriend
that wanting to hang on to youth
and misidentifying youth as life.
Life is there throughout.
The energy of life is the same
in the child as in the old person.
We move up next to one of anger.
You see, anger.
The angriness at the thought
and the subject and at the effect
and victim of this whole progressive aging process
that the calendar has the power,
you see, over your life.
You see, these are all negative energy fields
and in practice, really, they're usually mixed.
Rarely do you have just one level.
The anger is also mixed with some sadness,
some hopelessness, some guilt.
All of them tend to occur together.
But you see, the anger of old age,
the frustration about it,
the resentment,
resenting the aging process,
resenting the loss of youth,
hating it.
You see young people
who have not had good experiences
with their grandparents
and they hate older people,
don't want to be around them.
Out of anger, then,
this is a world of conflict and competition
and their anger at God leads to an unconscious guilt
and a fear that God will retaliate.
Another way to be about it would be denial,
to refuse to see all the things we're talking about.
Today, a certain arrogance and inflated position about that.
And so we have, then,
a way of being with the subject of age and aging
that would be totally negative.
The things we're talking about today
have more to do with the truth.
To begin to look at them, then,
would move us out of these negative positions.
We could let go of resisting.
We could let go of being attached to them.
We could let go of valuing them.
And we could be released from them.
In which case,
middle age and aging would start to look okay to us.
The God of that kind of an experience
would be a God of freedom.
The freedom to see that perhaps you are the source
of what happens to you in your life.
The willingness to look at that.
You say, yes, I'll agree with that
because my intention now is to find out
what is the truth about this.
And now, middle age and aging begin to look,
the world begins to look friendly.
We have such a world as promising and hopeful.
We can move up to the level of acceptance
in which we're beginning to reown our own power.
You see, the thing that shifts the energy field
from negative to positive
is the willingness now to accept the truth.
The truth is that we are the source
of what happens to us in our life.
We are the source.
By virtue of buying into and owning these belief systems,
we bring them into our life.
The truth is
that we have a choice.
The minute we see we have a choice
and begin to accept that,
now it all begins to look harmonious.
The God of such a universe begins to look merciful.
We can now move into a condition of lovingness,
begin to take responsibility for really loving ourself,
beginning to nurture and support,
beginning to forgive ourself
that we fell into these thought patterns.
Why did we fall into these thought patterns?
We did it out of our own innocence,
out of our own naivete.
We thought that's the way it was.
Nobody thought to question it.
People were not so conscious.
People were not so aware.
It's only by demonstrating examples you say,
wow, looks like I have a choice here.
You see, we stop saying,
well, it must be that person's genetics.
Or if I was that rich,
I'd be glad to be alive at 92.
You know what I mean?
We stop excusing it
and begin to really accept that
it's because of the patterns we've held in life.
And this comes almost as a revelation to us,
a sudden opening of the open mind.
And so the way to avoid this
is to then begin to have an open mind,
the willingness to look at the options,
that we do indeed have choices,
and then the world starts to look loving.
We begin to love now the prospects
because we begin to see the advantages
of middle age and old age.
And many people will look back and say,
frankly, I wouldn't want to be young again.
I mean, I would hate the thought of going through the teens,
the anxiety, the acne, the unknowingness,
the stumbling around awkwardness,
the endless social anxiety and self-consciousness.
I don't think I'd care for the 20s either,
wondering what am I going to be in this world
and the terrible anxieties,
and will I make it through college?
The struggle of the 30s,
trying to establish a family and all those kind of things.
Instead of now saying that the past was better than the present,
we begin to say, hey, right here, now in the present,
I have some beautiful options.
It's suddenly like the whole world opens up to us anew.
I can become reborn at age 60. Why not?
As we move from a negative energy field into a positive one,
we get closer and closer to the truth.
And we become progressively aware
that what we are is the experiencer,
that the phenomena that have been going through life
has not really affected the experiencer.
It's like we're the hardware of the computer
and the experiences have been the software.
The hardware is unaffected by the software.
That which experiences is unaffected by the experiencing.
That which we are has remained unaged,
is not subject to age.
Men are perhaps more conscious of this,
perhaps in certain areas,
because a man at 70 still finds a pretty girl attractive
the same as he did at 20.
And they'll say to each other with amazement,
you know, it hasn't changed any at all.
The inner experiencer has been unaware
that a change has been going on in the body.
And sometimes it comes as a surprise.
The people look at you differently
and you wonder why they're looking at you differently.
It's because that within you
hasn't experienced the passage of time.
Your real self, your true self,
hasn't experienced anything such as aging.
No such thing goes on
within the truth of that which you are.
And so this progressive awareness then
increases your freedom of choice,
the way you wish to be with yourself.
You realize that, for instance,
that sexuality in old age,
as we covered in our talk on sexuality,
does not decline at all.
That sexuality remains active very often to the very end.
And personal friends of mine,
I remember one in particular was a world famous person,
said to me at 76
that his sex life was better
than it had ever been at any time in his life.
That it expanded to unbelievable dimensions
that as a young man he had never even thought of.
As a young man he was interested in,
you know, the calisthenics,
the acrobatics, the performance.
And as an older person,
more mature and greater in wisdom,
he was interested in the greater dimensions.
So at age 76, I remember he confided in me
that he had really just discovered
what sex was really all about.
That it was incredible.
And he was just boggled by the quality of it,
what he had discovered.
So that brings us to some of these belief systems
that are so common in our society,
having to do with what happens in one's sexual being,
the so-called menopause,
the male and female menopause.
And here we'll go to a clinical experiment
in which a group of 30 women were given an injection
that they were told would bring their period two weeks sooner.
It said that this injection was a hormone
and their period would come on two weeks sooner.
So what happened was the whole premenstrual syndrome,
the whole premenstrual syndrome,
with bloating and weight gain and belching
and all the things that the various women complained of,
abdominal pains and colics and things.
All the premenstrual syndrome came on now a week early
because they all now in mind held that the period
was going to come two weeks sooner.
And so we see the intense suggestibility,
this whole belief in the premenstrual syndrome,
and the whole belief in the symptoms
that are supposed to go with middle age
in both the woman and the man.
The woman's belief in hot flashes,
all the phenomena that are supposed to occur,
can all be induced by hypnosis.
And it's been done over and over,
where a young person is put under hypnotic trance
and told whether they're going through the menopause
and asked what are the symptoms,
and their symptoms are reported out verbatim.
And so we see that the menopause,
the so-called menopausal syndrome,
varies from culture to culture
and from class to class within each culture.
So what is expected, what is held as the inevitable?
We see how the mind holds us then as victim.
It's as though the mind says,
this is how it is,
the situation is hopeless,
one can only give into it, buy into it,
be at the effect of it,
and thereby giving away our own power.
I've already, you know,
shared with you the example of the middle age man
and what is supposed to go on there.
You know, the cold hands and the cold feet,
the feeling tired, discouraged,
the loss of energy and libido,
the occurrence of all these middle age diseases,
diverticulitis and all these things,
and gout and all the things associated with a certain age group.
And I bought into all that,
and at age 50 I had a full-blown case of middle ageness.
So all these things are coming then
from the suggestibility of the naive mind.
I go back to, over and over again,
to the innocence of the mind.
It is out of our innocence that we bought all this.
It is out of the vulnerability of our humanness.
Therefore,
where comes out of that a compassion,
a willingness to forgive ourself
for what we bought into.
It's just that we didn't know any differently.
The purpose of these talks then is to share what we've discovered,
that we have an option, we have a choice.
We are not victims.
And the way to move out of that then
is to move out of the bottom of the box.
Realize that it is not hopeless.
If it was hopeless, I would still be wearing glasses.
I'd still have prostate trouble.
I'd still have all these middle-aged diseases,
which I bought at the time.
We have to choose then to move ourself
out of the bottom of the box.
Just by education, just by knowing about it,
just by hearing about it,
we begin to realize it is not hopeless.
You see, the mind would like to excuse its own responsibility
and say, well, you can do it.
After all, you're a psychiatrist, you're a doctor,
you've studied all these consciousness things.
It was really very simple and I really did these things
the minute I learned about it.
I took a course that increased your awareness
of the very things we're talking about today.
And within one week, many of these illnesses began to leave.
Within 90 days, there was the alleviation
of a great many of them.
I was not a sophisticated researcher,
not advanced in my knowledge of the field at all at that time,
barely a beginner.
Just knowing what I've talked about today is sufficient.
That's really all you really have to know
because I've distilled out of it what are the essential principles.
What do I have to do?
As though you have to start taking up tennis and calisthenics
and jazzercise or something.
You don't have to do anything to undo the aging process.
It's all what you know.
And what we've been talking about today is really sufficient.
If we look at this box
and look at it now from a slightly different view,
at the very bottom of the box,
people at this level of consciousness here,
value life and rate themselves and others on what you have.
Because this is coming from survival,
it's having this that is important.
And so a person's value of himself and others is what they have.
And we see certain people as they get progressively older
cling more and more to give themselves a sense of value
that which they have.
And there are certain subgroups in our culture with which I'm familiar
in which having this is predominant.
It's what you have.
And whether you have more millions than another person
is really what counts.
And if you lose all your money, now you're out of that society.
So it has to do with having this.
As we move up into the middle range here, closer to the truth,
courage, that energy field which sees life as opportunity,
that part that settled America, created all the big industries,
that powerful energy center coming out of the middle here,
it's what you do that counts.
And there, doingness is very important.
What you do.
And here, do is seen as cause.
You're important because of what you do.
And therefore, there's a great emphasis on doingness.
Well, we want to hold doingness as the effect rather than the cause.
What you do is coming from what you're holding in mind,
your belief pattern.
So doingness is a result and it's not a cause.
It isn't because of the tennis that you're happy and healthy.
It's because you're happy and healthy that you express that joy
of your aliveness in the form of tennis.
So the doingness then, which is so important there,
begins to fade out as you move and progress
in your own level of consciousness.
And as you get closer and closer to the awareness of what you are,
then it's what you are that becomes important.
And so as you progress in life, what you have become,
it's who you are that becomes important.
And so in other cultural groups, it's what you are,
what you have become, what you stand for,
your isness, your beingness.
It's the beingness that counts.
And so spiritually sophisticated groups are not interested
in what you have.
Nobody cares what you have.
Everybody knows that having is the result of doing.
And doing, if you want to work harder and more effectively,
will bring about havingness.
And doingness, they know, is just a matter of exercising options.
You can join the board of everything and run yourself around ragged.
So doingness no longer has status or value.
True value then comes out of what you have become.
The principles by which you live.
The committing yourself to the principle
of becoming increasingly conscious, increasingly aware.
The commitment to spiritual principles,
and to those things which are universal,
which transcend the temporary.
The identification then with progressive awareness
of that which you really are.
So this progressive increase in consciousness then,
consciousness then,
is not at the effect of the world anymore.
No longer do you need to have
and to realize the significance of your beingness.
No longer do you have to do.
It's the awareness of that which you are.
That gives you a different position then
from which to view the body.
And so we look now at what our relationship is to the body.
And we can see it's something that you have.
It's not something that you are.
It's something that belongs to you.
And so you can begin to enjoy the body now
and see that you have an option.
You can look at it as a fun thing that belongs to you.
And it's there for your enjoyment.
See as we let go our identification
and realize that I'm not the body.
I am that which is experiencing the body.
That gives me options and choices.
I can decide to enjoy it.
I can see that it sort of bounces around happily
and doing what it does relatively effortlessly
by letting go all my belief systems,
negative belief systems,
about sickness and illness.
I can be willing to let all those things go
and as I get older enjoy a progressively more healthy body.
And so that the body that I, you know,
that I enjoy now
is considerably healthier than it was 10 or 20 years ago.
So with progressive age,
you know, what the world calls aging,
the body has gotten increasingly better.
I enjoy the body much more at 60 than I did at 40.
And the body at 40 was very tired
because it had migraine headaches,
it had ulcers, it had diverticulitis,
it had colitis, it had hemorrhoids,
it had swollen ankles by Friday night,
it had elevated cholesterol, it had gout.
I had to carry a cane around in the trunk of the car
for this poor old body.
So at age 40 the body was old
and at age 60 I enjoy it greatly.
All those illnesses have left.
So with the letting go of those belief systems
and those limitations has come
the progressive enjoyment of the body
and seeing it now as something with which to,
you know, express one's happiness.
And how we view time becomes increasingly important.
You see, because if we look at time as our enemy,
then we subject ourselves to the whole aging process.
If we're holding in mind that the passage of time
automatically, the corollary, the meaning of that,
is the progressive deterioration of the body,
then we're subject to that
because we've been holding it in mind.
If, on the other hand, we view time as the space
which gives us the freedom to grow,
to become more conscious, to become aware,
then time becomes our friend.
It's over the passage of time, then,
which has been my friend over the last 10 or 20 years,
that these illnesses and middle-aged
and old-age diseases of the body have disappeared.
I've had the time in which to explore,
the time to become aware that there are options,
the time to become aware of how I was limiting myself
within my own belief systems,
the time to become aware of what is that relationship
between body, mind and spirit,
the time to realize that we have
a complete option, freedom of the spirit,
that we are not limited except
to that which we hold in mind.