I'm Dr. David Hawkins. I've been a physician for 35 years and specialized in the field of psychiatry.
For years I worked in the field of psychoanalysis and psychotherapy, various forms of psychotherapy and group therapy.
I did a lot of work on nutrition and its relationship to various bodily diseases, also emotional and mental disorders.
And for the last eight years I've been doing research into the nature of consciousness itself,
exploring that domain which the world calls spiritual, elucidating the basic laws of self-healing,
discovering what is common amongst all the people I know who have recovered from progressive, serious, fatal, even terminal illnesses.
And so in this series, the Sedona series, we're talking about,
the utilization of the basic laws of mind and consciousness
in approaching such serious illnesses as AIDS, cancer, heart disease, hypertension, alcoholism, drug addiction.
All of them serious confronts, all of them things that require us to change our view of reality.
And what is reality?
And so we'll be talking about body, mind, and spirit.
We'll be talking about...
We'll be talking about the nature of consciousness in today's talk,
which is addressed to patients with cancer, to families of people with cancer,
to people who fear they might have cancer, to people who are in treatment with cancer.
We'll be talking about a holistic approach.
So we're not talking either-or.
We're not saying, well, you know, the treatment has to be traditional or an alternate treatment.
What we're saying is and, to include in that larger dimension.
Because true healing...
True healing requires the larger dimension.
And all the people I know who've recovered from these chronic and very severe diseases,
many of them who were given up as hopeless by their physicians in the medical community,
have recovered and, without exception, they've all done so by exploring a greater definition of the truth of reality,
that which they are, exploring that realm of human knowledge called spiritual.
What is that relationship between body, mind, and spirit?
You know, other than a catchphrase.
Is it something real that you can work with in everyday life and see actual results?
Well, the friends that walk around who have recovered from all these fatal illnesses
are the walking evidence that we can all recover from any disease known to mankind.
I, myself, as I have shared in other series and other talks in this series,
had 15 or 20 aggressive illnesses, chronic, intractable.
Although they were treatable, some of the symptoms were handled, the diseases did not get better.
In fact, they were getting progressively worse.
So despite traditional medical treatment, I was merely holding the line on a few and losing the line on several.
And so it was exploring the greater dimension then, exploring those fields called consciousness
and how they relate to self-healing, that a recovery from all of these illnesses, without exception,
came about.
The alteration in the blood chemistry.
I once had gout in the high elevated uric acid level.
After I learned that the body only does what is held in mind,
I began to change what I was holding in mind,
then the body's chemistry literally began to change.
I learned that all the atoms and cells and elements, electrons,
all of that which the body has made is conscious.
But the cells of the body are conscious.
And this is very important in the approaches that we'll be utilizing in the treatment of cancer.
What is the relationship between body, mind, and spirit?
He said the principle is that the body reflects that which is held in mind.
And that which is held in mind reflects one's spiritual position.
And so it's necessary to know where all human experience takes place.
Because if we address that level, we will be addressing the most powerful level.
If the physical is the consequence of the mental,
and the mental is the consequence of the spiritual,
then it is in the area called consciousness itself that we should address ourselves.
And clinically this is so.
People who address that level, address the level of consciousness itself,
watch transformations come about in their body
without even having addressed the body directly in any kind of a medical approach.
We need to know where experience is experience.
And let go some of the common illusions which people hold in mind
just because they haven't looked into the matter.
The body itself is incapable of experiencing itself.
In other words, my hands as they are crossed here cannot experience themselves.
They cannot experience their existence, their position in space.
Even the sensations have no capacity to experience themselves.
It's because of something greater than the physical body,
and that is what we call mind.
So that all the physical, and all that goes on with the physical body, sensations,
is experienced in the greater dimension called mind.
It is in mind that the experience of body takes place.
Mind itself, curiously enough, has no capacity to experience itself.
A thought, for instance, a thought is just an energy form.
A thought has no capacity to experience its own thoughtness.
A feeling has no capacity to experience its own feelingness.
An emotion cannot be experienced,
other than the fact that mind itself is held within an energy field that is greater than mind.
And that is the energy field of consciousness itself,
which has no dimensions, which has no limitations,
and which has no form.
It's because of consciousness that we are aware of what goes on in mind.
And we know what's being registered in mind
is because of that energy field called consciousness.
Even consciousness itself is not sufficient.
There is an energy field of a very high frequency in vibration,
the same as that of life itself, called awareness.
It is out of awareness that there is the knowingness
of what is going on within consciousness,
which is reporting what is going on within mind,
which in turn is reporting what is going on with the physical body.
And so you can see the physical body itself is several levels removed
from that which is the most real,
and therefore the most powerful.
We find that the energy of thought is far more powerful
than the energy levels of the physical body.
And so to understand some of this,
we'll need a context in which to understand the whole field of self-healing.
In a one hour talk today,
we won't have time to cover the entire field.
But we have covered a number of things that have to be said
in other tapes in the consciousness series,
where we did a tape, a talk on illness,
we did another talk on health,
we did another one on pain and suffering,
and there we pointed out that the two are not the same.
Suffering is one thing and pain is another,
as I know because I just went to the dentist's last week.
And we did another one on stress.
It would be good to look at these if you can borrow them
or get them from somewhere,
see where you can sort of expand your awareness of this whole field.
So today we're talking about, then,
the nature of consciousness itself,
so that we create a context for ourselves,
so that the self-healing modalities that we will be describing later
will begin to make sense.
In the first place, how to hold that experience
of having a life-threatening illness,
such as cancer.
How to hold that? What to think of that?
Well, we have two ways we can go
about it. We can go up or we can go down.
Any kind of a confront, such as a death in the family,
any kind of a serious illness or setback in a person's life,
we always have that choice.
We can go down into feeling sorry for ourselves as victims,
we can go down into self-pity, depression, despair,
become suicidal,
or we can see it as a challenge, as an opportunity,
as a springboard to a greater awareness.
Over and over these confronts come up in our lives,
until we seize the opportunity
and realize that this is the springboard to a greater awareness.
Why is it so?
Because the ordinary events in life don't have the power,
they don't have the energy.
It takes max duress for a person to stop in their tracks
and begin to question the realities of all the things
that they have believed up to this point.
The mind will ordinarily not undertake
the enormous energy expenditure
of reorienting itself
and getting a new different point of view about life
and what is real,
unless it has to.
So this necessary growth, then,
will only happen when we're up against a major confront.
So the way, the first thing to get about the cancer
or the serious illness, whatever it may be,
is that the purpose of this major confront
is for us to grow and to grow rapidly.
That is the first message.
Message number one is
it's time to grow,
and to grow as fast as you can.
Because we have a certain time limit
with most of these fatal terminal illnesses.
Things that the mind says are fatal and terminal
become fatal and terminal because of the power of mind.
If the mind thinks that this is fatal and terminal,
then it will be so.
So we see now the beginning of the expression
of the power of belief systems, belief systems.
And of course, one of the main messages,
we want to get across today,
is that no one needs to come or be victim
of any illness.
And I count amongst my friends,
people who have conquered every illness known to mankind.
And the only reason I'm sitting before you today
and able to make this talk
is because I, myself,
did exactly the same thing in my own personal life
where I would have hemorrhaged to death
from a variety of illnesses,
all of which have remitted.
All of which have remitted,
including that I don't wear glasses anymore.
One time I wore bifocals and trifocals.
Even vision itself went back to perfect.
So that, that perfection which is held in mind then
reflects itself in the progressive perfection of the body
and the letting go of this E.
We have to understand that the body itself
is expressing what is held in consciousness.
The body is merely an expression of the mind.
The body is nothing but an expression
of that which is held in consciousness.
It is a reflector of what we are holding consciously or unconsciously.
A person looks back in their mind and they'll say,
well, I don't remember thinking about such a thing.
Well, if you don't remember thinking about it,
find out if it's in your unconscious,
all you have to do is look and see if it's in your life.
So to help us create a different context,
a way of looking at life,
a way of looking at experience,
a map from which we can understand
all the principles of self-healing,
we have over here on the blackboard
outlined a chart of consciousness
which we've utilized in other talks.
And if you've seen some of the other tapes,
just realize that the person who is watching this again
is not the same person who saw it the first time.
Because every time we go over this,
it's sort of like break-brain learning.
We learn it through familiarity.
The left brain is linear and logical
and it gets things piecemeal sequentially.
The right brain circles over a thing
and by sheer exposure and familiarity,
it just gets the whole thing.
So what we'll be talking about today
are really things that in your unconscious,
somewhere in the periphery of your mind,
you actually know.
And we're going to try to pull them together,
synchronize them in some kind of a useful way.
So on the board we have,
within this is called the box,
and everywhere I give talks,
they often call it the box.
And this is the human ego,
the self with a small s.
And that which people refer to
when they say I or me, myself,
the self with a small s,
is the human ego.
It's all that collection of concepts,
impressions, opinions, feelings,
conscious and unconscious.
The totality of that that goes up to
make up what the person means
when they say me, I, myself.
And within the box you see
there are various levels of energy.
And these are levels of consciousness,
starting at the very lowest
and going up to the very highest.
And they have all been calibrated,
the research that we've done
with my co-workers, with Lorraine Ross.
What we did was we found out
the directions of the energy fields.
You see these energy fields
from courage on down
all go to the left,
indicating that they have an anti-life.
Destructive, do not support life,
energy to them.
And all those from courage on up,
you see the energy fields begin
to swing to the right.
And as we get closer and closer
to the truth they become more powerfully
to the right.
And so then we notice that love
is way at the top of the scale
and guilt, on the other hand,
is way at the bottom of the scale.
Also they've been numerically calibrated
by some techniques which are very
complicated and difficult
and advanced.
And I won't go into the techniques
which is a science in itself.
But they can be confirmed by anyone
who is familiar with kinesiology.
The direction of the energy fields,
the calibrated numbers,
their relative powers,
can be reaffirmed by anybody
in their own living room
using just basics of kinesiology.
And to learn about that I would recommend
a book by John Diamond called
Life Energy.
It used to be called
Behavioral Kinesiology.
It's a way of testing out energy,
the relative powers,
and whether that thing is constructive
or destructive.
Very helpful, for instance,
to test out medical treatment.
You hold the medication in your hand
and you have somebody test your strength
and you say,
will this medication be good for me or not?
If the medication is not good for you
your arm will go weak.
If it's good for you
your arm will go strong.
So any kind of a treatment,
even the doses,
you can test out and find out
what's good for you.
It's necessary then to know
something about energy fields
because this is intimately related
to cancer and cancer research.
If we calibrate,
if we say that death is zero,
then we will discover that enlightenment,
to become a Buddha,
to become conscious of the absolute truth,
calibrates at about 600.
That energy field known as bliss,
those energy fields known as
illumination or enlightenment.
And then if we go down near the bottom
of the box,
we'll see for instance that apathy,
which calibrates at 50,
has about half the energy of fear,
which calibrates roughly at 100.
Grief at 75 has about half the energy of anger,
which calibrates at 500.
Being neutral,
that is to be detached or unattached,
at 250 has only half the energy of love,
which is at 500.
All these are extremely important.
Because body, mind and spirit
are actually all just one.
It's all the same thing.
It's just being reflected in different planes.
It's an artificial abstraction
to cause body or mind or spirit.
It is actually all the same thing.
All three are an expression of consciousness.
And therefore this energy field,
if it is a reversed or a negative energy field,
is that negativity,
that which is destructive,
destructive in all aspects of ourselves,
right down to the biochemical level.
So we see that the energy field,
which has a name to the right of the energy field,
is expressed as a certain emotion.
So if we want to know what our energy field is,
all we have to do is look at what is the emotion.
Self-pity, for instance,
automatically tells you what's happened with self-pity,
is that you are now in a negative energy field,
which calibrates at 50,
which is weak indeed,
as compared to love, which is 500.
The importance then we see immediately
of letting go of negative feelings and negative thoughts.
The negative energy of the feeling or the thought
transmits itself through the acupuncture energy system,
through the 12 meridians,
running down the body meridian,
and translates itself right into the energy of the body organ,
right into the cells of the body.
So if I hate someone,
the cells of my body get the energy of hate.
And where is hate?
Hate is right about here.
It is a very reversed and quite powerful now,
negative force.
150 is a lot of power,
twice as much power as 3.
Its power, therefore,
its capacity for destruction is greater.
So suppressed anger,
suppressed anger then,
has the capacity to change the energy fields
within the body's cells.
It has the power to actually change the programming
So what we are going to be talking about today
is the enormous power that mind has
over every aspect of the body's functioning,
right down to the smallest molecule, an atom.
It has been discovered that every atom is conscious.
Every molecule within the body
is conscious.
Every physiological and chemical transaction
that goes on in the body
is the result of a blueprint of that
within consciousness.
All of them can be changed then
by changing consciousness.
I say that from personal experience,
not only clinical experience
and personal experience with friends and associates,
but of course with my own physical health.
I watched my own body chemistry
literally change
as I began to change
what I was holding about that
within my mind,
within my consciousness.
And I came upon that basic principle
essential to healing
from all illnesses,
no matter what they are,
because the same principles really apply
to all illnesses,
that we are only subject to what we hold in mind.
We are only subject to what we hold in mind.
It's the mind's belief system
that we give power to
that then manifests in the physical world.
The physical body then
is an expression
of that which we've been holding in mind.
Now we've either been holding it consciously
or unconsciously.
See, people say,
well I don't remember holding such a thought.
Well, there is what Jung calls
the collective consciousness.
The thought form is there
within the collective consciousness.
And unconsciously
we can buy into,
support,
give energy to
a negative belief system
without ever remembering it,
without consciously being aware of it.
Certainly with cancer,
we are dealing with something
which has been given
so much emotional energy
in the popular mind.
All the fear associated with it,
all the negative connotations,
all the thought forms.
Therefore, fear itself,
the whole fear unconsciously,
this energy field here,
you see,
is a negative energy field.
Therefore,
if I am holding a lot of unconscious fear,
what happens is the fear now
opens the door
to bring into my mind unconsciously
those things that are fearful.
Those things that are fearful.
And of course,
cancer falls into that which is fearful.
And so therefore,
without ever having believed
that I am susceptible to cancer,
I may discover
that it is occurring within the body,
that I have unwittingly bought in
to this collective belief system,
the collective thought form.
So let's just look at this field a little bit
because it will give us a better orientation
to what we'll be talking about later.
We see that at the very bottom
is an energy field called guilt.
It calibrates at 30.
It says death is zero.
Well, guilt is 30.
And what is the emotion that goes with guilt?
It's one of self-hatred.
And a great deal of research into this
in psychology,
the psychosomatic viewpoints of cancers,
reveals that there is a good deal
of unconscious self-hatred,
self-condemnation,
lack of acceptance of one's humanness
at a deep level.
And we'll talk about how to heal those things
because that's the way we bring about a healing.
We're interested in these talks in healing.
See?
There's a difference between treating,
curing, and healing.
It's possible to treat an illness,
to treat symptoms,
to bring about an amelioration,
a capacity, let's say, to live with it.
In the many years that I had migraine headaches,
I had duodenal ulcers, diverticulitis,
gout, hypoglycemia,
a whole variety of things.
I had vibration disease of the fingertips,
threatening gangrene of the fingers and pillows and things.
Circulatory problems.
All of these illnesses, see,
came about as a result of belief systems
and they all were accompanied by
some degree of unconscious guilt.
We find that unconscious guilt
accompanies all illnesses
no matter what they may be.
If you have a physical illness,
you can just presume and you will be 100% right
that there is unconscious guilt
and without the unconscious guilt,
actually the disease cannot be there.
Why is that?
Because that which is,
over on the right you'll see the process,
that which is destructive,
that which is accompanied by self-hatred,
can only operate in a negative energy field.
That's the secret of healing.
It would be like certain bacteria
will only grow in a culture media
under certain conditions,
certain temperatures,
certain amount of light and atmospheric conditions.
If you change the conditions,
the bacteria cannot live in that feature dish anymore
and they will disappear.
Therefore, that which is destructive,
that which meets the unconscious need
for the process of destruction,
can only go on in an energy field
which itself is negative
and allows the negative energy of destruction
to take place.
Now that starts to give us a clue
to that which heals.
That which the energy field goes to the right
in nature,
in nature you see the rotation of an energy field
is all decisive.
For instance, a drug,
the chemical effect of a molecule
is totally dependent on whether it spins to the right
or it spins to the left.
Let's take dextroamphetamine sulfate as an example.
Dextro meaning to the right.
Dextroamphetamine sulfate is so-called speed.
And everybody is familiar in our culture
with what the effect of speed is.
Weight loss and the feeling of high excitability,
grinding your teeth and finally manic attack.
Revolve, meaning to the left,
amphetamine sulfate has no such effect whatsoever.
It's the same molecule
but the rotation is in the opposite direction.
So the rotation of an energy field then,
these are nurturing
and will support life and healing.
These on the left are destruction
and therefore that which is destructive
must take place in a negative energy field.
Obviously, all you need to do to heal yourself
is to move from the negative energy field
into a positive energy field.
Self-healing is so simple, see?
It's really, that's what it amounts to.
What it amounts to is changing the predominant energy field
within your consciousness from negative to positive.
Then the question arises of how do you do that?
Now that you see the physics of it,
the science of it,
the metaphysics of it,
the truth of it,
the emotional truth of it,
from medical, psychiatric,
holistic viewpoints,
you see why we should let go of these emotions.
Not in order to become a goody-goody person,
but frankly because to hang on to them will kill you.
All these things are,
we mentioned kinesiology.
See, with kinesiology you test somebody's strength
and they hold any thought
that has to do with any of these things.
Something you feel guilty about,
something you feel hopeless about,
something you're sad and grieving about,
something you're afraid of.
Something that you're into wanting and desiring,
something you're angry about,
something you're prideful about.
Some truth that you're denying,
some worry, some craving,
some regret, some loss,
some form of self-hatred.
And any time you do that,
the body instantly goes weak.
And when it goes weak,
it means you just blew your acupuncture system.
It just means you blew the meridian
to the various bodily organs.
It means that you just changed the chemical pattern,
the reproductive pattern,
and you're tearing up the cells.
So it's obvious that all we have to do to heal anything
is to move out of a negative energy field
and into a positive energy field.
Of course, the power of the healing increases.
The higher, the more positive the energy.
And that's why the holistic approaches have worked
where medical science has not been able to affect the cure.
And I myself, as I said, am a living example.
Without knowing what I'm talking about today,
I wouldn't be here to give this lecture.
I would have died, for instance,
22 and a half years ago of another disease
which preceded all the other ones.
A fatal progressive disease
which reversed itself right at the point of death itself.
So guilt is the most injurious, you see,
because it's accompanied by self-hatred
and the process that it brings in
is automatically destructive.
And we know that from the study of geomancy.
Geomancy is the study of energy fields in nature.
And if we study the effect of energy fields
in nature, we will find that a negative energy field
in nature is anti-life.
It does not support life.
So if a canyon, the energy field in that canyon,
if it goes into a negative direction
for a variety of reasons,
if the crossing of the ley line,
the cutting, like I know the situation where a dam
cut the ley line, reversed the energy field,
now the lives of everyone along that ley line
were influenced in a negative direction.
And so, in a way, you see it's impersonal.
This energy field then has a destructive effect
within nature itself.
And because you are part of nature,
then you have to suffer the loss
that comes out of that destructive quality
of the energy field.
So, obviously then, letting go of guilt
and letting go of unconscious guilt
is crucial to recovering from any serious disease,
especially cancer, where lack of self-esteem
and self-hatred and fear play such a predominant part
and the next energy field above this
to be accompanied by hopelessness and despair
is called apathy, which is an energy field of 50
and the world view, the view of the world
that comes out of that is one of hopelessness.
To fall into self-pity and hopelessness then
is to allow yourself to be overtaken
and become victim of an energy field
which favors the progression of the cancer.
So what about that is grief?
Of course, when people first get a cancer,
they'll have a diagnosis,
especially if they're a younger person.
They will say, why me?
And go into regret, a feeling of loss and despondency.
The world now begins to look sad, life looks sad,
and they can then become the victim of this energy field.
I keep repeating energy field because I want you to see
your own innocence in this matter.
It's because of your own innocence
that you literally allow yourself
to be run by this energy field.
The stage above that, the one
that's also very prevalent
in patients who develop cancer is fear.
You know, fear with a very negative energy
has more power now, an energy field of 100.
The world looks frightening, life looks frightening,
and God begins to look almost punitive.
What kind of a God is it that could give you cancer, etc.?
And the process of life itself begins to feel deflated.
The person is tempted to become dispirited,
de-energized, and give in to the destructiveness,
to allow the thing to progress, unconsciously.
Well, you can begin to desire something better for yourself
than being the victim, being the victim.
All the people I know recovered from all these illnesses
did not settle for being victims.
They all began to desire something better for themselves.
There must be another way.
And they began to research and began to look outside
of this traditional medical model.
You know?
They said, Doctor, well, is that all it is?
I mean, is that all you got to offer?
Well, it's going to take more than that to heal it.
And they began to find out,
is there something else that can heal it?
So out of that desire, out of the anger at being victim,
see, we can use the energy fields of these emotions
in a constructive way.
So we can use the energy fields of anger.
I lost my own stepdaughter, you know, years ago,
from Hodgkin's disease.
I remember her going through
a lot of anger.
Being angry.
Angry enough to begin to investigate and research
and see what can be done about this.
Angriness.
So the anger can be used constructively.
The anger, I don't have to be victim.
I don't have to give in to this thing.
And to begin to take pride in our ability
to expand our own consciousness.
The answer, as you look into it,
is there more that can be done?
Of course, it is yes.
Begin to take pride.
And now, to move up to a very decisive point
called courage.
You see, what happens at courage,
not only does the energy field go all the way up to 200,
which is twice the energy of fear,
twice the energy of fear,
but what is more important
is that the direction of the energy field has changed.
It's gone from negative,
from a field which supports that which is destructive,
and it has suddenly now gone neutral.
Well, these energy fields down here are like an antenna.
They're like an antenna tuned to the negative.
So the energy field which surrounds the human body
is like an antenna.
And when it's tuned to the negative,
it draws to itself.
It draws to itself that which is destructive.
And the body, of course, is right in the way
of that destructive energy field
and gets hit by it.
It's because of the negativity,
the destructiveness expressing itself through the body,
hitting the body, expressing itself.
And in this particular case of cancer,
it draws our attention to the fact
that there is some error involved.
There is some error.
The courage to begin to look and see
that there is perhaps some error.
The way I've been holding life,
the way I've been holding my belief system,
the way I think about myself
perhaps has been an error.
So one of the things about this level here of courage
is the beginning,
the beginning, you see,
of knowing.
Our expression of that is humility.
Courage is expressed by humility.
And now the world,
our view of the world begins to change.
Out of hopeless, out of sad,
out of frightened, out of frustrating,
out of competitive,
out of opportunistic and status.
It suddenly moves up to a world of opportunity.
So the doors begin to open.
Below this, the mind is closed.
It thinks it knows the answer.
Once we have the courage,
what happens is the mind begins to open.
And it says,
I bet there's answers I don't even know about.
In fact, I don't even know the right questions to ask.
And the minute we begin to open ourselves up,
what happens is we become empowered.
See the process over on the right,
when we have the courage to have an open mind,
is when we become empowered.
So below this, these are all states of powerlessness.
All states of victimhood.
Once we move up to an energy field of 200,
the capacity to face the truth
and begin to take responsibility for it.
See, the thing about victim
is victim doesn't take responsibility.
Victim says, well, you know,
the reason I got this is because of the bacteria.
And the reason I got this is because of the virus.
The reason I got this is because of the cancer cells.
It's always something outside of oneself,
outside of one's consciousness.
That one is the victim of that.
No one begins to own that I've had something to do with it.
What's happening in my life
is the result of something that I've been holding in mind.
The situation right above courage
is a level called neutral.
So see, at neutral, the arrow has now gone to the right.
And the energy field has jumped up to 250.
The emotional state of that is called detached or non-attached.
The process going on in consciousness
is one of being released.
One experiences the okayness of life
and experiences a new and greater freedom.
And that would be expressed, let's say,
in serious illnesses or serious situations
because all serious situations,
see, call forth the same need
to confront truth within yourself
and ascertain what is your position about that.
It can be expressed, let's say, as fatalism.
Fatalism.
The idea that we had during the war,
let's say, when I was in World War II.
The idea that the bullet, you know,
that's meant for you has your name on it.
So there's no point of being afraid of bullets
because if it hasn't got your name on it,
it's not going to hit you anyway.
That can be expressed as karma, see?
And whatever is going to be is destiny.
Karma is the way it's supposed to be.
So the fatalistic position
is a certain peace of mind.
A certain peace of mind.
We are detached.
So the person with cancer who reaches that says,
well, look, if I survive, I survive,
and if I don't, I don't.
You know what I mean?
I'm doing the best I can.
If I make it, I make it,
and if I don't, I don't.
I'm prepared to go in either way.
So that is certainly a far more comfortable position,
you know, than to be in grief about it,
self-pity, anger, resentment, arrogance, denial.
People go into denial
and deny they have the cancer, you know?
They will come up with a thought
that it's been cured and all.
Without having gone through the necessary work
to bring about, bring that about
as a reality in their life.
But it's sort of magical thinking.
We can move above that to a willingness,
a friendly view of the world
where we see life is promising and hopeful,
and we discover, yes, there are answers.
Yes, there are answers.
There are lots of people walking around.
We have had terminal, fatal,
given up all hope diseases of all kinds,
including cancer.
What's happened here is we've introduced intention,
increased one's power,
up to accepting the fact that, yes,
you can let go of this illness,
and there are healing modalities.
This is our harmonious world
in which there are lots of people
who have recovered from these illnesses
who are only too happy to share with you
the truths that they have discovered.
Why? Because they experience God
as that which is merciful.
The people at the bottom
experience God as punitive.
And even if they don't believe in God,
they believe in self-punishment
in one form or another,
or pain and suffering.
And feeling adequate, feeling confident,
yes, that there is an answer,
begins a transformation of consciousness.
It moves us up to the willingness to be coming
into this energy field called love.
This is a crucial level because
the energy field of love is the one that heals.
All those organizations of people
who are very famous for their capacity to heal,
Alcoholics Anonymous being probably
the most famous on the planet,
hopeless, progressive, chronic,
intractable disease,
for which there is no answer,
and medicine admitted
that there is no cure for the condition.
And yet, here is an incurable, progressive,
disease that destroys every organ of the body,
including sanity itself.
And we know there are half a million people
walking around who have totally
and 100% recovered from it.
In fact, their lives have been transformed
because there again, the affliction
was used as a springboard
to a greater consciousness
and a greater awareness.
To move into a commitment
to that which is loving.
And we said the nature of it is unconditional love.
Not the conditional love of
I will love you if you will do this
or you will do that.
To move into this begins a process
called revelation.
It begins the release within the mind,
within the brain,
of certain chemicals we call endorphins.
So, all these energy fields
have within the mind,
have within the brain,
concomitant changes in the enzymes.
There are neurotransmitter changes
there is the release of whole,
opening of whole banks of neurons.
So therefore, the person
has moved into lovingness,
which is a healing energy field,
has at their disposal
the utilization of millions
and millions of neurons
which people who are
in a negative emotional state
do not have at their fingertips.
And therefore, they have assets.
So to move into the energy field
of unconditional love then
starts the healing process
going.
We know that when we calibrated
we found that the healing
healing occurs in an energy field
which you calibrate at about 540.
That is the energy field
of the heart.
So how do we bring about
the self-healing then?
Because we have to let go
of a number of things.
We have to let go of unconscious guilt.
We have to discover,
how can I unearth that
which I feel guilty about?
We begin a self-questioning process.
In order to do this,
the person is fearful.
They say, well, even if it
would heal my cancer,
I'm afraid I can't do that
because if I start opening Pandora's box
I'm going to be swamped
by all the negativity and the guilt
that I have suppressed and repressed
and pushed out of awareness
all my life.
And so we need some kind of tools,
some kind of a practical way
to process these things
and to begin with,
we need a context,
a way in which to hold
all that comes up
in this self-investigative process.
And therefore we need a tool,
the realization of what has been
the basis of all our behavior
all of our life.
A context, a way to hold that
so that as it comes up,
the guilt is automatically wiped out
by a higher understanding.
We need to realize that
we've committed exactly one sin,
which is the word in quotes.
We have been committing exactly one sin
throughout our life,
and it's the same sin over and over again.
And that is that everything we ever did,
our intentions and our purposes,
was coming out
of the thought that
this will bring about happiness.
It's very important to know this,
to realize that the reason
we did what we did at the time
is because we thought that
that was necessary for our survival
and our survival was necessary
for our happiness.
And so everything we did,
we did in the name of
the innocent thought
that this will bring us happiness.
Wanting happiness is the basic
of all human emotions, is it not?
In fact, the basic premise,
the most primitive illusion of all
is that it is the body
that is the source of my happiness.
And therefore the fear of death
is really, if I lose the body
I will lose the source of happiness,
I will lose consciousness itself.
People who are spiritually aware,
of course this is nonsense,
because they no longer identify
with the physical body.
If I am awareness,
if I am consciousness itself,
out of which comes a knowingness
of what is happening within mind
and within body,
then body is the bottom rung
on the ladder, you see.
Consciousness is totally unaffected
about what it is conscious of.
So we need to let go
of these negative emotions
and let go of suppressing them
and repressing them.
And we have to have a tool to do that
and that is to let go of resisting them
as they come up.
We need to keep our eye on the fact
that consciousness innately within itself
is innocent.
The nature of consciousness itself
is the innocence of the child.
How did we begin to believe
the things that we began to believe
as we grew older?
We look at the child and we see
how innocent and trusting it is.
It is completely lacking in guile.
We know that its motivations
are pure, in at least our understanding
of purity.
How does that later become
the consciousness of the adult?
It's because the program
that the child buys
and buys into,
the fact that it's programmable
is coming out of the very nature
of innocence itself.
It's because the child is innocent
and trusting that it begins
to buy and believe everything
that it hears,
including all the thoughts
that later express themselves
as cancer having to do
with self-condemnation,
fearful thoughts,
thoughts of rejecting oneself
and its expression of its humanness.
And so to heal cancer then
we need an approach,
a willingness to heal ourselves
by means of compassion.
To come from compassion,
that is our greater,
our higher self,
understanding that out of innocence
all these belief systems came about.
And how does the belief system
express itself in daily life?
It expressed itself as the thought
that if I do this
or I have that,
then I will be happy.
And so does,
how does grief or loss
affect us?
The reason it affects us
is we thought that was going to be
a source of happiness.
So what we're regretting is what we see
when we're angry
because some obstacle
stands between
the way of ourselves,
our intentions,
what we want,
and that which we consider
to be the source of happiness.
So if we go back to the board here,
we ask what is the illusion?
What is the illusion
that was held in consciousness
now expressing itself in the form of cancer?
And the illusion was
all these levels from courage on down,
growth,
we all thought that the source of happiness
was something outside of myself.
That something outside of myself
has the power
to make me happy.
The minute I give away my power
and project it outside of myself,
I put myself in a negative energy field,
I set myself up
as a victim.
Now the unconscious purpose of the ego
is to prove that you are a victim.
And the test of cancer
is the test of whether or not
you will continue
to go along with this
and buy into it.
95% of the world does.
What I'm talking to today
are the 5% of the people
who are willing to wake up
and become conscious.
95% of the world,
you see the ego would rather be right
and have you dead.
The ego would rather be right
even if it costs you your life
rather than give up the position
that I am the innocent victim
or something outside of myself.
Once you see your true innocence,
then you don't need
the pseudo-innocence of victimhood.
See, the owning of true innocence,
you don't need
the pseudo-innocence of victimhood.
Inasmuch as there is no victim,
there was only a belief system
in the first place
which we kicked up out of our innocence.
The thought, for instance,
that success brings us happiness
is probably the most notorious.
As every middle-aged business man
who has become successful knows,
what he gets out of his success
is a daily headache and exhaustion
and a number of lawsuits
and some greed and envy
from his colleagues.
He says to himself,
where is all the happiness
that success was supposed to bring me?
Yes, it's brought me some pleasures,
a nice car, a nice apartment,
a nice address, and nice clothes.
But those things are not happiness
because worldly success
is an energy field of about
120.
So worldly success
does not bring about the thing
and therefore the disillusionment
and the feeling of guilt.
How does the guilt come about?
The guilt comes about
as a result of feeling that
we have sold ourselves out subtly,
that we have sold out
the truth about ourselves.
So to recover from cancer
or any other illness,
we have to reconnect
with our own intrinsic innocence,
which has been totally unaffected
by all of life's events,
to reown that level of awareness
of self,
which is beyond all worldly events.
Something within us remains the same
no matter what is going on
in our life experience.
Something has been unchanged.
That's something that wakes up
the first thing in the morning,
you know, before you realize where you are,
before you realize what day it is,
before you realize what it is
you're supposed to do today.
When you wake up into that state of awareness
you are much closer to the truth
of your own higher self
and you will realize it is totally unaffected,
it is beyond all of that.
It's only when your consciousness
comes down,
comes down into the world
of concrete thought
you say, oh yes, it's Monday
and oh yes, I have to go.
Now you're coming down into the level
of concrete thought.
You are really leaving
being closed to the truth of that
which is beyond all of that.
So we re-own then
the capacity
to decide what our position will be
about life's events.
Those things which bring about
extreme duress.
We can become victims
or we can see it as a springboard
to transcending that.
The first thing we have to let go of
is unconscious guilt.
And that's why something like
The Course of Miracles
which has become very famous
in the state in which I live,
in which I live now.
There is a day which is
Forgiveness Day
and it's taken directly out of The Course of Miracles.
The Course of Miracles is a teaching
of love and forgiveness
and the letting go of fear.
And many of the people I know
who've recovered from cancer
and multiple sclerosis
and other serious debilitating illnesses
have done so as a result
of this particular
or other courses which are similar.
They are designed to show us
how to change our point of view
and how to let go of condemnation
of ourselves and others.
How to let go of guilt and fear
and how to move ourselves
into the willingness to be loving
and forgiving and compassionate.
Out of that comes the desire to understand.
So in our self-healing then
we need to almost like
take ourselves in our own arms
become that which is compassionate
and healing
because all of us have the healer
all of us have within us the healer
and we begin now
to heal our humanness.
See?
How do we get rid of the ego?
Not by making it an enemy
not by trying to attack it
not by getting into an adversary position
with it
but by loving it out of existence.
We literally dissolve the ego
through compassion and love
and understanding.
When you see that anything
you've ever done in your lifetime
when you can really see that
when your main intention
is to understand it
so that out of compassion it becomes healed
when we do this with other people
when we let go of the desire to be judgmental
towards ourselves and towards other people
then what happens is
our own energy field begins to move
in a positive direction.
See, cancer cannot grow
in a positive energy field
it can only grow in a negative energy field.
And if we look over here
we see that love
is the one that's available
to all of us.
The commitment to unconditional love
what is that kind of love?
I'm not talking about
Hollywood style emotionalism
that sentimentality
that attachment, that dependency
that mutual control back and forth.
Instead we're talking about
an intention
that's described as lovingness
to commit oneself
to nurture and support
all of life.
No matter what it's expression.
See, when you think about it
life flows equally
into the saint
and into the criminal.
Life is true.
That which is the God within
makes no judgment.
It flows equally into all.
And as it says in the scripture
the rain falls equally on all.
To move out of judgmentalism
because that is the lesson
in that example.
Life flows equally into all
so we allow our unconditional love
to support the truth of everyone
including ourselves.
Our own capacity for self-healing.
Our own, yes.
That I and I alone
have the power to make that decision
about whether I'm willing
to go through the necessary inner work
to bring about a healing
of this illness.
To bring about a healing of the person
who has that illness.
And that's the difference between
cure and heal.
See, treating is treating a symptom.
Curing is curing the disease.
But healing is healing the person.
And so we set our intention then
on accomplishing that
which is peace of mind.
The accomplishment of peace of mind.
Because that is the end result
of healing.
The end result of healing
is an inner tranquility.
Not an indifference
to what happens to the body
but a transcendence of the body
the longer do we identify
as that physical thing.
It belongs to us.
It's part of us.
But it is within us
because we realize that we are more
than the physical body.
So the healing of cancer depends
on realizing that we are
the one who decides
that we are greater than
the physical body.
That it is within the power of consciousness
to call forth the healer
within us.
And realize some of the consciousness techniques
that we talked about today.
See, what happens
when you start to ask yourself
can I heal myself?
Is this healable?
What within me needs to be healed?
See, the cancer is only the outer
physical expression.
It still doesn't tell us, literally
in our own particular case
what needs to be healed.
When I had severe diverticulitis
recurrent for many years
and I would land in the hospital
the last time I had it
I almost expired.
To really get rid of it
following these general principles
you know, it improved
and it got better.
And I didn't have it for some years.
And then suddenly something occurred
in my life
and I had a recurrence
and I had the worst attack of diverticulitis
I've ever had in my life.
The pain was overwhelming
and the cramping and the bleeding
and the whole thing started all over again.
And I asked what is the meaning of this?
Why?
I began to question within.
And as I began to question within
then came to me a technique
of going way, way back
and discovering the exact
and the precise meaning
which lay within this particular illness.
And so for most of us
a general
following the general laws of healing
is sufficient to bring about
a recovery from an illness.
For some of us there is
a very particular lesson
that a given illness has.
A very particular message.
And the illness will get better.
But then something will linger on
or a recurrence may occur
and the purpose of that
is to bring about your learning
that there is a specific hidden message
that you missed
and please get it this time.
The message of all of this for us then
is that these major
confronts of life
are something
that transforms us.
They have the power to transform.
So if you give the cancer within you
your blessing
and you say thank you
because you are giving me the power
to transform my consciousness
to expand my awareness
then you will be in the end
very thankful.
Many people who have recovered
from these illnesses
will look back and they all say
how grateful I am
that that arose in my life.
How grateful I am
that this cancer came into my life
and has brought me to the level
of awareness that I am today.