I'm Dr. David Hawkins. I've been a psychiatrist for the last 35 years,
a psychoanalyst, nutritionist, researcher into brain chemistry and its relationship to nutrition.
And for the last seven years I've been doing research into the nature of consciousness itself
and its application to spiritual work.
And in this series we are looking at the application of the knowledge
derived from this study of the nature of consciousness itself
to human problems.
In this particular talk today we'll be talking about sexuality.
We'll be talking about the difference between sex and making love,
between high and low energy sex,
how to transcend being guilty and at the effect of social programming about sexuality,
how to experience it from the heart instead of just from the body,
how to make it an uplifting and grand experience
rather than one of manipulation and control,
how to get out of the energy interactions which result in impotence and frigidity
and sexual dysfunction.
We'll ask the question, does God approve of sex?
Is sex all over with advancing age?
Does middle age mean you're over the hill?
These and other questions as we address it from the viewpoint of consciousness itself.
We'll be talking from that position,
from the viewpoint of body, mind and spirit,
about which we have heard so much in the field of holistic health.
Is that a slogan? Is that a catchphrase?
What does it mean, body, mind and spirit?
What is spirit anyway?
Is it something we can experience?
Is there an energy to that that we can discover through our own inner research
and to our own inner experiences?
So we'll be talking today about our own inner experiences,
subtle states,
inner awareness
and the part they play in this important area of human behavior.
Before we do that, we want to get into the nature
of the relationship between body and mind and spirit.
We want to review where it is that human experience is experienced,
talk a little bit about consciousness itself,
demystify it,
and turn it into something understandable.
To help us to do that, we'll be referring to a chart
on the blackboard here,
which we've used in others of this series,
referring to the levels of consciousness.
We have a mathematical model that has come out of our research,
which is very helpful in understanding
the nature of the relationship between body, mind and spirit.
And so we'll review briefly what is that relationship.
And we begin by looking at the fact that the body itself
cannot experience itself.
When we're talking about sexuality, everybody automatically thinks
of the body and its allure and all the physicality of form.
And astonishingly enough, when we look at it,
we realize that the body itself is in ascension.
That is, it cannot experience itself.
The arm cannot experience its armness.
The leg cannot experience its legness.
Something else, something greater than that,
has to take place before experience happens.
So the body is experienced through sensations.
Sensations.
What we experience is not the body,
but the sensations of the body,
where it is in space and where it is in motion.
The sensations themselves cannot really experience themselves.
They have to be experienced in something larger,
and that is in mind.
When we look at it carefully,
we realize we are not experiencing the body.
We're not really experiencing the sensations of the body.
We're experiencing what is going on in mind about the body.
Mind itself, curiously enough, cannot experience itself.
A thought doesn't experience its thoughtness.
A feeling doesn't experience its feelingness.
Something larger than mind has to be present,
something that is unchanging in itself.
And so what is going on in mind,
the reason we become aware of that,
is because of consciousness itself,
a much larger energy field.
Than that of mind.
We're aware of what is going on in mind,
then, because of consciousness.
Mind is telling us what is going on in emotions,
thoughts, sensations.
Sensations are telling us what is going on in body.
Therefore, what we're experiencing,
then, is always going on in the field of consciousness itself,
which is like an invisible screen
that is really located everywhere.
Consciousness itself is really unaware
of what is happening within itself.
It is because of something infinitely larger
than even consciousness itself,
and that is awareness,
the nature of awareness itself,
that which has no dimension,
no locality.
And so we're experiencing experience, then,
within the field of consciousness itself,
in handling human problems,
behavioral problems,
understanding human behavior.
We can address it, then, directly
by going
to its experience within consciousness itself.
Because consciousness itself
is more powerful and more dominant,
we can handle problems that seem to be
arising in the body by handling them
on the level of consciousness,
on the level of mind.
And that's what we'll be doing today.
We'll be looking at human experience and events.
And we'll be seeing that events are one thing,
but how we choose to be with them
is something else.
We may not be able to determine or control
or choose the events that occur in our life,
but we can determine how we wish to be with them.
And therefore, the experience of how to be with that
is perhaps more important than the event.
We all know that in a certain mood,
a trivial, you know, an irritation may be trivial.
We know that in another mood,
that same event can be aggravating
or even send us into a rage.
Therefore, how we are with that,
and that brings up the whole concept of energy fields.
The energy field, the position from which
we're coming about a situation,
the way we are holding our own existence,
the importance of all events
is coming out of the context
created by our position.
And so we'll be referring to this chart,
which we referred to in other talks,
in which we have these levels of consciousness,
and each of these levels
has been calibrated
as to their relative energy field,
the power of that energy field,
calibrated mathematically,
which gives us an understanding
in our left brain way of understanding things.
Each of them has a direction of an energy field,
whether it is negative or positive.
Out of these energy fields come emotions,
which we'll be referring to.
Out of these energy fields
comes a way of viewing the world,
a view of...
a way of relating to that
which is greater than our individual self,
and a process that is going on in consciousness.
So we'll pull this all together then,
we'll pull this all together
as we address the questions
of high energy sex,
that which is coming out of the heart,
that which is coming out of our way of being in the world,
and low energy sex,
which is localized in a physical kind of an experience,
about which society has had so much to say over the ages.
How to resolve the conflicts
that come out of holding it from that position.
And we'll see that man's conflict about sexuality
is coming out of the energy field
of his position about that,
how he perceives it,
what it means to him.
Problems are best solved
not on the level at which they appear to be occurring,
but on the next level above them.
So today we're not going to be talking about philosophy,
we're going to be talking about clinical experience,
that which you can verify through your own experience,
through human experience.
We're going to look at the area of problems
from a level that is above the problems.
So problems are best solved
by transcending them
and looking at them from a higher viewpoint
in which very often
because there's a shift of point of view
the problem automatically resolves
or we see that there wasn't any to begin with.
And so we want to go back to
what is the difference between high and low energy sex
and see how what man considers sexual problems
are coming really out of an energy field itself
and how we can change our position with that.
What can we do about that?
In general, when people talk about sex
they are referring to a type of experience
but they are talking considerably
about an energy field which everybody presumes
and which Madison Avenue plays on called desire.
What they are talking about is
a certain perception,
a certain way of looking at things,
a certain wantingness,
the overcoming of a frustration,
the overcoming of lack,
the withholding of this,
the manipulation of this,
the gratifying of it,
the using it as trade in relationships,
the allure, the price,
the value added to this allure,
and to the physicality.
So in general, man is talking about physicality.
And from there, because of the physicality,
then he gets into the field of morality.
And so morality is coming out of physicality,
holding sexuality from the physical level,
from the lower energy fields.
And so we have the story of the Garden of Eden
and what happens in the Garden of Eden.
What happens in the Garden of Eden
is the man and the woman,
in a state of innocence,
in a very high energy field,
eat of the tree of knowledge,
eat of the tree of good and evil.
They buy into a world of duality.
You see, in the world of love,
there is no duality.
In lovingness, lovingness just is.
The heart doesn't say anything.
The heart just knows.
The heart is with life.
In eating of the tree of right and wrong, however,
and good and evil,
then what happened?
Then what happened is they saw themselves as bodies.
They came down into guilt.
You see, guilt is at the bottom.
So from a high state of joy,
that state of lovingness,
infinite being with life out of joy,
which is beyond right and wrong,
it doesn't even arise,
they fell into a field
in which they were looking at the body as a body.
As a body, they then became conscious of its bodiness
and out of that arose man's sexual problems.
So whether it's historically an event or not is immaterial.
Psychologically, it is an event that has happened to mankind.
And so the problems that man calls sexual
are really due to a
point of view,
a point of view about physicality,
seeing sexuality as a physical phenomena,
being run by the desire of that.
What is the opposite side of the coin of desire?
Aversion.
And so sexuality is then characterized by desiring this.
It's characterized by aversion.
It's characterized by avoiding the field,
wanting nothing to do with it,
taking a moralistic position about that,
that one is now superior to it.
Superior to what?
Superior to seeing it as an animal,
physical function.
It even degrades that which is the animal,
and calls it animal as though
the animal world which is
and was created by God
is somehow immoral,
calling it animal.
So what is the difficulty then?
The difficulty is not in sexuality at all, is it?
The difficulty is within consciousness.
It's how mind is holding what sexuality is.
It's arising out of
how in consciousness the mind is seeing sexuality,
and how it defines these relationships.
We know from our study of these fields of consciousness
that everything we call courage
in an energy field of 200
where we see that this arrow is neutral,
it's no longer negative,
we see everything from this level down
as positions of victim,
as positions of coming from lack.
You see, guilt and apathy and grief and fear,
desire, anger, pride,
are all coming from positions of lack,
of not having wholeness,
not being at one with life.
And so, holding sexuality then from the physical level,
dividing it according to gender
into maleness and femaleness,
creates a feeling of separation,
and out of that separation then comes desire,
out of that comes frustration,
out of the frustration comes anger and resentment,
and out of all that comes fear and grief and apathy.
And so some people are into guilt over sexuality,
some people are into apathy,
hopelessness, lack of desire,
and some people are into grief,
some people are into fear,
people are into desiringness and wantingness
and being run by that,
and anger over that,
or the endless pridefulness about sexuality,
the strutting one's macho image
or the sticking out of one's feminine attributes
in a prideful and tantalizing,
seductive kind of controlling,
manipulating, exploiting kind of way.
And we see the marketing industry do this,
use this desiringness,
use this frustration, this lack,
this feeling of separation,
to try to control people and manipulate them,
to have the pretty girl sitting on the hood of the car.
You see, what has a car got to do with a pretty girl?
It's trying to connect that.
If I get this car, if I get this shampoo,
if I get this hairdo, if I wear this perfume,
then I will overcome this separation
between myself and that which I desire.
And so that point of view then
is creating an endless painfulness,
an endless source of suffering,
and the suffering takes various forms.
Whether it's impotence or frigidity
or satiriasis, whatever the form may take.
It's coming out of holding sexuality from that view,
from its physicalness, from its desiringness,
from its wantingness.
And we see how therefore one is run by that.
We see one nature of this energy field of desire,
the emotions accompanying that
are wantingness, cravingness,
to be addicted to.
And we know people who become addicted
to sex.
Sexuality is what runs them.
It's their whole thing.
The endless going to bed with everybody
that is available.
The needing to prove one's desirability.
The needing to prove something.
And so we see over on the right hand side
what is the process going on in consciousness
on this energy level.
It's called entrapment, entrapped.
Within consciousness, on this energy level,
once you want something,
that wanting begins to run you.
The desiringness wants you.
The wantingness runs you.
Temporary gratification.
Because of the negativity of this energy field
which is endlessly frustrating,
endlessly wanting, endlessly craving,
the person still remains entrapped.
There is no completion.
There is no feeling of finality.
There is no feeling of happiness.
We see that happiness does not occur
until you get up to an energy field of about 500.
And therefore trying to find happiness
through the endless creation and satisfaction,
the cycling of this desire,
the release of the frustration.
Naturally frustration feels good
when you temporarily satisfy it.
It feels good when you stop banging your head
against the wall.
And that is not the same thing as happiness.
The desiringness, the cravingness continues on.
It is because of this then,
because of this physicality,
because of the energy field,
that all the moral questions arise.
Why does religion,
why does morality address itself
to this kind of an energy field?
Why is it called carnal?
It is called carnal because
it is like lower energy sexuality
coming out of the lower energy fields of the body
being held in mind
in a lower viewpoint.
And therefore the whole question of morality
then addresses itself really to that
which is carnality.
Carnality in this case,
looking down on one's animal nature.
Instead of prizing it,
instead of being happy,
instead of being grateful,
instead of saying it is beautiful,
it is being downgraded.
And that which is intrinsically beautiful
when it is not judged
is held in a degrading manner.
How to get off this cycle,
how to experience sexuality
from a much different energy field.
How to get released from it.
And that will take us back into
a discussion then of how
to let go,
how to let go being at the effect of this.
How to let go being run by
the cycling of this.
How to be with sexuality
from a different energy field
so that it is experienced
as a totally different experience.
When we hold it and look at it
from a different level of consciousness,
all the questions and problems
now disappear.
There is no such thing as manipulation.
There is no such thing as withholding,
frustration, being run by desire,
going into anger and resentment over that,
going into a feeling of lack.
If the desire is not fulfilled,
then what comes up?
What comes up is a fear that it won't be fulfilled,
a grief that it hasn't been,
an apathy, an anger,
a frustration, a self-blame.
We see that at the bottom,
guilt is accompanied by self-hatred.
We see that holding sexuality
from this level leads to a view
of the world of sin and suffering,
of hopelessness, of sadness.
And sexuality, the whole subject,
becomes frightening.
We want to guard our children from this.
It becomes competitive
when sex is used in a seductive manner,
in a manipulative power field.
We have competition.
We have its use as a symbol of status.
One's sexual attraction
then becomes a status symbol.
And the adornment of the human body,
et cetera, becomes a symbol of status,
another way of controlling and manipulating
and trying to influence one's sense of self-worth.
The worry and the anxiety,
the wantingness, the resentment, the hatreds.
And so we see that sexuality based on
this energy field often leads to hatred.
And we have the stabbings
and the violent murders based on
that infatuation, that seduction,
the manipulation of one by another
and the triangulations of these situations
and the unconscious exploitations that are going on
based on this desiringness, this attractiveness.
We see the denial about this.
We see the contempt.
So when we get up to pridefulness
because of the morality about it,
we get into contempt, we get into denial,
we get into religious conflict,
we get into people who hold all sexuality
from a contemptuous,
looking down their nose at it
as though anybody who indulges in that kind of activity
must be coming from a low animal nature.
They presume that everyone else is run by it
in the same way that they are.
People who hold contempt for it
are projecting their own way of being with it
onto others and saying,
aren't they carnal, aren't they animal, etc.
How to let go of that
and we'll contrast that with a high energy sex
with a different energy field,
with a different way of being with it
that then transcends all these problems
of competition, frustration,
of fright and guilt and regret
and worry and anxiety.
Just imagine, how can you enjoy yourself
in a human endeavor that is taking place
in this whole energy field
in which secretly you feel really
that God is probably going to punish you for it
because the view of God coming out of
these energy fields is punitive.
You are certainly separated from Him
and if you get any enjoyment or happiness,
very likely at the end there's going to be retaliation.
Some people can't stand the intensity
of this conflict between
the driving biologic urge,
the psychological need and religion
and so they just split out of it all together
and jump into atheism
which just handles the whole thing that way.
One has to either let go of one's
view of God and religion
or let go of one's sexuality.
And so for some people it is an impossible
conflict to resolve
and many people end up as atheistic
because there's no way they can handle
their humanness
and also their views of God.
How can we move out of that?
How can we move away from being run by that
so that we can begin to experience
this behavior, these experiences
from a different energy field?
We'll contrast it with
an energy field of lovingness.
Love as an expression,
I mean sexuality as an expression
of lovingness,
as a sense of aliveness,
of being with the truth of that which you are.
In order to experience that concept,
that kind of an experience,
we have to let go of this lower
energy field
in which sex is experienced really
as a local physical phenomena.
And most people, if you
sit down and ask them,
if I ask them in the office,
what is sexual experience to them,
is primarily a local physical phenomena.
And so you get all kinds of preoccupation
with anatomy,
immense preoccupation with their fitness
as a sexual partner,
and women's.
Focusing on the physical attributes of the body.
And along with the physicalness of it
goes emotionality,
emotionality, sentimentality,
and emotionality.
And emotionality plus physicality then
is the expression of love.
The mad passionate embrace
and the expression of the emotionality
of wantingness and desiringness.
Oh how I want you,
I crave you,
oh how I must have you,
and the thrill of all that.
And this is what the movies portray, you see.
If we let go of that,
what kind of an experience is possible?
What kind of an experience is possible?
We'll contrast with that.
What kind of an experience would happen
if it was no longer local,
if it was no longer a negative energy field of 125?
What would happen if it happened out of the heart,
out of a positive energy field of 500,
out of the space of being with the reality
and the truth of that which you are?
First we'll have to talk about how to let go
of this energy field then.
How to not be run by it.
How to experience sex
when it's extremely appropriate,
when there is no conflict.
How can we let go of this cravingness?
If this energy field is what is causing all the problem,
then how can we transcend it,
so that we can experience it from a much higher level?
We'll use a technique which is worked with weight problems,
which is worked with pain,
which is worked with illnesses of a great variety of nature.
The basic principle works the same
no matter what we apply it to.
And that is when the energy,
when the feeling,
when the expression,
when the desire comes up,
what we do is we let go labeling it
or calling it anything.
We let go of the images and the pictures.
And instead we allow the experience
of what it is, the sensations of it,
to occur.
We let go resisting them
and as we do we let them run out.
What are we letting run out?
We're letting run out the energy field of desiringness,
the energy field of cravingness,
that thing that seems to be coming out of your solar plexus
of wantingness.
When you look at wantingness
you will realize it is not a pleasurable experience.
It is not a pleasurable experience
to stand there in this door window
and look at what is inside
with a feeling of wanting, wanting, frustrated craving.
When you look at it and cancel the content of what,
whether it's diamonds, a fur coat,
or someone else's body,
you will realize that the experience itself is unpleasant.
To want and not have is unpleasant.
To want and not have at this moment.
To want a steak and smell it cooking
but not being able to eat it
is really frustration.
If you hold a steak in front of a dog's nose
and just don't allow him to eat it,
what is he experiencing?
Is he experiencing happiness?
Is he glad to be alive?
If you keep it up long enough
you'll end up with anger and rage
at the frustration of this desiringness.
It is not a pleasant feeling.
It is not that which contributes to sex.
The illusion is it is the desire
that brings sex into my life.
It's because I want it.
The wanting and the desiring of it
is why I get to experience it.
Actually, the opposite is true.
It's the wantingness and the desiringness
which is blocking its coming into your life
and your full enjoyment of it when it is there.
The letting go of this craving and this desiring then,
what eventually happens is all the suppressed desiringness
that you have repressed and suppressed in this lifetime
and shoved down like a tank of compressed gas.
The pressure of this comes up
and as you allow it to just be released,
allow it to flow through you
without doing anything about it,
without opposing it,
let go resisting experiencing it,
what happens is it begins to decompress.
Eventually, because there is a limited quantity of it,
it finally stops altogether.
What happens to your life then
when the cravingness, the desiringness,
the obsession, the compulsion,
the addiction to the wantingness,
the cravingness of this physicality,
of the sexuality happens?
What happens is you have peace.
What a shocking thought.
Where there was a desiringness, a cravingness,
a wantingness, a frustration, a feeling of lack,
a feeling of not havingness,
a feeling of low self-esteem
because this is not being gratified,
instead now you have a peacefulness.
The thing just doesn't arise.
The same thing happens when you let go
your hunger and your craving and your desiringness
and your appetiting all the time for food.
That greediness finally lets go.
You see, we're talking really about a variety of greed.
We're not even talking about sex, are we?
Greed can be a greed for this.
It can be a greed for that.
But the nature of it still,
of what the world calls sexuality,
is really a greediness, a wantingness,
a forever desiringness,
which runs people, runs their whole life, dominates it.
Instead of this, there is an inner state of peace,
an inner state of serenity,
as though the whole question has been handled,
as though it's no longer a problem.
What is the problem now?
There is no problem.
It no longer drives you crazy.
It no longer insults you, insults your integrity.
You no longer have to sell yourself out.
The person doesn't feel.
They have to now barter and trade their body
and their sexual expressions.
It is a give and trade, an endless bargaining
that goes on between men and women and sexual partners
for those that choose the same sex.
The tantalizing with it, the withholding,
the gift of it.
Now you owe me.
Now you've paid me.
I paid for your dinner.
Now give me your body.
The endless trade-off and bargaining comes to an end.
One is now free of being manipulated by that.
Let's not forget that when we manipulate others,
we are equally manipulated in return.
When we let go, manipulating through this sexuality,
this variety of sexuality,
that means we cannot be manipulated by it either.
So we become freer.
You see, once you are unattached,
we move into the field of facing and coping with this problem,
our willingness to face and cope with it.
And what happens is we become unattached,
we become released.
Down here we were entrapped and up here we are released.
What is the release state?
We haven't moved up to love yet, but we're on the way.
The release state means that I am so free of that now
that if it happens in my life, that's terrific.
And if it doesn't happen in my life, I don't miss it.
So it's like if we have steak for dinner, fantastic.
And if we don't, that's okay too.
We'll have beans and salad.
So there may be a choice,
but the first time we are now at the level
of being able to make a choice.
We're not run by the world.
We're not run by this manipulation.
Every billboard doesn't send us to the store
to buy the chewing gum or whatever the pretty girl is doing.
Hmm.
Our willingness now to handle this, to transcend it,
moves us up to an acceptance
and allows us now to begin to feel adequate and confident.
We feel adequate because somehow there's an inner knowing
that somehow the question has been finally answered in our life.
We know we're never going to be at the effect of that again.
It's not really going to run us.
That there's a certain sense of freedom comes in now.
So where there was frustration,
there's now freedom.
And therefore we begin to feel adequate as a human being
and far more confident.
And we're willing then,
willing to begin to move into a lovingness.
The world begins to seem more friendly.
See, when sex is something you bargain,
when it's something that your status depends on,
when it's your stock and trade in the world,
it hardly looks like a friendly world.
It really looks like a world of competition.
And now the world begins to look more okay.
It begins to look friendly.
It begins to look harmonious.
We begin to enjoy the opportunities for sexual expression.
As we move in and out of acceptance then,
acceptance, we move into an energy field
where we're beginning to approach happiness,
an energy field which calibrates mathematically at 500
as compared to 0 for death, 30 for guilt,
and the ones we've talked about.
The beginning of happiness,
a sense of mellowness,
a sense of feeling really good about ourselves
and with our behavior.
This lovingness then,
the beginning of nurture and support,
the willingness to forgive,
the capacity to experience our own being
with this field of behavior
from a whole different point of view.
Energy field then resolves all the problems
that arise in this lower energy field.
As we said before,
everything is experienced in consciousness.
So, let's say for instance,
if your consciousness was colored blue,
then everything you're experiencing
in your blue consciousness,
what you're experiencing is blueness.
If your consciousness is colored pink, let's say,
then all your experience
is going to be experienced as pinkness.
So that this negativity then colors
the whole experience of one's sexual life.
And what's characteristic of these lower energy fields,
because they're coming from a lack,
coming from lack,
is that everything is experienced as giving and getting.
So, wanting means what?
It means the exchange of giving and getting.
And so you hear expressions about one's sexual life
then in these lower energy fields
of, did you get it last night?
She's worrying about whether she's going to give it.
He's worrying about whether he's going to get it.
The adolescent boys get together in the locker room
and the question is, did you get it last night?
As you move up out of the lower energy fields
of giving and getting,
you move into the middle energy fields of doing.
In this case, people are preoccupied
with the doingness of sex.
You know, let's do it is the expression.
Let's do it.
And therefore, this style of doing
becomes the preoccupation.
And so we have the endless,
sex manuals all talking about doingness.
They, of course, throw in some love,
the more modern ones.
It would be nice to have love there too.
That should alter the experience.
But that's considered to be romanticism.
Romanticism and something that women require
to have happy sex.
Women are supposed to have an energy field
which she calls lovingness,
which generally is coming out of this
plus sentimentality and emotionality.
So she can now hold it from the viewpoint
of what she considers lovingness
so she can then indulge her desiringness
without experiencing guilt.
The energy field then of doingness
is in the middle here.
It has to do with how well you do it.
And so people then become anxious
about their performance.
If sex is something you do,
then you should do it well in our society.
And so we have the whole idea
of competitive performance.
The idea of competitiveness and performance.
And out of performance anxiety comes
frigidity and lack of desire
and the various forms of impotence
in which there is the anxiety about doingness,
performance anxiety.
Will he like the way I do it?
Will she like the way I do it?
Have I satisfied the other person?
It becomes sort of athletics,
sort of a refined athletics.
So from getting,
from having,
giving and getting,
we move up to doing.
And now what happens when we start moving up,
when we let go of all that,
when we're no longer run by that,
then it becomes a way of how to be with someone.
It becomes of how you are with that person.
It's a way of sharing your being with that person.
It isn't what you give and get.
It isn't how you perform,
as though there's a rating scale.
You know he got 82 on his doing list
last night.
It becomes a way of being with the person
in which the whole barter system falls out.
The whole performance system falls out.
Because this way of being with somebody
is no longer viewed from a lower position,
the whole question of guilt falls out.
All the moralistic questions are now answered.
To come from being with that other person,
to be with who they are,
now the desire is to be with that person.
It means a connection within the heart.
It means the opening up of a space,
a way of being with that person.
See the fear arises,
well if I let go of my desiringness,
if I let go of that wantingness,
doesn't that mean that it will disappear from my life?
Research and experience and clinical experience
has shown that the opposite is true.
That the letting go of that desire
that the letting go of the desiringness,
the wantingness,
which in itself in consciousness
sets up a resistance.
See that which we want and desire
sets up in the other person a resistance.
So when the salesman comes on to you
in his salesman style,
you know he's going to want to sell you something.
And when you get that he wants to sell you something,
what comes up in you,
how are you going to resist that?
So instead of resistance,
the pressure and the resistance,
the counterbalances,
which are going on in these lower energy fields,
in being with the person,
then out of a lack of,
a non-existence of desiringness and wantingness,
what happens?
We've created this space then
for the energy fields
which are coming down through the body,
through the energy of life itself,
to express themselves
in that way which is most appropriate to the people.
Instead of the energy coming
up,
the so-called Kundalini energy coming up the spine,
instead of being run by the entrapment of that energy
in the body's lower energy fields,
we have the energy field of life itself,
that which is life itself,
coming down through the body
and opening up through the heart.
The letting go of the lower energy field
opens the way for the higher energy field.
The opening up of joy,
the joyfulness,
the lovingness,
to express itself.
Now,
what happens in the relationship
instead of performance
is the desire to bring happiness and pleasure
and to support the other person's experience.
There is a compassion
to the love making.
See, no longer is it worried about
performance,
no longer is it worried about
morality,
no longer is it struggling
with moralistic questions
because those have to do
with being stuck in desiringness.
The negativity that arises out of that field
automatically brings other negative thoughts.
And the negative thoughts are,
of course,
is this right?
Am I being used?
Am I being exploited?
Am I doing okay?
Am I built correctly?
Am I in the right position?
Am I being like it's done in the movies?
Am I doing it like it is in the performance manuals?
And there isn't much space there
for the enjoyment.
There isn't much space there.
Space there for the love of sexuality.
You see, what happens when you let go
the desiring of sexuality?
People say,
Boy, if I let go of my desire,
I won't get any.
Right?
Get any.
What happens with letting go
the desiringness for it
is a love for.
A love for.
A love for a thing.
What happens when you let go desiring,
wanting to own something,
to have it,
to get it,
to master it,
to control it,
to clutch it.
You see?
Because when you want to desire it
and control it,
even when you get it,
what comes up next
is the fear of losing it.
Right?
You want the diamond bracelet,
you have the diamond bracelet.
What comes up next?
Thieves.
That's the obvious thing that comes up.
The fear of losing it.
And then the weeping and the wailing
when that which has been desired and gotten
is eventually lost.
The fear of losing comes up.
When we move into the energy field then
of lovingness
to be with,
what takes the place of desiring
and wanting sex
is the loving it.
We begin to love sex for the first time.
And as we said,
love is non-judgmental.
It just is with that.
It sees its naturalness.
It's aware of the intrinsic innocence.
It watches the animals now
from a different viewpoint.
It sees the expression
of the grace
of the animalness.
When it's out of a negative,
condemning,
moralistic energy field,
you can then begin to experience
the incredible beauty,
the perfection,
indeed the sacredness
of this expression of what?
The expression of one's aliveness.
The thrill and joy and experience
of the energy field of one's aliveness.
We begin to love sex.
And so now we're talking about
the sexuality of love
and the love of sex
as an expression of love.
Approaching sexuality
from the viewpoint of desire itself
is, as we said,
we saw that desire has sort of
a negative energy field.
And a negative energy field
seems to bring in the propensity
for all of these negative energy fields
to come in.
So that it isn't just the desiringness,
but it seems to bring with it
a whole negative energy field,
which makes us prone to this.
The guilt and the apathy,
the grief,
the fear,
the anger,
the pridefulness,
the anxiety about performance.
When we're free of desire, therefore,
we're released from guilt.
We're released from remorse.
We're released from anticipation
of maybe it won't happen.
All of these energies arising then
almost en masse,
almost as a unit.
We let go worrying about
what's going to happen with sexuality
as we get older.
The whole question of
are you over the hill
when you're 40, 50, 60,
whatever over the hill means
in your cultural group.
The anxiety of giving and getting,
the desire to keep,
to own,
to hold,
to manipulate,
to control,
all of that disappears.
If the orientation now
is coming from the heart,
if one has let go of desiringness,
then it is only a way of being
with another person.
And we find that sexuality continues on
into old age unimpaired.
Sexuality itself then
does not decline with age.
Instead, its quality improves.
And so clinically what we see
is that sex gets better
the older you get,
much in the reverse of what
the popular view may be.
The learning how to let go
of that which is trivial,
the letting go of the unimportant,
the realization that
as you grow older
of what is important,
the quality of the experiencing
of the other person's energy.
As we said,
because all things are experienced
in consciousness,
as you get older and more mature
and you own more and more
of the truth about yourself,
you become increasingly interested
in what is the quality
of the experience.
The quality of the experience
is coming out of the energy
that is being experienced
in consciousness.
And so in how to be with that person,
what is attractive now
is that person's energy.
Not the physical body.
The physical body comes and goes.
But the quality of the energy
of being with that person.
And we begin to experience
the energy of that person.
We begin to notice
as we embrace the person
that what we're attracted to
is their energy.
As we clear up
all the manipulative things
and manipulative games,
all the garbage that's in the space,
as the space becomes increasingly clear,
as the integrity of our relationship
with that person
becomes progressively more important
rather than trying to get
what one can get,
then what we become
increasingly conscious of
and we begin to experience
is the other person's energy.
You see, at the bottom of the box,
we're not experiencing
their energy at all.
What we're experiencing
is our own energy.
Sexual attractiveness,
as amazing as it may sound,
does not exist in the outer world.
It is something that you
project onto the world.
Sexual energy is something
that you own.
And what you consider
to be attractive
is something that you
project onto the world.
So in one society,
being extremely slim
is attractive.
In another society,
being plump is attractive.
Being brunette or blonde
or having a bone through your nose
or many rings
or rings around your neck
or earlobes that are pulled long
and things painted on your head
and your hair piled up,
all kinds of decorations
of the human body,
these are only projections
of our own images
that we are holding within.
And so we haven't even owned it,
you see.
Below this energy field here,
we haven't even owned
that we are the author of that,
that we're the source of our sexuality.
We think it's something
that you like run across.
You know, the sailor running around
by himself from bar to bar,
thinking that he will run into that
out there,
not realizing that
I am the author,
I am the owner of that
which is attractive to me.
And as we move into
a higher energy field,
we begin to experience
the energy of the other person.
Now, the physical attractiveness
doesn't mean much of anything.
You can go to bed with somebody
who,
physically,
you know,
has a center page fold,
might fall into
what the world calls attractive,
and yet the experience is repulsive.
The person's energy is abhorrent.
The energy,
not what they say,
you could tape record what they say.
You could type it out
as a transcript and read it.
Sounds okay.
You could take a photograph
and say,
is this person attractive?
Yes.
Why is it such a
disenjoyable experience?
Why is there no desire to repeat it?
You realize it was
the fulfillment of
some kind of a fantasy.
There was nothing there,
no energy there.
What's it like to make love
with somebody
in a reverse negative energy field
who's coming from anxiety
and fear
and low self-esteem?
It's not particularly pleasurable.
It ends up as sort of therapy.
You know,
you're really doing therapy
with the other person.
You get so preoccupied
with their unhappiness
about the whole experience.
As we move into lovingness then,
and we clear this out,
what happens then is
the desire to experience
the other person's energy.
We get a feeling.
So in that clear space,
the masculinity is attracted
to that femininity,
and it's almost as though
universal man
is with universal woman.
It's as though one transcends
the personality,
the desire to be with
that energy field
which we call the feminine
or the masculine.
Now that the experience
becomes totally different,
instead of a localized
physical experience
accompanied by some emotionality,
the beating of the heart
and all the physicality
of the emotions,
instead there is now
a quite different feeling,
a feeling of expansiveness,
a feeling of that oneness.
And where does sex arise?
It arises spontaneously
out of the being
with the energy of that person.
A second before,
there was no thought of sex
in either one's mind.
They're waiting for the toast
to come out of the toaster.
And then there's the embrace,
and if that embrace
is done in a field that is clear,
in other words,
the partners have let go
of any withholds of resentment
and things that they're obstructing
their being with each other,
then out of the embrace itself
arises the desire,
the desire now
is of a totally different nature.
It's the desire to be with
and experience that person
and their energy.
The spontaneity of it
arises out of the space,
not out of desiringness,
but out of the sense of aliveness,
the energy of being
with the space of that person.
That's a diffuse overall experience.
So instead of a local anatomical experience,
limited anatomically
to a small area of the body,
accompanied by emotionality,
instead,
there is an overall aliveness.
It's as though the energy field
encompasses and surrounds
the two of you,
and that the sexuality
is arising out of the energy field itself.
It seems to have nothing to do
with the personality.
It seems to have nothing at all
to do with that solar plexus wantingness
or desiringness,
or that genital excitability
which comes out of desire
and its frustration.
Instead is the joy
of being with that energy,
the gratefulness for the opportunity
to be with that energy
and the high joy and pleasure
of that which is a sense of alness,
of completeness.
At the very moment
that this desiringness arises
in this type of energy field,
it is already simultaneously complete.
So if the phone rings
and the whole set is interrupted,
it can be dropped instantly
with no feeling of loss.
There's no feeling of loss
because the sense of completion
within the heart,
the oneness,
the unification has already occurred.
You see,
when we come from wantingness
or desiringness,
if you hold a steak
in front of a dog's nose
and then you take it away,
he will feel loss,
he will feel grief,
he will feel anger.
In a state of being
at one with another person,
the satisfaction is running simultaneously
with the experience.
Wonderful phenomena
that begins to happen in our life
when we let go
of any particular appetite.
When we let go of being run
by any appetite,
it's as though the experience
is complete at all times.
We'll notice that with weight reduction,
that if we let go of
and disappear that hungriness,
that wanting of the food,
the being run by hunger,
what happens is that
the sense of wanting to eat,
the desire to eat,
now arise out of the eating itself.
When we sit down to eat,
there still is no feeling
of hunger or appetite.
But as we begin to eat,
the enjoyment is enormous.
If, however,
the doorbell rings
right in the middle
of eating your steak,
you can leave the meal,
go and be with a friend,
and there's no feeling of loss,
no feeling of lack.
It's as though the completion
accompanies the enjoyment.
So instead of coming
from a wantingness,
it's always as though
you're just this side
of the experience
trying to push the next second.
You know how that is in sex,
how that is with eating.
You're always anticipating
the next biteful.
You're anticipating
the next sensation.
You're always anticipating.
It's like you're reaching
so that there's always
an internal strain
between what is happening
right this second
and what you desire
and want and crave
to happen in the next second.
Once that wanting, craving,
desiring is let go of,
what's happening now
is the feeling of being
with the exact moment
so that each moment
is complete and total in itself.
Because of its completeness,
it can be stopped any second
with no feeling of loss.
When you're in a very
high energy state,
in a state of high energy,
joyfulness, blissfulness,
there's no feeling of loss.
Somebody can turn off
the television set
of the program you've been watching,
no feeling of loss.
Why is that?
It's because you're experiencing.
The nature of your consciousness now
is one of coming from completeness
all the time.
To be with that person now,
to feel it one with their energy,
to feel that acceptance,
that aliveness of that oneness
is at the very moment
of his experience
already complete.
There is no have to
continue this experience
because the sense of completion
is in the anticipated future.
The pleasure of the eating
is in the anticipation
of the next biteful.
That kind of sexuality then
has an internal strain.
It disallows the expansion
into the infiniteness
which rightfully accompanies
that experience.
The letting go of that desiringness then
allows us to be completely at one,
completely content.
Each moment then arises spontaneously.
Each moment seems to be arising
of its own.
Within the embrace,
the experience now is happening.
It's as though it's a movie unfolding
and you are a participant in the movie.
You are enjoying the unfolding
of this spontaneity.
What's happened is
you've owned yourself back as source.
Instead of putting it outside of yourself
as something to get,
you've owned it as something that you are.
It is your purpose
and your way of being
with that way about yourself.
The experience is coming from within you.
Therefore, there is no gap
between that which you are
and the experience.
You see?
When we're coming from a lower energy field,
it's like you are here
and that which is desired is over there.
And the desire then is pictured as
somehow coming across
and reducing the distance and the space.
But there's always that feeling of space
between that which you think you are,
your desiringness,
and that which you want.
There's the subject and the object.
As we let go of that and become free of that,
then we begin to experience
life spontaneously unfolding
of its own.
We begin to feel a reverence
for the nature of this experience.
Life becomes
that which is described by the mystic.
What is a mystic?
A mystic is a person who has really
let go of that desiringness
and is experiencing from second to second
the completeness, the totality,
and in it the exquisite beauty
and therefore a reverence
and the sacredness.
And therefore now the relationship becomes
an expression of that which is sacred,
the enjoyment of the exquisite
sense of aliveness.
It's like it has transcended the world.
How has it transcended the world?
We could say that the world is that
which is constantly changing,
that which begins and that which ends,
that which is limited,
that which limits us.
And if we identify with it,
then it limits our experience
to that local wanting, cravingness.
If we let that go then,
that energy field which begins to come
through the heart,
which unites us with that other person
in this spontaneous joyfulness,
means that we've really transcended the world
because now the energy that we're experiencing
is that which is infinite.
It becomes an infinite experience.
We're not talking about this philosophically.
We're talking about it experientially.
So that the sexual experience now expands.
Instead of a local genital phenomena,
we notice the experience
throughout the entire body.
From the entire body it may now be
begins to expand to like a space around the body.
It seems to be as though the whole room
is having an orgasm.
It seems as though some kind of an infinite space
is the source.
And the body is merely expressing
what is happening in that space.
The body then becomes like the marionette
which is acting out
what is going on in an invisible realm,
that which is infinite.
So the energy of this now,
we don't have our survival
on anything that is limited.
Instead, we're experiencing that which is unlimited.
Can we say that love is unlimited?
If we look around us,
we see lovingness everywhere.
The expression of lovingness.
It has no beginning, it has no end.
It has no limitation.
The only thing that limits it
is our willingness to experience it.
Our willingness to open ourselves
up to it.
It's like an infinite ocean.
And so when we open ourselves up to it
by letting go of that which opposes it,
we become an expression of that lovingness.
We experience it then as an infinite state
that transcends the personality,
that transcends time and space.
The greatest aphrodisiac
is that inner sense of aliveness.
As that aliveness intensifies,
it's as though that sense of aliveness
awakens all of us,
the totality of us.
That feeling of loveness,
godness,
is the greatest aphrodisiac of all.
And so we're talking about
the sexuality of the heart
instead of the sexuality of the body.
The sexuality that arises out of the heart.
And here when we're talking about heart,
we're not talking about the physical organ.
We're talking about heart
with a capital H.
Heart, that which is all-encompassing,
that which is all-diffuse,
that which is all-inclusive,
that intense sense of aliveness,
the exquisite pleasure
in the experience of our own existence,
expressed now within the energy field
of being with someone
whose energy matches yours,
its polar opposite.
We get to experience in this space then,
that opposite within us
which we have not experienced before.
We allow then to experience
in the man his own feminine.
He then owns it in the experience
and the embrace.
The woman experiences
that energy field within herself
coming back to her through the man.
And therefore there is that sense of oneness
and that completeness,
the magic of that embrace.
The magic of that embrace
is the joining of these two energy fields,
the masculine and the feminine,
as an expression of their oneness
out of that intense feeling of aliveness and joy.
That settles all the problems
that man has talked about
having to do with sexuality
because in that inner experience,
in the subtlety of that inner experience,
is the reconnecting
with the joy of one's innocence.
The whole question about
whether God approves of sex,
which is created by the intellect,
by man's left brain,
what he is asking is,
does God approve of carnality?
Does God approve of that
which is coming out of a negative energy field?
In the experience of that aliveness
and that oneness,
in the experience of joy,
as one moves up to an infinite state
of inner peace and completion,
because completion is peace,
what is peace but that sense
of absolute oneness,
the rejoining with the One?
And so, within that sexuality
which arises out of the heart
is the return to the experience
of being with the One
that gives it its mystical transcendent quality,
its sense of everywhere-ness,
its sense of completion.
It's as though it speaks for all men
and for all women for all time.
The inner feeling that one is all men
and all women for all time.
Wondering if one is Adam or Eve.
Many people have had that thought.
When that sense of oneness comes in,
it's as though one transcends all of time.
One has been all of men forever.
One has been all of women forever.
We own the source.
We are that,
and out of which that experience arises.
No longer at the effect of it,
but the expression of that.
It's incredible sacredness and its beauty.
The subtlety of that inner experience.
We look within.
How can we make this practical?
Does it sound like fantasy?
Does it sound like the mystical, the unreal?
Does it sound like the sex of unicorns perhaps?
Not real men and women?
There are certain ways in which one can
practically move into it.
One way to get unfocused
from the physicality and the body
arises out of an ancient
traditional meditative technique.
And it's really worth trying,
and you'll be amazed at the results.
Next time when you're having sexual experience,
focus your attention and keep it there
throughout the entire experience
one inch below your navel.
Just try it.
That's a point the Japanese call the hara,
one inch below the navel.
It's used in martial arts
where one focuses one's centeredness.
Instead of paying attention
to the movements of the body,
instead of paying attention
to the manipulations,
the endless anxieties,
concentrate, fix your attention right there.
Hold your attention no matter what is happening.
And you'll find that you're somewhat removed now.
And in this somewhat removed state
where you become somewhat the participant observer,
the entire experience now takes on
a whole different dimension.
It is now sort of happening within you.
But instead of being focused into the local,
you're experiencing now
from a more generalized energy field.
Try that as a way to move
from that local experience
on up to the heart.
Just move into that point called the hara,
H-A-R-A,
and you'll notice the change of quality
of the experience.
And then you'll see it's what we're talking about
is quality.
We're talking about quality
because when you move out of the localization,
you're moving into a different energy field
and the entire experience is then of one of expansion,
an expanded experience,
much greater, greater in intensity,
much more fulfilling,
much more gratifying,
subsequent to which one feels joyful and grateful.
Grateful instead of satisfied.
The difference is gratitude.
Look at the energy field of gratitude.
Gratitude is up here about 540,
akin to joy.
Instead of satisfaction of desire,
which leaves people often with a sense of loss.
And the Latin phrase meaning after intercourse,
there is sadness.
Why after intercourse is there sadness?
Or sexuality without a sexual partner.
Why does it leave you with a sense of sadness?
A sense of loss.
And it was becoming,
as it was coming from that sense
of non-completion,
that sense of lack.
It was putting the source of one's sexuality
out there someplace in the world
instead of reowning it
as part of that which you are.
The sense of innocence that arises
then puts you back in the Garden of Eden
as though you have just
uneaten,
uneaten
the tree of good and bad,
good and evil.
It's as though it takes you out of
the field of carnality
and puts you back into the innocence,
the awareness of the truth
of that which you really are.
Therefore,
one of the greatest of all human experiences.
In it,
we demonstrate that whole principle.
That it isn't the events of life,
it isn't what's happening,
but how we are with those things.
It's how we decide to be with that
that determines the nature of the experience.
Whether it's a guilt-inducing,
frustrating,
anxiety-provoking,
neurotic type
of a dysfunction,
or whether it is one of the greatest
of all human experiences.
All arises of how we decide
to be with that.
How we decide to hold that
within our experience.
What context we're coming from
about who we really are
and the nature of human experience.