I'm Dr. David Hawkins. I've been a psychiatrist for 35 years, psychoanalyst, physician, researcher
and the relationship between nutrition and the relationship to alcoholism and addiction
for the last 10 years doing research into the nature of consciousness itself and its
relationship to that which is called spiritual. And today's talk is going to be on understanding
the nature of addiction, letting go of alcoholism and addiction. And we'll be presenting this
whole topic of alcoholism and addiction from the viewpoint of consciousness itself, a different
way of approaching the topic, a way of discerning what is the essential nature of the addictive
process rather than what are its consequences or its physical correlates. We'll be talking
about the nature of consciousness itself and how...
All right.
So understanding of this will give us a different context in which to understand the addictive
process and its relationship to human behavior.
So we'll be looking today at a map of consciousness, one that we've used in this series of talks
and one which we have found has been very useful in research and making understandable
that which hitherto for has been perhaps considered mystical.
It's been considered mystical, or esoteric, or too right-brained for a left-brained people
to understand.
And so on the blackboard here we have what looks complicated but actually is quite simple.
The various levels of consciousness and these levels as you can see have been calibrated.
So out of the research we've done, for instance, we have calibrated the relative power of these
energy fields and their direction. And we will begin to understand a lot of human behavior.
And out of that we'll understand the addictions.
In this calibration you'll notice where death is calibrated at zero, if death is calibrated
at zero, then we will find an enlightenment, or leaving the world of duality, transcending
limitation calibrates at about 600.
We notice that the energy field of courage is at 200, pride 175.
We'll refer back to these numbers in the course of our discussion. Importantly also we'll notice that
the direction of these arrows shows whether it is a negative energy field, that which
is not inimicable to life, or whether it's a positive energy field, that which is supportive
to life.
In understanding addiction then, we need to understand the nature of consciousness itself
first, and then we'll go back to how this applies to the addictive process. We'll look
at what is the true nature of addiction, and what is the quality that society has missed,
because society's
understanding of addiction has not been very successful. Until the advent of Alcoholics
Anonymous, let us say, society's recovery rate from the addictions was zero. It was
never heard of that anybody ever recovered from alcoholism, and it was only the truth
as represented by Carl Jung, who said that science alone has no answer for this problem,
that something
over-ambiguously
beyond ordinary human experience, meaning within the limitations of science, has to
be sought, and there the answer will be found.
And that brings in then spirituality, and what does that mean? We'll be talking about
the relationship between body, mind, and spirit. What is the relationship between body, mind,
and spirit? And what is spirit anyway? Is it some kind of a mythical entity? Is it a
metaphysical fantasy? What is the nature of spirit, and how does it operate in a real
way that we can verify through our own clinical experience?
So we won't be talking about philosophy. We won't be talking about epistemology. We're
going to be talking about that which you can verify for yourself through your own inner
experience, and truth as it can be experienced within yourself, and then how this is going
to be applied.
So today we'll be talking about the understanding of alcoholism and the addictions, and the
importance thereof in their recovery.
And so today we'll be talking about context. The overall way in which you hold a thing,
and the space from which you're coming, how to be with a subject, because it's context
that creates all of meaning. It's context that defines goal, and coming from a context
of understanding
a day
And so we'll go to this map today, and we'll start explaining it. Within the box here is
the ego, the ego, that which is called the self with a small s. And within the ego we'll
see we have these different energy fields which we mentioned before. Starting at the
bottom, then, we have an energy field.
This energy field is called guilt. And you'll notice over to the right of these energy fields
is an emotion, an emotion, how we experience this energy field in our daily life. And to
the right of that we'll notice a process, the process which is going on within consciousness
itself.
That energy field will also determine how we experience and see the world, how we see
the world, and how we would relate to God.
The God of our understanding, because of the limitation of our own energy fields.
And starting at the bottom, as we said, is an energy field called guilt. And we see that
it is calibrated with 30, using death as zero, 30 then, is a state of, really a state of
destruction. And it's experienced usually in the form of self-hatred. And the world
is seen as a place of sin and suffering. And God is really the ultimate, the ultimate, the
threat or destroyer of the soul, because he will throw the soul into destruction, into
hellfire forever.
So this is really the lowest energy field, and one with very little power in it. And
when we move up to the next one, we move up to an energy field of hopelessness and despair,
which is calibrated at 50.
Hopelessness and despair means, for instance, like the old lady rocking back and forth in
her rocking chair.
She's staring out the window, and she got a notice from the State Department that her
son was killed in action.
And now, the family shakes her, you know, and tries to get her to respond, and she doesn't
respond to anything.
Because accompanying these energy fields, there's changes in brain chemistry. There's
been a happening now within her neurotransmitters, within her brain, and so that she doesn't
respond.
So hopelessness and despair represents a process going on within her brain, and so that she
doesn't respond.
So hopelessness and despair represents a process going on in consciousness of loss of energy.
The world is seen as hopeless, and if there is a God, he would have nothing to do with
you, because your own self-esteem is so low that God wouldn't want anything to do with
a worm like yourself.
So we call it sort of the worm view of the nature of God.
If we get the person out of that very low energy field, we can get them up to a higher
energy field called grief.
The person in hopelessness cannot help themself, and we have to pour energy into them, and
if we can, we can get them up perhaps to this energy field called grief.
Grief calibrates at 75.
It has a lot more energy than hopelessness.
Grief has a certain biologic purpose.
In other words, the child, when it cries, summons the mother.
It has the power to pull some kind of response from the world.
And the emotion that accompanies grief is one of regret, a feeling of loss, a feeling
of despondency.
And we see the process going on in consciousness is dispirited, spirit being that high energy
out of which all of life is a manifestation.
The person in grief then sees this as a very sad world and an unloving God who doesn't
really care for you.
And it is a very sad world and an unloving God who doesn't really care for you.
Now, if we have the old lady rocking back and forth in her rocking chair and not eating
and not responding, and let's say we get a telegram from the State Department that
says the previous telegram was a mistake.
It was really someone else with a different name.
And the family gathers around to her and they say, mother, mother, it wasn't Joey that got
killed.
It was all a mistake.
He's alive and well.
And she goes right on rocking back and forth.
Still standing there.
She's down there.
staring out the window.
If we could get that woman now by pouring energy into her up to a level of grief, all
of a sudden she begins to cry.
The expression of that emotion now indicates to us that she is getting better.
Interestingly enough, these two energy states come out of the failure to face the energy
field which lies just above it called fear.
The energy field of fear, still a negative emotion as you can see by the direction of
the arrow, but an energy field now of 100.
100 is a lot of energy.
You see, you can run a long way out of fear.
So the emotion itself, the form of the emotion is not constructive, but the energy out of
it can be utilized in a very positive way.
And so all these energy fields have their upside and their downside.
The downside which can be used.
Negatively, the upside, if you know how to utilize it, you can utilize the energy of
fear.
And if you know what to be afraid of, it can be a very constructive thing in your life.
Fear as we ordinarily experience it in ordinary life is experienced as worry, anxiety, panic,
eventually even terror.
So grief, you see, has to do with the past.
Grief has to do with the past.
And fear has to do with the future.
The process going on.
Consciousness is one of deflation.
The fearful animal shrinks and hides.
When you're in third grade and the teacher asks for a response to a question, you know
how we used to shrink and hide behind the person in front of us.
So we shrink and become deflated less than that which we are in fear.
And the kind of world that we see, our perception of the world that comes out of this energy
field is that this is a frightening and threatening world.
See how we can take away from the world.
And who is the god of a frightening and threatening world?
A very punitive god.
And so, god is seen as a punisher, and much to be feared.
Because of the holding of all the sense of sin and guilt, and low self-esteem in this
level of consciousness, holds god as the most frightening of all possibilities.
Moving a person out of fear.
You're able to that.
up to the next energy field, which we call desire, and desire at 125, as you know, has
an awful lot of energy, desiring to want.
So its expression in our ordinary emotion is that of wanting and craving.
That can eventually become an obsession, a compulsion, and we then call it an addiction.
And why is this so?
Because the process going on in consciousness is one of entrapment.
The person has become entrapped.
They are at the effect of, they are run by that.
And so the marketing industry, of course, this is their purpose, to create in you, to
play off your desires, to create a wanting and a craving, to get you entrapped to want
their product.
Once you become entrapped by that, whether it's a fancy car or a certain perfume or a
shampoo that's going to make you lovely, whatever, then that will run you.
and you'd be willing to give up your money and your energy and buy their product.
Desiringness, however, leads to a world because of the endless wantingness of this
coming out of your solar plexus of a very frustrating world.
So the difficulty with wantingness is though it can drive you,
the wanting a Ph.D., the wanting to be a doctor, the wanting to live in a good address.
All these wantings, which can run us for an entire lifetime,
lead to a certain sense of frustration because wantingness does not cure itself by getting.
It just leads to additional wantingness.
You see, after you finally get a yacht, you will find that as you tie it up,
somebody next to you has a bigger yacht.
And so the wantingness in and of itself is not satisfied.
And so this constant frustration leads to a picture of God from whom you're separated.
In other words, He's the God who forever,
who never withholds from you what you want.
And it leads easily to anger, which is our next level.
Anger, at 150, as everyone is aware, of course, leads to, has a great deal of energy in it.
As you see, it's still a negative emotion and it has a destructive downside.
But the energy of anger, if you know how to use it, it can be a very useful thing.
We experience the energy of anger, you know, in every day.
Life, in the emotions of resentment, of feeling hatred, grievances, grudges,
the unwillingness to forgive.
And we see that what's happened in the process in consciousness is one of expansion.
The angry animal swells up with anger, becomes larger than life.
The person who's angry, their veins swell, they swell up with this angriness
and try to become imposing on the biologic level, you see.
This angriness, then, leads to a competitiveness.
The angry person sees a world of competition, of conflict, of war, of me against you.
It's a polarized position of opponents.
And therefore, the God, understand, the view of God that comes out of that is an angry God.
So the person who sees God is the ultimate,
ultimate anger.
The God of angriness, the God of vengeance, the God who gets even.
He's the God who's coming out of his spleen, is he not?
He's coming out of a revenge, a hatred, an anger.
It's as though he now hates that which he created
and hates the humanness of that which he created.
The God of retaliatory, vengeful angriness.
If we move up out of this angriness, if we can move up to pride,
we see that pride has an energy field of 175.
That's a lot of power.
And pride is enough to energize the United States Marine Corps.
Pride can be a very useful emotion.
The difficulty with pride, because we see the energy field of it is still in a negative direction,
the emotions experienced with pride, the downside of it is denial.
And in the addictions, of course, this is very, can be very fatal.
Hmm.
Denial, taking the form of arrogance and contempt, saying,
well, it's good, you know, those people need it, but not me, I'm different.
And that comes out of the fact that the process going on in consciousness is one of inflated.
The person is coming from an inflated sense of self, a very dangerous position,
and therefore we see the pridefulness which leads to the destruction eventually,
the rapid destruction, coming down to destruction.
In the rock stars and people who get into drugs who are successful very early in life,
this enormous inflation of the ego, the denial that goes with it,
the contempt for the valuation of life, the inability to hear the advice of others.
So pridefulness leads us to then a very vulnerable defensiveness.
It is not a good position to be in,
but it's an energy field.
It's an energy that we can utilize when we're moving ourselves from anger up to courage.
You see, out of this energy field of pride.
The person in pride then is very preoccupied with status, with ownership,
with havingness, with symbols, with labels.
And it's a very defensive position to be in, this preoccupation with status.
How does that energy field, which comes out as denial, arrogance,
contempt, an inflated energy field,
how does that influence our viewpoint of God?
The relationship to God then would be one of usually two possibilities.
Out of the arrogance of the intellect, out of the left brainness,
the presumption that the left brain has the capacity to know all of truth,
could come a position of atheism.
And the position of atheism then is a denial,
a denial of the truth of which can be experienced through human experience.
Or it could take its opposite.
It could take the form of bigotry.
It could take the form of the religionist,
who takes the position then that my way of seeing things is the only way,
and because my way is the truth, your way, therefore, is not the truth.
So pride is a position which polarizes us,
in which everybody else then becomes,
see there's our position, which is correct,
and therefore everybody else's position is wrong.
So pridefulness then is a polarizing position of me against you,
and of course it is the basis of all the religious wars.
Pride has a useful energy in it, as the Marine Corps has found out.
And it's useful to us to move on through to a higher energy field called courage.
Now courage is a very crucial level to us.
And crucial because you see, for one thing, the arrow now suddenly goes neutral.
In other words, the energy field of that level of consciousness is now shifted to neutral.
It's as though the negative antenna, the antenna which was tuned to negative,
is now tuned to neutral.
It stops pulling to itself in experience that which is negative.
Its energy field is 200, which is a lot of power.
So courage has enough energy in it, you know, to settle the United States of America.
Courage has enough to get a man to the moon.
It has enough to establish all of science,
to explore intellectual frontiers of philosophy.
So courage at 200 is enough to create all the great industrial empires.
And it's a very powerful energy field,
not because it jumped another 25 points,
but because now the direction of the field has changed.
Much of that resistance has dropped off.
And for the first time now, the person emotionally is able to face,
to cope, to handle, to look at things.
And the critical thing that happens in consciousness,
the process going on in consciousness,
is that the person becomes empowered.
The person becomes empowered.
And what made this huge jump?
What made this huge jump in power?
What crosses the line and makes you go beyond that level
is the willingness to tell the truth.
The willingness to tell the truth.
This is going to be crucial in the understanding of the addictions
and the understanding of the traditional 12 steps.
Because it is in the first step,
the admission that one is powerless over alcohol and drugs,
that it is making our life unbearable,
that changes this entire energy field
and re-empowers the person now
and puts them in a position of recovery.
What kind of view of the world takes place
from this energy field of courage
when you start telling the truth?
You begin to see this as a world of opportunity.
You see it as a world of challenge,
a very exciting world
in which to grow and experience one's growth.
What kind of a view of God comes about now?
These were all below the line of truth.
If we tested them all with kinesiology,
we find that you go weak.
All of them are denials of the truth.
Out of this energy field,
what kind of view of God opens up
is the open mind.
For the first time, the person really tells the truth.
The truth is that through one's own experience,
one has not really had an experience
of what there is called God within the universe.
And so, through that question mark then,
for the first time, the mind is open.
The person begins to ask the traditional questions
which have always led to the ultimate realization
of the truth of that question.
Is there a God? Is He experienced?
Can it be experienced?
Is it something I can verify within myself?
Is God something out there or within me?
How does it express itself?
How can I get to know that?
The whole spiritual exploration begins then
with the beginning of integrity,
because this is the beginning
of the first level of integrity, of empowerment.
The capacity to tell the truth,
which gives us the power,
gives us the power to face and cope and handle
and for the first time be appropriate.
Out of the energy field of courage then,
the courage to look at the facts
and admit the truth about them,
we can move to the next energy field
which is called neutral.
Now here you see the arrow now
is positively going to the right.
The energy field has jumped to two levels.
It's at 250.
And how is that level experienced?
That's experienced as being unattached.
Once you've told the truth about a thing,
you may move up to a process
in which we call released,
in which you're no longer attached to outcome.
Now what is a person like
on this energy field of neutral?
They're in a state, we would say,
it's okay either way it goes.
So the person on this energy level then would say,
well, if I get the job, it's great.
And if I don't get the job, that's okay too
because I'll just find another one.
Or if this relationship doesn't work out,
well, then I'll find another relationship.
And so there's the experience then
of the okayness of the world
and a sense of God as being
the source of freedom,
the freedom to grow and expand
and become conscious
and to begin to look into oneself
and the nature of human experience.
A God who looks favorably then
on the exploration of your own consciousness.
So neutral is unattached.
The downside of neutral would be sort of
flat and indifferent, flat and indifferent.
The upside of it, we could move in
to a state called willingness.
Willingness, which calibrates out at about 310,
then has a lot more power and energy
because for the first time intention comes in
and we have said yes.
We say yes.
A person on the neutral level is sort of like
there's no enthusiasm there, right?
If you want to go to the movie,
okay, we'll go to the movie.
If you don't want to go to the movie,
all right, we'll stay home.
There's not much positive there yet.
We've let go of the negative
and by letting go of the negative,
we've created a space for willingness to come in.
So when willingness come in, on the other hand,
now we have the beginning of enthusiasm,
the beginning of a positive energy.
We say yes, we're agreeable, we're willing.
So this willingness now takes us out of
indifference, flatness and detachment
and we begin to experience this as a friendly world.
The whole question of God and of life itself
becomes promising and hopeful
because we're now saying yes to life.
See, this person is detached from life.
This person is willing to face
and cope.
These people don't experience what life is.
They're only experiencing attitudes and belief systems
which are resisting and negative to life.
We see the energy field of the arrow
is really opposed to life,
opposed to the truth of life.
So willingness then brings us,
the next step out of willingness
is to move up to acceptance.
Acceptance calibrates at 380
and then a person there is adequate
and confident, capable.
We have the beginning of
the transformation of consciousness.
And what's bringing about
this transformation of consciousness
is that the person is beginning
to reown their own power.
All these fields from courage on down
are all conditions of victim
in which the person has sold out
the source of their power
and given it away to the world.
This is going to be extremely important
as we look at the addictions.
The giving away of one's power
to that which is outside
of oneself which brings about
this negative energy field.
The person who is moving into acceptance
now is reowning that I am the source
of happiness in my life.
These people all think that happiness
lies outside of yourself.
They think that happiness
comes about through getting.
These are all conditions of lack
in which if I get that car,
if I get that title,
if I get that job,
if I get that relationship,
if I get that degree,
if I get that money,
whatever it is,
it's always outside of oneself.
And of course in the addictions,
if I get that drug
or if I get the right dose of that drug.
The thought that the source of happiness
is outside of yourself
is what accompanies all these states
of weakness and victimhood.
The person on the level of acceptance
has through the willingness now,
the letting go of the resistance,
the willingness to begin to accept
that I am the source of happiness
in my life.
No matter where you put me,
I will recreate something
that satisfies me.
And so that person is not coming
from powerlessness or victimhood now.
That person knows that if you put them
on a desert island someplace
and you come back a year later,
you know you'll have
a coconut factory going,
you'll have a tree house
built in the tree,
you'll be teaching French
to the natives,
you'll find a native girl
who started a new family all over.
That power then to recreate
for yourself,
the person who is putting
you in prison let's say.
You know what's happening in prison?
At one hand you have suicide.
On the other hand,
you have people who have written
great prize winning novels.
People who have changed the course
of all human history,
have written these incredible
and powerful and brilliant books
while in prison.
So it isn't,
you see the power is not in the prison,
the power is in the self.
So the capacity then to use
even the prison experience
in a valuable and positive way
to create a great novel,
a great book,
a political treatise.
Some of the greatest things
ever written were written
under conditions that the person
down here would see as impossible.
The acceptance that you are the source
then makes this seem like
a harmonious world.
That you are the source
of happiness within your world.
And the view of God
that comes out of this
promising hopeful view
is of course the beginning
of the merciful God.
The God of mercy,
the God of forgiveness
as you move up into
the energy field of love.
Out of acceptance,
out of the owning of the power
of that which you are,
moving more towards truth
is the willingness now
to become truly loving
and we move up to now
a powerful energy field,
a plus 500,
the energy field of love itself.
This is where happiness begins.
Happiness when you calibrate it
begins at an energy field of 500.
So you can see why
more and more of gettingness,
which is down in here,
getting money, sex, power,
positions, etc.
does not bring happiness.
It brings pleasure,
brings momentary fulfillment.
You can see why
if 50 million won't make you happy,
why 75 won't either.
Because more millions
is only a 200 energy field experience
and happiness begins at 500.
The beginning then
of the field of love
and what kind of love
are we talking about?
We are talking about
unconditional love.
a stable energy field
which nurtures,
which supports,
out of which comes forgiveness.
Out of it also becomes
the beginning of revelation.
Revelation into the truth of life
and this is due to the fact
that within the brain
at an energy field of 500
and especially at 540,
there is the release of endorphins.
The beginning real alteration,
the correlation
on the physical level
within the brain chemistry itself.
The view of the world
coming out of this lovingness
of course is a loving world
and a God of unconditional love
and unconditional forgiveness.
It's a very important point
for us who are in the addictions
to understand this energy field
because this is the energy field
of Alcoholics Anonymous,
Narcotics Anonymous,
Overeaters Anonymous.
The 12 step groups
which are based on spiritual principles,
calibrate out at an energy field
of about 540.
540 is a critical level
because the energy field
of the level of healing
is 540.
An energy field of 540
in and of the nature of that field
is a healing field,
one which is unconditionally loving.
This represents then
a commitment, an alignment.
This forgivingness becomes automatic
because out of the revelation
this is the kind of a world
which is revealed to you.
What's revealed to you
is that what is important
is to understand
and out of that understanding
eventually move up
to levels of compassion.
The capacity to understand,
the desire to understand,
that becomes foremost in the mind
is revealed as what is important.
The person has a fractured hip,
it is not important
whether they were right or wrong.
Is it?
What's important is to fix it.
And so lovingness then
becomes a healingness
out of its intention to understand
and to heal out of its understandingness.
This is a different energy field
than the one called love by the world.
What the world calls love
is coming out of sentimentality.
It's coming out of a solar plexus
emotionalism.
So when we hear somebody say,
well I used to love Joey
but I don't love him anymore.
What they really mean
is they never loved Joey.
What they had was a sentimental attachment,
a dependency,
a back and forth control,
a lustful attachment
controlling ownership
and an emotionality
coming out of their childishness
and a feeling of loss
if that person leaves their life.
That which is truly loving
is an inner intention and a commitment
so it creates a stable energy field
which never changes.
If I decide to love you
which is my own intention
then there's nothing you can do about that.
That is a stable unchanging energy field
and we see this
and we see it in the non-judgmentalism
of the 12-step groups.
Or somebody might have come into a group
let's say who shot three people last week
and ran over some innocent people
and what do they say
when he walks into the group meeting?
They say, Joe we sure are glad to see you back.
You sure need us.
The unconditionality of that
because what's being related to now
is the person's beingness.
What's being related to is beingness
the love of the true self
of what that person really is.
Moving from the small self
with a small s
up to the large self
with a capital S.
And so the sustaining, nurturing
healing energy field
of the 12-step groups
it's crucial for us to see
that that is the energy
that the energy itself
irrespective of the personalities.
And so we
you hear in AA the saying
you know, bring the body
and you'll get it by osmosis.
Just bring the body.
Principle is about personalities.
It means that the healing field itself
is what nurtures and supports
and brings about the miracle of recovery.
We see the importance then of that alignment
with that energy field
because characteristic of AA
is a feeling of gratitude.
Gratitude which is at about 540
the value of laughter, of humor.
And humor is about 550
the capacity to come from
a different way of holding our experience
instead of self-pity, instead of fear
instead of anger
in its expression as resentment
we now hold as humor as that
which at the time perhaps was tragic.
Because of this willingness then
to be forgiving, to be understanding
out of this healing nature of the energy field
we move up to joyful states
characterized here as compassion.
That desire to heal through understanding
the desire to understand
which brings about the healing
the beginning of transfiguration
in one's consciousness
the beginning of seeing the perfection of the world
experiencing the oneness of all things
the oneness of all life.
As we move up then to 560
which we don't have written on the board
we have an energy field called ecstasy
not the jumping up and down
kind of emotionalism
but an inner experience of extreme serenity
we move into states
which generically I call bliss.
These blissful states
and these blissful states
of feelings of expansive well-being
of being at one with everything
a feeling of generous lovingness and forgiveness
a feeling of inner extreme pleasure.
This blissful state is important
in the understanding of the addictions
because this experience is the most
addictive of all human experiences
addictive in a generic sense
not in the terms of the addictions
but that the experience
of what is possible within oneself
the experience let us say
that comes out of meditation
a person studies a meditative technique
and now suddenly they go into an expansive state
of infinite oneness and bliss
a state called samadhi.
From this experience of samadhi
the person now is aware of what is possible
and then comes into the mind
a desire to return to that state.
The knowingness now of what is possible
creates the desire to return to that
and the person's life usually changes
to a considerable degree
once that has been experienced
and many people will leave their lifestyle
and shift to a totally different lifestyle
directed towards spiritual purification
the removal of all that has obstructed
the experiencing of this state.
People who have had near death experiences
and there are many books on that now
near death experiences
where they are declared dead on the operating table
the movie Revelation
which is about such a person
very clinically accurate
the experiencing of that infinite state
of blissfulness
and subsequent to that
the dramatic change in the person's lifestyle
coming out of that experience now
with a different knowingness
a different orientation
a different context.
The movie Lost Horizon
which has always been one of my favorites
depicts extremely well the same thing
as you remember Ronald Coleman in the original version
when he falls into Shangri-La
a state of unconditional lovingness
a state which recalibrates
around a little over 600
and he experiences this
state of consciousness
and then when he tries to return
to the ordinary world
he returns to a world which
recalibrates around 200
the world of successful doing this
and getting this
he cannot find any satisfaction
in this world anymore
compared to what he has experienced
and so there was then
the desire to return
to that state of consciousness
that energy field
which in the movie is depicted as a place
but which we know is actually
experienced within consciousness
the desire at any cost
to return to that inner state of consciousness
we have to look then at where
all human experience occurs
as we said
the body is unable to experience itself
it's only experienced in mind
it is the mind that is experiencing the body
mind itself
is experienced by consciousness itself
otherwise you would not be aware
of what is going on within mind
and so experience is taking place then
within an energy field of consciousness
and it is this inner experience
within consciousness
of a blissful state
to which people become addicted
who have never taken drugs
now what happens then
in the drug experience
this energy field
the energy field of life itself
like the sun is always shining
these energy fields here
we could say are like the clouds
and the clouds block off the experience
of that which is
which is ever shining
and what a drug does then
is it blocks off our experience
of these lower energy fields
and allows us to experience
the presence of a higher energy field
within us
if we could block off
all these energy fields
let's say
up to the level of 560
which is the level of ecstasy
if we could find some way
of blocking off all the clouds
blocking off all these energy fields
up to 560
what would we experience
we would experience what's left
and that is
an energy field of ecstasy
and isn't there such a designer drug
and yes indeed
there is one
called ecstasy
designed specifically
to block off the experience
of all these energy fields
other than 560 or over
and so what's happened then
with the drug experience
is that pharmacologically
something has blocked off
this lower energy field
and allowed us to experience
something of a higher energy field
so the person coming home
full of fears and griefs
and regrets and anxieties
stops in for two martinis
and now suddenly
they jump all these energy fields
and they move up to an energy field
at about 500
what I call mellow
mellow
mellow is that field
where you sort of love everybody
you're willing to forgive everybody
you're generous
easy going
and all the kids love you
when you're in that state
you bring home toys for the children
and flowers for the wife
that's the energy state
500 and over
that is sought in the drug experience
the blocking off of that
which is below that
and allowing the person to experience
that energy field
so we said these are
addicting experiences
because the mind
once having experienced it
wishes to return
and so we asked the person
who's ever had an addictive problem
a person who has an alcohol
or addictive problem
to look at what it is
that they are seeking
look at what is the experience
to which they are habituated
to which they return
over and over again
no matter what the price
and we see
that as an inner state
as an inner state of consciousness itself
that in reality
they don't even care about the drug
the drug was only
the mechanics
it was the way of accessing
the only way that they knew at the time
a certain way of experiencing
their being
their existence
a pleasurable
highly energized state
and this is what was sought
and if a drug does not block off
these lower energy fields
and allow you to experience
that inner state of blissfulness
then it is no longer used
and it is not called an addicting drug
you see many of the psychological explanations
of addiction
try to present it as though
it is a running away
from these lower experiences
the person is running away from fear
or the person is running away from depression
well we have some excellent drugs
that will handle that
Thorazine for instance
will knock out your anxiety
for a couple of weeks maybe
you won't feel nervous
until the 4th of July
and yet nobody calls me up
and asks for refills
and the same with antidepressants
an antidepressant will move you out
of the depression
but nobody calls up
and says that their prescription
for the antidepressant
is filled on the toilet
like they would with Percodan
so the alleviation of the depression then
or the alleviation of the anxiety
or the fear
or the anger
which is well handled
pharmacologically by traditional medical drugs
are not good
they are not considered
to be addictive substances
why?
because they do not block off
these energy fuels high enough
for you to experience this higher state
so now we can see
what the person is addicted to
the person is addicted
to that energy fuel within
to that state of consciousness
the desire to return to that
and the price they are willing to pay
is all of it
because what the mind begins to demand
is a return to that experience
no matter what the price
and the willingness to pay the price
increases with time
so that in the end
finally it will ask for the body itself
it will say
if you keep on drinking like that
you are going to be dead
within weeks or months
and you know what the person does about that
they go across the street to the bartender
their old pal Joe
they order a martini
and they say
guess what the doctor told me today
at that point the bartender orders them a drink
for all good times
and they kiss the body goodbye
the willingness to let all of it go
and therefore we see the price that people
are willing to pay
for the so called addiction
to this state of consciousness
it mystifies people
who have not accessed that level of consciousness
in their drug experience
why are these people willing to sacrifice
all of it
they are willing to sacrifice
to return to this energy field
that energy fuel we call bliss
now let's remind ourselves that we see
the same thing going on with people
who have never taken a drug
who by virtue of their destiny
or previous spiritual work whatever
have fallen into the energy fuels
of these higher experiences
and we see them do the same thing
the willingness to give up power and money
and position and titles in the world
to devote all of their time and energy
to the returning
to this state of consciousness
and therefore that movie
you know
Lost Horizon
really tells us the whole story of addiction
the willingness to sacrifice all of it
for a certain state of consciousness
as though there is an innate inner
awareness
of what is really true
and there is this false start
to experience what is true
false start because it doesn't work
so the reason for the giving up of the addiction
the giving up of the alcohol and drugs
is not because it's wrong
not because it's wrong
but because it doesn't work
it doesn't work
because as you move from here
up to here what happens is you bring about
as we all know the progressive
loss of inner self-respect
because of the reversities and negativities
of these energy fuels the beginning
of the experience of
negative experiences in one's life
the beginning of the loss of relationships
the loss of credit cards
loss of status
loss of physical health
the loss of the function of the body organs
we see the progressive downhill course
brought about by the denial of the truth
and what is the denial of the truth
that is going on here
the denial of the truth as we said
everything from this level on down
is due to putting the power
outside of yourself
and so we see what's happened in
in the addiction
is that the person has given this source
which these people here accept
the source of their happiness
the source of meaning in their life
have projected it into the outer world
and given that power to the drug
they've given the power
to some substance outside of themselves
the drug in and of itself
has no power at all
to create these higher experiences
we've tested this out in research
for several years
with literally hundreds of people
and in the classes we've been giving
for instance
people who are fighting
and right in the middle of
handling their addictive problem
we've tested with kinesiology
the proposition
the drug has the power
to create this higher experience
and universally
100% of the people go weak
with that proposition
proving that it is a lie
the drug has no power whatsoever
and then we present them
with an opposite concept
and we have everybody in the class
hold in mind its opposite thought
that the drug blocks off
the energy fields that
are coming from that which I am not
and allow me to experience the joyfulness
of that which is my real self
and instantly everybody in the class
goes strong
indicating that it is the truth
so the truth is
the drug has no power
to create these experiences whatsoever
it has the pharmacologic capacity
to block off these negative energy fields
and allow you to at least
get into the ballpark
it isn't the real state of bliss of course
of the person who has earned it
through their own progressive spiritual work
but at least in the ballpark
of what that experience is like
to feel that energy
which is closest to
the truth of one's own being
can we utilize
this knowledge now
in understanding the recovery from addictions
when the person comes in with an addiction
they are usually at the bottom of the box
full of self-hatred, hopelessness, despair
regret, despondency
and we see that the energy field down here
of apathy, of hopelessness and despair
is one in which the person cannot help themself
and hopeless means just that
and a friend of mine
who was president of the county bar association
literally died of starvation
alone in a rooming house
addicted to a combination of valium and alcohol
never even picked up the phone
to call anybody
literally died of starvation
a person of that caliber
with thousands of friends
all of whom would have dropped anything
to come and help him
hopeless means just that means that
there is no point in making the phone call
because there is no hope
out of that hopelessness about one's condition
which often expresses itself as
my case is different
meaning you may well recover from this
but my case is hopeless
out of this apathy, this hopelessness
in which God is dead
what can we do for the person
because the process over here in consciousness
is one of loss of energy
the person is de-energized
the woman who is rocking back and forth
in her rocking chair
staring out the window blankly
all we can do is pour energy into that person
reason doesn't have any effect
we saw that when the telegram
from the state department came
and said it was a mistake
that her energy field didn't change
she kept right on rocking back and forth
and staring out the window
so the answer is to pour energy
into that person
by our concern
by our lovingness
by our physical presence
through nutrition
in every possible way
we pour energy into that person
and get them up to the next energy field
called grief
grief
grief has to do with the past
and next what the person will experience
when they come out of the shock
they come in a blank shock like state
is they will begin to cry
begin to regret
the loss that all this addiction has cost them
regret
feeling self-pity
sorrow for the fact that they are
in a rehabilitation place
or they are in the space they are in life
they are very sad about life
sad about their addiction
they feel completely neglected by God
and so there is this spirited state
spirit being that willingness
the aliveness
the energy field of life itself
so this regret about the past
we move the person's energy field up
and we move them up
to the next energy field
which is one of fear
at this point the person begins to fear the addiction
worry and anxiety
fear has to do with the future
they are no longer in the inflated state of denial
on the contrary they are deflated
the world looks frightening
and they perhaps feel that God is punishing them
for their past sins
so they are misinterpreting the addiction now
as a punishment
and they are fearing a punishment
of more punishment
and further loss in the future
but the energy of each thing can move up
to the energy of the next
and so we move the person out of the fear of the addiction
into the desiring for something better
desiring something other than being victim
the wanting this
the craving this
the wanting to move into something better for yourself
and move them up to anger
anger as we said has a lot of useful energy in it
not the form of anger
not the form of anger itself
but the energy of anger
in which the person then becomes angry
over their predicament in life
angry over being victim
this anger then
we saw that we see it used in society
in a constructive way
we saw the way we see the way minority groups
get angry over the injustices
of their social position
and use the energy of that anger
to mobilize social forces
and move up to pride
in doing something about it
to take action
to begin to move up into
caring for oneself
caring for one's position
and moving up to the next energy field of courage
courage is crucial in the addiction
the courage to tell the truth
and so we see the powerful effect then
that the first step has
the admission that we're powerless over alcohol or drugs
now allows us to face
cope, handle
and be appropriate
we become re-empowered
we now see the world
as an opportunity
and for the first time we have an open mind
truth has a way
to enter our mind
so we move the person
we utilize the pride
to move the person up in the courage
and to look at the facts
and in looking at the facts
encouraging them to move up to the next position
which is letting go, resisting the facts
to be released from that resistance
so they can begin to view the world as an okay place
and begin to utilize and experience their own freedom
freedom to explore, to expand
and move them up to the willingness then
to say yes in this exploration
to join it, to agree, to align with it
and they join their intention
so they begin to see
the whole rehabilitative process
and the world in which it is happening
as friendly
they begin to see Alcoholics Anonymous, let's say
as promising and hopeful
that perhaps they will recover
and move them up into acceptance then
a very powerful energy field
where you are beginning to see
that you have the power to make these decisions
the confidence, the feeling of adequacy
the transformation that comes about
and now the experiencing that the world is harmonious
it is on the one hand presented you with a problem
on the other hand it is harmonious
in that it also provides you with the answer
that which is a merciful God provides you with solutions
so although you may have an addiction
you find that there are hundreds of thousands of people around
who have found the answers
who are only too willing to help you with this
and now the world begins to look
friendly, harmonious, merciful, helpful, hopeful
and with acceptance and the letting go of the resistance
and the letting go of denial
we move into an energy field of lovingness
where the person then commits themself
to an energy field which is healing
by joining one of the 12 step groups
the person's willingness to align with it
their willingness to accept it
so through that willingness then comes acceptance
and the acceptance of the truth about this
is that we need to be in an energy field
which is nurturing, supportive and understanding
which is unconditionally loving
move the person into that energy field then
and we know that they are in a safe space
to remain aligned with that then
is to ensure one's survival
and with that experience comes the joyfulness
the beginning of the experience of an inner serenity
the beginning to see the perfection and the oneness
of the energy field which you are now part and parcel of
was the willingness to tell the truth
moving us up through this very critical level
the first step, our willingness to admit
that we were powerless over alcohol and drugs
that was making our life unmanageable
the second step then becomes very significant
it says in all of the 12 step groups
the second step was the restoring us to sanity
by some power greater than ourself
which is the intuitive understanding of the ego
of the small self
that it will take something with much greater power
than its smallness to handle this problem
we look at bliss and we see that the energy field of that
starting at about 500 and running all the way up to 600
is like a powerful electromagnet pulling one
back into wanting to re-experience
that experience in consciousness
and therefore to handle it something of an equal dimension
of an equal dimension will be needed to handle it
so the second step is really the intuitive knowing of that
that something greater than the ego
the limited small self
is going to be needed to handle the attraction
of such a powerful energy field
the third step then is the decision that comes out of that
the surrendering
and the third step is one of surrender
turning the willingness
the willingness to turn one's life
over to God as one understands him
and out of willingness
just out of willingness itself
you see
that the God of alcoholics
the God of one's own understanding
is already a friendly, promising and hopeful God
using the example of the people
that one sees who have done this
the beginning willingness to be trusting
the beginning elements of faith
and so the third step then
the step of deep surrender
really moves one into this alignment
this energy field of 500 and over
the rest of the steps now make sense
of course from the viewpoint of consciousness itself
as we've looked at it
the fourth step says
that we looked within the box
to find out
what was in the box
in our own particular case
took a fearless moral inventory
the willingness to look at all that was negative in our life
our willingness to own that
and then in the fifth step
a very healing step
admit to ourself, to God
and to another human being
the exact nature of that which we discovered within the box
by doing that
we change the energy field of it
we take the charge off of it
we take the negativity off of it
so that now the same event
although it hasn't changed in history
the way we are holding it has changed
so that which had the capacity to corrode
and destroy us before
is now rendered inoperative
see Bill Wilson used to say
that the correct attitude about the past
is a decent regret
a decent regret
one may regret it
but that's quite a bit different
than self-hatred leading to self-destruction
instead one comes from the heart
Bill used to say
AA is the language of the heart
and from the heart
with its humor
with its lightness
to look at the past
and the willingness to heal it
the healing then comes out of the step five
and then it's expressed in steps six through nine
which are really
the reparative steps
those are steps in which
the person takes responsibility
to actually do something in the world
to repair any damage that is repairable
to mend whatever fences can be mended
so that it's not just a mental intellectual exercise
so that it becomes real
and relieves all the guilt
about what one has done in the past
to one's best ability
one goes back into the world
and tries to repair
the damages that have been done
to the degree that they're repairable
step ten then
says that this way of life
of taking responsibility
for the content of our own consciousness
the willingness to clean it up
that this became our way of life
and we began to do this on a daily basis
on a daily basis
we looked within the box
to see what had gone wrong
what was out
what was lacking in integrity
where could we have done better
where could we have been more loving
so the owning then of the process
of spiritual progress
our commitment to that as a way of life
is step ten
step eleven is interesting then
because it says
what it says is if we do steps one through ten
if we make that our lifestyle
that we will reconnect with something
that we sought in the first place
through drugs and alcohol
it says sought through prayer and meditation
to increase our conscious contact with God
as we understood
asking only for his will for us
and the power to carry it out
see loving doesn't say
we began
it said it already happened
it said that when we committed ourselves to loving this
as a lifestyle
we reconnected
we began to reconnect through the heart
because that which is divine
that which is God
and that which is love
are all the same thing are they not
as we committed to loving this
as our style and way of being in the world
to the best of our ability
we began to reconnect with some
rock like inner experience
which was similar to that which we sought in the first place
then step twelve gives away
what the whole addictive process is about
what its whole nature is in the field of consciousness
step twelve says
having become conscious
as a result of this total experience
the language of the twelfth step is
having had a spiritual awakening
having become conscious
as a result of the entire addictive experience
we carried this message to others
and expressed it in our entire life
so the twelfth step tells us then
what the whole purpose of the addictive process was
it was to awaken us
it was to move us
from one level of consciousness
to another
from being asleep and unaware
to being awake and conscious
and aware and responsible
from being unconscious and irresponsible
from being helpless victim
to owning ourselves as the source
and being responsible
for the happiness within our life
to stop putting it out there
to stop saying that the source of happiness
is outside of myself
to realize that the source of my happiness
is the same as the source of my life
to own myself irresponsibly
as a spiritually aware person
so now we have a different context
in which the whole addictive process
a movement of advancing and increasing
consciousness and awareness
so that alcoholism and drugs then
require that a person become more awake
in order to survive
and here we have a disease that is
progressively fatal
and that the only way to recover from the illness
is to become progressively spiritually aware
progressively more conscious
so that life itself
depends on becoming conscious
a major self confrontation
something that our higher self
has picked for us
that will force us to grow
because there's no turning back
there's no reprogramming the brain cells
once they're programmed
there's not enough room on the tightrope
to turn around and change one's mind
and once one is into the addictive
alcoholic process
there is no turning back
there is only the confront
with owning the truth about oneself
and total recovery depends on
accepting that process
moving joyfully into it
being grateful
and so you hear now
and you understand why
you hear speakers at meetings of AA for instance say
that they're grateful they're an alcoholic
to the newcomer this sounds indeed like madness
grateful?
how could one be grateful?
because they're coming from self hatred
and guilt about this thing
how could one be grateful?
how could one be grateful
that one has become addicted or an alcoholic
because that forced us to grow
it forced us to become conscious
it forced us to become aware
we become grateful to the process
at first resenting it
at first resisting it
then actually accepting it
then agreeing with it
then beginning to love
then experiencing joy
and then achieving that state called serenity
the inner knowingness
that this was your destiny
this was your way of doing it
this is the way that you chose
it's okay
it's wonderful
it's sort of an awareness
that you never could have reached this understanding
any other way
some people just have to experience it this way
for those who did
great gratitude comes about
and a greater understanding of the nature of consciousness itself