Hello, I'm Dr. David R. Hawkins. I'm a physician, psychiatrist, psychoanalyst, nutritionist.
I've been doing research in the nature of consciousness itself and levels of awareness that the world calls spiritual.
Out of this, plus my 35 years of clinical experience, as well as my own personal experience,
we've derived knowledge that can be extremely useful in alleviating human suffering in all its forms,
many of which I've lived through in my own personal life,
and I've been forced to find answers that are outside the field of traditional medicine.
For today, we need to know a little bit more about the nature of consciousness itself.
We need to talk about body, mind, spirit.
Holistic Health has used this, body, mind, and spirit.
Is it just a catchphrase? Is it just a slogan?
What does it really mean, body, mind, and spirit?
What is spirit?
Anyway, is that a metaphysical abstraction?
Is that a religious dictum?
Is it a fantasy of people who are not too well connected with the real world?
Just exactly what is this relationship?
Because it will help us and speed up our work with a greater understanding.
To begin with, then, we want to describe how human experience comes about
and sort of look within ourself to see where this fantasy,
this phenomena, actually occurs.
So we want to look at this relationship now between body, mind, and spirit
from the viewpoint of experience.
So we'll say some things that sound somewhat startling,
such as, to begin with, the fact that the body cannot experience itself.
Now, that's a startling thought because all of us tend to think of ourselves as being the body.
We tend to think, I am the body.
We'll quickly see, as we go along, that the body cannot experience itself.
And if we look at it, that this is not so.
The body itself is unable to experience itself.
For instance, my arm cannot experience its own armness.
My left arm cannot experience my left armness.
What is actually going on are sensations coming from the body.
So we're not experiencing the body anyway.
We're experiencing the sensations of the body.
And these sensations of the body
curiously enough cannot experience themselves either.
The sensations coming from the arm have to be experienced somewhere.
And where are they being experienced?
They're being experienced in mind.
If we do an incision in the brain, for instance,
and delete part of the operating mind,
at least the way it operates on the physical plane,
we fail to experience the opposite side of the body.
This is common, for instance, after strokes, let's say,
where the patient is unable to experience in mind
even the existence of a portion of their body.
So the body cannot be experienced without the sensation.
The sensation can only be experienced in mind.
Interestingly enough, mind itself cannot experience itself.
A thought cannot experience its own thoughtness.
A memory cannot experience its own memoryness.
A fantasy doesn't experience its own fantasiness.
That which goes on in mind actually has to be experienced
in an energy field which is greater than mind itself.
And this energy field we call consciousness.
It is because of consciousness that you are aware
of what goes on within mind.
This is obviously so,
because it's the very basic reason for anesthesia.
When with anesthesia we delete consciousness,
then there is no awareness of what is going on in mind.
No consciousness, no awareness of mind or body.
No mind, no awareness of sensations or body.
Consequently, you will notice by some introspection
and watching yourself as you go throughout the day
that all of your experience is being experienced
in a more general way than you had realized
in a more general field of experience,
which is almost diffuse.
It's almost as though it's everywhere in space.
And this is within consciousness itself.
It's an interesting little experiment
to find out where you think you really experience a thought.
If I ask you, where do you think you experience a thought,
you will say, in here.
That, you see, is the thought about a thought.
You think that you experience a thought there.
But if I ask you now to let go of any belief about that,
any belief of where you think you are experiencing a thought,
and instead ask you to point to exactly
where a thought is being experienced actually,
the radical truth of where is the phenomena occurring,
you will find that it is in no particular place.
Thoughtness is occurring.
All you can say is that thoughtness is occurring,
and that you have an awareness of the thoughtness,
but you are hard put to exactly put your finger on it
where it could possibly be.
No particular place is where it is being experienced
in sort of a general overall way.
It is very necessary for us to know this
because some of the techniques we will be using
will be ones that cancel a lot of these belief systems
that are at the very basis of human suffering.
Consciousness itself, then, is like a movie screen
upon which that which is changing is experienced.
If you notice, if you look at it,
you will see that all experience is experience of change.
It is the coming and going, the waning and ebbing,
the flux, the movement that you are experiencing.
The reason we can experience that which changes
is because it is being experienced
from a background of that which in itself is unchanging.
It is because the movie screen is standing still
that we can see the movement of the movie.
So what is experienced, then, is change,
and where it is experienced is consciousness itself,
which has no exact location.
We are going to be talking about fear
as a level of consciousness,
to be addressed where it is,
not in its expression and its extension into the world,
fear of this, fear of that,
not trying to handle it on the level of the particular,
but handling it as a level of consciousness,
becoming aware of that which we are,
which is greater than the fear,
learning to disidentify with the emotion,
so that I am not that,
I am that in which that is being experienced.
It becomes a small thing,
a phenomenon going on with that greater experience
which I experience as myself,
that which I really am.
So we are going to be talking about
the letting go of fear and the techniques.
One of the biggest obstacles to fear,
the difficulty in handling it,
is the fear of fear itself.
And so we will be describing a technique
which disappears the fear of fear.
Once you are no longer afraid of fear,
it becomes a very simple matter.
What is it about fear?
It is your fear of it, is it not?
The person is afraid of the fear,
afraid of the fear,
just as the person going to the dentist
is afraid of the pain, you see?
So it is that initial fear,
and when we begin to look at the nature of fear,
we can see that the number of fears are endless.
The number of fears are endless,
and therefore people become victim,
they become convinced
that the source of fear is outside of themselves.
If you think the source of fear is outside of yourself,
there is frankly very little you can do about it.
In fact, there is really nothing you can do about it.
What you can do is try and jump at this time,
but because the source is always outside of yourself,
you will always be the victim of fear
until you begin to realize
that it is the pre-set conditions within you,
that you are the source of the fear,
which you then project onto the world,
and of course you are sure that you see it out there
because you just projected it out there.
When we look at fear,
we see how all-pervasive it can be.
If you realize that fear is a level of consciousness,
then you realize that from that level of consciousness,
fear can be attached to everything.
Trying to overcome particular fears
may have a certain limited value,
but it doesn't change you as a fearful person.
It doesn't change you as a fearful personality.
It doesn't change you as a fearful human being.
The fear of a specific fear may be clinically valuable.
It may be practically useful in your life,
but it doesn't alter who you are.
Today we are going to be looking more at who you are,
how the conditions of this can be changed,
so that you never more feel like a small self
who is powerless
and at the effect of the victimhood of fear itself.
You see, fear can be like a prefix
which gets attached to anything.
If you are in an energy field,
and we are going to be talking today about energy fields,
we are going to be talking about this map of consciousness,
which we have on the blackboard,
and which we have been using throughout this series.
Throughout the series we have been talking about
levels of consciousness here,
and you will see fear right about here.
We are going to be talking about fear as a level of consciousness.
That this level of consciousness here,
these are the lower levels of consciousness,
these are the higher ones.
We are going to be talking about fear.
We see that it is a negative emotion
by the direction of the arrow.
We see its relative power,
because this is a mathematical model.
In the mathematical model,
we have been able to calibrate the relative energies
of these different fields.
You see, starting from 30, 50, 75.
As we go up from the negative emotions
into the positive emotions,
we see that their actual power,
from the viewpoint of physics,
actually increases.
So we are going to be dealing today with this fear.
A negative energy field,
which calibrates on a relative scale,
where death would be zero
and enlightenment would be 600,
love would be 500,
we see that fear comes out at 100.
We are going to be talking about this energy field then,
and you begin to realize that
being fearful then can attach to anything
and everything in your life.
There is nothing in your total experience
as a human being
to which fear cannot be attached.
You love your mother,
up comes the fear,
what if you lose her?
You love your body,
up comes the fear of death, sickness.
You love money,
up comes the fear of loss,
or of being accused of being greedy.
No matter what you think of,
fear can be attached to it.
You love your automobile,
up comes the fear of an accident.
A fearful person then attaches the fear to everything.
So everything that comes into the mind
is coming into an energy field of fear,
and therefore gets colored with fear.
A fear of life itself.
And as the song goes,
afraid of living and afraid of dying.
Afraid of living and afraid of dying.
In other words,
this energy field has now contaminated everything.
So if I am the source of that energy field then,
all of my experience comes into the field of fear,
and everything in my life becomes fearful.
The future is fearful.
Old age, getting older.
What's going to happen to the body?
What's going to happen to my finances?
What's going to happen to my relationships?
What's going to happen to my family?
What's going to happen to my car?
What's going to happen to my bank account?
What's going to happen to my country?
What's going to happen to the world?
And so people who get into a global fear
will tell you about the fears of nuclear annihilation,
the endless fears of intergalactic wars.
You see, the expansion of the fear
doesn't change the fact that it is still just fear.
Glamorizing it, making it sound dramatic,
doesn't change that it's just fear.
The fear of intergalactic war and human demolition
and the expiration of the human race
is no different than the fear of the child,
the child's fear of the dark,
his fear that a dog might bite him.
What's characteristic of all of it
is an energy field called fear.
Fear of what is really immaterial.
And we're going to have to learn to look away from the thoughts
and look instead to the feeling.
Look below the feeling to the energy field
out of which this feeling is coming
and learn how to handle this energy field.
When we do this, we lose our fear of fear.
And as we lose our fear of fear,
we begin to learn how to handle fear directly.
Handling fear directly is extremely simple.
It is an extremely simple thing to handle
once we're familiar with some rather simple techniques.
Because the world pretty much runs you with fear,
does it not?
Because your life is pretty much run by fear.
Once you've learned a way to not get cornered by fear,
you're beginning to transcend the world.
You're beginning to transcend being victim.
Because really, what can the world do in its threat?
How can the world threaten you except through fear?
To cut off your bank account,
to get audited,
to run away from you,
to leave you,
to fire you.
The gun at your head is always the same gun.
It's always the gun of fear.
The fear of losing a part of your body.
The endless fears, you see.
There's no end to the number of fears.
But there is an end to fearfulness.
There is an end to being victim of fear.
There is an end to being afraid of fear.
We'll learn today how to lose our fear of fear,
how to enjoy the process,
how to really start feeling good about yourself,
when you realize that you are no longer the small victim,
the worm,
who is at the effect of this all-pervasive fearfulness.
So it's not fear but this energy field of fearfulness.
And we begin to see that we are in control of it.
We are the source of it.
See, I'm the source of my fearfulness.
Now we all know, in a different mood,
the same thing is no longer fearful.
It's not so.
It's not a thing that you're afraid of.
You say, I am afraid of that.
But when you're accompanied by somebody else,
when you're in a different mood,
when you're in a humorous mood
and having a good time laughing,
now that thing no longer engenders fear.
So the source of fear is not in the world.
There is no way of overcoming one's fear of the world.
There is no way the world can be controlled
to overcome your fears.
And society's endless efforts
to end your fears by changing society,
by changing the laws,
by changing the rules,
will not end the fear
because fearfulness is within you.
One is the event itself
and secondly, how you feel about that.
So having more police might make you feel better,
but in fact, where are the police going to be
while your apartment is being robbed?
At the other end of town, naturally.
So therefore, our handling the fear
is really up to ourself.
It comes out of our willingness
to own that we are the source of that fear.
That fear is occurring within our own consciousness
and therefore we want to address it
where it is actually being experienced.
Most people experience fear
in a sort of a physical way.
So that the first thing we want to do
about a fearful experience
is to eliminate paying any attention to thoughts.
The reason is that a fearful feeling
will engender literally millions of thoughts.
There is no end to fearful thoughts
because they are coming out of an energy field
of fear itself,
which generates an endless series of thoughts.
Clinically speaking,
handling the specific thoughts themselves
has a limited value
and that fearfulness
merely generates more thoughts later on.
So we want a technique that will handle fear itself.
You might just picture something
fearful in your life,
something fearful that you expect may happen
or which has happened,
or you can just fantasy a fearful experience
such as being tied to the railroad track
and a locomotive is bearing down on you.
When you look at what is being experienced
you'll see when you look past the thoughts
that it's being experienced first of all in the body.
What you'll notice is
maybe a tenseness in the stomach muscles,
a queasy feeling in the stomach.
A shakiness in the arms and the legs
or a dryness in the mouth.
Some people have cramps,
intestinal cramps or intestinal phenomena.
Whatever it is in your own case
you look within yourself
to see what is actually being experienced.
See radical truth means
what's being experienced actually
not what you are thinking about it,
not the thoughts about it,
the concepts that you're projecting onto it.
You're projecting onto the experience.
Not the labeling,
the putting of a word on it,
but what are you literally experiencing
within yourself.
The technique then is to let go resisting
the experiencing
of what is literally being experienced.
Let go resisting the dryness in the mouth.
Let it be there.
Welcome it.
Let go resisting
the flip-flop feeling in the stomach.
Let go resisting the trembling
in your arms and legs.
When you do this you're focused you see
away from thoughts
onto what is being experienced
and you let go,
fully let go,
surrender to
being with those sensations.
The letting go then is like
the willow tree in the wind.
Coming from
the Taoism of China let us say,
the ancient wisdom of China
which states that the oak tree
which resists the wind
is susceptible to breaking
and the willow tree
which bends with the wind survives.
And so like the willow tree
we bend with the incoming experience.
We let it be.
We blend with it.
We welcome it.
We say let's have more of it.
As you do that you'll discover
much to your surprise
that there is a limited amount
of that sensation.
It's as though
the amount of fear that we have
is limited in quantity.
How can this be?
It's as though
this fear is like a pressure tank.
All the suppressed fear
that we've had
throughout our lifetime,
starting in our childhood,
all that fear that we couldn't
allow ourselves to experience,
couldn't allow ourselves to express,
weren't allowed to express,
weren't allowed to have that emotion.
To the man let's say
in the service,
he wasn't allowed to express
that fearfulness.
It was thought to be unmanly,
maybe cowardice.
And so that fear gets suppressed.
It gets repressed.
It gets pushed down out of awareness.
Fears have come up by the thousands
in our lifetime
of which we were even unaware.
You see the fear comes up
and unwittingly you brace your back.
That fear just got pushed out of awareness.
Or you drum your fingers on the desk.
What's happening is the fear
is so quickly suppressed
that you don't even realize
that it was there.
As the years go by,
the accumulated energy of this fear,
the energy is what we're talking about.
The energy behind this fear
increases in pressure
and when it reaches a certain point,
as though you reached a red line
on the needle of the dial,
what happens is this pressure now
of this fearfulness
begins to express itself.
It spills out, spills over
into our experience
and begins to color it.
If we don't examine it,
we think that this fear
is coming from the world.
We blame the world for it.
We think that there is a fearful experience
happening out there.
Little do we realize
that it is merely our own fearfulness
being projected out into the world.
So we own that this source of the fear then
is our own accumulated fearfulness.
And we start to welcome
and look forward to the opportunities
to allow this fearfulness
to run.
Now, the sensations
and the inner experience of fear itself
remains the same
no matter what we think we're afraid of.
If somebody holds a shotgun
to your heart and says,
give me all your money,
what are you going to experience?
You're going to experience dry mouth,
weakness in the knees,
and that old familiar flippy-foppy feeling
in the stomach.
If an enemy tank rolls up to you,
knocks it over,
and they rotate the barrel of the gun
and put it right at your forehead,
what are you going to experience?
You're going to experience
exactly the same thing.
The same thing if somebody
holds a mouse over your head.
You're going to experience
a dryness in your mouth,
a queasiness in your stomach,
cramps in the intestine,
and that jiggly feeling in your muscles.
All that you ever have to handle
is those sensations.
See, with this fearfulness,
see, with experiencing this technique,
you'll learn that all you ever have to handle
is what you're experiencing
within consciousness itself.
Whether it's localized within the body,
or whether more sophisticated
after you've meditated
and worked with this technique,
you'll notice that this experience
is happening in a general and diffused
sort of everywhere-ness.
The phenomena of the queasy muscles,
the flip-flop in the stomach,
the dry mouth,
is being experienced
in sort of a vague,
diffuse everywhere-ness,
and you just let go resisting that.
You just allow the experience
to be there without resisting it.
Because you're focused on that,
the fear begins to diminish.
For one thing,
you're no longer paying attention
to the thoughts.
You see, the thoughts themselves
are engendering further fear.
If you're very busy with this technique,
just letting go, resisting the fear,
you're now focused
on the energy field itself.
Behind this fearfulness
is an energy.
And what you're doing
is letting go the resisting
of the releasing,
progressive releasing
and discharge of this energy.
By doing this,
you lose your fear of fear.
Fear is no longer an awesome terror
that awakens you in the middle of the night.
It's nothing but
an inner emotional experience.
The sensations of which
can be easily handled.
Ask yourself, truly,
can you handle a dry mouth?
Of course you can.
Doing research and experimenting
with this particular technique,
I had an experience
that I want to share with you
because it demonstrates
one of the principles
that we are describing.
I had had a lifetime fear of heights.
So severe, for instance,
that when I went to visit
the Grand Canyon for the first time,
I literally couldn't get
within 100 feet of the edge.
And it created that panicky feeling
when I even saw somebody else
get near the edge.
I was using this technique
whenever I could
and enjoying the progress
I was making with it.
And I just somehow never got around
to working on my fear of heights.
But I was working on fear
from all its other origins
within my experience.
And the next time I went back
to the Grand Canyon
was about a year and a half
or two years later.
And much to my amazement,
I could walk up within
about 20 feet of the edge
before this tight feeling
occurred in the stomach again.
And I continued to utilize this technique
over the next year or two.
And again, about two years later,
I went back there
with some members of my family
to revisit the canyon.
And much to my surprise,
I could walk right up
to the very edge.
In fact, I could dangle
my feet over the edge.
I couldn't say I was happy about it,
but I did it the impossible.
I was really so pleased.
But what it demonstrated
was the principle
that what I had been releasing
was that accumulated pressure,
the accumulated energy
of all that fear from a lifetime.
And like a pressure tank,
as it released itself,
now there was less and less
to spill over into life's experiences.
The letting go then of resisting
is so effective.
And why is it effective?
Because we see that resistance
traps us into a certain
state of consciousness.
And resistance is right
in here.
It's not written on the board,
but when we calibrate it,
it is a negative energy
at about 150.
And the important thing
over here, you see,
is the important thing,
I'm sorry,
the important thing
on this line
of this energy field here
is that one is trapped by that.
One is trapped by this.
One can't get beyond it.
One becomes victim.
So one becomes the victim
of their own fears
so long as they own,
don't own that they are
the source of it.
So long as we rationalize
and try to say
that the source of the fear
is out there,
so long as we think
the source of the fear
is out there,
we cannot overcome it.
Once I begin to own
that I am the experiencer,
I am the one that sets up
the way in which
I experience things,
now I become the one
who is master of the situation.
My soul's self-esteem
becomes affected.
I am no longer the one
who is the victim
or subject to fear.
I am something else
other than the fear.
You see, fear is nothing
but an experience
in consciousness
and I don't give it reality anymore
by labeling it
and by filling in fear of what.
The what-ness I'm sure
you see by now is endless.
Fearfulness is attached
to everything in the world
by a fearful person.
Changing the world
will not handle it.
A person can be terribly afraid
in a very safe situation
and afraid not at all
in a very dangerous situation,
one which hypothetically
is dangerous.
So we have two situations,
let us say.
One is being mugged.
That's one thing.
Then we have the fear
of being mugged.
That is something else.
The fear of being mugged
is not the same as being mugged.
It is quite possible
to have very unfortunate circumstances
happen in one's life
and not experience fear at all.
In fact, to experience
that one is the witness
of the phenomena.
Such a thing happened to me
in my own life
when I walked into
a very large-sized rattlesnake
on the top of a nearby mountain.
You see?
As I went to step into this cabin,
much to my surprise,
here was a giant rattlesnake
coiled up there
and as I lifted my foot
to step on him,
his head snapped back
and his tongue blew out
and he just was ready
and poised to strike.
So in that instant,
in that instant,
there was a flash
of fearful thought,
the thought of
I could take a club and hit it,
I could run,
I could yell for help,
I didn't have a gun
but somebody might shoot it.
You know, all the
automatic self-protective thoughts
that social consciousness
has programmed us with.
Happily and luckily for me,
or I probably wouldn't be here
giving you this talk today,
I had learned this technique.
Instead, instantly I realized
that my life, frankly,
depended on my utilization
of this technique.
And so what I did instead
is I automatically
went into this exact technique.
I automatically let go,
wanting to do anything about it,
wanting to handle anything about it,
wanting to change anything about it.
Instead, I went into my inner self
and I just allowed
the inner experience
to release itself
without any resistance.
I'll tell you,
I welcomed more of it
because somehow
when you really get into the
experience of your own
inner consciousness,
you really see that your survival
really depends on this
and it has all along.
So I saw that my
survival really depended
on the excellence
with which I let go
and surrendered and released
and let go resisting the experience.
As I did,
the fearful thoughts
instantly disappeared
and I felt like a profound
state of peace
settle on the snake and myself.
It was like I became the witness,
not the witness confined
to this body,
but the witness in consciousness
which seemed to have no dimension.
And this
formless dimension
was then the experiencer
of the presence
of a state of peacefulness.
This profound state of peacefulness
was of such power
that it prevailed
over the consciousness
of both the snake
and the personality
of this person speaking to you.
And so,
the snake looked at me
interestedly,
having not seen a human being,
I don't think in his whole life,
much less a foot away.
And I looked at the rattlesnake
with great curiosity
and thought of him as brother.
The two of us were included
in the oneness of this space
of our own beingness together
in a state of extreme intimacy.
And out of it came
sort of an inner joyfulness
and I like felt
the love for the snake arise.
It arises out of the field,
you see,
once the fear is removed.
If we look at our
scale of consciousness over here
that we've been talking about,
we can track what had happened.
You see,
we track what had happened.
The fear,
which has a negative energy field,
which the snake
would have instantly picked up.
He instantly would have picked up
or instantly would have picked up anger.
My desire,
let's say,
to strike at him
and his responses
through his energy system
are so fast,
the strike would have happened
before I could have moved
my shin out of the way.
Instead,
because of the severe threat
of the circumstance
and the circumstances,
I'll tell you,
I let go.
I mean,
did I ever let go?
And I jumped right through
the willingness to let go,
right through the acceptance,
right to the love,
right to the joy,
right to a state
of profound peace.
I would say
if I calibrated
the energy field
of that experience,
it would probably come out
around 599,
maybe 600.
Because there was
the feeling of a presence,
an infinite presence
whose essential nature
is one of peace
and whose power
is infinite
and that controlled
the whole experience.
And thus,
both the snake
and myself
transcended fear.
The falsity
of another one
of the mind's belief systems
that we have to learn
to let go of.
The idea
that fear
is the source
of our safety.
You'll notice
that the mind
sort of worships fear
as though it's
some kind of a demi-god.
And the mind
has sort of a program
that says,
the reason
I'm alive
is due to
my fears.
It's because
I allow fears
to decide
what I'm going
to do
that I'm alive.
A little introspection
will show you
that this belief system
is going on.
The person says,
well,
if I wasn't afraid
of being poor
in my old age,
I wouldn't get insurance,
etc.
If I wasn't afraid
of an automobile accident,
I wouldn't drive safely.
And so,
the person begins
to ascribe
the source
of their aliveness,
of their life,
the god of their life,
is fear.
They really begin
to worship fear.
Now we see
from the example
that I just described
that the opposite
is true.
What ensures
our survival
is the absence
of fear.
And you might say
that we have
managed to survive
in spite
of our fears
but not because
of them.
As you see,
we can make decisions
based on
rational choice,
our knowingness,
on our knowledge,
based on our value,
coming from
the beingness
of that which
we really are
without fear
entering the picture
at all.
All day long
we make decisions
that are just
based on
our awareness
of reality
with no fear
particularly
involved.
Fear is not
necessary.
The idea
that fear
is good
for you,
that it's
valuable,
that it has
all kinds
of mysterious
values,
people will
look back
and rationalize
how fear
got them
to do this
and fear
got them
to do that.
You know,
I can say
it's too bad.
Too bad they didn't
do it out of
love for themselves,
out of love
for their fellow
human beings.
Too bad they didn't
do it out of
love for life
itself,
love for their
own aliveness,
body.
Why not do
this?
Why not keep
it healthy and
happy because
you love it
and value it,
not because
you're afraid
of a heart
attack or
afraid of
something.
Do it out of
valuing it
and loving
it.
Ways to let
go more
of this fear
will describe
another technique
which I call
the worst
scenario.
You see,
if you follow
fear as you
will see,
if you ask
yourself,
are you afraid
of driving
your car?
Well, I might
have an accident.
Well, why are
you afraid of
an accident?
Well, because
then I might
get injured.
Well, what if
you got injured?
Well, then I
might suffer
pain, etc.
And you'll find
that every fear
ultimately will
lead you to
the fear of
death.
Fear of the
body's dying.
It'll lead you
to fears of
whether other
people like
that.
What fear does
that bring up
and what fear
is the basis
of that?
We finally get
to the worst
scenario.
The worst
scenario,
let's say your
financial fears,
are that you
will totally
run out of
money,
have no
place to
live,
no money
for food,
for clothing,
so you will
end up
semi-naked
somewhere on
a street
and constantly
let go,
resisting the
feeling of this
and picture the
worst scenario.
What's the worst
possible thing
that could happen
to you?
You end up
in the poor farm.
sitting on the
street corner
as a bag lady
or a bag man.
So you allow
yourself to
picture the worst
scenario.
There you are
with your bag
next to you
sitting on the
cold street
corner at
midnight
friendless.
And you continue
the same
practice.
You go within
yourself and
you keep
letting go,
resisting the
inner experience
of what is
coming up
now.
And as you do
that,
pretty soon
the fear
will run
out.
The fear
of the worst
scenario
will run
out.
Eventually,
if you continue
this practice
long enough,
you'll finally
sit down
with the
worst
scenario.
And that is
the worst
scenario,
right?
That most of
us can visualize.
Those of us
who still think
that we are
that material
body,
that that's
all there is
to us.
So,
sooner or later
we come to
that.
And when we
come to that,
what we do
is we sit
with it,
the same
as we sat
with any
of our
past
beliefs.
You have no
experience
of the
truth
of that.
Therefore,
you have to
label it
fantasy.
It's only a
fantasy in
your mind.
What you
actually
experience
is you
picture
that and
let go
resisting
those feelings
and sensations.
A very
surprising
thing is
in store
for you
is the
fact that
you're
not
going to
be
the
person
you
want
to be.
And I
want to
be
the
person
that
you
want
to be.
And I
want
to be
the
person
that
you
want
to be.
Because I'm
coming from
choice
then,
because
there is
no fear
in that,
the fear
disappears.
The worst
thing that
can happen
is I end
up on a
street corner
and live
that kind
of life.
And the
fear about
it is
gone.
I may
not choose
that kind
of a
life,
if I
should run
out of money
someday.
No matter
how many
millions you
have,
that fear
is there.
The thought
that I
can earn
more and
more money
and pile
up more
and more
in the
bank,
etc.,
is futile.
I know
somebody
who was
recently
worth
$60
million
and today
is putting
six locks
on our
doors,
hiring more
police.
It's owning
that I'm
the source
of my
own experience,
that I'm
master of
it,
that I can
handle
it,
that I'm
greater
than that.
The mind
will,
of course,
will always
try to
justify
our
fears.
The mind
will try to
justify
our fears.
But it
will try
to justify
our fears.
I think
that's
the most
important
thing to
think
about.
I'm
not
going
to
go
out
of
choice
in a
way that
you know
is not
going
to bring
on such
And my free choice is made by a mind which is not fearful.
It is the not-fearfulness is why I'm alive today to talk to you.
It was not being afraid that held back the rattlesnake from striking when he was really
only inches away.
It's the loss of the fear, the letting go of the fearfulness.
And having been in very severe, you might say to the eyes of the usual observer, dangerous
situations, and experienced only joy and happiness and trust in those circumstances, and walked
through cutthroats who would have really attacked a person who was holding fear and did it with
a happy, gleeful smile on the faces of everyone, I mean, they got off on it that a guy like
me would walk right through them, you know, with their guns and chains and knives.
Had I come from fear, they would have challenged that and danger would really have arisen.
But it was the letting go.
Letting go of the fear.
So when they saw there was no fear, there was nothing to bounce off.
Letting go of the worst scenario then is extremely beneficial.
As we do this, we'll get to an awareness that something has been setting up the fear within
us, that now we've lost our fear of fear, and when it arises, we just walk around with
it.
I've walked around with fear for two weeks.
I let fear run one time for two solid weeks.
That trembling.
That electric feeling ran through the body.
I went about my business, just kept letting it run.
I just let it run.
So let it run.
You let it run when you realize it'll run out.
But as we do that, you may come across that there is another source underlying this fear
to begin with, and we come up against guilt as the source of fear.
We now begin to see the value of work that the world calls spiritual consciousness, whatever
terminology.
We begin to see the value of, for instance, techniques such as concentrating on the value
of forgiving.
We see forgiving our self and forgiving our human beings, and turning over any judgment
to God.
We begin to see, if not to God, to some higher power, some energy, fate, whatever you want
to call it.
We find that by letting go, condemning our self and others.
That the unconscious guilt, that that builds up, then also begins to alleviate fear.
Because fear, then, you see, is held in mind because we expect the return of our attacks.
We expect revenge.
We expect retaliation.
So every negative thought that we hold, every hostile thought that we hold about others,
engenders our own fearfulness, because on the psychic plane, on the mental plane, on
the plane which is invisible to the naked eye. It is though we are building up for ourself
that which is going to come back to ourself. And so we learn that fearfulness begins to
diminish as we let go our angriness, hostile, critical, our thoughts which condemn others
that make them wrong. And we learn the value of letting go the thoughts that make other
people wrong. We begin to value them and love them for their beingness, for what they
are. We begin to see ourself as different. Therefore we begin to see others as different.
We become willing to forgive, willing to forget, willing to overlook. We begin to see that
all the things that we have condemned in others are really expressions of their humanness.
What we have been condemning in ourself and what we have been condemning in everybody
else is their humanness.
The innocence of the little child within them that believed everything it heard as
it grew up. What do you suppose the political persuasion of a person is as they grew up
as an innocent child? The consciousness of the child is innocent, is it not? It loves
its parents, it trusts its parents, it loves the mother. And therefore the innocence of
the child is what gets programmed. It is the innocent child that believes everything that
it is told, that the teacher tells it.
The political programming that comes in via television, via the political system of the
country. I ask you, who bought that? Who bought what you believe? To the listener right
now, all the belief systems in your mind, who bought them? You know who bought them?
The mind of the innocent child within you. Because that innocent child's mind, the nature
of consciousness itself, has not changed since you were born. That which is listening to
me right now.
Is the innocent consciousness of the child. Listening, alertly, saying, should I believe
what he's saying? Should I take it within myself? The innocent child never dies. That
innocence is still there.
And so you begin to see that intrinsic innocence and you realize that all the things that you
ever learned that ended up wrong were bought out of that intrinsic not knowing the truth
and learning that which was not the truth. Therefore we're willing to let go of our condemnation
of others.
We're beginning to own our own innocence and the innocence of others. Misfortunate, perhaps.
Regretful that the misinformation came into the innocent mind. You might look at the mind
sort of as the hardware of the computer and its belief systems as the software. Can the
five year old child in Russia think other than the political system that he hears in
his kindergarten from his fellow students, from those parents, from his friends, from
his parents, from his family, from his grandparents, you begin to see it's out of his not knowingness,
it's out of the innocence of his not knowingness, that he believes what he believes.
We're willing to forgive others then and instead of condemning them, understand them. And out
of this understanding then, develops a certain compassion. The compassionate person has no
fears. What is there to fear in a compassionate world? Inasmuch as we're the source of our
own experience.
Our compassion as we own it back within ourself, as we see our own innocence and the innocence of
others, brings to us the experience of a compassionate and loving world. No longer do
we walk around fearfully because we are not creating it ourselves anymore. We see that we
were the source of our fears. The world was never the source of our fear. We are the source of the
fear. Having let go creating it, having let go propagating it through the endless guilt which
comes about and through the endless judgments which social conditioning has brought us into
the habit of, having let go of this now the unconscious guilt diminishes. The letting go of
unconscious guilt progresses outside of our awareness. When we decide instead of condemning
that person, I'm going to try to understand him. Every time we do that, our own store of
unconscious guilt goes down. As our store of unconscious guilt goes down, the
existence of our own conscience goes down. The existence of our own conscience goes down.
The existence of our own conscience goes down. The existence of our own conscience goes down.
expectation of retaliation goes down. You see, in the unconscious, it's an eye for an
eye, a tooth for a tooth. If you wish somebody would drop dead, what do you suppose its equal
is in your unconscious mind? That you should drop dead. You don't think that your thoughts
about if only your so-and-so would drop dead has anything to do with your fears of a heart
attack? Of course they do. As you let go wishing other people would drop dead, you'll find
curiously enough that your fear and obsession that you're going to get a coronary, you might
get a coronary, and all the dietary nonsense that goes with that will diminish. Instead you're very
peaceful about the whole thing. When you go, you go. If you stay, you stay. Big deal. What you value
is life and you no longer focus on the potential ending of that life. So you come into a different
experience of the experiencing of life. You come into a different feeling about who you are.
See, I am that in which this experiencing is going on. And like the ox herding pictures
that we've referred to before, instead of being dragged about by the ox of fear against
our will with bleeding knees and rumpled clothes, now we tie this ox to a tree. Now we've located
the culprit, where he is, you see. Having let go our fear of him now, we've become the
master. We get on top of the ox, the ox becomes tame. We are
the master.
Master, we've identified now with that which we really are, no longer the victim, you see?
Victim comes out of unconsciousness. It means being unaware of this game setup that's been
going on within our mind. Merely becoming aware of it means that you're already out
of it. By the time you've heard this talk today, you've gotten up from being victim.
You're already tying this ox to the tree. That's what we're doing today, is tying that
ox to the tree. And then, as you practice these techniques we've described, you'll be
sitting on top of the ox. When the fear comes along, you welcome it. You say, great, what
an opportunity to let go more of that. Because by now you're feeling the benefit. You're
feeling the decrease of fear and fears that you've had your whole lifetime. Little do
people realize the extent of the fear that they're holding until it begins to disappear.
And then it's mind-boggling. You say, I never realized that was such a fear.
You're a fearful human being.
Perhaps more easily understood by referring back to this map of consciousness, so that
we can see how the energy fields here relate to the way we experience the world. You see,
mind is so powerful that the way it holds your experience literally determines your
experience. Fearfulness creates a certain view of the world, and it becomes a self-fulfillment.
Self-fulfilling prophecy. In psychoanalysis, psychiatry, it's called the self-fulfilling
prophecy. And recent university research, as well as our own research in Sedona, shows
that what you hold in mind tends to make it happen within what you think is the world.
The world of your own experience, then, becomes the external representation, actually, of
what you have been holding in mind. So that your life, the world, is really a world of
mirrors.
What you're actually seeing, what you're actually experiencing, is a projection of
your own level of consciousness. This is hard to believe and hard to really fully grasp,
but to give us a glimpse at it, it's a whole field of study in itself. On this map of consciousness,
let's compare the level of consciousness with its emotion and our view of the world, and
how this would give us a view of God if we believed in such consciousness.
Subtitles by the Amara.org community
reasonable scenario. As your consciousness raises and you reach an energy field of 50,
the energy field of hopelessness, the one of loss of energy, the world is seen as a
relatively hopeless place. This world and life in it is hopeless. And so we have some
of the famous existentialists that said that man is nothing and God is dead. And so the
view coming out of this is a hopeless world, the view of God from that level of consciousness
then is that God is dead. God is dead. If we raise our level of consciousness and advance
in our awareness, we then move up to the level of grief. Grief. Again a negative view of
the world, of ourselves. The emotions of that would be regret, loss, feeling of despondency,
dispirited.
A person
into grief holding that energy field sees this as a sad world. As they walk down the
street, a person holding this energy field sees sad, just as this person sees hopeless.
He walks down the city street, he sees the hopelessness of mankind's conditions. This
one sees the sadness. When this person looks at older people, they see how sad it is. How
sad it is that they are old. When they look at children, they think how sad it is when
they are little kids, what these poor innocent children are going to have to experience
in life. When they open the newspaper, they see the sadness of all that goes on in the
world, and what kind of a God would fit that sadness. A God who ignores you. Out of this,
the person is worthless. So, the person says. I am just a worm, and God couldn't possibly
have any interest in me, if he exists at all. He would just be a God who ignores you. What
this energy field of fear. We see that we are the creator now of that. We are the owner. We are the
source. The emotions of worry, anxiety, and panic. The deflation of self-esteem. And to them, this is
a frightening world. As they walk down the street, they see danger everywhere. These people see
danger everywhere. They open the newspaper. It's alarming. Bankruptcy, murder. They walk down the
street. They see automobile accidents, potential for starvation. Who would be the god of a frightening
field of consciousness? A very punitive one who really sort of hates you and throws you into a
nightmare. So this world is an endless nightmare. The creator of such a nightmare is a very punitive
god. Because of revenge, because of retaliation, we'll move up into retaliation. He becomes
the punisher. As we move up into desire, the solar
plexus, craving, what makes Sammy run, wantingness. There's no satisfying that, is there? No matter what
the person gets, it's not enough. This is the millionaire. He's got 50 million. He's going for
60. He's got 60. He's going for 70. He never gets to the end. There's no end to the road. And when
he's old and his fingernails are long and he's paranoid and he lives on a yacht and he's paranoid,
he thinks that the world is against him, he can't understand why he can't find happiness. We said
happiness. He's like, I don't know. I don't know. I don't know. I don't know. I don't know. I don't
know. We're gonna give it 100%. Somebody gave me this Și designer and we'll give that a go,
ián, o q Гărè gjèз, you know, the one in the building up here
at 500. More and more, getting this in the world, wanting, craving, by which the person
is trapped is frustrating. So here is a frustrating world. If you're always wanting, then the
world is always holding back from you. As you look in the department store windows,
that cravingness comes out. You want those jewels. You want the want want want.
If you get them, what will you feel? You'll feel a satisfaction. You won't feel happiness.
Because that's at 500. But you'll feel a depth. And sometimes we kill people. Endless suffering.
It's not enough. motel accommodations. translates to gefallen sense. It can be found in a crazy внешraps辿
of satisfaction temporarily, and you feel separated from God. What kind of a God is
it that withholds from you that which you desire? So you see yourself as separated from
God, if there is a God at all. There's me and there's God, but the two of us have no
relationship. The frustration of this frustrating world of desire leads to anger, resentment,
hatred, grievance, war, murder. The expansion, the over-expansion of the angry person, the
standing out of the blood vessels, the angry animal flares up with anger. The angry person
sees this as a competitive world. When somebody opens up another used car lot next to him,
he's angry. He thinks that this person is going to take his business away. See, he hasn't
moved up to a world of cooperation, which knows that the more used car lots near you,
the greater the business, because it draws people from everywhere. So he wouldn't think
of cooperating. Instead, he thinks of competition. So he's polarized. It's me against
them, you see. And therefore, he sees a competitive world and a retaliatory God, who out of angriness
is very punishing. This is the angry God that will punish you, retaliate against you, and
seek revenge. I am a jealous, vengeful God who will get you. I'm out to get you. So God
is somebody who is your enemy. He's out to get you, you see, out to get you. How can
you relax and reach any kind of awareness in that kind of an angry energy field? You
move up out of angry then into pridefulness. But we see that pride carries with it the
downside of denial, of arrogance and contempt. We see that the process in consciousness is
one of being inflated. This person lives in a world of status. When he walks down the
same city street, what he sees is not only your Cadillac, but the year and the model.
I didn't even realize they came in models. I thought a Caddy was a Caddy. No, sir. There
are different models of Cadillacs, I've discovered.
And so whether you have a, I forget the name of them, but whatever they are, one has more
status than the other. So the interest in other human beings then is their position.
Oh, he's president of so-and-so, or he's only a blue collar worker, or it isn't the money,
it's the status that the money gives them. What comes out of pridefulness? What kind
of a God can you see out of pridefulness? Well, you've probably got two options. Because
of denial and because of intellectual arrogance, you can say that my left brain intellect denies
there is a God, and that's atheism. Or you can say my position is the right one, and
everybody else is therefore wrong, and you end up with bigotry. This is the source of
all the religious wars. My view of religion is right, therefore, yours must be wrong.
So pridefulness leads us into a polarized position of me right, you wrong. This is the
world of win-lose. The anxiety that goes with win-lose, so the person in pride is defensive.
This is the world of win-lose. As we move up to courage then, we see what happens is
the energy field now is turning to the right. It's actually at neutral, turning to the right,
we see it jump to 200. Now we see for the first time appropriateness. The person is
able to face, to cope, to handle. They become empowered because they have begun to tell
the truth about themself. The person from the level of courage walks down the same street,
and what does he see? He sees the power of God. He sees the power of God. He sees the
power of the light. He sees the ability to move. He sees the power of God. He sees that
he has power. He sees the power of God by just looking at everything he's able to see.
He sees a challenging exciting world of opportunity. What a thrilling world of growing, of learning,
of expanding, of watching others grow. The inner joy that comes from expanding your own
space. Courage is what settled the United States of America. It settled the West. It
creates all the industrial empires. It creates all our scientific enterprises. It's what
got us to the Moon. The world of exciting opportunity of growth
expansion. What kind of a God is the God of that level of consciousness? The person of that level
of consciousness, for the first time, has an open mind. He doesn't come from, I got the answers.
He doesn't come from vengeful negativity. He says, for the first time, I wonder if there is such a
being. I wonder if there is something greater than the personal self. I'm open to learn about this.
Hmm. He then treats the God question the same as he does the world question. An exciting world of
exploration. And let me tell you, spiritual research is extremely exciting. The things
that you discover. As we move up to the next energy field, then, courage has resulted in being
unattached. Hmm. This person says, it's okay if I get the job. It's okay if I don't. He's released.
He's not run by the world. His power greatly increases because now,
well, he's no longer victim. Hmm. You can't control him now anymore. He says, if I get the
job, great. If I don't, I'll just find another job. If this person stays in my life, great. If
they don't, I'll find somebody else to be with. They're no longer living in fear. They've moved
up to a certain okayness. So the view of the world is the view is now okay. What kind of a God would
be the God of an okay world? It would be a God of freedom, then. A God of freedom to
expand, to explore. If there is such a God, if there is a God, it's okay with me. And if there
isn't okay with me, there's sort of an inner sense of fairness about. If there is a God, he'll be
fair. And I'll learn about it when the time comes. And if there isn't, that's okay with me, too.
As we move up to willingness now, for the first time, see, this person said okay either way. But
this person now, at willingness, declares an intention. Begins to say yes to life. I join. I
align myself.
I agree with things, you see. This person waits on your table. It's okay if he waits on you. It's
okay if he doesn't. This person begins to experience a willingness to be of service,
a certain happiness. And this person views the world as friendly. When you're willing,
the world is friendly. Now you walk down the street, you see all the friendly people,
potentially friendly. All you have to do is walk up to an old lady and say, hi, what a beautiful
day. She goes, hey, nobody's talked to me all morning. Isn't that nice? The world is a friendly
place, and God becomes perhaps a promising and a hopeful concept. The god of a friendly world
would become a friendly god. Even if you don't believe in them, you begin to trust them. If you
don't have a belief in God, at least the friendly person says, well, if there is one, he'll be at
least as kindly as my grandmother. He'll be, you know, he's gonna be a positive pop kind of a guy,
you know. He's gonna understand human nature. He's not gonna throw me into the pitfires of hell for
human. He created me as human. I am his handiwork. What is he going to do, condemn his own self?
So there for God, certain trust in God if there is such a thing. As we move up to acceptance,
what's happening in acceptance is you've begun to own yourself as the source of your own
power. You are the creator of the happiness in your own life now. And that transformation
in consciousness brings a feeling of adequacy and confidence and life, the view of the world
now is harmonious. As you walk down the street, you see the subtle, beautiful naturalness
of how everything interacts, that everything is really where it should be, that everybody
is wanting to be what they are. The bag lady is there because she wants to be a bag lady.
Nobody's forced her to be that. She's chosen to be that which she is.
We can stop blaming God for everything. We can stop blaming God for everything. We can
stop blaming the wonderful, beautiful, perfect, awesome all that God did. We can stop blaming
ourselves for all the things that understanding has done to our soul. We can stop blaming
God for everything. We can block not surprised at matters of personal themselves whether
to
or his Mate.
very powerful level, because this is unconditional love in which we begin to nurture, support
life.
We are willing to forgive it.
Beginning revelation occurs because of the release of these endorphins.
We begin to see the lovingness that is everywhere.
We see the lovingness in nature, the lovingness of the animal world.
We see the natural lovingness of the child within everybody.
The loving heart of the child is still alive in everyone.
If you don't experience it, it's because you don't know how to tune into it.
But I tell you, the innocent loving heart of the child is in everyone.
It can be appealed to.
That's why the merciless killer, in the presence of a loving person, becomes harmless.
In the presence of the fearful person who creates the space for him to attack, he attacks.
This loving person then experiences a safe world, and God must, of necessity, be of at
least as high a level of consciousness as you are.
And therefore unconditionally loving.
The experience of the truth of this brings you into a joyfulness.
Joyfulness brings about a transfiguration in consciousness.
It brings you into compassion.
The inner serenity of the compassionate person begins to see the perfection of creation.
The perfection of creation.
This unconditional love of the Creator creates a oneness.
You begin to experience a oneness.
The oneness of all beings.
Therefore all of life, in all its expressions, are sacred, beginning awareness of the sacredness
of life and merging into an illuminated enlightened state, into a blissfulness, into a feeling
of infinite peace, in which the total oneness of creation brings an awareness of God as
the essence of beingness itself.
As I stood on top of this mountain in the presence of the rest of the world, I saw the
rattlesnake.
What was it that transfixed both of us?
Into a state of infinite peace.
Into a state of oneness.
I couldn't really say in that state that the aliveness, the life of the snake and the life
of myself were two different lives.
It's as though there was one.
The two were being controlled by the nature of the one, that which brought what seemed
to be the two of us.
Together as one experience.
There was really only one experience going on.
The one experience was being experienced, you might say, through the two.
The two experiencing their oneness.
No thought of attack therefore arose, because the energy field of that experience had already
risen up here.
The feeling of infinite peace.
It's called by many, peace of God.
It's called by psychology.
It's called by psychologists, perhaps, peak experience, Maslow's term for peak experience.
Meaning one has transcended all these levels, you see, and experienced the truth of their
beingness.
There are certain teachings that say there are only two emotions at all.
There is love and there is fear.
And that all these negative feelings from love on down are nothing but variations of
fear.
And it certainly can be looked at that way.
You can see all of these as expressions of fear.
Fear of moral wrong.
Fear of the inability to survive and exist.
Fear over the loss of the source of one's happiness.
Fear that one won't get.
Anger over the intrinsic fear that not getting brings to the person.
So we could say that they are all forms of fear.
There really are two expressions only.
That which is love.
Starts here and becomes infinite in its expression.
And that which is fearful and begins here and goes ever downward in its expression.
Therefore, the handling of all the negative feelings arises out of the willingness, the
willingness to accept that we have the power within us to handle this inner fearfulness
and to recognize that we are the source of it, to stop projecting it onto the world or
onto God.
No one created a fearful world.
There is no such thing.
The fearful world is within us.
We carry it with us.
And thus we can let it go.
We can let the fear of the fear go.
We can let the fear itself go and move into the presence of love itself.