Hello, I'm Dr. David R. Hawkins. I'm a physician, psychiatrist, psychoanalyst, nutritionist.
I've been doing research in the nature of consciousness itself and levels of awareness
that the world calls spiritual. Out of this, plus my 35 years of clinical experience, as well as my
own personal experience, we've derived knowledge that can be extremely useful in alleviating
human suffering in all its forms, many of which I've lived through in my own personal life,
and I've been forced to find answers that are outside the field of traditional medicine.
We'll be talking about, in this particular workshop today, pain and suffering, the alleviation of pain
and suffering. To begin with, that the world thinks that they are the same thing. To get off
the idea and to show how to separate that suffering is one thing and pain is another.
To look at the world as a whole, as a whole, as a whole, as a whole, as a whole, as a whole,
to look into what it means, physical, mental, and spiritual. It is said that all diseases,
all illnesses, all human problems are physical, mental, and spiritual. What does that actually
mean? As a physician, I've learned all about the physical. As a psychiatrist, about the mental.
And in consciousness and spiritual work, about the spiritual dimension.
What is meant by spirit? Is this a fantasy? Is it something real? Is it something we can
work with? Is it something that's only useful for religious people? What do we need to know
about that, that we can experience the truth of for ourself? How can we utilize this knowledge
for the alleviation of our own problems and of those that we love?
So today we'll be talking about how to handle acute pain, how to handle chronic pain,
how to handle the pain itself, and even more importantly, how to be with that pain.
You see, we have two different things to address. One is the problem itself, the symptoms,
how to handle them specifically. And there we'll also be looking at such things as
the use of hypnosis and acupuncture, what part do they play in alleviation of pain.
And we'll be looking at levels of consciousness. In other words, how to be with that experience,
how to be with the experience.
Of that problem, and the problem, of course, we're looking at today, is that of pain.
And in going into that, we'll be utilizing a map of consciousness, which we have evolved
as a composite of many fields of endeavor and joint study that I've done with others.
And so you'll see on the blackboard, we have something that we'll be referring to that is
extremely useful and we've found very helpful. And that is sort of a mathematical model
of the levels of consciousness. They've been calibrated as to their relative power, the
direction of their energy fields, what the emotional component is, what the process going
on in consciousness is, how that influences our view of the world, and our view of a God
if we have one. And if we don't have one, what does that come out of?
So we'll be addressing clinical examples, things that I've experienced,
through myself, even recently in my own personal life, so that I can attest to the fact that
they work.
They work.
They've worked for me.
They've worked for others who've tried it.
They've worked clinically.
And out of this experience we demonstrate certain principles of consciousness which
have a benefit to our life as a whole, to our life as a whole.
What we learn in studying one specific problem then generalizes to our life as a whole.
So we'll be turning lemons into lemonade, how to turn something that the world considers
to be awful, such as pain, how to derive benefit from that, how to have your life prosper as
a result of what you've learned from this one specific incidence.
We need to know something about what is the nature of consciousness itself, and from that
we'll learn a lot that will help us in our life in general.
What is the nature of human experience?
Where is experience?
What is experience experienced?
So to begin with, we'll look at the relationship between body, mind, and spirit.
What does this mean?
What is it besides just a catchphrase?
Everybody says body, mind, and spirit.
What does that mean?
What is it practically?
I myself came, you know, as a scientist with a skeptical, pragmatic mind.
I'm very impressed by what works.
I'm very unimpressed by.
The hypothetical and the theoretical.
I'm very interested in what brings about results and what you can reduplicate through your
own experience.
So I'll be sharing my personal experience, my clinical experience, and the results of
our research.
So we'll look at the relationship between mind, body, and spirit, and how these are
experienced.
The first thing to realize is that the body has no capacity to experience itself.
This is a surprising thought.
Because we think we're experiencing our body.
We all think we are our body.
How does the body get experienced?
Well, the arm, for instance, has no way of experiencing its armness.
The leg cannot experience its own being a leg.
It's because these parts are experienced through sensations.
So sensations of the body is what we're experiencing.
We're not experiencing the body.
We're experiencing our sensations of the body.
And where are these sensations of the body being?
Where are they being?
They're being experienced.
They're being experienced in the mind.
Without a mind, you cannot experience what is going on in the body, the sensations that
are telling us about the body.
And so experiences going on then of the body is occurring in the mind.
Your experience of your body is not occurring in your body.
It's occurring in your mind.
That's the first surprising thought to get used to.
The next surprising thought is that mind cannot experience itself.
The next surprising thought is it not.
A thought cannot experience its own thoughtness.
A feeling cannot experience its own feelingness.
A memory cannot experience its own memoryness.
The mind itself has to be in something greater than itself in order to know what is going
on in mind.
How do you know what is going on in your mind?
You know what's going on in your mind because of consciousness itself.
So mind itself and the content of mind, what's going on in mind, is not going to be in the mind.
It's going to be in the mind.
is being known through consciousness
so that all experience is occurring then in consciousness.
Your awareness of what is happening
is occurring within your consciousness.
We know this if, for instance, you cut a part of the brain
so that a part of the mind is no longer operative
in the physical domain.
If you cut part of the brain,
then the opposite side of the body, let's say,
is no longer experienced.
So, body is experienced in mind,
no mind, no experience of body.
We know that if you eliminate consciousness,
there is no awareness of what is going on in mind.
That's the whole purpose of anesthesia.
The purpose of anesthesia is
when you cut out consciousness,
there is no awareness of what is going on in mind.
Interestingly, consciousness itself
is experienced from an even greater domain.
So, as this progresses,
you get that the lesser is always experienced
from that which is the greater.
It is the greater that encompasses
and allows the experience of the lesser.
And consciousness itself is then experienced
in the greatest domain,
and that is the one without limit,
called awareness.
It is awareness itself.
It is the nature of awareness,
being itself,
to know,
to know what is going on in consciousness.
It is the nature of consciousness
to know what is going on in mind.
It is the nature of mind
to know what is going on with sensations.
And the nature of sensations
to know what is going on with the body.
What is the importance of this?
The importance of it is to know
that all experience,
ordinary experience,
is going on in consciousness alone.
Where is consciousness?
When we say,
when we experience something,
where do we experience it?
Is there a place?
Where is consciousness located?
Does it have a specific space?
Is it someplace?
It is important for us to know
that consciousness has no space.
It has no area.
It has no limitation.
The common fantasy is,
well, I experience things in my head.
Actually, you don't experience them in your head.
Where do you experience a thought?
You are experiencing a thought nowhere.
There is no specific space
in which you are experiencing,
experiencing thought.
The nature of consciousness is
that it has no particular form.
Consciousness is without form.
Its content is with form.
But the field of consciousness itself
is like space,
having no particular locality.
This will be important to us later today
as we discuss
one of the techniques of handling pain.
Because pain can be handled
both locally and generally.
So we have several ways
in which now we are going to
be approaching the handling of pain.
How to handle the specific sensation.
How to handle the experience of it.
And how to handle
and be with that
as you exist, as you are,
the way you as a being are
with that experience of that pain.
And how you have evolved
in your own consciousness
will determine whether the pain
involves suffering or not.
Isn't that a surprising thought?
That pain is one thing,
and suffering is another.
So the first thing we want to
get rid of in our minds
is the belief system
that pain is therefore suffering.
Because that sets up
a whole series of programs
which we are going to need to undo.
Pain is one thing.
It is quite possible to be with pain
and be totally indifferent to it.
It is possible for pain to exist in the body
and to have relatively little or no experience
of that pain.
No suffering about it at all.
Those of you who have ever had surgery,
for instance, and have had anesthesia,
have had analgesia,
is the better term.
You know, an injection of Demerol or something
will know that
you've had a gallbladder attack,
let's say, or something,
and you've had analgesic,
will know that in that state
the pain is still there.
The pain exists on its own.
And yet, you as a being are no longer
suffering about that pain.
It's as though the pain is there,
and you are here,
but you are not necessarily connected
with that pain.
The pain exists on its own,
but without you being at the effect of it.
In other words, it's not necessary
to be the victim of the pain.
One can be with it in such a way
that the pain is there,
and I am with that pain
in a way that does not involve suffering,
does not involve
any kind of agony.
To realize that that is possible
is the first step
that leads us out of it.
Letting go of the belief
that pain and suffering are the same thing.
And today in this we'll talk about
the fact is,
is going to the dentist necessarily painful?
Frankly, no.
At one time in my life
going to the dentist was agonizing.
It took a handful of pills
and tranquilizers,
and this is many, many years ago.
But I remember I would
put off going because
my pain threshold was so low
I literally had to have analgesia
to get my teeth cleaned.
And my pain threshold was so low
that I was pain prone.
So we'll be talking today
about pain proneness.
What is it that sets our pain threshold?
What is it that sets our readiness
to experience pain?
And as the years went by
and I learned these various
spiritual techniques
and consciousness techniques
and began to apply them,
the experience of pain began to diminish.
Much to my surprise,
I could go to the dentist
and experience moderate pain
instead of agony.
And then the pain became mild.
Then it only became a discomfort.
And when I go to the dentist now
I don't even notice any discomfort.
It's like I'm in the chair for a minute
and I'm out and I say,
are you done already?
I can hardly believe you're done already.
So when we get to near the end of the tape
we'll discuss some perhaps
self-hypnotic techniques
to reinforce what we've learned.
We'll be utilizing that
sort of auto-suggestion
and how to reinforce what we've learned.
How to utilize a somewhat
altered state of consciousness
in your own behalf.
How to come from a suggestible space
to learn more quickly.
Not to relieve pain.
We'll be talking about it
as a means of quickly
educating yourself.
When you've got to go to the dentist next week
you don't have much time
to learn the techniques.
And we'll learn some ways
to speed them up.
First thing we want to address ourselves to
is the handling of acute pain.
You're walking along
and suddenly you sprain your ankle
and the pain is agonizing
or you break your leg
or you suddenly have a gallbladder attack
or renal colic
or a coronary
or just an ordinary accident
or you bark your shin
you hit your head on something.
How to handle that acute situation
will reveal to us a technique
that we'll be utilizing
throughout the series
in healing a variety of illnesses
and a way of utilizing it
in healing both acute and chronic pain.
So let's start with acute pain.
The sudden shock
of suddenly finding yourself
you've had an accident.
You've scalded yourself.
You've poured hot water on your hand
and you've burned yourself
on the sink or the stove.
This is a technique
that we're going to get a lot of mileage out of
and that is the whole concept
of letting go resistance.
We want to look at
what is the benefit in letting go resistance
and compare it to what mind ordinarily does.
What mind ordinarily does
is resist an experience.
It resists it
out of the expectation of suffering.
It has a program already set up.
Pain means suffering
and I'm going to resist this.
And the fantasy is
that if I resist it
I will eliminate it.
So the first thing we have to know
is that the relief of pain and suffering
comes rapidly
by going 180 degrees
in the opposite direction
and that is by letting go resisting the pain
and we'll talk about exactly how to do that.
And we'll use some clinical examples
of rapid healing
that come about
through a completely different technique
than is used by the mind
in an average situation.
Letting go resistance
is a process
that takes place
in everyday life.
To let go resistance means
to be with the thing
and totally surrender
to the sensation.
It means to ignore the thoughts
that you may be having about it.
Instead of thinking about it
you go right into the direct experience
of the sensation
and you totally let go resisting it.
Let's say you burn yourself by accident.
At first it will be like an overwhelm.
It's like
you ask for more of it.
You let the doors open
and the pain rushes in
and you totally surrender to it
and let go resisting to it.
In fact the way to do this
is to say more, more, more, more.
And the way to hold this in mind
so that this is acceptable to you
is to know that there is only so much pain
in any experience.
It would be like let's say
it's a 50 pound pain experience.
You open the door to it
and you let the whole 49 pounds of it
run out rapidly.
So I let go resisting
this experience.
I let go resisting
being with it.
I ignore the thoughts
because the thoughts are not going to be useful.
Instead I totally surrender
and I allow myself
to experience it totally.
What happens then
is it's like the door is open
and there's a rush.
It's like I'm going to be experienced out
in a very rapid few minutes.
I remember twisting my ankle
in San Francisco
and it was a severe twist
that ordinarily would have put you
you would have ended up
seeing the orthopedist
and getting your ankle taped
or maybe even a cast put on
for say six weeks or so.
Instead what I did
is I sat down on the park bench
and I just closed my eyes
and I surrendered to it.
I was in waves of excruciating pain.
If I had resisted it
I would have ended up in a cast.
In other words it turns an acute
into a chronic condition
if you resist it.
So what happens is I sat down on the park bench
and I just let it
swamp over me.
I just surrendered to it
and waves of pain came over me
and yet curiously enough
it's devoid of suffering.
Why is that?
Because I was choosing to experience the experience.
And in doing that
I'm the master of the experience.
I'm no longer the victim.
I'm the one that is saying
I choose to experience it
give me more of it.
Because of that
the amount of suffering involved
as you look at it
is really minimal.
The alleviation of the pain is very rapid.
And I would say within
three to four minutes
I was up again and walking.
And now the pain had gone down
I kept letting go
resisting that pain.
When I broke my left foot
I did the same thing.
I broke my left foot
chopping wood and a huge
oak log fell on it
and crushed all the bones across the front of the foot.
And you know by Christmas
I was dancing.
By Christmas I was back in the ballroom dancing.
Never had a cast
did nothing about it except
consciously choose
to let go resisting that experience.
There was an accidental amputation.
And again the same thing
the shock of the experience
and then knowing now
how to handle it
the letting go of resisting
this experience
the constantly letting go of the sensations
letting go resisting these sensations.
And as you do that
what the world would call miraculous
happens right before your eyes.
As I let go resisting
because I cut this thumb off
with a saw, a circular saw
the first thing I did is
I instantly stopped resisting the experience.
I just stood still
and allowed it to sweep in over me.
And as I did that
within seconds the bleeding stopped.
I literally
I have the visa board in which this happened.
There is eight drops of blood.
There are eight drops of blood.
By letting go resisting the experience
the digital artery which had been cut across
and should have pulsated
in a grotesque kind of fashion
no such thing happened.
Ross with whom I have done
a great deal of this research
had burned herself severely in the kitchen.
And she just stood there
and consciously released letting go resisting
that burn
and the pain of the burn was gone
in a matter of a minute or two
and later there wasn't even a blister there.
It should have by rights swollen up
to a big water blister
and taken months to heal.
And the only thing that happened
was a discoloration.
A member of my class did the same
thing. He burned both of his hands.
He is a woodworker,
a cabinet maker.
He burned both his hands
and he followed the same technique.
Instantly let go resisting that
and instead of two hands
he should have had two hands
by rights two hands swollen up
like this full of blisters
and should have had his hand in bandages
for weeks.
Instead in a matter of he said
three or four minutes
the pain was gone
and there was no formation.
So we see an instant healing.
The body knows how to heal itself
the minute we let go of resistance.
Now let's look a little bit
at why this should be so.
There is no magic involved.
Anybody can experience
the truth of this.
This has been a common teaching
for thousands of years.
Those of you who have ever
tried Zen meditation
will know that the first thing
they teach you is the handling
of the physical body
is to go into that
and let go of the resisting
of the experience
and to cancel out thoughts about that
to become one with it
and thereby disappear it.
So we are doing what in consciousness
work is called disappearing.
By totally letting go of the resistance
of a thing we disappear it.
We disappear it out of our experience.
So you see experience is prolonged
by resistance.
So long as I resist the thing
that gives its existence
my resistance is what gives it
the power over me
and I now become the victim of that.
I am at the effect of that
which I resist.
The minute I let go of my resistance
become one with it
I disappear it.
Now we will see the reasons for it.
I have always been a very left brain person.
I have learned to enlarge
my right brain capacities.
But for most of us
all of these things make more sense
so we will go over to the blackboard
where we have this map of consciousness
that we referred to before.
And we will look at some energy fields.
Here in this particular box
a lot of people
who followed our work here
call this the box.
What is in the box
are levels of consciousness.
And these levels of consciousness
are labeled according to common
human experience so that they are understandable.
Each of these levels
of consciousness
has also been calibrated mathematically
so that we can see
what its relative power is.
We also have
been able to discern
what is the direction of the energy
of that field.
What is the direction?
And so these arrows indicate
whether the direction of the field
is in a negative direction
or a positive direction.
And this of course is extremely important
in the way that we experience things.
These things in a negative direction
are experienced as painful,
experienced as suffering.
They bring about detriment
and destruction
in our lives.
So at the bottom for instance
we have death calibrated at zero.
And you will see that guilt
is at 30,
apathy at 50,
grief at 75,
fear at 100,
desire, wantingness 125,
anger is 150,
pride is 175.
What is amazing happens here
at the level of courage
the field which was in a negative direction
now goes neutral actually
at an energy level we calibrate at 200.
When we move up to 250
the level called neutral
the field is now
in a positive direction.
We then move up to willingness
which calibrates at 310,
acceptance at 380,
love at 500,
joy at 540,
ecstasy at 560,
the state of infinite serenity and peace
and the emotion there
is commonly called bliss.
These energy fields influence
our emotions.
They are indicators
of a process going on
in consciousness.
They influence how we see
and experience the world
and how we experience our relationship
to something that is greater
than our personal self
which the world calls a deity.
Or for those of you who are not
aware,
a deity is a person
who is in a higher level
to a greater field of consciousness
the powerful fields
which come about on these higher levels.
The only reason to review this
is so now we can understand
what happens in our handling
our technique there of handling
acute pain.
We found that resistance to pain
resistance to pain
is a negative energy field
and if you can use your will power
against it and resist it
what you are bringing forth
within yourself
is a negative energy field
that calibrates about 150.
This would be about the same level
as the emotions of resentment
or grievance.
Emotions of grievance
we resent the pain
and you see
we are angry about the pain.
If we move up to letting go resistance
if we have the courage
to use this technique
out of our faith and trust
in what the doctor is telling you
about his own personal experience
and what he has learned
if we have enough faith in that
and we are willing to try it
the first thing we can move up to
is this level here
at an energy field of 250
called detached.
Moving into neutral means
now we are into a positive energy field
that means
I am willing to experience this thing out.
Willingness moves us up
to an energy field of 310
where we say yes
to life and its experiences
where we join with it
where we agree with it
where we align with it
and where our will expresses itself
as a positive intention.
Instead of resisting life then
I go with life
that is the wisdom of the Tao
spelled T-A-O
the wisdom of the Tao
that the willow tree
bends with the wind
the oak tree which resists it
breaks.
So instead of resisting
what has occurred
once you have barked your shin
all you can do is be the willow tree now
and go with that
let go resisting it
allow that experience to flow through you
and by doing that
you move yourself out of
a negative painful energy field
full of resentment and anger and fear
which is only a negative field of 100
these are low energy fields
they are a long way from joy
you see the higher the number
the greater the feeling of happiness
you can actually choose then
and be willing
and you can even accept
that that is what is necessary
to handle this
which moves you all the way up to 380
that is a very high energy field
so when I choose to go with life
whether it is running across
a rattlesnake or whatever
I do
when I surrender to that experience
then I invite
I bring forth within myself
a greater power
a higher energy
those people who are experiencing this technique
therefore end up calling it
a higher power
and you will hear people say
I called upon my higher power
those of us who haven't heard that experience
consider that maybe flaky or far out
because it is not real to us
so how can we make these experiences real
by doing them
it is actually through the doingness of it
that these things become real
by the doing of this exercise then
you begin to experience
that something other than your personal self
is handling this experience
and within moments
what was agonizing
is now very bearable
you are out of the fear and the suffering
and the resistance
so we want to avoid
we want to bypass a negative energy field
a low energy power
and we want to move up higher
why because as we move up to higher energies
love for instance
unconditional love
is an energy field of 500
when we move into lovingness
which is an energy field
of about 540
the energy field of 540
has the capacity to heal
those
who are healers
when we calibrate
what is the field that they generate
it is an energy field of 540 and up
it is an immensely loving
it is experienced as lovingness
the emotion
is experienced as lovingness
it is that desire
to be with life
to say yes with it
to let go resisting
so acute pain then
and the healing
that comes about automatically
from this technique
can be experienced by anyone
I have done it over and over again
and everyone that I have told about it
who has tried it
and many people have had the opportunity
I remember a class on a Sunday night
in which I described the technique
and during that week
several members of the class
had acute injuries
where this was life saving to them
literally able to carry them through
a terrible experience
how can we then utilize this
in our handling of chronic pain
chronic pain
is a somewhat different
experience isn't it
and yet one of the aspects
of handling it
is the same as we did
with the acute pain
we are going to be doing it
with the chronic pain
in a somewhat different way however
as we said
all experience is being experienced
in consciousness
if you look to see
where is the pain being experienced
so let's take this thumb
you know just happens to be handy
where is the pain
of it being experienced
we can say number one
the pain seems to be coming
from right here
the mind would say well the pain is in
the thumb
actually where is the pain being experienced
if I go away from the thumb
and let's say I move into
the top of my head
let's say I focus on the top of my head
and now from the top of my head
I look at
from that space I now experience
the painfulness of the thumb
where is the painfulness of the thumb
happening
if I do that I begin to notice
that the painfulness
is being experienced everywhere
the painfulness is being experienced
when you first try this technique
you'll see that the painfulness
is being experienced
like all around your body
all around the energy fields of your body
that it's really going on
sort of everywhere
you all have the experience of pain
you're sick to your stomach
and flip floppy and weak in the knees
it's being experienced everywhere
so if I go into the top of my head
this is just an exercise
that you do you see
and from there I begin to experience
the pain
I then notice that this pain is everywhere
and now I use the same technique
that I used
in handling the acute pain
I let go resisting
what is being experienced
everywhere
it's in no place
that this is going on
and I let go resisting it
I want to review again this technique
of letting go resistance
to clearly differentiate
that which is the feeling
the sensation, the experience
and that which are the thoughts
we're going to be doing this
with all of life's problems
and especially with physical illnesses
that there is
an absolute sensation
coming in
to what is being experienced
and what the mind then does
is elaborate
about that experience
conceptualize about it
label it
and put concepts on it
for instance you cannot experience
an ulcer
you cannot experience diabetes
you see those are labels
those are concepts
those are diagnoses
what are you actually experiencing
what you're actually experiencing
let's say
what the world calls an ulcer
is a sensation right here
then your mind says
well if I can't call it ulcer
I'm going to say it's burning
that again is a concept
we've learned what that means
that's a thought form
which we have learned in our learning
actually you're not experiencing a burning
you're going inside now
to an experiencing of the experience
which has no words
to the experiencing of the experience
when the animal experiences it
it has no words about that
it just is with what's going on
so we sort of call up
our animal nature
and just be with
what's being experienced
without saying anything about it
without elaborating
why?
because these thoughts
all bring in programs
complicated programs
and we then become
at the effect of these thoughts
if I say to myself
that I have an ulcer
then I've got a whole bunch of programs
that go with ulcer
and because of the nature of mind
I begin to experience all of that
because of the power of mind
and one that
people find most difficult to
really grasp when they
enter research and
work in the field of consciousness itself
and that is the realization
of the power of mind
how powerful it is
we just cannot be careless
about our thoughts
once we understand
the power of mind and the nature of thought
we begin to realize that
one of the principles
of consciousness
is that we are only subject
to what we hold in mind
in this one sentence
is
the key to the healing
of all illness, pain and suffering
we are only subject
to what we hold in mind
the mind is extraordinarily
powerful
the great difficulty
that people have in getting
is how powerful the mind is
and therefore in dealing with pain
or with suffering of any kind
the first thing we have to do
is discontinue
let go of and cancel
all of our belief systems
about that
it is
as the research has shown
the belief system itself
that literally creates
the experience
the incident is an expression
of that belief system
it is like the mind justifying
that what it believes is true
we can find out whether
this is so or not our self
by beginning to cancel it
to cancel as we said
at the beginning of this film
the belief that pain and suffering
are the same thing
we have to cancel
all thoughts
and all thoughts
are really belief systems
and instead we have to go
for radical truth
radical in that we drop off
everything except
the experiencing
of what is literally
being experienced
and letting go the resistance
to that
when we do
we will experience a relief
of the suffering
and curiously enough
we will reach a point
where we don't care
whether the pain is there or not
that may be a difficult thing
to conceive of in the beginning
because the mind wants to be
rid of the pain
our whole approach instead
is to accept it
to accept it
to let the pain be there
but to move away from it
in other words it is like the pain is here
and then you experience the morphine
the pain of the broken ankle
let's say is there
and then you begin to feel yourself
move away from that pain
it's no longer you
it's no longer yours
in this case the narcotic does
what we are explaining
can be done by consciousness
actually the narcotic
actually doesn't do it
the narcotic enables
our consciousness
to make this very move
and we can learn to make
this very move
without being triggered
by a narcotic
I have had to do that
I myself have been allergic
severely allergic
to any kind of analgesic
or narcotic or anesthetic
for well over 20 years
and over those 22 years
I have had all kinds of
severe illnesses
and accidents etc
and so of necessity
the usual measures
I have had to investigate
what is the capacity
what is the power of consciousness itself
and I saw that all
that the analgesic did
was allow consciousness
to exercise its own power
therefore we can own
that we have that power
within our own consciousness
to achieve the same result
without the analgesic
we begin to move away from it
by letting go resisting it
let the pain be there
and what we are going to do
is shift our way of being
with that pain
we are going to shift our way
of being with it
to the point that we don't care
whether it is there or not
does that sound amazing
that you don't even care
whether it is there or not
it is very simple
many things in your life
you have been upset over
you know what I mean
some place in your backyard
that was driving you crazy
and one day you say
oh the heck with it
suddenly you move right
you see on this field
you move here from
trying to do something about it
and control it
and change it
and exert your will
see when you try to change others
or you try to change people
places and circumstances
the minute you let it be there
you like disappear your experience of it
you move all the way up to here
and we are going to show you
by the time we end the film
how to move all the way up
to a state of painlessness
a state of painlessness
in the presence of pain
the experience of that
the sensations
coming from
let's say a painful injury
are going on
and who cares about it
the sensations from this amputation
which I only did a few months ago
are going on
but I don't care about it
it makes no difference
if they are there, they are there
and if they are not, they are not
that all comes about
through that very simple practice
very simple practice
in which you are totally indifferent
most of the time
the pain that I have experienced in my own life
and other people who have used this technique
eventually the pain disappears of its own
minutes in the case of an acute injury
or it may take months
I had one illness that took
well over a year
of constantly letting go
constantly releasing, constantly surrendering
before it finally disappeared
so I know that the sensations
will eventually die out
but I am not doing it
to try to achieve that
you see that would be trying to change it
and trying to get rid of it
but I do know as a matter of clinical observation
that as you let go resisting it
you come to a point
where you don't care whether it is there or not
and then suddenly one morning
you wake up and it is gone
but we don't let go resisting it
in order to get rid of the pain
that is a happy side effect
when you reach the point
where you don't care whether it is there or not
then what difference does it make
whether it continues it or not
because at that point
you are like immune to the pain
this is a very good thing to know
that your mind has this power
and all you need is somebody
to point it out to you
and encourage you to try it
and you will see that it works
there is no need to be
in a state of suffering
over pain of any kind
pain is one thing
suffering is another
you have to say that over and over
to yourself
and begin to utilize these techniques
and then you will experience a separation
where there is you
and then there is the pain
you are not connected with it anymore
you are something over greater
than and beyond
that which is painful
and no longer suffering
how to handle the acute situation
how to handle the chronic situation
that leads us into the subject
of how to be with it
how to be with it
life's experiences
what is the meaning of them
is how you experience them
how you feel about them
it doesn't make any difference at all
what happens in the world
if you can be with it
in a certain way
so it isn't what's happening out there
it's how you are with it
people who are quite evolved
can be with
situations that look
dramatically tragic
and be unaffected by them
and how is that so
because they begin to become aware
of who they are
and so
one of the things that we can do
about pain
is consciously progress
in the movement and growth
of our own consciousness
pain proneness comes about
as a result of holding
a lot of negative kinds of thoughts
and feelings within us
so that general spiritual work
general work in consciousness
then has an overall value
the more
for instance
we forgive ourselves and others
we have a process
of forgiveness
which was not really heard about much
except in religion
and has now become
almost a social phenomena
now when you go about in your social life
and somebody brings up a resentment
the other people will look at them
because they know the next step
is this person has to learn
how to forgive that
or they are going to be at the painful effect of that
so we find that all pain and suffering
comes about
that which we are already holding in mind
why are some people
so susceptible
to pain and suffering
and other people it is very transitory
the pain and the suffering goes
through the surface of them
but not into the core of them
so that you can get extremely upset
over something
but that who you are within
remains unruffled
somehow there has been a differentiation
of who I am
from the experience
the pain is totally unruffled
and allows the experience
to flow through me
and upset
the upset lasts for hours
the emotional conflict
whatever it happens to be
but that which is within
that which is myself
does not even participate in that
that beginning differentiation
of what is my real self
from what is experience
letting go of the habit
of identifying that I am experience
that something is happening
but I am not the experience
how can we bring about
this evolution and this growth in our self
that takes us back
to the scale of consciousness
that we have here
and as we look at it
we will see how to be with chronic pain
so that we can transcend it
and no longer be
in a state of suffering
about it
you remember at the bottom of the chart
we said guilt has a negative energy field
which we calibrate at 30
death is zero
so prolonged and excessive guilt
for instance
makes us prone to sickness
accident, injury, pain and suffering
we see that the view of the world
the view of the world
that comes out of this guiltiness
which is a constant habit
is one of sin and suffering
we see that it brings about
self-hatred
and we see that the process
in consciousness is one of
destruction
self-destruction out of this self-hatredness
so one of the belief systems
we have to give up
is that
guilt and suffering
have any particular value
as we look at this
where we see
as we go up the energy fields
that those who are approaching
the energy fields of the saints
and the great beings
the closer you get to God
and suffering
as you experience the ultimate reality
you go through the doors
of a progressive lovingness
because love increases and expands
as you go up
through joy, through ecstasy
to a state of infinite peace
the Buddha or the Christ
or the great saints
or the enlightened beings of the planet
do not get there through guilt and pain and suffering
they go there through joy
so we have to give up worshipping
the God of suffering
we have to give up worshipping
for those of you who are Christians
the God of the crucifixion
the Christ of the crucifixion
and move on to the Christ
of the resurrection
the message was not that of death
and sin and suffering
people who identify themselves as a body
the strict materialist
looked at the Christ on the cross
as a body
and came out with pain, sin
guilt and suffering
was that the message?
is that what Christ died for
to teach everybody
that we are a physical body
or was his message the direct opposite
his message was the direct opposite
that we are not limited
that we are not that
and so we have to substitute
our confused ideas
and begin to look at
moving towards
a lovingness
to a higher state of consciousness
to get what the message was
the Christ of the resurrection
so we have to give up
that penance, guilt and sin
and suffering
are somehow of enormous spiritual benefit
frankly
all the hundreds and thousands of people
that I've clinically treated
over 35 years
who had chronic pain, guilt
sin and suffering
were the most selfish and self-centered persons
I had ever met
chronic pain and suffering
does not make you an enlightened loving being
it makes you usually cranky
horrible
selfish, self-centered
and brings you up to the next level
of
self-pity
most people with chronic pain
are into self-pity
they are into grief
they are into poor me
they are into the endless fear
of the continuation of their state
and whether it's going to get worse
they're constantly resisting it
the desire to get away from it
these are all negative energy fields
they are very very angry
the anger of the person
in chronic pain is enormous
they are stuck in it
and they are very proud of the fact
that nobody has been able
to help them with this
and they will tell you
of all the doctors they went to
and all the treatments they had
and how all of those things didn't work
we want to move up to the
courage, the capacity
the fact that something can be done
about the way we can be
with this pain
the way that we can be with it
by using our simple
letting go resisting
technique
our willingness to do that
are we willing to try something
do we have the courage to try it
to let go resisting it
and end up at least detached
to at least move out of this
state of suffering
you see these energy fields are negative
we move up to an energy field
up around here you see
that the needle swings to the right
it means these are states of less and less
suffering as we move up into joy
so how can I be
with that chronic condition
can I be willing to be with that
can I let go resisting it
can I begin to differentiate
that I am that which is with it
how to be with that
can I accept that
can I accept
my capacity to be with it
in a state of
non suffering
we see that the
we look at the emotions that go with these
particular energy fields
and we see the emotions
that go with chronic pain
we see self hatred
the feeling that one is
a victim
the self hatred of the victim
we see the process going on in consciousness
there is a destructive one
we see the hopelessness
nothing can be done about my condition
what we said about
the nature of the power of mind is
that if you hold that in mind
you literally create that as your experience
the person who
says my condition
is hopeless
then creates for themself
a condition which is hopeless
and resistive to treatment
we see the
person in grief
we move them up into apathy into grief
that they are in a constant state of regret
a feeling of loss
a feeling of despondency
these are feelings which are only human
these are not feelings
that we want to feel guilty about
these are feelings we want to understand
through understanding
they become resolved
when I recently cut this thumb off
I went through all of these
first the feeling I was being punished somehow
attacked by the forces of
retribution or something
the pain was acute
and I looked at it and I felt hopeless
into despair
and replaced etc
and I went into grief
and mourning
you know grieving and mourning
as though you had lost a loved one
a fear of the consequences
a fear that this pain and suffering
was going to continue and go on
and I felt myself resisting
the desire to get away from
the injury the disability
the pain the suffering the surgery whatever
and feeling angry
angry at life angry at fate
angry at myself
I felt I was only very human
and then moving into pride
that I was going to do something about it
and the courage to begin to look at
what are the techniques that I know work
in this kind of a circumstance
and the willingness to begin utilizing them
and begin letting go
resisting and using that technique
and eventually moving up
into the acceptance of it
so that if it's there
it's ok if it's there
and if it's not there
it's ok if it's not there
that's the field here
there's one in which we say
yes it's ok either way
it's ok
when we're totally released
from our resistance to the pain
we don't care if it's there
if it's there it's fine
and if it's not there that's fine too
the willingness to be forgiving
and we want to move eventually
into compassion
that acceptance of the human condition
and of the human experience
without being resentful about it
without feeling pity
without being angry
without being prideful
and going into a make wrong
without attacking ourself
how can we move up to an energy field
called love or even joy
in that I can only go back to my own experience
my own personal experience
of what is possible
what is possible
when somebody shares with us their experience
then we learn what is possible
in human consciousness
as I move through this experience
what happened was
I began to call on
some power greater than myself
I kept surrendering it
turning it over
I remember I went to the emergency room
I had to inform them
I couldn't take anesthesia
or analgesia of any kind
and so the surgeon was
somewhat perplexed about
how this was going to be handled
and I said I have my own ways
I have my own ways
and to make him feel better
I had a self hypnotic technique
and this would make
so anyway he relaxed
feeling that it was being handled
and what I did then was
I went in with inside myself
and I released and let go
and let go resisting
and I called upon
the God of my own understanding
that aspect of one's greater self
we don't need to believe in God
but we can believe
that there is some energy field
greater than our personal self
which has unlimited power
and so what I did
is by constantly surrendering
and let's face it
when you're in a situation like that
overwhelmed by excruciating pain
and suffering
all the props are pulled out
I mean this is when you really come up
with what you really believe in
and it is a great opportunity
and so as I let go
surrendering
and let go resisting
suddenly it was as though
I was lifted out of my body
I came into a state of profound inner peace
an incredible state
of stillness
exquisite inner serenity
and joy
and I realized that something
other than my personal self
was handling this experience
something other than the personal David
was handling the pain
and so this is something
we've learned to do
with chronic pain
to surrender it
to one's personal God
to whatever one believes in
to handle the pain for us
what happens when we do this
is the experience of
something greater than
one's personal self
handles that pain
that was my personal experience
that some great energy
came in
and that great energy
you can call it a great energy
because you can verify the existence
of that great energy
this great energy
handled it for me
it's like I said
God I can't do it
you do it for me
and so I turned my burden over
and allowed that
which is in the universe
to handle it for me
for those of you
to whom this seems like
perhaps an outlandish experience
let's look at it then
from a level that would be understandable
if you're in a state of
550 where healing begins to take place
within the brain
there is the release of endorphins
in other words
the brain within itself
from this energy field
begins to release endorphins
endorphins are those
things released by narcotics
it isn't the narcotic at all
that has the effect on the brain
but the fact that the narcotic releases
these so called opioids
that are released
the endorphins within the brain
and so therefore
subsequent to the experience
I was aware that within me
there was something
that was handling the pain for me
automatically
it didn't involve my personal self at all
and as the
intensity of the pain would increase
that within me
that energy field
which expresses itself
on the physical plane
through the release of these endorphins
automatically handling the pain
when we calibrated
the energy field
of that power
within our self
which is automatically handling the pain
we calibrated
an energy field at 750
within us
is the capacity
of letting go our smallness
you might say this is all our smallness
and summoning forth
that which is already
present and within us
a powerful energy field
of a plus 750
that energy field has the power
to handle the pain
the pain and the suffering
was completely and totally relieved
and there was instead
a state of infinite inner serenity
and peace
that inner serenity and peace
stays within
in a permanent kind of a basis
those are ways
to be with that
ways to be with that
and how can we
augment our
endeavors in these directions
because certainly
spiritual work
work in consciousness
we can do it acutely
but those processes
such as forgiveness and all
take a period of time
in the meantime
what can we do
what about such
ancillary procedures
as acupuncture and hypnosis
we know that acupuncture
can be extremely effective
there is certainly nothing wrong
we said that all illnesses
all pain suffering forms
are physical mental and spiritual
and so I just described to you
how it's handled from the spiritual
before that we described
how it is handled on the level of
consciousness itself
through the mind
and certainly at the same time
we want to do what we can physically
acupuncture in my own experience
extremely effective
I myself had an ulcer
for some 20 or 25 years
it was intractable and incurable
I had every treatment
known to medical science
it was only a matter of time
before we would have to have
a subtotal gastrectomy
and reparative gastrointestinal surgery
which is a major procedure
let me tell you
and so I tried acupuncture
and frankly by the third treatment
the pain and suffering left
so I know myself that these
are very very effective
and I would certainly add acupuncture
for chronic intractable pain
it certainly is one of the things
that we want to try
we know that the reliance on analgesics
has two negative effects
one is because it is such a
magical short term solution
you never grow in consciousness
you feel that the power
you give away your power to this pill
the power which is really
that of your own consciousness
you give it to the pill
and you stop your own growth
so that's one negative effect
the other of course is the progressive dependency
on the analgesics and the narcotics
which create and compounds
the whole problem now
with a problem that may be more severe
than the one you started with
so what other techniques are available to us
let's talk a little bit about hypnosis
certainly a great deal
is known about hypnosis now
it once was a subject
that medicine avoided
but now medicine is very interested
in acupuncture
and hypnosis
what kind of hypnotic techniques
what is the place of these
in the healing of chronic pain
first thing we need to know
is that the only form of hypnosis
that is really acceptable
is that of self hypnosis
it is not advisable
for reasons having to do with consciousness
and for other reasons
that we can't go into in this tape
it is inadvisable
to seek hypnosis from another
but to learn it from yourself
and what do you do once you learn it
once you learn this technique
and we will describe in the next few minutes
exactly how to do it
it is extremely simple
you can use the hypnotic state
which is really only a state
of high suggestibility
to learn the very things
we have been talking about today
if you put yourself in an extremely relaxed state
and begin to experiment
and experience out
the truth of what we have been talking about today
the learning is much faster
what is the value of self hypnosis
in my experience is
that it enables you
to reach a level of concentration
that you wouldn't be able to reach otherwise
that is really its value
in that suggestible state
you are capable of
degrees of concentration
that you aren't ordinarily capable of
because you are too distracted
by what is going on in consciousness
so what is a very simple technique
that you can utilize
and I think anybody
who has any chronic physical condition
should really learn how to do this
it is extremely simple
you just sit down in a very relaxed state
and what you are going to do now
is progressively relax yourself
so instead of the word hypnosis
which has all kinds of stage
stage meanings
and occult meanings
forget all that
we are going to talk now
about extreme relaxation
and a state of heightened suggestibility
and the capacity to concentrate
and so we can do this
with a very simple technique
of counting from 1 to 10
we sit down
we lie down in a very comfortable position
and we start out
by saying to ourselves
number 1
that announces to us
that we are about to do this procedure
we then go into number 2
you can picture yourself
in 10 steps
the first step
you are initiating the experience
in the next step
what you do is
you allow yourself some time
to relax all the muscles in your head
all the muscles
and you notice as you do that
the soreness in your face muscles
and your jaw muscles
the tension of the day
your cheeks are actually sore
just poke right here now
as you watch me and you will see
that you are in 10 all day long
so you allow yourself several minutes
to relax the head
you move on to number 3
where you relax your neck
you relax all those tensions in your neck
and your upper shoulders
you move into number 4
where you say to yourself
focus 4
you move and you relax your back
and your chest muscles
and number 5
you just progressively relax
starting with the biggest muscles
the upper arms and the lower arms
and the fingers and the hands
number 6
you allow your chest and your torso to relax
number 7
you move into the lower abdomen
relaxing all the tensions
that you have been holding in your belly
and your guts
number 8
you move into the hips and the buttocks
and the general regions
and allow all those relaxations
number 9
you allow that to flow down your legs
now you tell yourself
I am in focus 10
and you use that letting go resistance
which we have been talking about
throughout this
visit today
allowing yourself to let go
all resistance to this profound
state of relaxation
and in this profound state of relaxation
you now tell yourself
the things you want to know
and let go resisting them
let go resisting the thought
that pain
is something
and suffering is something else
there is no such thing
as suffering in pain
when that pain is not resisted
in that profoundly relaxed state
now you let go resisting
the pain
because it is going to be used
for a chronic pain condition
you are going to go back to the things we said
notice that the pain is everywhere
notice that you can let go your resistance
to that pain
notice that you can like open the door
that you can let it happen
without it affecting
that which you really are
in it you can begin
to move yourself up through these energy fields
as we described before
you can move yourself up
to a lovingness for yourself
a compassion
for your beauty as a human being
we said it about an energy
field of 540 to 550
this lovingness comes forth
how do you know when that has happened
it has happened when you can
become light hearted about it
when you can laugh at yourself
you see I tell everybody
they say you lost your thumb
I say that is right I can only count up to 9
you can only count up to 9 now
so your capacity to laugh at yourself
humor
we got the energy field of humor
is at about 550
humor heals
and certainly there has been books out recently
by people who are celebrities
who are well known
who have healed physical illnesses
the use of laughter
and so laughter
the choosing of laughter
the choosing of humor
putting yourself in a loving
laughing energy field
which tends to heal of its own nature
we know that an energy field
a positive energy field
of 550
the capacity now to laugh at that misfortune
what does that do for you
it means that
the experience is one thing
and that which I am in truth
is something else
I am not that experience
you see I am not at the effect of that
I am no longer victim
I have stopped struggling with it
I have stopped resisting
you notice that as you go through
acceptance and willingness
and through neutral
you become released from that
and what does that mean
you see when you are resisting it
and trying to get away from it
you are down here
and you see the process is one of entrapment
and suffering
so long as I resist the pain
so long as I am angry
and grit my teeth
and struggle against it
and try to force my will
I become further enmeshed
it's like the quagmire
the more I struggle
the more entrapped I become
the being let go of going free
see this energy field over here
is one of freedom
as we go into freedom
means to be released from that
the courage to face this issue
and do something about it
empowers me
my willingness moves me up
through a transformation of consciousness
into my willingness to be forgiving
and loving and compassionate
and through my own experience
one can transcend it
literally move beyond that
identification with the body
and what has happened to it
into a conscious awareness
that one is something other than the body
when we talk about health
one other visit that we'll have
about this series
we'll talk about the body being in such a state
that one is hardly even aware
of its existence
that everything is so harmonious
the letting go of resistance
has been so complete
that there is hardly any awareness
that the body is even there
this also happens with pain
in which the thought
the memory
the awareness
that there is some pain there
only happens for a few fleeting seconds
during the day
although this happened a few months ago
I use this example of the thumb
only as an example of the realness
of what I'm talking about
it only comes to me a couple seconds
throughout the day now
that there is pain still there
after I'm up about an hour
suddenly I'll notice the thumb
and I'll say, oh
it's like I'm not even aware of its presence
maybe a few other times
in the daytime
that I experience in a 24 hour period
now
with this which is still
as the world would say, painful
is literally amounts to
probably a few seconds
maybe 5 or 10 seconds in the morning
maybe a few seconds in the afternoon
the totality of suffering
coming out of this experience
which is only a couple months old
and for an amputation that's not a long period of time
amounts to probably less than 30 seconds
can all do it
because through doing it we realize
who we really are