I'm Dr. David Hawkins. I've been a psychiatrist for the last 35 years,
psychoanalyst, nutritionist, researcher into the relationship between nutrition and brain chemistry.
The last 10 years I've been doing research on the nature of consciousness itself
and its relationship to that which the world calls spiritual.
This involves the relationship between body, mind, and spirit.
What is the relationship between body, mind, and spirit?
And how does it relate to our topic for today, which is how to let go of depression?
Depression, despondency, that plague of mankind which has been there since ancient biblical days
and which today is being called a minor epidemic.
A minor epidemic with a rising suicide rate amongst young people, especially adolescents.
Very timely, very important in all of our lives.
Few of us have managed to live on this planet.
For any great length of time without experiencing depression.
Maybe minor in the form of regrets, mourning, loss, loss of loved ones,
the loss of things that we have valued in our life because of their meaning.
And so we're going into that today looking at it from the viewpoint of consciousness,
but we'll also cover what is the place of biochemistry, what is the place of antidepressants.
Are these the cause or are these the effect of the depression?
In talking about this, we'll again have to review what is that relationship between body, mind, and spirit,
which we'll be talking about because we'll be talking about the treatment
and the understanding of depression on all three levels.
So we need to review again, as we have in other talks in this series,
the fact that the body has no way of experiencing itself.
The body cannot experience its own bodiness.
It cannot experience its own sensations.
The body is experienced in mind.
Mind, curiously enough, also has no real capacity to experience itself.
Memories, thoughts, feelings, fantasies of the future, daydreams,
all of these are registered and experienced in a field which is larger and more diffuse,
a field of energy that we call consciousness.
A field that is currently being researched with advanced theoretical physics.
The relationship of mind to this great field called consciousness.
Consciousness itself, curiously, has to be experienced by something even greater
and formless, and that we call awareness.
So it is because of awareness that we're aware of what is going on within consciousness.
Consciousness allows us to know that which is going on in mind.
Mind allows us to know that which is going on in our feelings, our emotions, our memory.
It allows us to know what the sensations are from the body,
reporting to us our experience of the body.
Therefore, all of this is going on within consciousness itself.
And in this, as well as our other talks, we have emphasized the importance of addressing issues,
and addressing the highest level, the level where there is the most power,
so that a change on the level of consciousness, a change within mind,
brings about an alteration within the body.
In talking about depression, that aspect of the part of the body we'll be interested in is the brain.
The brain and its hormones and its neurotransmitters,
and how depression affects the physiology of the brain.
What are the real causes of depression then?
As we look into that, we will be looking at a map of consciousness,
which we have been using in this series of talks.
A mathematical model in which we have levels of consciousness in what we call the box.
The levels of consciousness starting from the lowest,
which we have calibrated at zero, death,
all the way to the highest, calibrated at 600,
which is a very high, joyful state,
and one beyond which the world calls enlightenment.
Within those levels, you will see that the energy fields have a direction,
indicated by the arrows.
The indication of the arrows is whether we experience this as a positive asset in our life,
or whether it has a negative deleterious effect.
And we notice that in about the middle of the box,
at a level called courage, which is calibrated at an energy field of 200,
that these energies now,
suddenly go neutral.
And we notice that those energy fields above the level of courage,
a level which we cross by telling the truth,
now the energy fields swing to the right and indicate a positive
or life-supportive energy field,
all the way up to love at 500 and joy at 540.
This will be important for us to refer to,
to have a context in which to hold our subject for today,
because we are going to be talking about the bottom of the box.
We are going to be talking about those human experiences,
starting at the bottom called guilt, apathy, grief.
These energy fields expressing themselves in an emotion,
self-hatred, self-recrimination, hopelessness, despair, despondency,
all these accompanied by feelings of regret, loss and despondency.
In these energy fields of depression then,
our view of the world, our view of the world is that it is a sad
and hopeless place of sin and suffering.
Our view of God then, the God of a world like that,
would be one who is unfeeling, uncaring,
from whom you are separated, who ignores you,
or possibly is dead, or at its worst, if he is alive,
would perhaps be the destroyer.
Out of your guiltiness, worthlessness, sinfulness,
a God like that would throw you into hell,
absolute destruction forever.
When we look over at the process going on in consciousness
in these lower energy fields,
we see coming out of deflated, the one right above it,
we come into one called dispirited,
the loss of that energy of life, the desire to live.
Coming lower to this apathy state,
we see that the process going on in consciousness
is the loss of energy.
Because of the loss of the life energy within,
which comes within the being,
it no longer attracts energy from the universe,
and so our process is one of being de-energized,
leading to the self-hatred of destruction
and these states preceding death,
so that out of this we often see a pattern of passive suicide.
So today we'll be looking at
active suicide and passive suicide.
What do they come out of?
How can they be handled?
What do they really mean?
In what way can we create an understanding
of this whole field of depression,
this plague of mankind?
How can we benefit from an understanding
coming out of the study of the nature of consciousness itself?
We notice that all these energy fields below the level of courage
have a direction,
and a negative direction.
And seldom do one of these emotions come through
all by themselves.
Generally, one negative emotion tends to pull
all of them to some degree,
so that in depression then,
there is also feelings coming from this level
of self-blame, self-hatred.
There's feelings coming from this level
of hopelessness and despair.
There's regrets about the past,
and fears about the future.
Very often there is anger,
and we often hear it said
that depression is anger turned inward.
So one way that's recommended in traditional psychotherapy
is to try to energize and bring up the anger
which is accompanying the depression.
But then we have to ask,
so then what is the source of the anger?
And we will find out that both the anger and the depression
are coming from the same error.
From having made the same mistake
within the mind, within consciousness itself.
And what is that error which we're going to find,
whether we look at the anger,
we look at the fear,
we look at the grief, the apathy, the guilt.
We'll find that for some reason
the person has placed their survival
on something outside of themself.
We see that all these energy fuels here,
which are in this direction,
are based on placing the source of your happiness
as something outside of oneself.
It comes from having been vulnerable.
It comes from being the victim.
Being the victim, being at the effect of
a cause that we see as being outside
of our own consciousness.
We put the source of our happiness
somehow out into the world.
And so that vulnerability to depression
is there, and so long as we
put the source of our happiness
as something outside of ourself.
That common frailty of human consciousness
to say that, well, when I get that degree,
then I'll be successful and happy.
When I learn that foreign language,
when I get to move into that apartment,
when I get that fur coat,
when I get that new car,
when I get that PhD,
when I get my medical license,
if I can only get that internship,
if I could get that relationship,
if I could just change that person out there,
if I could get my aunt to stop drinking,
if our company would only come out of the red
and go into the black,
it is always out there.
Placing the source of one's happiness then
outside of oneself is putting oneself
in the vulnerable position to depression,
anxiety, fear, and a potential loss.
It's only by owning ourself
as the source of our happiness,
the experience of our own existence,
independent and beyond that which happens
within the world that we become immune
to depressive episodes.
And so to understand that,
we'll have to review briefly
this map of consciousness again.
Those of you who have seen the other talks,
each time that we look at it,
we're going to be looking at it from a different angle
with a different emphasis.
And each time we look at it,
it alters our own understanding
of the nature of human consciousness.
And so it's never the same every time we look at it
because we're coming at it from a different context
now with a broader understanding.
And so we look at it again and we'll see,
as we said before, that these energy fields
are calibrated as to their energy,
the relative energy and power of them.
That they have either a negative direction
or a positive direction.
And that there's a crucial crossover
in the middle at the level of courage,
which we said is crossed over by the telling of the truth.
In this case, the telling of the truth
is that my happiness does not depend
on anything outside of myself.
I myself, by my own inner decision,
by my own integrity, by my intentions,
by the way I see myself and my relationship
to the events of life,
am the source of my own happiness.
And so at the bottom we have maximum victimhood.
In which the total source of one's happiness,
the total source of one's happiness
has been placed outside of oneself.
The loss of that brings about self-contempt,
self-hatred, there is nothing within the self now to love
because that which was loved
was seen as something outside of oneself.
The stage above that with an energy field of apathy,
which we know as hopelessness and despair,
is a state of no energy.
So that a person in that state,
we would say, is in a severe clinical depression.
The person is usually unresponsive.
They sit in the chair and stare blankly out the window,
very often unresponsive,
into any communication, unable to talk,
very often stop eating,
may not be able to sleep,
unable to function in the world.
Those are the severe depressions.
And these people, of course, are seeing their life as sad,
they see the future as hopeless,
they see themselves as empty and worthless.
Their conception of God, as we've mentioned before,
the God of that kind of a world
is a God who ignores you and doesn't care for you,
so it's a state of total unlovingness,
feeling unloved.
Our clinical experience indicates that these lower three states,
which collectively we call despondency and depression,
come out of the failure
to have handled the energy field above it,
which we call fear.
The facing of the underlying fear.
Because the depression is coming about
from the loss of meaning.
So it isn't the things outside of ourself
that we've placed our happiness on,
that is the difficulty,
it's the meaning that we have attached to that.
It isn't the PhD degree,
it's the meaning of that PhD degree.
It isn't that relationship,
it's the meaning of that relationship.
It isn't that position or title as president of the company,
or financial success,
or having the right address.
It's the meaning,
the way in which we held those things,
their importance and their value.
What we projected onto that,
the way we hold it now then,
depends on the meaning that we have given it.
In and of itself, it has no meaning.
In and of itself, it merely is.
So meaning is a construction.
A mental construction
that we have projected out onto
by giving a thing value.
The value then is coming out of our own consciousness,
projected onto something that we are seeing
as outside of ourself.
Seeing oneself as separated
from the source of happiness.
There is myself,
and then there is that outside myself
from which I feel separated.
Then the fantasy that if I could reunite with that,
have that, control it,
then that would heal
the inner feeling of lack and separation.
To feel separated from that which one wants
is to feel separated from God.
So that over here the view of God then
in these depressed states
is that you are totally separated
from the source of your happiness.
As we move out of depression into fear,
the way to get out of the depression then
is to look at the underlying fear.
What is the fear?
Let's take the woman rocking back and forth
in her chair staring out the window
who got the telegram from the State Department
that her son was killed in action.
And we said in another talk on this subject,
and this is actually clinically
an example of what actually happened,
is within several weeks she got a telegram
from the State Department stating that it was a mistake
and that the serial number was off by one day.
And curiously enough the name had been the same.
Then they corrected the error
and the State Department regretted
the previous telegram.
So when the family told her this,
she just kept on rocking back and forth
and staring out the window.
Mother, mother, they all shook her and said,
didn't you hear? Joey is not dead.
He's alive. He's fine.
He's in an R&R camp in Vietnam.
And she kept on rocking back and forth.
So that something had happened.
You see, something had happened.
The energy field then, the state,
she had obviously been holding her son
and her relationship to her son
as a source, a major source of happiness,
being a widow.
That relationship was prime in her life.
Now something had happened.
The energy of the field had now brought about
a change in the brain chemistry.
And so we see that the shift in brain chemistry now
is a consequence.
It was due to the loss of the meaning in her life.
This energy field then expresses itself
on the level of brain chemistry.
We said all things are physical,
mental, and spiritual.
Spiritually, the meaning here,
the separation from God.
Emotionally, the significance of this relationship.
And now on the physical level,
in the brain chemistry,
there was a shift.
There was a loss of neurotransmitters.
So we see in the brain then,
in a depressive condition,
a depression of essential neurotransmitters,
in certain areas of the brain.
And this accompanies the depression.
And it's possible then to ameliorate
the expression of this symptom
on the physical level
by the use of antidepressants.
And in treating all these conditions,
we find it most efficacious to treat them
all levels simultaneously.
To address the person in a dialogue
where they begin to examine
how they have placed meaning and significance
fill the emptiness,
internal emptiness of their life
with things from the outside
to give it meaning and significance.
Thereby creating this vulnerability.
The way it's held psychologically.
And at the same time to treat it
on the physical level.
So the antidepressants nowadays
are very effective.
The side effects are easy to watch for and control.
Generally it is a very safe thing
to treat pharmacologically.
And the antidepressants are very effective.
Often used in combinations
perhaps with some other drugs such as lithium.
They're extremely effective.
They take the person out of the bottom of the box
and lift them up to a higher state.
So that in a higher state
they're then able to respond to psychotherapy
or spiritual counseling
to try and alleviate the conditions
that brought about this vulnerability.
Facing the fear then,
facing the fear
that underlies the depression,
relieves the depression.
And what is the fear?
The fear is I have lost the meaning of my life.
I have lost that which is of value.
And it will never be replaced.
See depression, hopelessness
means that the expectation of the future is zero.
There is no hope that meaning and significance
that a context will be recreated
that will re-energize
and give one's life meaning again.
This of course is an illusion.
But at the time the hopelessness
is based on this perspective,
this perception of one's self
and one's relationship to life.
The willingness to face the fear.
So when we have a depressed person
we look to see what is the loss here.
The loss of the job,
the loss of vitality,
the loss of youth.
People become depressed.
Middle age, the loss of opportunity.
They see middle age as
life having passed them by
and now they've lost their opportunity.
The loss of looks to a person
in whom their looks
has been very important in their life
and their way of relating
and their sense of self-value.
The middle-aged woman
who feels she is losing her looks.
And if she is based on her power in the world
and valued that greatly,
then the loss of the looks to her
is a great danger.
And not just a superficial thing
such as vanity.
It's far more than that.
It's her whole sense of self-worth and value.
Beauty to her has become
that which is valuable
and makes her a worthwhile person.
So we look to see
what is the underlying fear
and we get the person
to be willing to look at this fear.
Instead of depression,
now what the person has to handle is fear.
Because fear has to do with the future.
How am I going to live
without this which has given my life significance?
We see this in the addictions, for instance.
You might say
that anybody who gets depressed
has been addicted.
Addicted to what?
Addicted to
placing their survival
on something outside of themself.
In the addiction,
if we threaten to take away
that which is outside of themself,
the person has been placing their survival
on happiness, in this case the drug,
we see terror.
Not only fear, but absolute terror.
The conviction within
that it will be impossible to live in this world
without access to that substance.
And so we have the person look at the fear
and then utilize the time
and the techniques, clinically,
that we have found handle fear.
The willingness to be with the fear.
Stop labeling it.
Stop the thoughts.
Focus instead on the exact experience
of what is coming up
as one looks at
that which is feared within mind.
To look at that
and then to go into the radical truth
of what is literally being experienced
within oneself.
And the willingness to surrender to that
and to let go resisting the fear.
As this happens,
the sensations run through the body.
I say to the person,
what are you experiencing in your body?
My mouth is so dry I can hardly talk.
My heart feels like it's fluttering.
My stomach feels like it's turning over.
I feel cramps in my abdomen.
My knees are so weak I can hardly stand up.
Then we start with them one by one.
We say, all right,
the tingling in your legs and your knees,
could you let go resisting that?
Could you just let yourself experience that
and be with that?
What are you feeling here?
Just sense what you're sensing.
What are you sensing?
Well, I'm sensing a tingling in my legs.
And I say, can you handle a tingling in your legs?
You've handled headaches.
You've handled major surgery.
You've handled deaths in the family.
I'm certain you can handle a tingling in your legs.
And the person will say, yes, I can handle that.
I say, okay, let go resisting the tingling in the legs.
Now, how about the cramps in the abdomen?
Could you let go resisting that?
Right.
Could you stop calling them cramps?
Can you let go resisting that?
Right.
Let's go up higher.
What about the flip-flops in the stomach?
Can you handle that?
Yes, I can handle that.
Can you just handle the experience,
stop calling it flip-flops in your stomach?
How about the beating of your pulse?
Could you let go wanting to resist that?
Just let your pulse beat away if it wants to.
How about the dry mouth?
And so we get the person to realize,
yes, I can handle that.
And we agree.
Nobody can handle fearful thoughts.
There is no such thing as handling fearful thoughts.
Fearful thoughts create themselves by the thousands.
And as you handle one whole bank of fearful thoughts,
a whole new bank will arise.
I'll be late for the plane.
I won't get on the plane.
I'll be afraid of the plane.
Something's going to happen on the plane.
I might go to the bathroom.
I mean, the mind will just create an endless series of fears.
What it can handle is a dry mouth,
tingling in the legs.
And the only thing a person benefits
is relief of depression.
They say, oh, I see I'm not depressed.
I see I was terrified of the future,
that I will never find happiness
without that which I wished,
longed for, desired.
And I was convinced that I had to have that
in order to survive and be happy.
You know, when you talk to people
who were convinced of that
and were on sizable doses of drugs,
I mean, they were really as close to actually
needing something to survive
as anybody could be on the planet.
When they faced the fear of it all,
they found that life was joyful.
Life was complete. Life was full.
They enjoyed life for the first time.
So we know it's based on an illusion,
and therefore we have the courage
for the patient to take them with us
to look at the fear,
like we take the child by the hand.
When I was a kid, you know,
somebody on the block told me about boogeymen.
And so my mother had ridiculed
boogeymen and ghosts and things like that,
but somehow this kid's convincing this.
You know, he was five years older than I was,
so he knew what he was talking about.
So what my mother did is take me by the hand
and we went down to the dark basement
with flashlights and we looked all over for boogeymen.
So to have someone with you
to look at this fear then is helpful
because our child is frightened.
Our child doesn't understand
the nature of real life in this world.
And so the child comes up and says,
gee, without that I won't be able to survive.
And very often it has been
a parent substitute,
which was envisioned as being out there.
What about animals?
They don't understand anger
because it said, you know,
as we said before, that depression
is anger turned within.
What is the basis of the anger then?
Let's take somebody who is really
into survival on something outside of themself.
Again, we'll use the attic, let's say.
And you threaten to take away his bottle
or his supplier, flush his drugs down the toilet.
And he goes into a rage.
Now it's very clear to us
what the source of the anger is, is it not?
The source of the anger
is exactly the same fantasy,
that the source of happiness
is something outside of myself.
I have placed it on some object,
some person, place, or thing.
The place,
the source of your happiness
on something outside of yourself
puts you in a negative energy field
because basically it is a lie.
The source of your happiness
is not something outside of yourself at all.
It's only when we own
that we are the source of our happiness
that the energy field goes
in a positive direction.
So we can move the person then
out of depression and despondency,
get them to face the fear,
get them to desire something better
for themself,
turn that anger into the anger
at being victim.
The anger instead of at the loss of the object.
See, the endless rationalizations
and explanations
to try and make this anger sound justified.
They promised me this,
they signed a contract,
they sent a check
to make it sound good.
The source of that is always outside of ourself
and the explanations,
the details,
the events are only justifications
for this anger.
And so we use this anger now
instead we turn it at anger
at the vulnerability.
You say, now it's time to be angry
at what the real cause was
and the real cause was
I was brought up in a world
which taught me to think this way.
I was taught that this is the right way to think.
This is the way to be angry at.
That we were taught how to think
in a way that set us up
as potential victim,
the source of happiness.
The great American way is success.
Is it not?
Will success bring us happiness?
Where I used to live in the East
was a whole row of millionaires
and they routinely committed suicide
and took overdoses
and they were not at all immune
to the human vulnerabilities.
So worldly success,
what we need to be angry at
is what got us to sell ourselves out
and how did we sell ourselves out
and then to take pride in the fact
that we are willing to look at this.
Move up to the courage
to tell the truth about it.
The truth is
something within our consciousness
set us up to be vulnerable.
That's the truth.
And so if I start to take responsibility now
and I say,
the way I was looking at this
set me up for this depression.
Set me up for this frustration and anger.
Set me up for this let down.
Set me up for this disappointment.
The courage then to look at that
and be willing to tell the truth about it
now changes the way I feel
about the whole subject.
And I can now move up to a situation
where I say to myself,
well, it's okay.
It's okay.
That's how people are taught in this world
and I grew up in this world
and I guess I learned the same as everybody.
But I'm willing to look at it
in a different way
and so we move up to willingness.
The willingness to look at it
and say, yes, I agree to look at this.
My intention is up
and I see at least the subject
is promising and hopeful.
The God of a friendly world
In other words, there's going to be
some benefit to me
not only in this particular situation
but there's going to be
a benefit to me as a human being
that will last my lifetime
because if I solve this one
I've solved it for all time within myself.
The willingness to look at that
and the willingness to accept
what I find out
gives me a certain confidence.
A certain confidence that there is a process
going on within me.
That this depression has arisen
to bring something to my attention.
It's as though it's saying
something is out, something is wrong
within my mind, within my consciousness,
within my spiritual position.
That's what pain means, doesn't it?
Pain means, please look at me,
something is out.
Pharmacologically we can treat the depression,
of course, we can get the person
out of it temporarily.
But the person and his way of being in the world
and the way he's holding who he is
and how he relates to the world
and his universe and his expectations
is not changed.
So the vulnerability remains the same.
And we know that people who are treated
with just antidepressants
will recover from this episode.
Why?
Because the whole context has not changed.
Without an understanding
and depth into the nature of
consciousness itself,
the vulnerability remains.
And so the person is subject
to repeated bouts of depression
within their lifetime.
In looking at this in a holistic way
from the viewpoint of body, mind and spirit
we want to address what is the basic cause
so as to
bring about an immunity
from further episodes
of this debilitating experience.
The acceptance then,
moving into accepting
what is the setup
and seeing what the setup is
without blaming oneself,
without getting into a make wrong.
There's nothing wrong with it,
it's just that it doesn't work.
We've been trained in our world
to think that way.
We're all set up to think that way.
Our parents were set up to think that way
and therefore they set us up.
They just passed it on down.
There are several times
when there's descriptions
of very severe depressions.
So it belongs sort of
in the collective consciousness
and we all got brainwashed
with the same programs
that somehow happiness
and the source of it
is outside oneself.
You see as we move up here,
the willingness to tell the truth,
the willingness to look at this,
we see the energy fields,
the numbers, the power of the field
numbers jump like this
and why is the energy field positive
instead of negative?
It's because above the level of courage
the person has stopped projecting
the source of their happiness
outside of themself.
The person has begun to re-own
their own power.
We see that the level of courage,
the willingness to tell the truth,
to face with the situation,
cope with it and handle it,
we see the process going on
within their power.
And by the time we move up
to this energy level of acceptance
which we see they're a person
that's confident and easy-going,
what is the confidence
and easy-goingness coming from?
It's coming from the awareness
that I am the source of my happiness.
It means that person
has realized by now
in their emotional and psychological
and spiritual growth
that they are the cause
of the happiness in their life.
It's like a person on a desert island
somewhere in the South Pacific
and sail away.
And you come back a year later
they'll have a coconut factory
and they'll be making flutes out of bamboo
and the children will be learning songs
and be teaching French to the natives.
He'll find a native girl
and build a tree house within the tree.
Recreated now for himself
the world around him as an expression
that we are the source of our own happiness.
The anger now,
the anger was based on
a deeper level
is the anger at having sold ourselves out,
having been sold out,
by having been given this program
to operate by
and then find that it doesn't work.
Our accepting that it doesn't work,
our willingness to look at that
and our willingness to change
and say, okay,
because how long does it take
to find a position from which it will work?
It only really takes a matter of seconds.
How long does it take to come out of depression?
It only takes as long as
it takes for one to become willing
to look at the truth of what's happened,
you see.
The acceptance that that is what has happened
and the realization
that I am the source of my own happiness,
that that capacity is within me
and my unwillingness
to give it out to the world anymore.
The reowning of that power
and suddenly you feel
a state of lovingness.
Suddenly it doesn't matter
what happens out there.
The realization of that truth
allows you to experience yourself now
in a far more whole
and complete way.
Not from that lackingness,
not from that vulnerability.
Just this realization
that I am the source,
I have the power to create.
It is myself that projected
the meaning onto this.
Therefore,
they say one man's meat
is another man's poison.
The same event
which would make one person happy
is another person happy.
I have watched people resist
coming into money for instance
because it was not within their value system.
It is not what they valued.
What they valued at the time
was not having money
and therefore
you were just giving them a problem.
Winning the lottery
might make one person joyful
and fill the other one with guilt.
Why?
The difference is meaning.
Who creates the meaning?
Who gave this something
outside of oneself
the power and the significance?
I am the creator of the meaning.
I am the one who chooses
what meaning to give.
Therefore I have to look at
the way in which I have
bought into social consciousness.
Look at the values that I have
unwittingly allowed myself
to be programmed by
and say to myself
do I agree with that?
Am I willing to give it that same value?
The realization now
that I have the power
to resource myself
to recontextualize my life
to see how I have been doing this
it brings me a state of inner joy.
The realization that
I, I alone have the choice now.
I have the power.
I am the one that sets up the meaning
and gives these things
the power over me.
Therefore it is really possible
to come out of disappointment
and grief and sadness
and anger about the event
or even indifference
to become willing
to really look into it
and re-experience my own inner self.
Actually a depressive episode
even a brief one
has within it then
actually the potential for joy
because it is something
coming up in our life saying
look at me, look at me, look at me
here is a mistake that has been causing you
pain and suffering for endless amounts of time
and which will continue to cause you pain
and suffering for endless amounts of time.
You see that inner state
of inner joy and serenity
really comes about from a knowingness
of one's own invulnerability
and therefore even though the depression
is not currently clinically there
the knowledge that one is vulnerable
precludes
that incredible state
called the peace of God.
Peace of God, knowing that one is not
separated from the source of anything
that one is connected with it
that one is one with God.
How does one then experience
that which in body, mind and spirit
is called spirit?
That subtle knowingness
it can come from any one of life's
exigencies
from any one of life's tragedies
even from a minor disappointment.
All of these things have within them
the seed
the truth is always present
that which is the spirit
that which reveals itself
of the truth
the truth behind consciousness
is always present
and therefore can be discovered
at any moment
in moments of high joy
in moments of depression
and so in Zen they say
heaven and hell are only a tenth of an inch apart
heaven and hell are only a tenth of an inch apart.
I myself of course
and I share my own personal experience
that I have experienced
and that I have witnessed the truth
of what I am talking about
my own inner experience has been
a time of great depression
severe depression
agonizing depression
way down in the pits
and from that state
of absolute hopelessness
in which time stopped
and the experience
went on for literally eons
because you know in a severe depression
our experience of time
is altered
each second seems like an eternity
and so in this depressed state
time stopped and it went on for eons
eons and eons
and in these eons
there was no hope
it's almost as if there was a sign
in fact that sort of fantasy
the sign that went over the top
it said all ye who enter here
give up all hope
like Dante's Inferno
one of the hells
and in that experience
of that infinite suffering
and agony
and self-hatred
that total feeling of being separated from love
and from God
came a great knowing
suddenly came a great knowing
and from that pit
from those pits of agony
suddenly there was the awareness
of the infinite presence
of eternal love
the knowingness of truth
so the kernel of that is
within any experience
and once we've investigated
a thing and found out the truth
for ourself
this encourages us to continue to do this
to never buy anything
to be detrimental in our life again
to use each one of these experiences
to search
right into the heart of the matter
to look for what was the fear
what was the misunderstanding
we have to do this
from a viewpoint of forgivingness
and so essential to this
self-healing is the willingness
to love ourself and forgive ourself
the willingness
to look at our vulnerability
and to call it our humanness
the capacity to love
our humanness
for its weaknesses
for its errors
for its foibles
to see that within this humanness
as mistaken as it might be
there was an intrinsic innocence
you see once we get off the anger
about our expectation
and the fact that it didn't work out
because it can't in a changing world
this is a world
in which there is only one thing
that is certain in the phenomenal
aspects of this world and its expression
as we experience it
and that is that all things change
look at that
all things change
all things change within human experience
because human experience is
that of change
if all things change
and nothing remains the same
then to place the source of your happiness
outside of yourself
on that which changes
it's only a matter of time
before the depression ensues
is that not correct
and not appearing
coming and going and changing
then the vulnerability is ever present
that simple mistake
which we all make
which is common to the whole human condition
which we are trying to look through today
arises out of something
that is also the same in all of us
and which can be rediscovered
and rediscovered right in the pain
of this experience
and that is the intrinsic innocence
of consciousness itself
the intrinsic innocence
of the inner self
and this we can see
in two different ways
one by reaching that state
of compassion
and compassion ourselves
by reaching such a level of consciousness
that we literally see into the hearts of others
and we just see and know
that innocence
the other way is to
through introspection
look and see how this arose
we notice in the child
we notice the innocence of the child
the young child we say
is innocent
and what do we mean by that
we mean that he is trusting
he has faith in the integrity
of those around him
it never dawns on the child's mind
to doubt the truth
of that which is being told
so the young child loves the parents
and those extensions of the parent
called teacher
other family members
peers
playmates
television
commercials
the child looks at a commercial
as though it's just as truthful
as its parent
because of its trustingness
because of its openness
because of its lovingness
because of its lack of paranoia
you might say
it's easily programmed
and therefore it begins to buy
out of its innocence
that which it hears
or that religious group
etc.
and we don't like people that do this
and we don't like people that do that
and we don't like people that vote that way
and the child's identification with those
that he loves is family
the programs start coming in
so the innocence of the child now
gets programmed
why? because of its innocence
it's because of its innocence
that it buys such statements as
all of us Jeffersons are allergic
heart disease runs in our family
we all have a weight problem in our family
and all these negative programs now
are bought out of the child's innocence
and so we might say
the child is like the hardware of a computer
the hardware of the computer
will play any software program
that's put through it
and yet the nature of the hardware
the nature of that which is
truly the computer itself
is unchanged
no matter what floppy disk we play
no matter what software
what programs we play through the computer
its intrinsic innocence
its purity, its integrity
has not been sullied
it has not changed at all
we take out all the programs
which are erroneous
and the hardware remains the same
the same with consciousness
that childlike consciousness
with its innocence
with its purity of motive
with its capacity
to remain pure
no matter what the programs may be
remains essential and unchanged
it is exactly what is listening
to my voice right now
it is that childlike consciousness
in all its purity and innocence
that is what's listening
to this voice right now
not the person
not the personality
but that consciousness
in all its pure and simple purity
even if that which is listening
says I don't believe a word of it
where does I don't believe
a word of it come from
it comes from another word
another belief system
that the child bought out of innocence
the father says don't trust anybody
or
some disappointing experience
sets up the program within the child's mind
don't trust anything you hear
so if you're saying to yourself
I don't believe anything he says
you're saying that because out of the childlike innocence
you bought that program
the way to be secure in this world
is don't believe anything you hear
or you'll be misled and led down the primrose path
but the nature of the innocence
you bought that program remains the same
is it not
because it's not the mind right this moment
trying to listen to the truth
discern that which is the truth
out of its hopefulness
out of its trustingness
hoping to hear that which will be helpful
that which will nurture life
that which will relieve suffering
and so you see that intrinsic innocence
so that when you look within yourself now
into the self healing
into the understanding
of what was the program that was set up
you have to re-own that innocence
in all spiritual work
I think it is so crucial
in all work in psychological research
within yourself
and introspection
to always keep within your awareness
that whatever you bought
you bought out of the beauty of what you are
you bought it out of your own love
and your own trustingness
and you really bought it out of your own integrity
because you projected your own integrity
onto the world
and thought this is a place that you can trust and believe anything you hear
because that is where you were coming from
until you got programmed
that sometimes it is very useful to lie
sometimes it is useful
to tell them the check is in the mail
we all know that one
we got programmed into the idea
that the only way you can survive
as a body in this world
is you have to
tailor the truth a little bit
create a business
business ethics
but didn't we buy that out of our own innocence
we thought
that's what they say
you got to do in this world to survive
so I guess I got to do that
and of course when you do that
you pay the price
anytime we go below the line
we pay the price
and the price is we lose our power
the loss of power within the world
so that's what the anger is about
I lost my power
the source of my happiness
will never be returned to me
because it is outside of myself
I projected it out there
the healing of it then comes
from the willingness
to look at the truth of this
to say to myself
out of my innocence
like other humans on this planet
like most of us in fact
I brought a certain way of looking at life
in which the source of happiness
is first of all
outside of myself
secondly it's always in the future
the separation from the source of happiness
is not only in space
but it's also in time
tomorrow or the next day
or next week
or the year after
or when I finally graduate
when I reach middle age
or when I get that big house
or when I get that Cadillac
it's always in the future
so we're always separated
from the source of our happiness
and we never feel complete
the realization that we are the source of our happiness
and that we can create it at any second
gives us a sense of completion
the sense of completion then
so that it can be cut off at any second
and feel complete
if we suddenly stop this talk
right now
it is complete right as of this moment
I have with the best of my ability
said exactly what I wanted to say
not feeling I'm going to say it in a minute
not saying it's going to come tomorrow
but right now
being with the experience
of experiencing the joy
of doing the best I can at this moment
and so
the joyfulness then
accompanies the experience
there is no
tomorrow about it
because of the sense of completion then
whether someone enjoys the talk
is immaterial
that is frosting on the cake
but it is not part and parcel
what one does in the world
has to be accompanied by
the sense of completion
in the doing of it itself
so that the payoff is not something
which is an aside
which is something as separate
from the doingness
the experience of it right now
the completion is with
the experiencing right now
not something separate from it
in that then one is aware
of the lovingness of all experience
that is the way one is
with the experience
the loving of life
then in all its expressions
the loving of life in all its expressions
including its disappointments
its ups and downs
the continual
process of making the mistake
and learning from the mistake
so that is nothing but a mistake then
you might say depression
is nature's way of saying to us
God's way of saying to us
our own psychology's way of saying
it to us however
looking at it
is okay with you
it's our psychological way
our biologic way
our spiritual way
it's our body our mind and our spirit
saying look what's out
there needs to be fixed
please understand me
out of your compassion heal
heal me heal all of us
which leads to the depression
is this inner sense of separation
that
I will not be complete and whole
unless I become united with something
out there
this brings up the difference
in the precipitating event
that leads to suicide
or depression
very often between men and women
men experience the presence of God
within them or the connection to God
and very often in the form of power
we remember that the three
classical attributes
of God are omnipresence
omniscience omnipotence
so that God is often
experienced in the unconscious
of men as connection
with power so that power
becomes that
which they seek and therefore
the precipitating event
very often in men
leads to the depression
was feeling separated
from the source of one's power
in this case the power has been put out
into the world so it would be
the loss of a title
loss of a position loss of a business
loss of the status
symbols that signify that power
and so that sense of
separation that vulnerability
because it has not been really healed
remains there
therefore money position and power
become their traditional goals
of men
women experience in the unconscious
their connection with God
more in the form of love
so that relationships are all important
and the experience of love
through the relationship
we remember the example
of the old woman who sat in the rocking chair
rocking back and forth staring hopelessly
out the window
it was because of feeling cut off
from a relationship and she experienced
that lovingness
coming through that relationship
and so the interruption of the relationship
then was the precipitating factor
and so we see that the basic
problem is still the same
it's just that it takes different form
different expression
between the two sexes
depression leads us into
something we mentioned in the beginning of the film
the whole subject of suicide
when we look at suicide
we'll see that
what is desired is not
really death of the body
what is desired is relief
from suffering
the realization that that is
what is sought
relief from suffering
see the body did not create the dilemma
the body cannot experience the dilemma
and therefore the idea
that if I get rid of the body
I will get rid of the source
is fallacious
the body neither created it
nor did it experience it
the whole problem is going on within consciousness
therefore the solution is within consciousness
to look at
the nature of consciousness itself
and see that that is where it arose
and that is where it is being experienced
therefore that is
where it has to be solved
the solution is to realize
that what is desired is the relief
from suffering
and in the mind
which identifies itself with the body
and thinks I am a body
then the loss of the energy
of life due to the fact that
the person is dispirited
leads to a decrease
of energy
and we have the forms
the many forms of passive suicide
I would say that
the majority of deaths in the United States
in the world in fact
are really forms of passive suicide
the loss of that sense of aliveness
that excitement
and commitment to life
and the passive suicide
then takes many forms
statistically it shows up
as the automobile accident
what is passive suicide
really failure to get out of the way
of the bus isn't it
for some reason we just didn't care enough
to take the precautions
we didn't care enough
to love our life
we didn't value it enough
to care for ourself to preserve it
and so passive suicide
takes the form of the person
who ignores their physical disease
the diabetic who just
doesn't care to stay on
the diet
doesn't care to take the insulin
constantly goes into
insulin reactions and overdoses
and diabetic coma
3, 4, 5 times in the hospital
in diabetic coma until they leave
in the addictions
we see that in the form of the overdose
traditionally the overdose
the person who is taking
multiple drugs for 20 years
and then dies of an overdose
how could that be a miscalculation
there are experts on psychopharmacology
they've dosed themselves thousands
and thousands of times
it's called an accident
there is no such thing as an accident
the automobile accident
where the person was just careless
what we really see is a loss
of desire to live
is that not so
the failure to heed health advice
the failure to take care of one's health
the failure to take care of one's assets
all indicating a loss
of that energy
that sense of aliveness
coming from deflated
first entrapped
deflated then dispirited
then the loss of energy
and then unconsciously
seeking a way out
so that one doesn't have to feel guilty
one doesn't have to feel guilty
that they died of diabetic coma
one didn't bother to alter one's lifestyle
to prevent that coronary heart attack
if we realize
that what we want
is the relief of suffering
then the relief of suffering
comes about through an understanding
of the nature of consciousness itself
through the processes
that we have described in this talk
the willingness
to experience out
and it can be experienced out
all the symptoms
that are being experienced
the looking at one's life
and using a technique
I call the worst scenario
to sit down and look at your life
and say
what is the worst possible outcome
what is the feeling
that comes up with that
and so resisting that feeling
to constantly cancel out
the thoughts about it
and instead handle the feeling directly
and as we do that
we'll notice that the symptoms
begin to abate
we come out of the depression
we're willing to look at the fear
we're willing to look at the way
that this was set up
how we got set up
our anger about that
using the energy of the anger
to want something better for ourselves
what it really means then
is we have to recontextualize
our whole life
we have to look at everything
and say to ourself
how can I hold this
so that it will have a value
that is great enough
that if it left my life
I would still have that
which is worth living for
to what about this
can I dedicate my life
what about my job
gives it meaning and significance
how can I see it in such a way
that my value as a human being
will not be changed
if that should leave my life
and so we have to look at our goals
and our motives
what are we willing to dedicate
our life to
what does have significant meaning
service to others
even if we lost all capacity
to serve our own life
what is the meaning then
of being of service to others
we see people of course
have all kinds of disfigurations
all kinds of losses
and they go on
somehow life still has meaning to them
what does that mean
does it mean we are weaker than they are
that morally they are superior
no, it means that somehow
they have sensed
some greater meaning in their life
they had to let go of a lesser meaning
and find a greater meaning
so that is what depression means to us
it means that we settled
for a smaller meaning
less than the truth
we have to re-examine
and see what was the true meaning
of that in our life
what about our life makes it worthwhile
even without that
direction by asking ourselves
a very simple question
we can do this as we go about
our daily life
growing in consciousness
is something that we do
as we go about our everyday business
and we ask ourselves
the question
I couldn't live if I didn't have blank
life wouldn't be worth living
unless
and then we fill in
what in our own mind
we have put in that blank space
where is our vulnerabilities
our vulnerabilities
are where we think
we couldn't live without that
what if we put our survival on
so the whole technique then
is to first find out
where the areas of vulnerability lie
sit down and picture
and then we go about
the process of
letting go, resisting
all the feelings that come up
and ask your own inner consciousness
ask your own unconscious
ask the God within you
ask your super consciousness
however it is
ask your intuition
however you hold that inner questioning
and you begin an inner questioning search
all of us have to do that
what is the meaning of our life
what is it's significance
is worth living for? What do we value that is greater than that which is limited and temporary?
By removing all these things one by one, we find that that who we are is growing in stature.
We're no longer so vulnerable to external events because there's always two things going on.
There is the event out there as we see it in ordinary consciousness happening out there,
and then there is how we feel about that, and how we feel about it depends on our attitudes.
We can decide how we want to be with that. See, that who we are then and what its relationship
is to that event, see? So I am one thing and the event is something else, and I have power over
how I want to hold that, how I want to value that relationship, how I want to picture it,
and whether I'm willing to give it the power over my life. Am I willing to give money enough power
over my life, that if I lose it, I no longer desire to live? Am I willing to give a relationship that
power over my life? Am I willing to give possessions, titles, degrees, cars? Think of all
the things that people put and value greater than their own life and you see the enormous vulnerability.
It's high up there within the most important causes of death,
and especially so in adolescence.
So what does it say about the values, then, that we're teaching our adolescents?
What are the transitory things that we're telling them to base their life on?
We have to reevaluate for ourself what is the importance,
what is the meaning of our life,
what do we hold of sufficient value that it will preserve us
in the face of any kind of a loss.
Out of this inner understanding, then, comes a reevaluation of that relationship
between body, mind, and spirit.
Because it is mind, then, that is setting our goals and our purposes.
If we begin to question our values, reevaluate our position with them,
whether we like it or not,
whether we like the term or not,
we're really doing that which is called spiritual work.
What is spirit?
What is it, that energy of life itself?
You see, we have a decision about its form.
We can decide what to give meaning to, what to give value to.
Within that energy field called consciousness, then, we have great freedom.
We have great freedom.
It is up to our own inner choice.
By seeing that, by merely seeing,
that we have the choice of what we want to give value to,
we reown our power.
We move up on the chart.
We move up from victim to source.
We begin to accept back our own power, which we have given to the world.
With that comes an inner state of serenity.
An inner state of serenity that I am experiencing the value of my existence,
that I need no proof.
The world doesn't have to do anything.
I don't need to bring home the truth.
I don't need to bring home any trophies to give it value,
because I see its value within myself.
I see and I treasure and I hold sacred the value of life itself.
No trophies are needed.
I accept that which is given me with thanks.
With gratitude, I hold the essence of that which I am,
without asking that the world give me back anything that I've demanded of it.
In doing that,
we move into an invulnerable position.
We're no longer prone to these disappointments, the anger, the rage,
turning against ourself and the thoughts of suicide,
that hopeless, fallacious idea that by killing the body,
we will kill the source of our suffering.
By owning that we ourselves are the source of our suffering,
we transcend it.
By transcending it, we bring about that inner healing,
which is the purpose of today's talk.
Thank you.