I'm Dr. David Hawkins. I've been a psychiatrist for 35 years, psychoanalyst, nutritionist,
researcher into the nature of consciousness and spiritual work.
And in this series of talks, we're using the knowledge that we gain from our research
into the nature of consciousness itself for the alleviation of human suffering.
Today's talk is addressed to letting go of weight,
how to let go of weight in a way that's practical, easygoing, joyful,
and does not involve any kind of suffering.
Can this be done?
Well, all we ask for is some of your attention,
maybe an hour, hour and a half is all it's going to take of your attention,
over a day or two, during a day which you're doing the other things that you would be doing anyway.
The benefits can be long-lasting.
They can last a long time.
A lifetime.
The reward for a couple hours of just paying attention to a few simple principles
is a lifetime of freedom from this problem.
How do I know it works?
Because it's worked in everybody who's tried it.
It's worked in my patients.
It's worked in my own self.
Because I myself lost 50 pounds using this very simple technique
coming out of our consciousness research.
The alleviation of a problem should be simple,
direct,
to the point,
long-lasting,
and its effect costs nothing.
Diets not work and appetite suppressants will look into that.
The usual techniques that people try
end up with sort of a guilty self-recrimination.
They work temporarily,
but because they don't really change the way you are with your body,
because they don't really change those Pavlovian reflexes
which drive you into eating despite your best interests.
We'll talk about a shifting state of consciousness
that we've discovered occurs in the process of eating itself
and how you can easily overcome that
so that your weight loss becomes permanent.
So we're going to say give up trying willpower,
give up dieting,
give up resisting eating as they don't work.
They make you miserable
and you're going to end up the same as you were easier.
Anyway, there's a much easier way that is truly joyful.
We'll be talking about,
and we'll be using during our talk,
this scale of consciousness that we have over on the blackboard
that we have been referring to in the other talks here in the office.
This is a mathematical model of levels of consciousness
as we commonly experience them in everyday life.
And through our research,
we were able to calibrate the relative energy power of these energy fields,
the directions of these energy fields,
and the importance that this has
when we're trying to handle any kind of a human problem.
And through a simple understanding of some very simple concepts,
we are then put in a place of being able to handle things
that up to that time were baffling and not successful.
We're going to talk about how to image yourself as slim
and love and energize that image
and then let go of it so that it actually materializes.
So we're going to be using some of,
the techniques based upon the nature of consciousness itself.
How to come from your heart instead of your head.
How to come from your heart instead of your stomach.
The head criticizes you and the stomach wants to eat.
And the only way to handle this problem
is to come from your heart about the whole thing.
And so we're going to be somewhat lighthearted about this subject today,
in which many people get quite heavy about.
The lightheartedness comes with the eating
and then the self-recrimination,
and the guilt comes, you know, as you go to bed,
you lie in bed and you wonder,
why did I eat all that?
And begin to attack yourself.
So we're going to find a way beyond all these problems
that will work for us.
And so to start with, let's talk about,
let's talk about the common medical model,
the one that is commonly tried.
And we see that it's really based on the idea of diet.
The whole concept is based on,
based on an assumption that the number of calories you eat
is what determines your weight,
plus maybe some thought to exercise.
Now what we're going to say today
is not necessarily going to agree
with traditional medical thinking.
If traditional medical thinking
and counting calories has worked for you,
you wouldn't be watching this film.
So we're going to talk instead about things
that we have clinically observed
as being true experientially.
You see, consciousness work has to be done
with the truth of one's own inner experience.
It does not have anything to do with theory
or a hypothesis or scientific reasoning or logic.
It has to do with the experiencing
of the truth within you.
So the first thing we want to do
is to begin to cancel some of our beliefs
about diet and food that have contributed to our problem.
To begin with, we have thoughts coming such as,
well, overweight,
it runs in our family,
it's in the genes,
it's due to my thyroid,
it's due to the fact that as an infant I was overweight
and that caused too many fat cells.
Now these are all popular medical theories
and if holding those in mind works for you,
then that is very good.
But we have found experientially
this really isn't so, is it?
Because two people will eat exactly the same diet
and I've experienced this myself
over the last several years,
where myself and another person would eat
practically the same number of calories.
One would gain weight and the other would lose.
So how do you explain that phenomenon
in as much as the activity levels are about the same
and everything else is about the same?
So we have to question some of the basic medical hypothesis
and we see that some of them are very simple to understand.
To begin with, why assume because you eat 100 calories
that the body therefore absorbs 100 calories?
What makes you think that two people,
the two people's gastrointestinal tract are exactly the same?
I ate a 1,000 calorie piece of pie
and another person eats a 1,000 calorie piece of pie.
Maybe I only absorb 500 calories out of that 1,000.
The other 500 runs right on through.
And so we have other factors such as the rate of movement
of the gastrointestinal tract.
We know that the faster things move through the tract,
the less things are absorbed.
So we have other factors to consider
than just calories.
And so we're going to talk about these things today
and arrive at a way of handling this problem
that will not involve counting calories.
There are some dietary tricks that are helpful
and so we'll throw in some tricks about eating
that are helpful in the beginning until the results
of your working on yourself have adjusted your epistat.
So today we're going to be talking about,
a portion of the brain in the hypothalamus,
which is called the epistat and how to set down your epistat.
It takes you a day or two to handle this problem
and then the epistat gets reset.
And because the epistat controls your feeling of satiety,
it will now control your weight and as you hold a certain weight
in mind, it begins to materialize on the physical plane.
So we'll again be talking about the power of mind over body.
The power of mind over body and we'll be looking at the fact
that it is mind that creates body being what it is rather
than the other way around.
We have to reverse the conventional so-called common sense
of the left brain logic which says it's the body
that creates the mind.
Instead we have to look at the opposite, that what is held
in mind manifests within the body so that our thoughts
and our beliefs about weight, activity,
calories and all the phenomena surrounding this have been
what is affecting our weight.
We know this from let's say cases of patients
with multiple personality.
One personality will come into the patient and take
over his consciousness named Dick.
Now Dick doesn't have any eating or weight problem at all.
In fact, he eats very little.
He's spry and active.
And while Dick is in the body, the person is slim
and loses weight.
Then the person will go into a trance state
or become intoxicated or something.
And Robert comes into the body.
Robert loves to eat.
He gorges himself on all kinds of things, et cetera.
And the person's weight suddenly rises dramatically.
So you see the response now of the body is therefore to the mind,
to the mindset, to the mind's beliefs, to the mind's attitudes,
to the way the person holds their relationship
to their body in their mind.
It is the mind that is going to be setting our epistat
and is using consciousness techniques within the mind
which are going to release our weight problem.
So we can let go of the weight almost automatically.
I want to review again with you the nature
of consciousness itself.
That relationship between body, mind and spirit.
Spirit being that energy field of consciousness
which is all pervasive throughout life itself.
The first thing to understand is that the body has no capacity
to experience itself.
At first this seems like an amazing thought.
Because most of us, unless we're enlightened,
assume that we are the physical body.
The first thing to realize is that the body has no way
in which to experience itself.
My arm cannot experience my arm.
My leg cannot experience my leg.
Instead it has to be experiencing something greater
than itself.
And so we experience the body via the senses.
It is the senses that tell us what is going on with the body.
So we're not experiencing the body.
We're experiencing the senses of the body.
Now the senses of the body themselves have no capacity
to experience themselves.
They have to be experienced in something greater
than what they are and that is mind itself.
So we have the mind is the place
in which the body is.
The body is experienced.
In which the sensations from the body are experienced.
Mind itself is incapable of experiencing itself.
Now this seems like an amazing thought also, isn't it?
A thought cannot experience its own thoughtness.
A memory cannot experience its own memoryness.
A fantasy of the future cannot experience itself.
An emotion cannot experience itself.
What goes on in the mind has to be experienced in something
which itself cannot experience.
Mind itself is greater than mind, and that is consciousness itself.
So we have the body is experienced via sensation.
Sensation is experienced in the mind.
Mind is experienced in consciousness.
We can see this very easily because if something happens,
let's say to a portion of the brain,
we know that the person is unable to experience,
let's say the opposite side of the body.
So without mind, body cannot be experienced.
We know.
We know because of anesthesia, for instance.
In fact, that is the whole point of anesthesia.
That without consciousness, we're not aware of what is going on in mind.
If you delete consciousness via the anesthetic,
there is no knowledge or experience now of what is going on in either mind or body.
So consciousness is higher than mind and body.
There is, in fact, a state beyond consciousness itself,
which is still and unmoving, against which,
we are then aware of what is going on in consciousness.
And that is the state of awareness.
The state of awareness, which is not different
than the great powerful energy field behind consciousness itself,
which is not different than the energy of life itself,
which is not different than one's godness,
if these are terms that are acceptable to you.
It is necessary to know this because we then become aware of where all experience is taking place.
The experience is taking place within consciousness itself.
All human experience is taking place in consciousness itself.
Consequently, I cannot experience the wall or the floor or you.
What I'm experiencing is within my own consciousness of you or the wall or the floor.
This gives us an understanding of an area in which we can work then,
which is less restricted by consciousness,
which is less restricted by the commonly held belief systems.
If the entire weight problem is a phenomena occurring within consciousness itself,
if consciousness is more powerful than mind,
which is more powerful than senses,
which is more powerful than body,
then we can bring about a shift in the body by merely addressing consciousness itself.
If we address the problem there,
because the body will only do what is held in mind,
we don't have to really bother much with the body.
The body will automatically correct itself
because the problem is really a problem within the experience,
within consciousness itself.
So we'll be addressing techniques which have to do with the mind and with consciousness,
and we won't have to be very much concerned then with handling the body as such.
You might say that the body is an effect.
The cause is in mind.
The cause of what happens in the body is in mind.
It's only an effect.
Consequently, the attempts to solve the weight problem
which are addressed to the body only are notoriously unsuccessful.
Practically every month you see endless magazines and newspapers
and the headline on the cover which sells them is a new diet.
This tells you that diets don't work.
When you find multiple solutions to a problem,
when there are endless articles on the same phenomena,
you know they don't have the answer.
If you had the answer to the weight problem,
there wouldn't be any articles on diet at all
because everybody would have handled it.
Addressing it on the physical level alone just doesn't work.
It just doesn't work for many other problems
which involve complicated human behavior,
such problems as alcoholism,
many illnesses including duodenal ulcers, etc., diverticulitis.
All these things are notoriously non-responsive
to addressing them on the physical level only.
We have to become more sophisticated and more conscious ourselves
to bring about a resolution of long-standing behavioral problems.
The technique which I used personally when I lost that 50 pounds,
which may not sound like a lot of pounds to some of you,
but it was 30% of my body weight because at the time I weighed 175,
and with this technique I went down to 125,
which was the weight that I desired.
This technique really only worked
because it only takes, as I had promised you,
really a matter of minutes over a day or two.
Collectively, we're asking for maybe an hour,
an hour and a half of your time and attention.
You can actually do this while you're going about the house
or going about in the office, driving back and forth to work.
You can just fit it into your daily routine.
It isn't something that you really have to stop your life in order to handle.
It isn't like going away to a milk farm
or going to a dance studio or something.
This is something that works right into your life.
For a thing to be effective, it has to fit in with your life pattern.
I found that any behavioral modification technique
works if it fits in with your daily life.
If you have to change your whole lifestyle,
then usually the results are temporary.
In this case, what we do is when the sensation comes on
that you have previously called hunger,
what you do is you ignore the thoughts that go with this,
especially canceling that thought, hunger,
and instead you go right into the sensations,
right into the inner experience
of what it is you're actually experiencing
and where you're experiencing it in your body
without labeling it, without calling it anything,
without putting any name on it,
to just experience it and begin to let go,
resisting those sensations.
We go into consciousness itself.
We go into the inner experience
of what you're experiencing
without labeling it with anything,
without calling it anything.
Instead, to silently go within
and experience what's being experienced
and let go, resisting it.
In the beginning, you are so controlled
by the Pavlovian conditioning
that the minute you get this sensation,
the behavior goes into immediate action to satisfy it.
And so, like Pavlov's dog who ate,
you know, salivated every time the bell rang,
what you've done is set up a conditioned reflex
and what we want to do is unset this.
How can we unset it and how long does this take?
How much effort?
Very little effort, very little time.
What we do instead is when we get this sensation,
which in the past we've called hungry,
I'm hungry now,
what we do is we let go, resisting it.
We just agree and we're willing to be with the sensation
but do nothing about it.
So I let the experience
run within me.
I'm willing to be with that inner experience
of whatever it is, the sensation.
Some people may sense it in the stomach.
Some people may sense it in sort of a physical weakness.
Whatever the sensation is,
we stop talking about it in our mind.
We stop languaging it.
We stop giving it a label.
Instead, we go into the inner experience
and we let go, resisting it.
In letting go, resisting it,
we can move up to a higher energy level
if we choose it, if we're willing,
if we say to ourself,
I want more of whatever that is.
Now the reason for that
and the way that it will make it acceptable to you
is that there is a limited amount
of this sensation that's coming up.
The mind thinks, if I don't satisfy this,
I'm going to be beset by this hungry feeling continuously.
That's not so.
That is coming from resisting it.
When we go with it,
like in the Tao,
you know, the Chinese philosophy,
where the willow tree bends with the wind
and therefore doesn't break,
as compared to the oak tree,
which resists the wind and of course is broken.
So instead of being the oak tree
who resists this sensation
and tries to battle it with willpower
and fight it,
we're like the willow tree.
We go with the sensation
and we let go, resisting it.
In fact, we will resist it.
In fact, we welcome it.
It's like we're saying more.
We want more wind.
We want more of this inner experience.
As we call forth more of it,
we like empty it out.
So if I sit with this inner feeling now
and I let it be with me,
I can actually stop,
if I'm doing this at home
and I suggest you start it at a weekend when you're home,
I can even stop everything
and really focus on that.
I don't want anything to distract
from my being with this sensation
and as I sit with it,
in a matter of minutes,
it will suddenly disappear.
After it disappears,
I can go about my business
and after you become used to this technique,
you don't have to stop your activities at all.
When that experience comes up,
you fix and focus on it.
You concentrate on it.
You fix your attention on your welcoming it.
It's like you're opening the barn door
and allowing that to come into you willingly,
being with that sensation
but not doing anything about it.
We want to break that cycle
where you get that sensation
which your mind then labels hunger,
you then satisfy it with food
and what you've just done is reinforce,
made yourself victim,
made yourself at the effect of that behavior pattern.
Instead, that which you are,
your person, yourself,
stands aside from this sensation
and begins to master it
so that you're no longer at the effect of it,
you are the master.
You know, in Zen,
they have the famous ox herding pictures.
And in the first picture,
it shows the monk
and he's hanging on to this rope
which is attached to the ox
and the ox is dragging him all across the ground,
you see,
and his knees are bruised
and he's bleeding from his ears
and he's all a mess.
Then you see the next picture,
he has the ox
and he's got this ox,
the rope tied to a tree.
In other words,
now he has caught the ox,
he has identified what the problem is.
And then the next picture,
you see him,
he's riding on top of the ox.
He has become the master.
He's no longer the victim,
he's no longer at the effect of it.
And how did he do that?
He did it just,
that's what we're doing right now.
We're going to tether this ox right now
by identifying what is the pattern
that has to be handled
and then we're going to be on top of it
so that the person that we are now
stands independent above and beyond
and becomes the master of this.
Very simple thing to solve.
It's very simple,
it's merely the willingness
to experience what in the beginning
may seem like some discomfort.
In other words,
to experience this sensation
without satiating it right away.
As we do this,
we weaken the reflex.
Well, what about our eating during the day?
What do we do about that?
Well, what we do about our eating
is what I call anticipatory eating.
You never eat when you're hungry.
The first two days that you do this,
and in fact,
probably for the first week or two,
never allow yourself to eat when you're hungry.
Instead,
you let go of this hungriness
by using this radical truth technique.
And what you do is you anticipate
periods of hunger.
You know your own hunger patterns.
So instead of waiting until you're hungry
and eating,
which reinforces the pattern,
instead you anticipate.
You know that habitually
you're going to be hungry around 6 o'clock.
So what you do,
instead of waiting until you're hungry
and then satisfying it,
thereby reinforcing your own conditioning,
what you do is you anticipate it
before you're hungry.
Quarter to five,
you're not even hungry yet.
you have a cheese sandwich.
When you're not hungry.
So the technique is simple then.
You eat when you're not hungry
and you don't eat when you are.
Instead,
you substitute this technique
for the hunger pattern.
Now, how long will this take
before you disappear hunger?
What is going to happen?
What's going to happen
is that you will no longer experience hunger.
You will no longer experience appetite.
It will seem to disappear.
By the second day,
you'll notice that it is already so weak
that you barely notice it.
How many minutes a day will this take?
The first day,
maybe a total of half an hour.
You'll notice that
if you do nothing about this sensation
and really let go resisting it,
that it will disappear
in a matter of minutes.
After you do this a number of times,
it will disappear in a matter of seconds.
You'll know that if you sit down
and let go resisting this sensation,
that in seconds it's over.
In seconds,
you're no longer at the effect of this appetite.
You're no longer driven by it.
You can be absolutely free of it.
In place of this pattern then,
you may feel instead sort of a blankness,
sort of an emptiness,
like where there once was this hunger
and the drive to eat,
and then the appetite,
and then the enthusiasm about it,
and then the satiation.
It seems like nothing is going on
in that space in your life.
So what you can do instead
is do some other pleasurable activity.
Do some other pleasurable activity.
Reward yourself.
The book that you've been wanting to read
and have never had the time to read.
Well, now that you're not out in the kitchen all the time,
eating all the time,
you'll have some time to read that novel,
you know,
the one that you just want to read for enjoyment,
and you feel too guilty to read it
because you really have more important things to do.
The trashy magazine that you've been wanting to read all week,
but you feel too guilty to give the time to it.
Well, get yourself something that you really enjoy doing.
One thing I like to do, for instance,
is take a nap.
All the time you spend eating food,
and preparing food,
and cleaning up from the food,
and shopping the food,
you know,
can take up a great part of your day.
It gives you time for a short nap.
It really feels great.
After a 20-minute nap,
you feel fantastic.
After a 20-minute hunger engorgement,
you know that you don't feel fantastic,
you feel horrible.
You just had four Milky Ways,
a caramel sundae,
and finished off a piece of cheese,
and now,
instead of feeling happy,
you're feeling guilty.
The way off the guilt trip, then,
is to really know that there is a very simple technique.
It sounds so simple,
but that's why it works.
You know,
things that are extraordinarily complicated
are usually far from the truth.
The truth is usually amazingly simple.
As people, let's say,
in Alcoholics Anonymous have found out,
stay away from one drink one day at a time.
It sounds so simple.
The intellect says,
nonsensical,
I know that.
You know it.
The intellect knows it,
but you,
your person,
doesn't know that.
We only know a thing through our own validation,
through our own inner experience.
Within a day or two,
it usually takes me exactly one day
to get off eating,
and hunger,
and appetite.
If you've allowed yourself to get reprogrammed,
you'll notice as time goes on,
you're beginning to look forward to meals,
you're starting to get into the habit pattern
of getting hungry and satisfying it.
It's very simple to get back off it,
to release yourself back off of it,
by doing this just a few times.
It's so effective with me now
that I can do it just once.
All I have to do
is allow that feeling of hungriness to come up,
just be with it,
welcome it,
wait until it runs out,
and that handles it.
Maybe every few years
I have to do it.
Maybe I'll have to do that
if I've really gotten into holiday indulgence
for a number of years.
Because another thing that goes on is,
as we do this,
there is a center in the base of the brain,
in the hypothalamus,
called the apostat.
The apostat sets our degree of satiety,
the amount of satiety that we are searching for.
And the less we eat,
the more we set down our apostat.
Now, talking about satiety,
you see,
it's something else
that is not really understood
in traditional scientific medicine.
Scientific medicine talks about calories,
as though one calorie was the same as another calorie.
But we all know
that satiety plays a great place
in our hunger and our weight problems.
Satiety is more important than calories.
Therefore,
the diet I follow
would make most people who follow diets faint.
But I know
what creates a feeling of satiety
within myself.
Certain types of things,
like a hamburger smothered in onions.
By the time you finish that,
you get that totally filled up,
satisfied,
you know,
meat and cheese
and those kind of foods.
Cheese is not on,
you know,
anybody's reducing diet.
But we know that cheese has quite a,
you know,
satiety factor.
So that once you've eaten a certain amount of it,
it's like your appetite is satisfied.
We also know that calories are released
at different rates.
And so that fats,
for once,
for instance,
are released at one rate,
protein at another.
We know that it takes a lot of calories,
a number of calories,
to burn up every gram of protein.
So one of the tricks,
of course,
which you can use
to speed up the process
of the weight loss with yourself
is to go in for a heavily,
you know,
high protein diet.
We know that some foods,
we're not going to be talking about diet today,
but I'll just throw in a few tricks
that I've observed clinically
and I know work.
That eating sugar on an empty stomach
is sort of deleterious to the goals of your program.
Why?
Because the body takes it in so fast,
it's absorbed so rapidly,
it can't be metabolized that fast,
and it just has to be stored within the body.
So one thing we do for our own sake then,
because part of this is caring for ourself,
loving ourself,
is to try and avoid sugar and sweets
when we're introducing this program into our life.
Downstream, you can eat them.
I eat hot fudge sundaes all the time,
and I love chocolate fudge,
and anything chocolate.
So I haven't found at this point in my life
that eating those things has any effect on weight.
But in the beginning,
because you want to see a fast result,
and I believe you should,
I believe you should have the satisfaction
of doing this thing now
and seeing some return, some reward.
Seeing the image that you've been holding of yourself
come into manifestation.
It's probably best to avoid
things that are heavily sugar,
especially on an empty stomach.
So our technique then is to let go resisting
and to disappear hunger and appetite.
You then live in a world
where you're no longer in the cycle,
you see.
You get used to an eating cycle
of overeating,
feeling guilty about the overeating,
then trying to control it.
Then up comes hunger.
With the hunger comes guilt.
With it comes appetite.
With it comes the expectation of satiation.
Then comes the overindulgence.
Then comes the guilt again.
So you have this endless self-defeating cycle.
The only way to beat it is to rise above it,
to transcend it,
to be beyond it.
And by disappearing,
you'll find that appetite and hunger
actually disappears.
And you'll have the experience
of never being hungry.
Well, the next thing the mind says,
I don't want to give up the pleasure of eating.
Sounds like you're going to come into a loss, right?
You're not going to be able to enjoy
a molten milk or a hot fed sundae
or a hamburger smothered in onions.
Quite the contrary.
What happens to the enjoyment of eating
once you do this
is that appetite arises out of the eating itself.
So I'll sit down with no hunger
and no appetite at all.
But the minute I begin to eat,
it creates appetite.
And the pleasure of eating
is more than it ever was.
I enjoy food now more than I ever did.
It's why it's not accompanied by guilt anymore.
It's not accompanied by self-blame.
It's not accompanied by anxiety.
Am I eating too many calories?
Am I going to gain weight from this?
All that's eliminated.
So you're not going to give up
the pleasure of eating at all.
You'll find that when you eat
when you're not hungry,
that you're enjoying the food considerably.
When do you start enjoying the cheese sandwich?
The minute you take a bite into it.
Not even hungry.
I pick up the cheese sandwich.
I bite into it.
The enjoyment is there.
There's no loss of enjoyment.
I don't believe in letting go enjoyment and pleasure.
On the contrary,
I believe in increasing it.
So now you'll have the enjoyment
and the pleasure of eating
as well as the enjoyment and pleasure,
and the justified pride
in having a body that's more appropriate
to your own aesthetic ambitions.
And we'll be talking about that next,
your own aesthetic ambitions
as to what you would like to look like
and a technique perhaps
that will help bring that into manifestation.
First, we need the actual handling
of that cycle of eating, getting hungry.
So you see what's happening.
You see that you are the victim
of a behavioral pattern, a conditioning.
It has nothing to do with willpower.
It has nothing to do with morality.
You see, we can condition any kind of an animal in this way.
What's happened is sort of a Pavlovian dog conditioning,
and it has nothing really to do with your personality.
It has nothing to do with your self-worth.
It has nothing to do with the fact
that you're self-indulgent.
It has nothing to do with oral narcissistic needs
or whatever the psychoanalytic theory might be,
oral aggression, oral passivity.
It's got nothing to do with that, you see.
It merely has to do with a simple,
very primary type of conditioning
which has been favored in our society.
You picked it up from your own social conditioning
as a child, that's all.
And we'll be talking about the child
and the part that the child plays.
And moving on now,
to a different way of looking at the whole eating pattern.
Mind, the body is experienced in mind,
and the mind is experienced in consciousness.
So where you're really experiencing
that which you've called hunger in the past
is in your consciousness.
And where is that localized?
You'll notice that it's only a belief system
that it's experienced in the stomach.
It's actually experienced
in sort of a generalized way
in sort of everywhere.
The thought that it is in the stomach,
is just a belief system from childhood.
As we said before,
the body cannot experience anything.
What is going on is experienced
in a more diffuse, generalized area.
So another trick, another technique
in letting go of suffering of any kind,
whether it's pain or illness or physical symptoms,
in this case, what we've been calling hunger,
is nothing but a physical symptom.
You'll notice that it is being experienced
in a general, diffuse kind of way.
It's being experienced sort of everywhere.
Because where do we experience all experience?
Actually, it's being experienced
in an everywhere-ness,
rather than a localized situation.
The localization is coming from
the strong belief systems.
You know, we have all these thoughts from childhood.
As we let go, resisting this energy
of this sensation,
it becomes diffuse and finally it disappears.
Well, this is very interesting
because we'll go over to the board now.
We'll go to this map of consciousness,
this mathematical model,
and see if we can get some kind of sense out of it
from the viewpoint of energy fields.
Here we have the levels of consciousness,
these energy fields starting at the bottom,
the lower feelings.
And we notice as we come up here
to desire,
which is what has been running us
with our appetite-hunger satiation cycle,
we notice that it has an energy field
that's been calibrated at 125.
We notice that the direction of the energy field
is in a negative direction.
In other words, it has a deleterious effect on our life.
And we notice that the emotion
that goes with this energy field
is wanting and craving,
and all the addictions then fall into this.
So calling a weight problem a food addiction
in a way is correct
in that we're talking about
this particular energy field right here.
And we see what is characteristic
of this negative 125 energy field
is a feeling of wantingness,
desiringness, cravingness.
And we see that the process going on,
the process going on in consciousness
is entrapment.
The person therefore feels like this,
like a victim.
And because of the direction
of the energy field here,
there are negative feelings about the self
having to do with this whole cycle.
As we let go resisting it
and get released off of it,
go beyond it,
you see what's happening now
is we start moving up to the courage
to handle this problem,
the pride and our willingness to look at it.
And we move up,
we make it off this cycle
and to this level here
which is a plus 250
in which we become unattached, detached.
And at that point the phenomena,
the process going on in consciousness
is that you're released.
Because the energy field now goes to the right,
we have a positive good feeling.
It's constructive
and it makes us feel better.
It has a lot of power in it.
And how do we experience that detachment?
It's an experience that,
well, if we eat it's okay
and if I don't eat it's okay.
People say, you want to eat something now?
I say, well, if you're going to fix something, fine.
Then, you know, they'll say,
well, what do you want to eat?
Do you want to eat this?
Do you want macaroni
or do you want baked beans?
And you say, well, either way.
Because when you reach this level
of handling appetite and hunger,
you're no longer really fixed
on one particular food or another.
You can say, well,
if we have a steak tonight, that's fine
and if we don't, that's fine.
So it's okay either way.
It means you're free, you see.
And one characteristic is freedom.
Freedom from what?
Freedom from being run by that.
Freedom from being a victim of that.
Freedom from the entrapment
which made us feel bad about ourself.
The negative energy field
makes us feel bad about ourself.
So automatically,
as we get detached from these sensations,
we begin to feel good about ourself.
In fact, our willingness to do that
moves us up to 310,
which is an even better feeling about it.
We begin to accept
that this is nothing but a phenomena.
You see, it's just a set of vibrations
going on within consciousness.
It doesn't have to do with food.
It doesn't have to do with the body.
Those are all programs.
In essence, the physics of it is
that it's just a set of vibrations
going on in the field of consciousness
which are within our power to alter.
And once we do that,
we can really begin to love ourself
more than we did before.
There's another aspect going on in consciousness
that's very interesting
that will be very helpful to you also.
Something you can observe within yourself.
Something I picked up within myself
and saw it happening.
You see, the cycle in the past
has been to be run by this hunger, appetite,
satiation, and then guilt.
What happens is,
your good intentions suddenly flew out the window.
The good intentions that you had about
taking off weight and dieting and all that
have disappeared somewhere.
And after you have filled yourself up
with far more than you knew you needed,
suddenly you go into a feeling
of this self-disgust and guilt.
And people who have severe eating problems
often do that.
They go in the bathroom
and throw all the food back up again
and they go into self-hatred and guilt
and even suicidal depressions.
The self-hatred becomes severe, the blame.
So, what is going on here?
Well, what I saw happening was
when you sit down to eat,
you see, the one who wants to take off weight
and all this is the adult in us.
Remember Eric Berne,
the transactional analysis?
A lot of people in that kind of psychological work
have talked about our child tape,
our adult tape, and our parent tape.
It is like there are three voices within us.
One is the child,
one is the adult,
who is the rational, intelligent, educated person,
and one is the parent,
who tends to be punitive,
who tends to be moralistic.
The parent tape is the one that tells you about right and wrong.
So, you will see that this is what has been happening.
As you sit down to the table
or as you walk into the refrigerator,
you go unconscious.
You go unconscious and what happens is
the child takes over.
Now, what does the child know about diet, weight, calories?
Nothing.
The consciousness of the child is
I want and I satisfy, I get.
So, what happens is
we go into, without realizing it,
a different state of consciousness
in which the child is really...
So, who is in the refrigerator poking around?
The child is.
Who is ordering a second hot fudge sundae?
Who is having a second helping of potatoes and gravy?
The child is.
And after we indulge the child then,
without realizing this is what is going on,
and after the meal is over,
what happens now is
the child leaves.
I mean, he has had his fill.
And who takes his place?
The parent.
The parent says,
how could you have been so stupid?
Why did you have seconds?
Why did you add a piece of pie?
Why did you put ice cream on top of the pie?
I mean, think of the calories.
You are really stupid.
You are really weak.
You don't have any willpower.
You are no good.
Your self-worth is rotten.
So, now what happens is
you are subjected to the angry parent blaming you.
Blaming who?
Blaming the child.
Where has the adult been all this time?
He has been out to lunch.
He wasn't there at meal time
and he isn't there after meal time.
The child and the parent have taken over the whole eating program.
And isn't that natural?
Because where did these eating patterns set up in the first place?
They set up with the child.
And who is sitting next to the child but the parent?
So, the child and the parent tapes have been
what has been running the whole eating pattern.
The adult hasn't had a chance.
Now, the way to counteract this then
is to be aware that this pattern is running.
Just to be aware of it already begins to change it.
And now you make a note to yourself.
You can put it on the table.
You can put it on the refrigerator
and call forth consciously your adult.
And I tell my child,
look, you are going to be handled.
This is a place for an adult now
because my adult is very conscious of his eating.
My adult knows about calories.
My adult knows all these things.
And so I consciously call forth my adult
to be there at the meal.
I consciously summon him forth.
I say, you know, the adult me is here now.
And I consciously reject the presence of the child.
Now because the overindulgence doesn't happen,
when the meal is over, my adult stays there.
No parent comes in to blame me for what's been done
because no crime has been committed.
The crime is not committed by the adult.
You see, the crime is committed by the child.
So allowing ourselves then to go unconscious when we eat.
We don't mean unconscious like pass out.
You know, that's not what we're talking about.
We're talking about that aspect of our personality
that comes forth.
We're not aware that it's the child now
coming in to take over.
And the child doesn't care about weight.
The child doesn't care about having a good figure.
These are not things that bother a child.
These are not things that bother the parent.
So we want the adult to take over
the actual experience of eating.
Not the child and not the angry punitive parent.
We don't want to be at the effect of either one of them.
This is no place now for the child
because he has no self-control
and no intelligence about such matters.
And we don't want the parent there
because the parent is into the no, no, no
and the self-blame and the self-hatred.
So let's get rid of them at meal time.
We send the child out to play
and we'll tell the parent to go take a nap
and we'll tell them it's time for the adult
to come forth now.
These you'll find work extremely well.
You see, it doesn't take willpower.
It doesn't take self-control.
It doesn't take resisting anything.
It just takes being aware.
Be aware.
So you sit down.
You say hello to your adult, you see.
And when you sit down to eat, be conscious.
I've watched myself do this.
Just as you sit down at the dinner table,
you watch the kid come up in you.
Oh, look at that.
Who is that that's there at the table?
Oh, wow, look.
Look at the pile of mashed potatoes.
Look at the gravy.
I mean, you watch people's face when they sit down at the table
and you'll see who's up in them.
You see the eyes pop open.
You watch the pupils go like that.
If that isn't a five-year-old kid, I never saw one.
So you see a businessman, you know,
and he walks into the restaurant
and he's got his briefcase and he's so serious
and he goes down to the cafeteria line
and he sits down.
Watch his face now as he puts his napkin in front of him.
He picks up his napkin.
He goes,
Somebody else is there already, isn't it?
There's the kid all ready to have a good time.
And, of course, after he leaves,
he gets up, he folds his paper,
and now you see,
Oh, I ate too much.
Instantly, now who's there?
Look at the frown and the...
He's already berating himself
as he walks out of the restaurant.
He's counting all the calories in his mind.
He just ate 3,850 calories for dinner.
And his doctor told him he's only supposed to eat 900 calories a day.
He figures he can't eat till next Tuesday now.
And how is he going to survive?
So how to break out of this self-defeating pattern
just by being aware?
You know, make a little sign for yourself that says,
Hello, adult.
Be conscious. Beware.
You'll find that the adult enjoys eating a great deal too.
He just doesn't go crazy so easily, you know.
I forgot to mention something before
when I was talking about avoiding eating a lot of sugar and sweets
on an empty stomach,
and I want to mention it so that I don't forget it.
And that is we want to avoid fluctuating blood sugar
as much as possible when we're first initiating this program.
Because in the unconscious,
a drop in blood sugar is often associated in the mind
with hunger and hungry feelings.
So if we, on an empty stomach for instance,
eat a hot fudge sundae,
then you'll watch the blood sugar shoots up like this
and then adrenaline is poured out
and insulin is poured out
and you'll see what happens is the blood sugar then
tends to drop rapidly.
Behaviorally, in the past,
we have associated that then with feeling hungry.
You see, we're not actually hungry.
Our stomach is still full.
We have more calories in us than what we need.
But it's the rapidity and the degree of drop of this blood sugar
from where it started previously
then triggers the sensation of hunger again.
It's much easier when you're initiating this program
to try and stay on a high protein or a high fat diet
because then your blood sugar tends to stay somewhat level.
You don't hit those sudden drops.
They give you that feeling that you want to eat something right away.
And therefore it makes it a little easier on yourself.
The point is we want to avoid suffering in all its forms.
We don't want to experience suffering in any kind of a program
because otherwise it's not going to work.
Counting calories and depriving yourself
is setting up a form of suffering.
So what happens then is the unconscious guilt gets satisfied.
You see, the overindulgence sets up guilt.
So then we diet and that is sort of like self-punitive.
You sort of punish yourself by going on bread and water
like a prisoner for a certain period of time.
Then after we've punished ourselves sufficiently
for all this overindulgence in the past
what happens now is the guilt disappears.
And once the guilt disappears
then the old eating habit pattern returns.
So that overindulgence, feeling guilty, going into a self-punitive
you know, bread and water kind of diet, going to that extreme.
So we want to get off that imbalance of extremes.
First swinging to the overeating and overindulgence
then swinging into the guilt and the self-punitive deprivation.
Deprivation is not the way to happiness, you see.
Nor is overindulgence.
But transcending it and being in the middle of the two
so that you're over and above the problem.
So that the adult is there to take over.
Using consciousness techniques, making it easy, making it enjoyable.
It's really delightful to realize that you have just handled that and transcended it.
Something that's plagued you your whole lifetime can be handled
you know, in a matter of minutes.
The first day, I think the first day I tried this
I don't think I spent over a total of 45 minutes
sitting down handling those sensations.
And the second day maybe 20 minutes.
The third day maybe 10 minutes.
And the next day maybe 4 minutes.
And since that time I don't think I've spent collectively an hour
in the last 10 years.
Collectively over a 10 year period I don't think I've even spent.
You see, if you take a stopwatch and start.
You start to feel hungry, you start a stopwatch.
And then you sit down and you use this technique.
And when the hunger feeling is gone you hit the stopwatch again.
If you did that I don't think you would even collect an hour
over a 10 year period of time.
So that certainly is not much in the way of effort.
Not much in the way of suffering.
No willpower is involved.
Instead of willpower what we're using instead is willingness.
See, willingness is a positive energy.
It's powerful at 310.
And using willpower, resisting.
Willpower means I will resist this.
Is a negative energy field.
And it has a weak power of only 125.
So instead we're going to be using willingness, acceptance.
We're going to be happy about it.
If your willpower is at about 300,
let's say it's at about 500,
we're going to end up joyful and feeling great about ourself.
Feeling wonderful about ourself.
And of course the body begins to feel wonderful about itself.
And so we begin to experience our body in sort of a happy way.
A happy way.
Another way to increase the rapidity of the effect of this
is by watching your activity.
See, we said exercise is great.
But if you're going to set about taking off weight through exercise,
How many mornings are you going to get up and do calisthenics, you see?
No matter how attractive the person is on the television set,
you're just going to do this a number of times,
and the enthusiasm by the fourth day wears out,
and before you know it, you're back into the same old pattern.
Exercise is wonderful.
It's good for that sense of well-being.
But as weight reduction folks, we all know the truth of that one.
It works so well, actually,
that you may end up having a problem of being thin.
That's what happened with me.
This worked so well that pretty soon the appetite disappeared,
the hunger disappeared, all these cycles of eating, indulgence,
and then feeling guilty disappeared,
and I noticed that I would forget to eat.
Forgot to eat breakfast, forgot to eat lunch.
I would get busy with the activities of the day
and totally forget eating.
Once in a while it would come to you in the beginning
because it's a habit.
It's meal time.
And then what you do is you sit down
and you let go resisting that the same as you did the sensations.
And you'll notice that the idea that I must eat breakfast,
I must eat lunch, I must eat dinner,
these are cultural conditionings.
They don't have any reality to them.
It's just as easy to not eat all day.
And I've actually gone days without eating
and didn't even notice it.
One time I went from Monday to Thursday.
I was so busy with activities.
And on Thursday I suddenly realized
I don't think I've eaten the last couple of days.
And sure enough I hadn't.
And the family began to complain that I was too thin.
So then I had to consciously be aware that it's necessary to eat
and sort of reprogram myself a little bit back into eating.
So it works extremely well.
It brings a great deal of happiness.
And we might talk about something else too.
We might talk about using another consciousness technique
which has a general application.
All the things we're talking about today,
it of course will dawn on you,
have many applications.
There is a technique also
where you picture the kind of body you want to have.
You see?
You picture the kind of body you want to have
and you picture the kind of feeling
that you want to have about having this kind of a body.
Remember some time in your life
when you were feeling joyful and pleased with yourself.
And now picture yourself,
picture that body the way you want it to be
and reawaken that emotion.
Picture yourself as, let's say you want to be slim,
picture yourself as slim
and begin to love that picture.
Love that picture of yourself.
Love that picture of the body.
And now let it go.
Now let it go knowing that that,
what you've done is you've set up a program,
you've set up what is going to be in the future.
Because the mind will now begin
to move in that direction automatically.
Just love that picture of yourself
and if you like you can put the number of pounds under it.
Right now I have 132 under my picture.
So I picture how I want to look.
You know, relatively slim so your clothes feel comfortable.
And under that I have a picture of 132.
So I just love that about myself
and I say, you know, fantastic at your age to be slim
and active and feel good about the body.
I love myself for that.
You see, we want to stop identifying with the body.
You know, I am not the body.
I have a body.
So how I view my relationship to body,
it becomes important.
I am that which has a body.
Like I am that which has a car.
I am that which has a house I live in.
So the car, the house, I mean the car,
the body becomes like those things.
It becomes like my pet.
It becomes like my pet animal.
My friend, Gloria Ross, calls it her pet.
And that is a great way to look at it.
See, this is my little pet.
This is my bicycle.
This is my vehicle.
This is my car.
This is my pet that carries me around.
But you see, it is different than saying I am that.
I am that.
Because if I say I am the body,
then I am subject to what goes on with the body.
And if it gains weight,
then it is me that is fat.
I am the one at fault.
I berate me thinking I am the body.
It doesn't take too much in the way of meditative self-awareness
to realize that you are that which experiences the body.
You are not the body.
Right in the beginning we said that
body cannot experience itself.
It only can be experienced in mind.
Mind can only be experienced by consciousness.
Consciousness itself can only be experienced by
a field greater than itself called awareness.
So I am that which is aware of the body.
I am that which is beyond the body.
So how I am with that body now?
I am one thing.
The body is another.
And this body is going to reflect
what I am holding in consciousness.
So that my problem is not the body at all.
The problem is what I am holding in consciousness.
My problem is merely to change the vibrational body.
To change the vibrational patterns within consciousness.
And this body is going to do automatically
what it is told to do.
The body can't think.
The body has no mind.
What I am, that which I am, has the mind.
And the body follows what I tell it to do.
So this imaging technique,
the way in which I hold as pleasurable my relationship,
and I enjoy its activity now.
I enjoy the way it sort of bounces around.
It sort of does its...
You see, as we keep letting go
and keep following these techniques,
what happens is the body seems to get lighter.
The body, having nothing to do with weight,
is experienced as progressively weightless.
And as we move up the scale of consciousness,
after a while we are hardly aware that the body even exists.
Let's look at the scale of consciousness then
in a different way.
Let's look at
how we are with our weight problem.
How am I holding this problem
so that I can get out of the emotional destructive patterns
which have accompanied it?
It's generally thought that these negative feelings
are the cause of the weight problem.
If you look into it, you'll see this is really not so.
You'll see that these are the reactions to the weight problem.
These are the reactions to the weight problem.
And sometimes they are the corollary
or the parallel.
Let's look and see how we've been holding
the weight problem up to this point.
Most of us have been down here at the bottom of the box
called guilt.
See?
Guilt is an energy field of 30.
It's very weak.
If you try to handle your weight problem
or any problem, alcohol, relationships,
if you try to handle anything from the level of guilt,
you can see how much energy you've got to work with.
You've got like 30 bucks as compared to love,
which is 500 bucks.
30 bucks isn't going to buy you much progress in anything.
Not only that, but the energy field is negative,
meaning you're going to feel lousy about the whole thing.
You're going to be full of self-hatred,
and actually the process is destructive.
The process is destructive.
I mean, people have actually committed suicide
over their weight problem, their self-indulgence.
Even if you don't handle it from guilt,
you move up to hopelessness.
This state here, which has an energy field of 50,
is accompanied by hopelessness and despair.
This means my case is hopeless.
I've tried all the diets.
I've tried the milk farms, all that.
I've lost the energy with which to even address this problem anymore.
I'm the victim of it, and I just surrender to it and give up.
So this is, I am hopeless.
The next one above it is grief.
This is the depression.
This is the depression about the problem,
the regret, feeling despondent and dispirited.
You see?
Or the fear of this problem and its consequences.
These are all negative feelings.
You see the direction of the arrow.
That I'm going to die of a heart attack.
This overweight is going to kill me, etc.
This is full of worry, anxiety, and panic.
It's going to destroy my relationships and my future.
And of course, your self-esteem is deflated.
So people with a weight problem often socially withdraw.
They compensate.
They compensate in other ways,
because they feel inadequate due to this energy field.
They're not inadequate people at all.
It's just that they're holding that about their situation,
and then the negativity of it affects their emotions.
We've already talked about this level here.
You know, the desiring, the wanting, the craving,
behind all this, the entrapment.
And we move up to the next field, which is anger.
You know, the person is angry about their weight problem.
They resent it.
They're full of grievances about it.
And although 150 is more effective,
you're probably going to be more effective utilizing anger,
certainly, than guilt or hopelessness.
If you're angry enough about your weight problem,
you can move up to pride, which is 175.
That's enough to run the United States Marine Corps, pride.
That's a lot of power.
And try to move through pride,
because that's not exactly a great place to hang out in,
because of the inflation of the ego that happens there,
and move up to courage.
The courage, now that you know some tools that are really going to work,
the courage to try them out.
That's 200.
200 is a lot of power as compared to 30 or 50.
It enables you to face, to cope, to handle.
And what happens there is you become empowered.
You now become empowered.
The truth of it is you haven't known how to handle it up to now,
or you would have.
Isn't that so?
If you really knew how to handle it, you would have.
That's the truth of it.
You use these releasing techniques, this letting go,
these letting go techniques,
and you become detached from the whole problem.
If the weight stays, it stays,
and if it doesn't stay, it doesn't make any difference.
At this point, you say, it's not apathy, it's not hopelessness.
On the other hand, you're released from the thing,
and therefore, you're feeling good,
and you move up to a willingness.
Willingness at 310 is a lot of energy.
Compare it to guilt.
Compare it to grief.
Compare it to...
You see how much power you've got now,
and here you're in agreement.
You're aligned with this technique.
Your intention is finally up,
that you're finally going to handle it,
and you accept that it can be handled,
that you're an adequate person.
You start becoming confident,
and there's a transformation now occurring
because you realize the power to handle this is within you,
and you start moving up into a lovingness.
The desire to really love yourself,
to love this body,
now that you don't identify with it as me.
This body is not me.
If you take off my left leg, I'm still me.
If you take off my right leg, I'm still me.
Take off the left arm, I'm still me.
Take off the right arm, I'm still me.
Take off both ears, I'm still me.
You get that the me is me,
and I'm not the body.
So whether it weighs 200 pounds or 85 pounds,
that which I am is unassailed by that,
and I must learn to love that body now,
begin to really value it,
and see that it's just an enjoyable little puppet.
The way to relate to the body is that it's a happy little puppet.
You see, and it goes about its way,
and the less attention you pay to it,
the better it really handles itself.
It just does what it's doing automatically.
And you see, if you get to love it, you see,
your brain begins to release endorphins.
Endorphins.
When endorphins are released,
a process goes on in consciousness called revelation.
You begin to see things differently.
What do you see differently?
You see how wonderful your little body is.
That's one of the things you begin to see.
You begin to love it and get a kick out of it.
When you're overweight, are you getting a kick out of your body?
No, you don't get a kick out of it.
Every time you look at it, it throws you back into guilt again.
Up here, you start getting a kick out of it.
You start getting playful with it, sort of a joyfulness.
You see, a joyfulness and a happiness about this little body.
It bounces around and you're just sort of dimly aware of it.
It's because you're experiencing your existence
from a position of allness.
See?
Once you become conscious about where experience is happening,
you get that experiencing is happening everywhere.
You begin to identify with everywhere-ness.
Instead of stomach-ness or bulge-ness or ulcer-ness,
all those localized things,
that which I am is a conscious being.
Consciousness is everywhere.
So I begin to experience my existence
as being almost everywhere in space.
And within this everywhere-ness, within this allness,
this happy little puppet bounces around.
You see how it just does what it does.
And it has a good time doing it.
We start to come from the heart about it then.
Heart with a capital H.
Heart not meaning the physical organ.
Heart meaning that quality of valuing your existence.
Coming from that greatness.
Coming from the big-ness.
Coming from the joy of aliveness.
And seeing the body as a contributor to that.
As something that's enjoyable.
As something that you can have fun with.
Something you can experiment.
Something you can play with.
This talk today gives you something
to have a good time with.
It's really fun to sit down and watch this phenomenon happen.
It's really joyful.
It's really fun.
You know, within a day or two,
within a day or two, it's all over.
Within a couple of days, once you're released off
this appetite-hunger cycle,
the rest of it is automatic.
You know, you don't have to do another thing.
If you want to throw in some common sense
and have a diet soda, you know,
have a diet Coke instead of a regular Coke,
and save yourself 100 calories,
well, that's common sense.
That's up to you.
That's different than being at the effect of.
It's different than being run by.
It's different than being run by the guilt of.
That's considerably different,
because now you're at choice.
So if my weight gets a little on the high side,
another trick that works is never to allow yourself
to go over a certain number of pounds.
If I pick 132, that means that by accident
it runs to 134.
Then I go back to this technique again
and get off that cycle,
because those old patterns can tend to recur,
but they're very easy to let go of once it recurs.
You can really do it once or twice.
The first time you feel hungry, you sit down and you skip it.
You skip the eating until that hunger disappears.
Then you can go out in the refrigerator if you want.
And don't forget to have your adult at the refrigerator.
Put a note inside your refrigerator when you open it,
maybe a picture of yourself as you as an adult, you see,
so that you realize you've got a choice
of whose arm is going to be reaching into the refrigerator.
Keep that kid out, you know,
because the kid is going to help himself in the refrigerator.
And let your adult be there.
So the whole thing becomes a very enjoyable experience,
one in which you truly begin to love yourself.
The basis of all these self-healing techniques
that we talk about are merely ways of loving yourself,
ways of really beginning to value yourself.
Really ways of loving that which you are,
that which you really are in truth.
And that which you are in truth then looks at the body,
that which you really are looks now at your little body
and begins to get a kick out of it.
It says, gee, I'm having a good time with you.
You're a fun thing.
You begin to see that it really runs almost on automatic all by itself.
You'll see that the mind, the ego,
has played a trick on you.
You think that you make a decision
and then the body does that.
You see, actually it's doing it by itself.
It's on automatic.
Once you've released it out of a negative pattern,
the body will just handle itself very well.
We know this with scientific experiments with young children,
that if you allow them to spontaneously select their diet,
they will automatically select a balanced diet.
So you begin to get a return of faith in nature.
You allow your mind, you allow the body now to sort of be itself.
The nature, the nature,
that which is natural within the body itself
will automatically handle its nutritional needs.
Once we get off the social programming,
then that which is automatically self-healing
and healthy within the body takes over.
It takes over and it looks after itself
and it chooses what it needs to eat and what it wants to eat
and it does extremely well.
My body eats lots of cholesterol
and it loves cheese and eggs
and it would make any dietician faint,
any nutritionist I'm sure would faint
when they see what I have for breakfast.
And yet the cholesterol is normal,
the blood sugar is normal,
all the blood chemistries are normal.
I have a faith then, you might say,
in the God within nature itself.
The God within nature itself.
The body being part of nature.
The body being part.
Of the beautiful nature of this planet.
It has its own inner wisdom
and when we remove the artificial conditioning of our society,
its own innate inner wisdom comes forth
and it expresses itself in a sense of aliveness,
a sense of joyfulness, a sense of lightness,
the capacity to feel good at all times
and you'll see that its weight handles itself automatically.
To do this then all we're asking for
is really a few minutes of time
with many years of joyful reward coming as a result.
Have a good time with this little body.
Love it. Be good to it.
Kiss it.
Give it all the love and attention that it needs.
Realize that it belongs to you
but it is not what you are.
It is not you but it belongs to you.
It's a lovely possession.
Enjoy it while you've got it.
Why not have a good time with it?
Take it out of the category of pain,
sin, suffering and guilt.
Give that up forever.
Choose joy as your way of being with it
and have a good time.