Our
next talk is improving your
relationships.
>> Oh. Oh, I'm sorry.
>> Okay. So, this can be um your
spiritual relationships.
>> Well, improving relationships,
spiritualizing them to begin with
improves all of them. Oh,
>> the awareness that that God is present
at all times
to be as loving as possible towards all
of life and all of its expressions.
um means to be kind to to to your
environment, to be kind to this couch,
to be kind to you, to be kind to myself,
be kind to my sweater, and not go and
tear it or rip it or something,
not spill things on it.
So, I try to be as kind to my
environment as I can.
>> Okay.
>> And invite and kind to other people's
environment. Uhhuh.
I hear an airplane coming overhead.
You hear them?
>> Yeah. We're just going to wait until it
goes over.
>> He's coming to torment us.
>> Oh my goodness. If If that doesn't give
you paranoia,
how did that plane know that we didn't
want the sound of an airplane in the
background?
Well, probably our dislike of the sound
of the air airplane in the background
attracted it.
>> All right. So,
>> great. Uh, all right. Um, all right. So,
improving your relationships.
>> Can you talk about u what one should
have consideration for other people?
I think that's a general rule of life.
Consideration for life in all of its
expressions.
>> Okay.
>> And of course, one of its major
expressions
is the aliveness of the life of the
persons that are near you and you
contribute to your life and to your
happiness.
And so we try to be as loving as we can
towards all of life in all of its
expressions
and especially those that are closest to
us
and then they in turn pick up that
energy and pass it on to others.
>> Mhm.
>> So when we're loving towards a friend
they can they are therefore more loving
towards their friends and where are more
loving. So love you know like
>> so it's kind of passed along.
>> Yes. So lovingness I think to be as
loving as you can towards all of life
and all of its expressions all the time
is making a major contribution to life
to the overall energy of life
>> and it creates a certain ambiance
that affects everyone.
So, as far as it goes, it says um re uh
your relationship with God. Let's let's
cover that one first. Um
>> wow.
>> Your relationship with God should be
well on a daily, weekly, hourly basis.
>> Should be continuous.
>> Could be continuous.
>> Yeah. that you're you you're aware that
you are all constantly in the presence
of God
>> and you pray to God whenever you
remember that fact.
So I I ask God to help us speak as
fluently as we can at this moment in
whatever manner might be most useful to
the listener or the viewer of this tape.
Mhm.
>> So part of God's love
then expresses itself through me to the
viewer and the listener.
>> Um can you talk a little bit about um as
a spiritual uh person
um or
the spirituality of one's life? Do you
turn your life over to God
uh when you know you know life is not
smooth? So you turn your life over to
God. Is that what you do?
I I think the overall awareness that
everything and all that you do is
constantly in the presence of God
already alters
your way of being.
I I think it tends to cancel
negativities that you otherwise might
indulge in.
>> On the other hand, God doesn't get upset
if you get mad at something.
>> So in my view of God, God accepts human
limitation.
And uh I was created by God and I was
created the way I am.
And so instead of being unhappy or
cursing the way I am,
uh I thank God that I have such a
versatility
of
experiencing the different aspects of
life. I can experience angriness,
irritation and all those things and not
not have it really interfere with my
real basic happiness which includes all
of those
>> as far as it goes. is repro improving
your relationships. We have different
kinds of relationships. You know, we
have a husband or a a partner
relationship. We have a husband and wife
relationship. We have, you know, child
uh parent relationships,
>> siblings,
mother, father relationship. There's all
these different relationships.
So, can you tell us a little bit on how
to handle uh juggle all these
relationships
>> because with one you're this way and
with one you're that way and it's just
you know
>> Yeah. We are we we we tend to alter our
behaviors
uh depending on the person that we're
with.
>> Uh because some people are playful and
we can be playful with them. Other
people are more serious, take everything
serious. other people you have to be
businesslike at all times.
>> So people limit limit the way you can
relate to them by the way they hold
themsself and present themsel.
>> Mhm.
>> Some I know some people that you have to
be like businesslike with. You can't
really be jolly or joking or you can't
give them a hug.
>> Uhhuh. I wonder what would happen if you
gave him a hug and got scared. Well, I
wouldn't think
>> they probably would think it was
inappropriate.
>> Yeah. There you go. Inappropriate. There
you go.
>> Inappropriate behavior.
>> There you go. There you go.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. So, on top of everything else, we
have appropriateness.
>> Mhm. Not only the kind of person you are
in a given situation and setting
but how you handle the whole range of
that which could go from mild to
considerable
uh intensity of expression.
I think it's okay to be who you are
uh with limitations.
>> Um does God play an important part in
relationships?
I think it's the prevailing overall
attitude
um for many people
and other people are completely
oblivious.
Uh just ignore that God is present at
all times and it would put a damper on
what they can do.
>> It's hard to kill somebody if you're
aware that you're doing this in the
presence of God.
>> Mhm.
Happily during the war I didn't have to
kill anybody.
I managed to uh steer the ship through
typhoons and keep us keep us alive while
other ships other ships I think 90 ships
sank in the Okanawa tycoon.
And we went over to 90 actually 90
degrees. We were as horizontal as we
were vertical.
And I stayed at the wheel for I don't
know close to two days without stopping.
uh cuz I was not prone to seasickness. I
never got seasick
and uh and other people were laying on
the on the deck very sick. I mean a lot
of them were very pathetically sick. I
really felt sorry for him and I thank
God that I was not subject to uh to
seasickness and
so I was very thankful to be of service
and um
grateful for the opportunity to
be of service to others.
Um can you um talk about
um what I want to talk to you about is
um how can one be loving when one's
feelings are hurt
to say a partner? How can one be loving
to the partner when their feelings are
hurt?
>> Well, you mean you're the object or the
subject?
>> Well, you know,
>> somebody hurts your feelings.
>> Feelings. Yeah. Okay. So, how can you be
loving
>> when Yeah.
>> When somebody's hurt your feelings,
>> right? You know,
>> well, you can turn around and say the
more people have hurt your feelings, the
more loving you should be to try to
overcome that.
>> You want You know what I'm saying?
>> So, if I'm being difficult right now
uh about understanding what you're
saying,
>> I double my efforts to really understand
what what it is she's trying to say to
me.
>> Okay. what is it she really wants to
bring out in the conversation.
So I'm I'm doubling my effort now to
comprehend
uh the point you would like me to make
for the sake of the listener or the view
>> viewer.
Okay. So um so you should then you know
I mean in the Bible it says turn the
other cheek.
Sometimes
I don't feel like turning the other
cheek. So, what do you do then?
>> I don't remember that that I tore that
page out.
>> Oh, okay.
>> I threw that and threw that page away.
>> What does that repeat? What does that
says?
>> What is that teaching?
>> Well, you know, it's like the meek shall
inherit the earth and turn the other
cheek. And you know, when you've been,
you know, insulted or hurt, you turn the
other cheek, you know.
>> Oh. Be become non retaliatory.
>> Non retaliatory. Yeah.
>> And to just go with the flow.
>> Yeah.
>> Uhhuh.
>> That reminds me of a funny card. It says
only dead fish go with the flow.
>> That's funny. That is funny.
So
would you say then that by turning the
other cheek, say you've been insulted or
your feelings are hurt, by turning the
other cheek,
does that help promote a better
relationship?
>> It might and it might not. There's times
to turn the other cheek is the wise
thing to do and there's other times when
it is not the wise thing to do because
it'll invite more of the same.
>> Okay.
uh I think only up to a certain
limitation,
>> right?
>> I turn the other cheek out of
consideration for the other person's
state of consciousness.
>> I realize that they're doing the best
they can.
Uh but if they could do better,
>> uh I might expect them to do better by
saying I'm I'm not going to go along
with that. I understand what you mean by
it, but I'm not going to go along with
it.
>> Okay. I think that you could do better.
>> Um,
>> you know,
>> how important is it to be with
like-minded people?
>> I think it's a matter of comfort to be
with like-minded people
because you don't have to explain
yourself.
Uh, it just everything goes by
presumption.
>> If you're not with like-minded people,
you have to explain yourself.
So in a foreign culture, I've lived in
foreign countries
where there is some degree of
explanation, you really need
uh to explain yourself. So so they will
not be offended.
So for the sake of their happiness,
I would provide explanations that I
wouldn't ordinarily
just that so that they feel more
comfortable.
>> Mhm. So you reach a certain point of
life where the happiness of everybody
around you uh is important and you do
what you can
within limitations
not to violate your own certain inner
expectations.
You don't want to violate your own code
inner code.
>> If everybody's stealing something
doesn't mean I'm going to join them
>> because I would experience guilt about
it.
There are certain situations in life
where thievery becomes prevailing.
>> How can we have a deeper connection to
our higher self? Um, and
as far as that goes, um,
would you
bring the awareness of our higher self?
So, you just got done explaining, you
know, that your principles um, you know,
if you everyone was stealing something
that your principles would hold you back
because you would have guilt over over
stealing something. So
>> um when your principles are being um
challenged that's when you would say
don't turn the other cheek then.
>> There you go.
>> Okay. So in your principles of who you
you know right and wrong or whatever uh
your principles are um that would be the
turning point as to not
>> so you don't want to facilitate other
people's negativity.
>> You know if they're all stealing
something doesn't mean you have to join
them.
>> Uhhuh. Mhm.
>> Many of these things are so subtle and
so complicated
>> that you can't really explain them in,
you know, because language is, you know,
linear,
you can't explain a lot of things in
linear logic. Mhm.
>> There might be moments when joining the
furry would be the thing to do.
>> Mhm.
>> And
moments when the opposite would prevail.
Would be wrong to join what prevails.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Okay.
>> So let's say during a typhoon, everybody
was scared.
So if I'm not frightened
and everybody sees that I'm not
frightened, it could have what a couple
of different influences.
>> Mhm.
>> It might throw them into shame over the
fact that they're afraid and I'm not.
Or it might encourage them that it's
okay to exhibit your fear. Uh there's
nothing wrong with being scared to
death. Mhm.
>> There's times when it's very smart to be
scared.
>> Yeah.
>> So the fact that you let them know that
I'm, you know, frankly I'm scared scared
lets it be okay for them to be scared.
>> So when you were in that typhoon, did
you have uh did you know that u God was
with you? I mean did you know that that
or
>> and no in moments of high terror
uh the conscious awareness of the
presence of God disappeared.
It's more like a prevailing condition
that expresses itself less specifically
>> under certain circumstances.
It's a presumption. I don't think about
the presence of God all the time.
In fact, I seldom really think of it
specifically.
>> The fact that we are speaking right now
in the presence of God is obviously a
fact.
But as we speak of it, I am not
consciously aware of God being a
witness, observer,
>> participant, supervisor, prevailing
condition.
So if a thing is a presumption of life
then it doesn't have to be necessarily
repeated. We could just assume that it
prevails under all circumstances.
What I'm saying to you now I hope will
be the best possible explanation I can
of answering your question.
uh not for God's sake but for the sake
of the listener
for the good good of all that it might
be of help to someone to be more
accepting of human limitation.
It's okay to be scared and cowardly and
fearful and regretful and it's okay to
have negative feelings.
U and the thing is to not let them
dominate your life
>> to accept them as a passing phenomena
and often a necessary one.
I mean just as they're going to put you
to sleep to do surgery on you naturally
you're going to feel natural feel fear.
You hope that everything goes all right.
You don't cut off the wrong ear.
Oh, this year you cut the wrong ear off.
>> Does um would you say in a in a partner
relationship um does love hold you
together?
>> Does it is it the love for each other
that holds you together or is it the
love of who that person is? What really
holds you together in a in a loving
relationship? I think that that specific
energy
love is both specific and non-specific.
But in a specific uh relationship, the
specifics become very important.
So we love those who we love because
we're a loving person to begin with. In
addition to which
we we learn to love many of their
characteristics.
I know for instance that you will always
do the best possible j job you can about
anything that you do because that's just
who you are and it's okay that at times
you don't you say no it's too much
bother to make breakfast this morning
we'll do without it today
so then you say we're not having bacon
and eggs this morning okay
if we are it's terrific and if or not,
it's okay.
>> Mhm.
>> So, but um the love that you have for
each other, does that hold you together
or is it just
another aspect of
>> Well, you are together.
>> I I I feel it holds us together. Yeah. I
feel
>> I feel that it holds us together.
So in other words,
>> yeah, is a generality.
>> You have to love yourself before someone
else can love you. Is that what you're
saying?
>> Well, that's a nice way of putting it. I
don't know necessarily true.
>> Okay.
>> You cannot love yourself too much and
love other people a lot. I think
uh or vice versa. love yourself and not
love many people.
So, it's a variable quality
and I think different circumstances
bring it forth.
>> Mhm.
>> There's that airplane that loves us. You
hear it comes over us.
>> Yes, I did.
>> It keeps flying over us to say, "Oh, I
love you down there. You're talking and
you don't want me to make noise, but I
love you so much. I'm going to make some
noise so you can say how much you love
me even though I'm making noise.
Um,
>> so you're saying that uh in uh the love
for each other that you hold, the love
that you have for each other as a couple
um that
would you say that um similar goals as
far as it goes as your spirituality is
important as well as um
your relationship with each other.
>> Well, if you call love spiritual to
begin with, you know, then then it it
prevails all the time.
>> Okay.
>> Uh if you call it just an emotion,
then that's a different thing.
But love is both an emotion and a
spiritual condition. In my my experience
of it,
um the willingness, the capacity to be
loving
is already a spiritual
condition that prevails.
Some people tend to be loving uh at all
times and in all places
>> with few exceptions.
Takes a lot to make them stop being
loving.
>> All right. um if someone was in say a a
bad relationship or quote toxic u
relationship
um
you know is that in their mind is tox
toxic or is it in you know I mean you
you always ask yourself that how can I
what am I doing wrong in this
relationship you know how can I make
this relationship better especially if
you've been with someone for quite a
Or is it just that you ignored those
uh behaviors?
>> Well, I think that one's one's capacity
to uh comprehend limitation varies
depending on many local conditions.
>> Okay. uh your willingness for instance
um and then every relationship goes
through periods of ups and downs I think
and periods when the other person is
preoccupied with other demands
uh in our relationship I'm very aware
uh of timing
because if my timing is wrong and you're
under stress
uh from other demands in your life, I
know you won't have the the time or the
energy or the tolerance for for an
additional one.
>> So, consideration, part of love is
consideration.
Uh knowing what kind of the situation
the other person is in,
you know, as far as stress, family,
relationships, physical health, and many
other things, many other factors.
>> Mhm.
So when you you're under a lot of
demands by a lot of people, which you
often are, I try to make my request to
you as limited as possible because I
realize you're already under stress.
You know, multiple family members,
friends, neighbors, God knows what all
>> and uh so I try to keep my own
expectation down to
more appropriate time and location. Mhm.
>> So we try to time our expectations.
>> Well, we know that um in one's
relationship with other people, it's
very difficult to you know be totally
>> emerged in that relationship at all
times.
>> It's not even very healthy to be that
way really.
>> Um you know, so you do some things apart
and some things together.
>> Yes. you know
>> and that adds to the enjoyment.
>> Yeah.
>> So some things you enjoy being with
somebody
and other other people other things you
enjoy being apart.
So that adds to the flavor. It's like
the weather being different different
days of the week.
>> You know, a rainy day would not be happy
every day,
>> but once in a great while it's sort of
fun. and all of a sudden it's raining
out and it's exciting.
I think there's a there's one roof where
we live where you can really hear the
rain and I always get a kick out of
going on that room and you can hear it
peling down on the roof and Wow, listen
to that.
>> Yeah.
>> I always know when it snows because you
can't hear it when it hits. It just kind
of drifts and so you come out and all of
a sudden everything's white.
The rain you can hear, but the snow it
always comes down very softly.
>> You never know it's there until you get
up.
>> Well, I grew up in Wisconsin and more
snow was not exactly an exciting
development for the morning. In Arizona,
snow is exciting.
>> Yeah, it is.
>> So many of the things then depend on the
circumstances.
Snow in Wisconsin was not an exciting
development. Snow in Arizona. Wow.
Everybody gets up and runs to the window
and says, "Look, there's snow."
>> That's true.
>> Very exciting.
>> They do the same with rain, too, though.
>> For what?
>> Rain. They do the same with rain.
>> Oh,
>> yeah. Another rain.
>> I think more people go out in the rain
in Arizona than stay in.
Um,
so when we get back to relationships and
would you say that um a relationship
that has a spiritual base is stronger
than say one that does not.
>> I I think it isn't that um the spiritual
base means accountability.
>> Accountability of what? Accountability
of one's overall condition of
lovingness.
So a non-spiritual relationship allows
people to do things that uh uh spiritual
people would never consider doing.
Hurting other people's feelings in
certain ways for instance selling them
or
>> uh
>> or physical violence or whatever
>> cruelty of any kind you know and if you
make a mistake you apologize for it.
>> Mhm.
So, for instance, if I if I'm being
dumb, you know, I apologize for being
dumb and I'll say, "Geez, that was a
dumb thing to say or a dumb thing to
do." Or
that would dumb.
>> So, um, would you say that knowing when
to say gosh, I'm sorry, is a very
important part of a relationship?
>> I I think that really helps really helps
a lot. the willingness to say uh
uh I was mistaken. I'm sorry that I
complained
and um
so cordiality that that's part of being
cordial.
>> So loving relationship is also one
that's cordial.
Cordial means a consideration for the
feelings of others
>> to express things in a way that is
uplifting rather than downgrading.
>> So would you say that you would put
someone else's feelings ahead of your
own or would you say you would just con
you should consider the other person's
feelings?
>> You would consider it and sometimes you
would put the other person's feelings
ahead of your own. Uh other times, uh
they could wait.
>> Okay.
>> Uh you can wait till you get home.
You don't have to express everything
while you're in the middle of the
highway.
>> Mhm.
>> You know, and then when you get home,
you can say, you know,
you shouldn't have passed him on the
right.
>> Mhm. Mhm.
>> If you don't want to say it at the time.
>> Mhm.
>> So many of these things have to do with
timing. Mhm.
>> And the subtlety
and the totality of the overall
uh set of conditions.
>> Mhm.
>> But we all uh could improve in some way
in some area. So it's it's fun when
you're bored. You can sit down and say
now in what way could I improve myself
>> and under what conditions could I
improve myself?
So if we took like a uh an inventory
>> there, there you go.
>> So you take a personal inventory,
>> a moral inventory, right? They do that
in the 12step group. You take
periodically you take a moral inventory
>> and uh ask God to point out where you
could improve and ask for help to
improve in that area.
>> You could be more considerate of others.
You could be less selfish.
>> I know. That's something people don't
take the time to do
>> is to
>> uh
>> well if a spiritually oriented person
does take time to do that
um you do take time to do a periodic
moral inventory
>> you know where could I improve myself
>> in 12 12steps group you do that every
day every day you ask for knowledge of
God's will for you and the power to
carry it out I ask for God ask for
knowledge of God's will for me and the
power to carry that out. In other words,
and then you're asking divinity
um to point out to you where you would
be of greater service to God to man your
fellow human being and also of course to
your own self.
Uh so it might be more kind, more
thoughtful, might be
um or it might be the opposite way to
stop being so selfacing and speak up for
yourself periodically.
>> It just depends on the individual
>> and the circumstances which in human
life can be quite complex.
So if we were to sum this up kind of
it's you should have some kind of
spiritual base for a strong
relationship.
>> I think of a spiritual orientation by
both people gives much greater strength.
Yes.
>> Right. And you should have consideration
and timing for the other person
when approaching.
Part of lovingness is right
>> being considerate of their mood and what
other pressures are prevailing on their
life and
>> what time demand is on them
>> and um
uh what was the other one I was going to
say? Oh, and taking a moral inventory of
yourself
>> periodically. A moral inventory.
I think of course going to church serves
that for some people.
>> Yes, it does. I mean on Sunday they do a
moral eliminatory when they go to church
period.
>> Other people it's a way of life.
Other people it's constant to always be
aware where you could be doing a better
job.
>> Like right now I could be doing maybe a
better job of explaining
my answers to your questions. So as I
answer it, I am also sort of like
feeling within myself how I could become
more fluent, how I could be more fluent
and express uh in
more explicitly
the answer I would like to deliver to
you.
>> Okay.
So relationships
we will always have to deal with them.
uh whether it's um a partnership a
uh
>> God
>> mankind
>> children
>> accountability
>> accountability we haven't touched on
accountability
>> no because it scares people the idea
that you know you're accountable for
your actions
>> and of course that's one reason people
are scared to death of dying is they're
they don't want to be accountable able
and to God for their shortcomings and
their limitations and their sins and
of commission and omission.
God, how can I explain that I did not
spend more time
being considerate of others instead of
cons of being selfishly preoccupied with
my own self and my own possessions, my
own pleasures.
Some people play golf. Other people go
to church on Sunday morning.
Is one better than the other? No. You
could do a bad job of going to church
and a great job of great job of being
loving and friendly playing golf.
>> Yes.
>> So you can't always tell by the
impertinances. Mhm.
>> So if so we have to when we do that
moral inventory then we have to at least
address being accountable for our acts
>> that you're willing to take
responsibility
>> that it was you that yes and said it and
did it and
and you don't have to be hard on
yourself. In other words, it doesn't
mean to be tough on yourself.
>> You can realize that at the time you
were working under limitations
and you did the best you could under
those limitations.
>> Mhm.
>> Had you had better conditions, you could
have done a better job. Yes.
So, in theory at least, we all could be
doing a little bit better than we are.
I could be speaking more clearly than I
am possibly.
But not likely
because my intention when I speak is
always to be as clear
>> uh as as possible
for the sake of the listener
and uh for the sake of myself that I'm
I'm being understood in what I'm saying.
here. Huh.
>> Do you think that um well, you know, men
are from Mars, women are from Venus?
That's a great book because it points
out they just address things
differently. You address, you know, a
woman would address it from this angle
and a man addresses it from this angle.
>> Yeah. You know, and once you read that,
you understand how why thing they just
think differently, you know, when
handling problems, you know, and I
noticed that with you. You you are
always very concerned about solving the
problem. Now, what is the problem? You
know, you always say to me, now what is
the problem?
>> You know, after I've emotionalized on
it,
>> you always say, now what exactly is the
problem?
>> Is that what I do?
>> Yeah.
So, you know, then I have to stop and
think, well, yeah, I did emotionalize on
it and I have to present you to with the
problem that I'm trying to solve.
>> What is the problem?
>> Yeah. What is the problem?
>> I do that.
>> Well, yeah.
>> Oh,
>> you make me go back instead of
emotionalizing about it.
>> Oh, I see.
>> You make me
>> look at the under problem at the real,
you know, what exactly is it that's
bothering
>> I'm a fragmentist, right? Yeah. Well,
you I mean I think it's just a man
thing. I don't think it's anything that
you are. I just think it's the way a man
looks at things that come up in life.
>> Could be.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Pragmatically. Yeah. So the the
man is more pragmatic is
>> uh although when in other conditions
though it's the woman is more pragmatic
>> sometimes
>> when it comes to healing people's
feelings especially those of children
and people around them.
Um to that to the woman, the most
practical thing is to calm everybody
down and make them feel better.
>> The guys thinking they can take care of
their own
feelings.
>> That's true, too. But um it just seems
like re all relationships are very
complicated.
>> They really are when you examine them.
when you really look at them and examine
them, no matter what kind of
relationship it is, it's very compliment
complicated with all these different
aspects and then you add emotion to that
and I don't see how anything ever gets
healed or solved or you know fixed
you know after how do they get you know
how do you even come to a conclusion on
this? Well, because there's enough
tolerance. There's enough cushioning in
life.
No, we want to be polite to the
policeman.
>> Uh
he says, "You got to wait for the red
light." And so you uh try to be polite
to the policeman. You wait for the red
light, but you might be in a hurry and
say, "The heck with the policeman. I'm
going to cross against the red light
whether he likes it or not."
So the conditions that prevail dominate
all the decisions and how you feel about
them.
>> Okay?
>> It might be there might be times when
it's wrong uh to do exactly what the
policeman thinks you should be doing
because he doesn't know the other
conditions that you have to face when
you get to the other side of the street.
>> Mhm.
So at times we have to take charge
of our own situation
whatever the consequences might be.
And the willingness to accept the
consequences of those variations
uh are what add to our the strength of
our adulthood. You might say
if I look at myself as capable of
handling many different situations
and different conditions
then um I'll feel better about myself
and and I'll be more willing to take
chances.
So it would make me more capable as a
person than one who's more limited and
intolerant. Mhm.
>> I got mad yesterday about something.
Uh oh yes, I remember. I got mad that I
couldn't see the way I used to see.
Well, I went blind in one eye and poor
poor vision one eye and blind in the
other
for some reason. I've gotten used to
that. For some reason, I suddenly got
mad about it
and uh I did something stupid. But I
couldn't see very well. And so I got mad
and threw my clothes on the on the
floor.
Didn't I Is that what I did?
>> Yeah, that's what you did.
>> I think I did. I I said, "I can't see
the damn thing." And I threw the clothes
on the floor.
>> Well, that's more frustration than it
was anything.
>> Yeah,
that's the inner child, right? The inner
child.
>> Yeah. I got mad at myself. I got mad at
not being able to see. And so I threw my
clothes on the floor. I think it was
funny. And as soon as I did it, I said,
"Was that good or bad?" Well, depends on
how you look at it.
>> I didn't pick them up.
>> Well, I thought it was good that I I
suppress my emotions most of the time
that I I feel are unsocial,
not socially acceptable.
Ordinarily, I would repress being angry
over limitation.
Uh, but for some reason I was freer with
myself. I said, "The hell with it." And
I took my clothes and I threw them on
the floor and I was mad that I can't see
out of my right eye anymore.
>> I was mad.
>> Yeah.
>> Mad that I can't see like I wish I could
see or I used to see.
Then I let it be okay to be mad.
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah. So then I then I had to give up
feeling guilty that I was mad.
>> Yeah.
>> Then I felt good I was mad. I said,
"Well, thank God you felt mad about it.
Express your being mad about it.
At least you're being emotionally
honest." And
>> but see, those are things that come up.
You know, you with the physical, too.
You know, you never know. Um, you know,
people can be very um short with you and
you don't know if something's going on
physically with that person.
>> Yes, that's true. or you know they just
were told bad news. You never know. So
you know a lot of people go well they
weren't very nice to me
>> you know so
>> you know
you have to take all those things into
consideration too
>> right? So it's best to be as tolerant as
you can be under the circumstances.
Of course the downside of that is people
consider you're wishywashy and they can
walk all over you and abuse you. So it's
a so everything that we say there's a
limitation. There's a top side to it and
a downside to it.
>> There is
>> uh it's not they're not we're not
dealing with
>> it's not clear. We're not dealing with
clear things.
>> When you when you come with human
emotions, you're never dealing with
absolutes.
>> You're always dealing with relatives.
And depends on circumstances and timing
and your age at the time and how old you
were and what your physical, mental and
financial condition was.
Is it wrong to spend this much money for
something or other? Depends on your
overall financial condition.
>> Mhm.
>> And that of your family and
your obligation to society and your
culture etc. Mhm.
>> Everything is really far more
complicated on the one hand, far more
complicated than it seems.
Uh and far more difficult than it seems.
On the other hand, alternately
paradoxically,
uh things are also quite simple and not
as complicated as as they seem.
>> So I just took the clothes and I said
the heck of them and threw them on the
floor.
That was simple enough.
>> Yeah.
>> And then I feel guilty about that. So I
picked them up again.
>> But at least you got your frustration
out.
>> Yeah. Right. Yeah. Yeah. It was fun.
>> It was fun.
>> I mean, I seldom indulge myself that
way, you know? It's like,
>> I know.
>> I couldn't throw your clothes on the
floor. I mean, it's like unheard of.
>> Yeah.
show you might say was it pleasing my
inner child.
>> So, so out of all of this we should take
uh we should try be considerate of other
people.
>> Yes.
>> At all times try and take a moral
inventory on how you can either see it
differently or to improve on oneself.
And these things can all go on sort of
automatically,
>> right?
>> Uh semiconsciously without necessarily
exclusively focusing on them in a formal
way,
>> but always aware that you're accountable
for your maturity of your responses and
your emotions.
>> You should respect the other person's
feelings and situations they may be in.
>> Yes.
And I believe in being as tolerant as
you can of other people's limitations.
I think being a human human being is a
very difficult
>> very is frankly quite difficult.
uh we may not think so we've gotten in
nerd to it
>> because we're used to it but it's
frankly quite difficult
being a human being very often
>> and um being consideration having a
consideration for um
situations
um
I think being sympathetic to other
people's
conditions of other people's lives and
their limitations.
Don't you think so? Yes.
>> Makes you compassion.
>> Yeah. to a compassionate human being is
aware of the limitations of being human
uh in general and then specifically in
certain circumstances
>> to be more forgiving than usual and more
loving than usual
>> and then re respecting uh the other
person's you know space basically and
their and their um complicated life as
well as your own. So you know we have a
tendency to only look at ourselves and
say I I want you know I can't handle
this. Yeah. Uhhuh.
Can you consider the conditions that
other people infect other living beings,
not only people,
>> but even your pets and your animals? And
>> how many days can your canary go without
being fed and have new water and all,
>> right?
>> How many hours can you be gone and your
doggy, you know, start to miss you
badly? And you got to really try to make
your doggy feel better when you get
home.
>> Mhm.
make it. There's nothing makes you
happier than a dog's waggy tail.
>> That's true.
>> So, I like to think of other people in
those terms. I like to see other
people's tails wagging.
>> I like it when you're wagging your tail
and you you think
>> Thanks, Nate.
I mean, it's not everybody that gets
called a dog. if you if you please.
Well, I mean that's the waggginess
>> is a quality of of feeling feeling life
>> and making it
>> and u wagggininess is is something we
like to bring forth in others. You know
that
>> other people will enjoy our presence and
we're doing what we can to
>> butter their toast on one side instead
of both sides.
Well, so relationships are, you know,
they can be good, they can be bad. Um
it's is it some of it is what we make it
>> a good deal of it certainly what we make
it
>> okay
>> consciously but as I said that
>> that varies from condition to condition
because some some things are just
>> you've decided on a certain lifestyle
>> that automatically has consequences.
>> Okay. Then you've decided on you've
settled for certain human attitudes
uh as habits of ways of being in ways of
being a human being
>> and they have consequences too. So
we it's it's a many many uh multifaceted
and complex situation
how you decide you want to be as a human
being in this life.
you want to be lovable and and loved.
>> Um or you want to be completely
self-centered and disputatious.
So, we make these decisions all the
time.
You could be disputatious in the morning
and then decide that's that's horrible
and lunchtime change to being friendly.
>> I think being a human being is very
complex.
So it's a wonder that anyone has a
relationship that works with all these
blocks that
>> all things that could go wrong
>> could go wrong.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. It's very difficult.
>> The other thing is say if we could be
better we would be.
>> Okay.
>> That could be is the hypothetical.
>> Mhm.
>> In reality you can only be as friendly
as you're capable of being that day.
Some days you're capable more capable of
being friendly than other days. you're
not really capable
because you have other human conditions
that prevail,
>> right?
>> And all these conditions, you know,
dominate brain chemistry.
So all this doesn't happen in a vacuum.
What you're talking about is human
hormones
and emotions and the biochemical
physiologic reactions thereof.
All of which have very uh strong
consequences, very serious ones.
>> So what words of wisdom can you give us
about relationships
>> to be God or
>> I think to be as loving as possible
and to be aware in the back of your mind
that you're accountable.
I'm always aware that I'm incountable
for one thing to myself
speak as fluently as I would like to
have spoken but I'm also aware that all
this is not happening in a vac in a
vacuum that there is an ultimate
accountability to divinity
to fulfill my potentiality to the best
of my ability
not only for myself but for the people
around and the world around me
>> to make life as pleasant as I can. So if
I'm in a store, I want to make the
encounter with the clerk behind the
counter as pleasant as possible for the
clerk
to be a pleasant customer instead of a
complaining obnoxious one.
Some people don't seem to mind being
obnoxious
and uh they always sort of amaze me, but
they do. They don't care how nasty or
demanding they are or vulgar or loud.
And uh I always say to myself, now how
are people like that brought up?
Who brought them up or failed to bring
them up rather?
I believe in being as loving in as you
can in all conditions.
to be as loving to the clerk behind the
counter as you are to the cop on the
beat to your family and your grandmother
on the phone.
Be as loving as you can towards all of
life. To the doggy on the corner and to
the kitty that's lost and is hungry and
wants some milk.
I'll say kitty kitty kitty. This morning
I did.
>> They all line up.
>> I did. I said, "Kitty, kitty, kitty."
Oh, all the kitties lined up.
Uh
>> so um relationships
um we have good ones, we have bad ones
and uh in the end uh a relationship that
is centered around God
um kind of keeps us in check.
>> I I think it brings it back to reality.
>> Yeah. that no matter how how how you
much you want to excuse it that that uh
you're still accountable to to get to
God in the end that you did the best you
could under the circumstances.
If you could have done better, you would
have.
>> Okay.
>> I'm I'm always aware that we are always
in the presence of God at all times and
accountable to God.
Also, God in a way is like a giant
recording machine. Everything you've
ever said or done is registered somehow
in in the reality of divinity.
>> Mhm.
>> Forever.
So there's a to me it is there's a
certain permanence to divinity
>> that uh a thing you have done or said is
a permanent imprint
doesn't mean the consequences are
permanent but the happening the event
and how it was handled the
>> is a is a permanent imprint that's there
historically.
Mhm.
So you might say each of us represents a
collection of our own personal history
from moment to moment
and that personal history is variable
from moment to moment.
So right as I speak now I'm either
making it better or worse.
uh by trying to be flexible,
I try to create an atmosphere that the
listener is as forgiving and gentle with
themsel as I'm trying to be in a general
way.
>> Mhm.
>> That we all make, you know, errors that
we wish we had not made. That that's
part of the human condition. It's okay
to love oursel
>> even though we've made mistakes.
And also part of our loving ourself is
to try to avoid him in the future you
know for sake of pleasantness of
existence for the sake of the welfare of
others. So the happier we are as a human
being more satisfied we are the more
beneficial we are to other humans. So
you're being good good to other people
when you're good to yourself because
you're becoming a more pleasant and
positive human being to be around. So
what you're adding to the pool of human
experience is something that's positive
instead of something that's negative. So
I believe in being as happy and positive
as you can at all times under all
circumstances for the good and the
welfare of everything and everyone
as well as
uh gratitude to God for one's existence.
One way to express gratitude is to be
the best, most loving, generous,
capable,
pleasing human being that you can be.
Mhm.
>> Okay. Thank you, honey.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
Hallelujah.