Today's questions are going to be
related to the chat topic of um how to
see the reality of life.
>> I see the reality of life
is coming to torment us
called an airplane. Right overhead
right overhead. Right overhead.
>> Okay. All right.
Um these some of these are questions
that people have sent in and some of
them are ones that I wanted to ask. So
they'll be kind of a combination.
>> Um why is it that we feel that life is
so difficult here on earth?
>> Well, it's because it is
to begin with. You got to defy gravity
all day long.
>> You were hitting the mic with your king.
I'm sorry.
>> That's right.
>> To begin with, you have to defy defy
defy gravity all day long.
>> You know, you're standing up vertically
like this on on on a narrow platform
just two feet
and all kinds of things jostle you and
push you. And then you have a certain
number of senses and they're also
assaulted.
vision. You got to watch all these
things here and you got to listen to
everything that's going on. You have to
be careful not to bump into things. And
human body, as tough as it may seem, is
really quite fragile. I mean, you can
break it pretty easily.
All you got to do is push it over a
cliff or something.
>> That'll do it.
>> Push it into a lake and you're done with
it.
You know it it it takes constant
awareness. So no matter what we're doing
in the back of our mind there is always
the security and safety and continuence
of the physical body
>> and that's presumed. It's presumed that
it's being looked after.
>> Just like at this moment, I presume
that this couch is going to hold us up
and we're being reported recorded
correctly and that the lighting will be
sufficient. So, I'm making a dozen
presumptions already.
And then this airplane keeps going right
over our head to try and drone out our
microphone.
Anyway, all right. Yes. Survival is uh
it takes up 90% of our time and 10% is
amusement.
90% of our energy is really survival.
Eating, standing up, walking, breathing
in and out.
>> Mhm.
>> Just staying alive.
>> Yeah. Because um well a lot of times we
feel that there is um suffering and it's
a struggle you know to stay alive. So
you're attributing it to the physical.
>> Yes. Yes. Yeah. The psychological is a
whole different program,
>> but but just staying physically alive
itself is already a challenge to not get
run over or have a heart attack or stab
yourself in the eye with something
>> accidentally.
So physical survival is is presumed
and and then you've got psychological
and emotional survival
which gets more subtle and more
difficult.
Do would you say that by um leaning on
one's faith that it helps with these
struggles and these um uh turmoils in
life by having by uh having faith
involved?
>> Faith.
>> Faith involved in one's life.
>> Faith or faith?
>> Faith.
>> How you spell it?
>> F A T H.
>> Oh, faith. Yes. Uhhuh.
>> Yeah. Without faith, you wouldn't be
able to survive more than a couple of
minutes.
>> Yeah.
>> I have faith in this whole process that
we're going through right now
that it's being properly recorded and
that we have a safe secure place to sit
that our safety is assured that our
survival is guaranteed. Mhm.
>> Okay.
>> Presumptions.
So by having uh faith in God and um you
know what would be a typical way of of
praying about that? Would you say um you
would pray that um to let God handle all
of our problems or
>> I think um the one they use in the
12step programs.
I asked God for his knowledge for me
this day and the
I pray for God's will for me and the
power to carry it out.
>> It's pretty hard to improve on that one.
>> Mhm.
>> Uh that's a 12step movement. Praying for
knowledge of God's will for me and then
the power to carry it out. So that
pretty much covers the basis about as
well as it can be done.
>> Okay.
>> Pray for knowledge of God's will for me.
Everybody presumes they know what God's
will for is for them because if you go
to church, you have your, you know,
presumptions.
Mhm.
I pray for knowledge of God's will for
me and the power to carry it out.
That's a
that's a that's a basic that's a basic
of life.
>> Okay. How does one maintain a spiritual
awareness in in going on in in one's
daily life? How does one how does one
maintain a spiritual awareness in
going on about one's daily life?
>> Well, because you you become that kind
of person.
So by spir following spiritual
principles you become
a spiritualized person in which
spiritual realities
automatically take priority in in the
back of your mind. Mhm.
>> So just as we talk now, the spiritual
realities of our relationship and what
we're doing this very instant take
dominance over anything else. I don't
stop in the middle of all this to have a
glass of root beer. You know what I
mean?
Root beer was my favorite when I grew
up. Today's rule is Coca-Cola. My year
was root beer.
That's good.
>> I love root beer floats.
>> You like root beer? Oh, yeah. Root beer
floats. Can't beat that.
>> No. On a hot summer day, that's
>> Oh, boy.
>> Yeah. But um Okay, getting back. So,
you're saying that spirituality
uh does it take the edge off of um
this constant struggle?
I think it um it creates an atmosphere
that that prevails over and dominates
everything.
>> Okay.
>> Just as we speak now, it's prevailing
and dominating.
>> I'm quite aware where we are and what
we're doing and what our commitment is
>> and the presence of God and that I'm
accountable to do the best that I can.
Mhm.
>> accountable to myself, to God.
Um,
and so in the back of my mind, I'm not
consciously saying it, but
there's a domination of my decision
to be as lucid and cooperative and
informative as I can be. Just as we sit
on this couch right this moment. Mhm. If
I could be more lucid, I would hope to
be more lucid. If I could speak with
greater clarity, I would hope to speak
with greater clarity.
And so those intentions dominate
everything I do and say.
So when um
daily problems become overwhelming
and very difficult to handle, you know,
well, for us at least, like we had a
recently had a toilet bust and the house
flooded. So, you know, I mean, it was
this whole disruption that lasted for
months because the new carpet, you know,
cleaning up the mess. It was just, you
know, constant. So, how do you when you
have these disasters that happen? How
how do you h handle them and still be
spiritual? Because I wasn't very
spiritual when this was happening.
>> Spiritual is whatever you name it. The
willingness to the willingness to tackle
the uh obstacles of life is already a
spiritual commitment.
So spiritual commitment is is a
commitment to staying alive.
>> Mhm.
>> So it's a commitment to life itself.
>> Okay. When you give up altogether, then
you don't bother trying to stay alive
and you quit eating and you quit
drinking water and you don't go to the
doctor and you don't take the medicine
and you just give up and roll over and
die. Mhm.
And uh there's no law against that.
Although if you try, most people will
drag you away
and put you in an institution.
>> Yeah.
It's presumed
a priority
that your survival is number one in your
mind. So we all make that presumption
about each other
and I presume that you are hoping we
will make the best use of these few
minutes and uh that that is a
presumption on my part that you are
hoping that.
Yes. Uhhuh. Okay. Um, you know, greed. I
want to talk a little bit about glamour
and greed. It seems like, you know,
everybody watches TV and on there is
always the glamour and greed uh that is
portrayed. Um,
how does one handle
uh the
wants, the human wants, you know, of the
everyday life?
So they're they're talking about
appearance,
>> right?
>> So um I'm not too familiar with those
terms in my own particular daily life,
but um we all want to look our best. So
I mean I tried to look halfway decent
today.
Do I look halfway decent?
>> You look halfway decent.
>> Good God.
>> Glamour is a patina on top of that.
>> Okay. Uh so first there's survival
and there's adequacy. Then there's
trying to look your best
whatever aesthetically and stylistically
may be considered to be uh you know like
mink coats are not in anymore. Mink
coats. When I grew up, a mink coat was
the ultimate. And now nobody would be
caught dead in a real mink coat. Uh
because it would mean killing a mink.
And killing animals is no longer okay.
So nobody wears leopard coats or mink
coats. Mhm.
>> They may wear artificial ones cuz they
don't want to kill a real animal.
>> Mhm.
>> Just to satisfy the human ego that they
can afford a leopard or a mink coat.
>> Yeah. When I grew up, a mink coat was
the ultimate.
>> So when I say glamour, I mean, you know,
it's the glamour of having the brand new
car. It's the glamour of living in the
best house or the biggest house on your
neighborhood. But it's
>> well they say that glamour is actually a
specific energy.
>> Okay.
>> That there is a specific energy. Could I
have your arms again? There is a
specific energy called glamour. It is a
specific energy.
It is a specific energy. So it isn't
just in our imagination.
There is a certain energy that it
attracts to itself.
It creates a certain glitter and appeal.
>> Mhm.
>> And attraction. Uhhuh.
And people will sacrifice a a great deal
for that glamour. Uhhuh.
>> And it's associated with success and
impressing other people.
>> And so it's the ego's home.
>> The ego goes home to glamour. All that
goes with glamour.
I hope I'm I hope I'm passable. You know
what I'm saying? I I I haven't got the
time and energy to get involved in
glamour.
>> So, do you would you say that most
people over um
o uh you know, most people, you know,
they're they get a they get their house,
they get a a good car, they raise their
family, but yet that isn't enough for
them.
Well,
>> and they want more.
>> They want more.
>> Yeah.
>> More than having everything you need,
>> right?
>> Uh, that would be for what? Amusement.
>> Well, that's only one bicycle at a time,
so you don't really need two.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Well, that's your interpretation,
but I mean there are there are a lot of
people that are not satisfied with where
they are or their station in life, you
know.
>> Oh, cravingness. Yes.
>> Like a cravingness. So, they're always
pushing themselves to
>> do more and do more and
>> to be driven more and
>> well, you know, just being conscious of
what you're being driven by,
>> okay?
>> And what its qualities are. You say,
"Well, I'm worth a quarter of a million
and uh I'd be happy if I was worth half
a million." So, you drive yourself till
you get to half a million. And now at
half a million, you say, "Well, if I had
3/4 of a million, I'd be happier."
So, it's the idea that more more is
better.
>> More money will make you happier.
I've been poor and I've been rich and uh
uh
being rich was more convenient.
>> So it's the convenience.
>> It's more convenience than anything.
>> But there's a lot there's a certain
amount of responsibility that goes along
with that.
>> Oh yeah. Yeah. The upside is you got
convenience.
The downside is you got more to polish
and take care of and worry about and get
insurance on and guard and lock up at
night and be afraid people are going to
break in your house to steal it. So if
you've got a lot of flashy diamonds and
you flash them around,
uh you're going to attract all kinds of
uh attacks and people wanting to steal
your diamonds.
So the glamour has its limitations
in that it also attracts vandalism and
hatred and envy and jealousy and attack.
So we like to applaud
uh famous people at the same time
they're envied and hated and
they're it's about 5050.
Um,
what could you give us
uh like a tool to use when
daily life is just too overwhelming to
handle? Can you give us a a prayer or or
a thought or a daily tool that we can
use when that comes about in one's life?
>> I think
uh the reality of the awaren the
awareness of the presence of God.
>> Okay.
I mean what I myself have used over the
years is the awareness of the presence
of God.
That bride is continuously God is always
present and and continuously
prevails
as we speak. Now I realize that we are
speaking in the presence of God and I am
accountable to divinity
for the truth and sincerity with which I
speak.
And uh I would be confronted confronted
with uh the conflict of falsehood if I
was speaking contrary to what I actually
believe.
Um that dominion of God prevails over
all things at all times
pervades the essence of all that is.
Um that on a certain level there is
nothing except God.
and how we accept that reality.
Nothing exists except divinity
including our own existence.
So I thank God for my existence.
Um because without it we and I would not
even be sitting here talkinghu.
So God is not only the background but
the context and the essence
of all that is all that prevails as
divinity.
All that exists is divinity. Nothing
except God exists.
So would you say that when we get that
point where if someone was pushing
themselves that they want more, they
want more, they want more to take say a
mental inventory
>> to slow down and take a mental inventory
>> of of uh what is really important to him
rather than this constant push.
And in part of one's daily prayer then
is to ask God uh what should I consider
important today? What should I treat
with with a greater respect than
anything else?
What should I be appreciative of?
Now today you and I are sitting on this
couch in front of a camera
>> and that's rather unique. We don't do
that every day. So uh my
uh
um self- reggard then would depend on
how well I think I fulfilled my
uh ca capabilities
if I could have been more fluent. So I
could regret later that I was not more
fluent. I did not explain things as
adequately as I I wish I could have.
But then I expect that as part of part
part and parcel of life. No matter what
you do, you can look back and say,
"Well, I could have done that better."
No matter what you do,
>> well,
>> and you begin to accept that's one of
the downside of the human mind
>> is that it's always self-critical.
You could have been funnier. You could
have gotten your hair more better combed
or you might have gotten a better
haircut. I mean there's no end to it,
no end to the self torment of tra
travail or perfectionism. So on taking a
a a mental and physical inventory um one
would say you know would you do like
you know for instance you have all right
so you have a house now and you have a
car and your kids are you know doing
well and you so you take like a basic
inventory and say you know that kind of
slows you down and makes you realize
that uh the things you thought were
important or not important.
um that
you know that
extra trip or whatever you're you know
is
>> yeah daily inventory brings you back
down to uh spiritual basics
>> right
>> I mean if you have love like right now I
have love and I now I have companionship
I have love and companionship
>> and I have whatever is adequate to
physical survival I've got you know
enough clothes to wear in a cold room is
rather chilly
chilly room, but it's a warm enough
coat. So, I've covered the necessities
of survival. And then beyond that, I
would like to have the pleasure of our
conversation and share our conversation
with others.
>> Why? Because I would like other people
to appreciate the value of their own
existence.
And um you know, for years I saw people
that were they had no self-regard, no
self-respect. They didn't love themsel.
So to love yourself, to appreciate your
own existence
and God is aware how difficult it is to
exist. And it would seem very easy. It
seems easy when you've got momentum
going.
And the reason it's easy is because the
momentum is carrying you along. But it
took a lot of energy and effort to get
the momentum going.
you know that we didn't just magically
appear in this couch, you know, two
seconds ago.
>> We had to travel here in a golf cart and
travel across the ground and park it
correctly and walk up the stairs and
walk through the find our the right room
in this building, then find the right
furniture to sit down.
So, every mode is really a challenge in
a certain way.
So we learned not to focus on the
challenge to handle the challenge
without focusing on it. So we let it let
our awareness be aware of it without
distracting us.
So
I make a joke and I say don't let
reality reality distract you.
>> Don't let reality reality distract you.
Right.
>> Yeah. Don't be distracted by reality.
just presumed that whatever is is.
>> So in the re so when looking at life and
the reality it is
your spirituality is one of the most
important things to look at
>> that that's a primary. I guess that's a
primary
because if you ignore that everything
else begins to collapse
and um there's a certain way in which
the whole week seems you know those of
you who go to church you know if you go
to church on Sunday morning you feel
somehow that you fulfilled a certain
requirement or commitment and that'll
last you all week. the fact that you
went to church on Sunday did this you
could
uh if you couldn't then the knowledge
that you would have if you could have
>> that your commitment is one of value
so we base our self-esteem on what we
value
and I value or myself value our
relationship
and appreciation gratitude the divinity
for our existence
and for the um
religious commitment of uh friends
and and the people with whom we is
associate I appreciate the the fact that
they value spiritual principles
>> doesn't mean you have to have perfected
them but that you value those principles
of fairness equality lovingness
gentleness
uh that you those are principles that to
hold dear to your heart.
>> Train page.
>> God blesses each and everyone. Said T.
Tiny Tim said that.
>> Yeah, Tiny Tim. God blesses everyone.
>> God blesses each and everyone.
>> Okay, here's a good question that
someone wrote in. Does everyone on Earth
evolve?
>> Everyone does.
>> No. Does everyone on Earth evolve? No,
not true. No, some de devolve.
They get worse the longer they're You
know what they do? They devolve. The
prisons are full of them.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, this morning the TV news is full
of, you know, the most grotesque crimes.
People go out of their way, you know, to
commit
cruel and and and
heartless acts, you say. And I say to
myself now, why would a person be so
interested in putting forth that much
energy and effort into something that is
so valless
>> except at the time they were under the
influence of some animal emotion,
envy or rage or retaliation.
Uh
so under animal in animal emotions
people will do things that are almost
unspeakable.
Unspeakable how they could have done
that. You know killed three children.
Three innocent children walking down the
sidewalk are are killed for no reason.
So that's the nature of human life. This
is not heaven.
It has a big downside as well as a big
upside.
>> So we earn our way into a safer
environment called heaven.
>> Um to me it seems like you know here on
earth you have it you have that like you
always said the little magnets you can
turn this way and that way. You know you
always say that you know we're like
little magnets.
>> Yeah.
>> In a field. You go ahead and say that
because you are really
>> Yeah. We are like little magnets and we
either repel
>> retail repel or we're attracted
>> right
>> and uh depending on their polarity.
>> So,
>> so let's say we took a person that had a
spiritual polarity.
>> Yes.
>> So would that would that person attract
similar like beings to them? I I think
so. I think that which is kindly and
loving
attracts that which appreciates kindness
and lovingness.
>> Okay.
>> Um well, let's take just something
simple like a dog, you know.
>> Well, on the way over this morning, the
dog was just happy and wagging her tail.
Then she realized that we were leaving
the house and
>> so her tail stopped wagging.
>> Yeah.
she was facing
being separated from us and of course
she doesn't know for how long.
So I appreciate the dog's feelings and
we try to anticipate her feeling of loss
and I hug her extra special and I tell
her how much I love her and then I'll be
back in a few minutes and I try to give
her a little treat to distract herself
with a toy or something to chew on.
Uh, right now she has a chewy bone. So,
her chewy bone.
I cover her disappointment that we're
leaving in the house. I give her I say,
"Here's your chewy bone." Oh, she's
happy with her chewy bone. I know
that'll keep her happy till we get back.
>> So, you see, part of my happiness is
caring for her needs and fulfilling her
happiness.
So, I'm happier because I know that
Kelsey is happier.
And uh knowing that the dog is happier
makes me feel satisfied and happy with
myself.
>> So, when I please the dog, I'm pleasing
the dog, but I'm also loving myself
because I'm making myself happy that the
dog is happy. So, then love tends to
prevail.
So a household in which love prevails
then is a pleasant place to live because
everyone is concerned about the other
person's comfort instance for instance
is warm enough in here for you u
is the quietude sufficient is you know
the acoustics good enough so I am
concerned right now as we talk with your
comfort are you warm enough and did we
warm this room up enough before we got
Am I speaking loud enough to record it?
So I'm aware of every instant
uh of the overall context of this very
moment
without specifically speaking of it but
I'm constantly aware of it as a
prevailing
uh overall conditions the temperature
the location the acoustics the place the
cameras
uh any other witnesses in the room
the loudness of my voice the uh
appropriateness of the my verbal
responses to your questions. Yes.
>> So,
>> and then I'll be either happy or
unhappy.
>> So, if I do poorly, then when this is
over, I'll say, well, I could have been
more eloquent. I could have explained
that better. You know what I mean?
There's no end to the self-criticism
that you can indulge in.
So, you get to know that that's the
nature of human consciousness.
Even though you do the best that you
can, the mind will always say, "Well,
you could have done better." Holds out
the hypothetical,
but after a while, you get smart and you
learn the hypothetical. There's only the
hypothetical.
And if it was really real, it it
wouldn't have been hypothetical. It
would have actually happened.
>> So, it's kind of like the broken window
theory that, you know, there's one
broken window and then all of a sudden
there's another broken window. So
>> when when people
so they would you say that they attract
that to them?
>> I think that's a good principle. I've
forgotten the broken window principle.
>> I'm glad you brought it up that if you
don't take care of things that need
repair.
It'll bring further detriment. So it is
the whole principle of detriment.
>> That that which is poorly kept and not
cared for will attract to itself other
detriment. Well, you know, such as
>> some people that
um are, you know, they they start off,
you know, smoking marijuana and they
advance to harder drugs and harder drugs
and their life slowly spirals down. It's
kind of the same principle, wouldn't you
say, as the broken window theory?
>> Well, there's a certain similarity.
Yeah.
When you start on drugs, you're part of
the broken window principle. You go to
harder harder drugs.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, not everybody does that, but
some do.
>> Many do. Yes.
>> So, I would say that, you know, that's
kind of the same principle. You attract.
In other words, you attract what likes
to you. In other words, if you're a
spiritual person, you're going to
attract other spiritual people. In daily
reality, you you like tends to go to
like,
>> right?
>> That's correct.
In in daily actuality, like tends to go
with like.
>> So, if you were to change one thing in
your life, such as, you know, pray over
your food or um eat every time before
you eat. Um and uh say a prayer for
mankind at night. And when you get up to
them in the morning, say a prayer that
the day would go well. Um that would
change your whole life then.
>> Well, that
>> eventually
>> then that that constitutes the quality
quality of your life. That's correct.
>> Right.
>> Uh some people seek perfection at all
times as a matter
u of a matter of their own reality.
>> Mhm. I would like to speak as eloquently
as I can with you on the couch right at
this moment. If we especially if we have
a camera focused on us, I would like to
be as eloquent as possible.
Explain things so that could be easily
understood.
>> But what I'm saying is that likes
attracting likes. In other words, if you
become more spiritual in your belief
system, you're going to attract more
spiritual. I think that's true
>> and if you don't such as the broken
window theory um then uh you would
attract that to you also
>> life goes to like
>> right
>> so
>> as little magnets then we are shifting
you know and so each day our choices if
we choose this this is going to happen
if we choose that that is going to
happen so you want to think about your
choices
>> every day in life so that you know you
uh choose the for the better good.
>> You constantly try to choose the the the
best of all the alternatives
>> last night for reasons I have no idea. I
was unable to sleep
or at least a good part of the night. I
wasn't worrying about anything.
>> No,
>> I wasn't thinking about anything.
I wasn't physically annoyed with
anything for some mysterious reason.
Uh, sleep did just did not arrive. Now,
why in the world didn't I sleep last
night? I wasn't worried. I wasn't
preoccupied. I didn't have a pain
anywhere.
I didn't have anything to do. Nothing
was keeping me up. I didn't have the
television on. No distraction.
So, why in the world was I laying there
wide awake for a couple hours?
And I said to myself, why am I lying
awake here for a couple hours, not
thinking about anything for no reason?
And you know what?
>> There wasn't any answer.
Then I realized I'm not going to get an
answer. So that was okay. And I said,
uh, lots of things happen and and are
what they are,
uh, without our understanding it or
knowing the why or the where the what
for of it. It's just the way it is.
>> So acceptance is an important part also.
>> Yeah, there you go. to accept uh what
>> just however it is at the moment just
like the temperature in this room I
accept whatever it is right now
and uh it's satisfactory
so I don't know why I didn't get bored
when I look back at it now I say why
wasn't I bored while I was lying there
wide awake with nothing to think about
wasn't making any plans for the day uh I
wasn't reminiscing about the past.
Uh just lying there doing nothing.
Well, that's major progress, isn't it?
In a way,
>> to just lay there and do nothing, it
doesn't even bother you that you're
doing nothing.
That sort of rubs the Protestant ethic
the wrong way. You should be doing
something useful at all times,
even if you're just serving as an
anchor.
Well, I have one that goes back into
greed and money and everything. This is
a question that uh someone wrote in and
says, "Can you have money and still be
spiritual?"
>> Well, of course, the church proves it.
>> You're not going to make any brownie
points on that one.
>> No. You can have all the money in the
world and and be spiritual or you can be
poor and be spiritual.
Also, being poor doesn't necessarily
make you spiritual. You know, people
say, well, to be really spiritual, you
got to be, you know, poor, a little bit
poor. Uh, that doesn't necessarily make
you more spiritual at all. You know,
>> I know poor poor people who are very
spiritual and I know rich people are
very spiritual.
uh doesn't seem to have to do with
money.
Money and social positions seem to be
superficial pertinances.
You can live on Fifth Avenue in a
multi-million dollar
um apartment and be very uh spiritual
and uh you can live in poverty right
next to a church and be very vicious.
So it doesn't depend on neighborhood.
>> So actually it isn't what one has, it's
what one is
>> and what it means to you.
>> Yeah.
>> What it means to you, the value that you
put on it.
>> Okay.
>> I mean, I value the time that you and I
have together right this moment.
Uh how often will it recur? I don't
know. We don't know how long life we're
scheduled for.
So, I value every moment I have with
you. I value our sitting here on the
couch and talking together.
How do I know that this couldn't be the
last mo few moments of my life? You
know, there could be a loud noise and
both of us vaporize.
I think of it lately because there's a
helicopter that keeps going over our
house.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. There's a airport not far away.
>> And for some reason the helicopters go
right over our house. So I say
everything is peaceful and wonderful and
then I hear
and it gets louder and louder and
louder.
And you know the main reason that upsets
me is because I know it upsets you.
If if I didn't if I if the helicopters
didn't bother you, I'd pay no attention
to them. But uh I get annoyed because I
know the louder they get, they're going
to be right directly overhead and it's
going to bother you. So it's not the
helicopter, it's the fact that the
helicopter
interferes with your peace of mind and
happiness. That's what I hate about it.
>> Yeah.
>> I have to get out my machine gun and
shoot it down so it stops ruining your
happiness. Right. It's a
It's a military helicopter that keeps
>> I don't know what it is. Yeah. Right.
Yeah. Right.
>> That makes it a little tough.
>> Well, one part of love is that we want
everyone that we love to be happy
and so we we try our best to
>> Yeah.
>> to fulfill their their needs and and
bring about the greatest happiness
possible.
So in other words,
>> um, like you were saying, one could be
spiritual and live on Fifth Avenue.
>> Yes.
>> And then, so what it is is that one can
be spiritual and live on Fifth Avenue,
but it's the label we put on that.
>> That's the label we put on. Yes. Cuz
I've lived on Fifth Avenue and um
had a very exclusive penthouse
apartment,
>> but it's the label we put on it. and and
I've also lived in in in semi-poverty
>> and I can't say I was necessarily
happier in one condition than the other
tell the truth.
>> Mhm.
And Department of Truth Avenue
and uh and stayed on Long Island all at
the same time.
Mhm.
So you you can have the good things of
the life
frankly
they don't make you happy
>> right
>> but they fulfilled the certain desires
and uh they contribute to being content
anyway satisfied.
If my shoes didn't match today it would
feel a little weird.
Oh you'll notice they they do match
don't they?
My shoes do mesh today.
>> Yes,
>> they didn't this morning earlier.
>> Well, that sometimes happens.
>> They didn't match earlier. No, that's
true.
Confessions of a married couple.
>> Yeah,
>> the shoes didn't match. Thank God for my
wife. Otherwise, they would not be
matching.
So, I thank you that I have matching
shoes today, Susie. It's
>> so hard to love. So what we have to
learn to do is not judge.
>> I think there there you're putting it
correctly, huh?
>> So the lesson is, you know, uh not to
judge.
>> You know, they always say don't judge a
book by its cover.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> You know, it's an old saying. I forget
who said that, but
>> it's um so in other words, it's our
we're we're projecting what we think
onto them
>> onto things. Yes.
We're projecting value,
>> value, prestige. Yeah. Um
>> desiraability.
>> Desiraability, you know, and so we're
projecting that on to
>> social image,
>> right? Social emulation,
>> glamour of things,
>> so we need to change that
uh in our own thinking, in one's
thinking. And that way you know we
change us as a person as individual.
>> The more realistic uh our our values are
that I think the happier we are.
>> All right.
>> Um
so right now there's actually nothing I
really want that I don't have. I really
have nothing to be unhappy about.
>> Mhm.
>> I'd have to look Well, the doggy could
be sitting here next to us there. So you
see I could pick something.
>> Yeah. Right.
>> Or one of my favorite kitties could be
here.
I love kitties. I've always loved
kitties.
And throughout my life, I was that
kitty. One kitty or another.
Kitties and doggies and pets of one kind
or another. Now, there's other people
that hate I'm sure hate them. Hate cats
and dogs and pets and taking care of
them and cleaning up them, combing them,
and caring and caring for them.
Uh, but I've always loved having pets
around.
>> Mhm.
>> So, do you think that we've covered the
subject for today?
>> I don't know. What is the subject for
today?
>> That um h how to see life, the reality
of life. How to see the reality of life.
>> How to see the reality of life is to
realize that the value of every there's
there's a value in everything
>> all the time.
And just the failure to appreciate it or
see it doesn't mean it's not there. It's
just that we're distracted.
So we come back to basics. I'm very
happy that we got a chance to sit
together
uh on this nice comfortable couch and
chat about a subject that we want to
bring to people's awareness. Why?
because it makes me happy to think that
there could be something I could do that
would help other people to become
happier.
>> Anything I can do to help other people
make become happier already makes me
happier.
>> Mhm.
>> Uh-huh. So, I appreciate the opportunity
to speak uh to the viewers right now
that I might be able to contribute
something to increase the the awareness
of the value of their own life to
themsel and to others.
As other people appreciate and value
their own life, they contribute to
everybody around them doing the same
thing.
So we all add to each other's happiness.
The happier we are, the happier we make
others,
the greater the world benefits.
So in a certain subtle way, right this
moment, we are benefiting the world. of
you and I
>> what we say is transmitted to another
which is transcended to another which is
transmitted to another and it comes
about as a invisible energy so many most
of what we're talking about
you know uh take place as movements in
the fields of energy
so right now what we're affecting is the
fields of energy
uh to the listener or to the viewer of
this
picture that we're presenting to the
world right now.
>> Well, thank you. Thank you for the
teachings today.
>> Thank you for sharing it with me,
sweetheart.
I love you and I love your love and I
love the fact that your love makes me
happy.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu
Hallelu.
Hallelujah.