Thank you for such a lovely
introduction.
It is of course a great pleasure to be
here today and to meet with such a
wonderful audience.
We do have some slides which will help
us explain things with a visual assist.
The information which I came upon which
resulted in the writing of power versus
forth
was an astonishing discovery.
For the first time
in all of human history
there
evolved the way to discover
truth from falsehood.
A statement that is so stunning. I'm
sure nobody in the audience understands
it.
It took some years to recover from it.
Five years in which I had to decide what
to do about it.
It was discovered that consciousness
itself,
consciousness itself records
all that
ever occurs mentally, emotionally,
physically.
Everything that has ever happened has
been recorded throughout all of time.
All of what we experience is time. On
the level of consciousness, there is no
time.
So everything is recorded.
As though all of the past is present.
We could recover anything about anything
that had happened anywhere in time or
space.
But we could not tell anything about the
future.
Using the kinesiologic test, we could
discover anything that is or was
and but it cannot be used to foretell
the future.
The consequence of discovering how to
tell truth from falsehood then ended up
in calibrating levels of consciousness
from one to a thousand.
One is bare physical existence.
And we asked what is the most advanced
consciousness that has ever existed
on the planet? And we got calibration
level
1,00.
Actually, the numbers were far greater.
Therefore, we ended up using the
logarithm of the number.
We ended up with a usable
scale much like Fahrenheit, centigrade.
Anybody can make up their own scale if
they like
on everybody's scale no matter what you
make it there will be at a point that
differentiates truth from falsehood. So
the kinesiologic test which I first saw
Dr. John Diamond back in the early 70s,
I believe it was.
Up to that time time, it was thought to
be a local phenomena.
You hold asparagus over your solar
plexus, and if you're allergic to it,
your arm goes weak.
It was thought of as a local phenomena.
But by the time I saw it, I had already
had
a number of rather extraordinary
transformations of my own consciousness.
And I saw it from a cold different
viewpoint.
It was obvious that it was the energy of
life as consciousness that was
responding to the question and not the
individual purpose person. And so we
found that the response to the kinesis
kinesiologic test had nothing to do with
the personal opinion of the test
subject.
And this morning we were asked to
demonstrate it. We we'll show you
briefly how to do it
characteristic of life that life knows
that which is supportive of life and
that which is not much like protoplasm.
So it's an impersonal response much like
protoplasm knows that which is favorable
to it and that which is enimicable.
And so using this simple test we were
then able to go back over human history
calibrate the level of consciousness of
anything and everything that ever
existed.
Every writer, every philosopher, every
spiritual teacher, every movie, every
writer, every philosopher
we're able to do countries and
continents.
What appeared then
is though the history of mankind was
two-dimensional,
black and white, and now we had
three-dimensional technicolor.
It brought forth awarenesses
not before possible.
We found that if you hold something that
is true in mind, the arm of the subject
that you're using goes strong
and if it's false, the arm goes weak.
This does not have to be verbalized. So
Susan and I will show you exactly how to
do it. It's very quick and easy.
There's no point to try and complicate
it in your mind. It's very very simple.
That which is supportive of life and
true makes you go strong. That which is
unimicable and false allows your arm to
go weak.
It's not a true or false response. It's
true or not true.
The universe cannot respond with no. It
can only respond to yes collapse the
wave function
and the resulting der equation tells you
the new state of the universe.
So it coincides quite well with quant
the theory of quantum mechanics
and advanced theoretical physics as
well.
My own personal experiences which I'll
have to give you a bit otherwise some of
the things I s say will sound strange.
They'll sound strange anyway, but
uh rather extraordinary experiences
began in this lifetime what the world
calls this lifetime at age three.
At age three out of complete oblivion
from oblivion from absolute nothingness
suddenly there was a
severe shock like experience a sudden
intense awareness of existence. Out of
nothingness suddenly there was
existence. existence as such
the knowingness of existence
which at age three was non-verbal.
No words for such an experience.
But the
the confrontation with existence was
profound and stunning.
Shortly after there suddenly came into
awareness the possibility then of
non-existence
that it might have come about
that it might not have come about this
existence.
And so there was the polarity the
duality of existence versus
non-existence
which are actually doesn't get resolved
till consciousness level 850.
Yeah.
So that was the presentation of the task
of this lifetime to transcend
the ultimate truth is allness or
nothingness.
Existence versus non-existence
and
beyond a certain level of consciousness
which calibrates at 600
one remembers what the world calls
previous lifetimes. They're not previous
lifetimes, but the world calls them
that. And one remember is the lifetime
of Hinana Buddhism in which the ultimate
reality was void.
Consequently,
at each physical death, the sanity went
into the void.
That which you hold in mind is what you
experience.
But the void is not the ultimate
reality. Or you could stay there. And if
the void were the ultimate reality, who
would be there to tell you about it?
There'd be nothing to recall it. So the
confrontation then was with
the ultimate truth. Yeah. Confrontation
with what is the ultimate truth
which became something of an obsession
in this lifetime.
as a teenager. As a teenager then I had
a severely exhausting
18-mi paper route in Wisconsin,
10 below zero blizzard,
pitch black, miles from home, no
electricity on the highway.
And to get out of the wind, I dug into a
big snowbank,
10 below zero blizzard and pitchbuck.
So I climbed into this hole in the snow
and a profound, incredible peace
replaced whatever
illusion there was of a personal self.
an infinite exquisite peace.
Its presence is unmistakable,
exquisitely gentle,
melts. It's it melts what one thinks of
as oneself.
And it's diff this diffuse.
It's like the presence of love on an
absolute level
which goes on outside of time.
experientially
perhaps eons
because that which I am existed
before all universes
and will still be here after all
universes have disappeared
and that is apparently clear.
It's like the profound essence of the
knowingness
And subsequent to the experience, the
fear of death has never recurred,
including during the World War, World
War II, and minds are going off and I
was on a mind sweeper and there was
never even the thought of death. To this
day, there's no thought of death.
There was no response to sudden loud
noises. So, there seem to be alterations
of the way in which life is experienced.
My father came and uh our 1929 Model A
Ford
and uh discovered my whereabouts
and he seemed perturbed
and uh I realized that if I didn't come
back in the body and breathe again, if I
didn't breathe the body, there was no
desire to breathe the body.
In fact, there hasn't been any desire to
breathe it since. But anyway, breathe
I saw that he believed in death. Oh, and
that if I didn't rep breathe and
reenergize
the body, whatever you want to call it,
that he would think I had died. They
would take away the body and bury it and
my father would grieve.
So, I love my father a great deal. And
so
I I made the mistake
of breathing the body again and saved
him the grief.
Anyway, that was so there was a series
of such experiences, you know,
and um that led to sort of we'll skip
over a number of such experiences but
there was always difficulty in
maintaining a sense of a personal self
because it kept dissolving into an
infinite presence and I would have to
focus on being Dave and you're sitting
here in this chair in this classroom
and hanging hang on to
the personal self, you know, which
seemed elusive.
And then there seemed to be I was a very
religious young man uh brought up by
Episcopal, very very religious
and scrupulous in fact. And one day uh
at some time in my early life, I was
walking along in the woods. It was
absolutely beautiful and still.
And suddenly out of nothingness, out of
nothingness
arose
a revelation, a comprehension
of the totality of the suffering of
mankind
throughout all of time in its totality.
The totality of its agony and fear and
suffering.
It's it was stunning.
And in that instant, I became an
atheist.
I held God responsible for the totality
of human suffering
instead of the human ego. But at that
time, I did not understand that.
I thought God created everything. 1930s
religion. That would be a common belief
system.
Nobody spoke about the ego. They only
spoke about sin.
So I didn't realize that the ego was
this was the creation of the ego.
Anyway, I became an atheist and frankly
it was a great relief to get away from
sin.
You didn't worry that a passing thought
might condemn you to hell forever. You
know, it was quite a relief.
And I was a devout atheist.
I went to a Jesuit university and got
straight A in theology,
ethics, metaphysics, the whole thing.
But that wasn't satisfying. Later on, I
went through psychoanalysis. I became a
psychiatrist.
I had in fact the largest psychiatric
practice in the United States.
2,000 outpatients, thousand new patients
a year,
50 employees, 25 offices,
electrophilographic laboratory, clinical
laboratory, research laboratory.
We had one of the few first computers
available. It was a giant thing. It
stood in a room of itself. We used to
genulect to it.
Had to be air conditioned, special
cables of electric.
It was a wondrous machine
to do our research.
Anyway, all of this
intensity
to realize the essential core and truth
of existence persisted.
Uh
it finally
this huge practice
uh and the seeing of thousands of
patients thousands of patients
in the most severe conditions.
Uh eventually the the pressure of trying
to help so many people, I began to
develop all kinds of psychosmatic
illnesses.
And uh
at that time the desire to know the
truth then came back with a greater
intensity than ever. And I despared
I despared of being able to
realize the essential core of truth.
The great books of the western world
which I have caliberate about 460
Aristotle
Plutinus comes to close.
You go through all the great minds that
have ever existed through their inlex.
all the great psychoanalysts,
the great philosophers, great thinkers
of all time
and it wasn't there.
Philosophy
takes you to theology,
the metaphysics,
GNOSIS.
Still not there. It's not there. I'll
save you time.
read books of the western world
calibrated 460. If you're looking for
the absolute truth,
you become educated but you won't find
what is the core of the absolute truth.
And so I went into meditation and I go
within myself.
And then
and then I found the way to hell and the
doors to hell opened up and I began to
descend into hell.
How Dante knew the details of hell
precisely.
How did he know it? I don't know. In the
upper level, they chop chopping people
up in torture and all what the world
considers hell.
That part is just a joke. That's just
jacks for openers.
That's just way of saying hi.
And from there the despair deepens, gets
blacker and blacker
and the agony is that of the soul.
And how daddy knew it, I don't know. But
there is actually a level where you
leave time and go into timelessness.
And there's a knowingness.
A knowingness. Abandon all hope ye who
enter here and by God it is so.
Then agony of endless hopelessness
goes on for young
and at the depth of this that it's
beyond despair far worse than despair
the atheist
at the time and somehow from somewhere
came the question
if there is a god I ask him tell me
And then oblivion.
Oblivion.
And then with the return of
consciousness,
with the return of consciousness
sometime later,
all had been transformed,
which it is to this day.
The mind was silent
still.
The incredible magnificent of divinity
shines forth is all of creation.
It shines forth
thusly. Now
the mind still
and I noticed that the body kept moving.
The body moved about by itself. As you
can see, it still does
its own thing like some kind of a pet
friend.
Everything happens spontaneously.
There is no personal self causing
anything to happen.
All that personal self we worry about
doesn't even have any existence.
What must God think? We keep praying
about this thing that has no existence.
She thinks
human beings are so pathetic. What can
we do for them?
So since that time everything happens
spontaneously.
There is no cause of anything.
There is no thought going on at any
time.
There's no knowing what's going to be
said until I hear it.
There's nothing that thinks what it's
going to say. It just says it because it
is it.
So how to function in the world in that
condition?
You have no idea what the body's going
to do. It seems to behave properly.
It seems to say the correct things.
And I left uh east and a very elite
lifestyle
and has huge practice.
I took my tools from the tool room, put
them in the back of my truck and drove
away,
drove out to a small town and went into
about 10 years or so of withdrawal from
the world. And
that led to this kind of research which
we're reporting today.
And so
there are certain
things that once you've heard them are
transformative. Certain information is
in and of itself transformative.
And so I'll give you the crux of it.
We'll get to these charts in a minute.
But
few are the people on the planet who
transcend the consciousness level of the
400s which is the intellect.
The intellect
4% of the population ever transcends
consciousness level 499.
499 is the level of Freud Einstein Sir
Isaac Newton.
Impressive 499
is intellectual brilliance,
genius.
But the intellect which is in a way the
savior of mankind with science, science
certainly brought us great benefit
now becomes the ceiling now becomes the
block.
And very few people escape the snare of
the mind and thinking this.
Escape the duality of thinking there is
a this causing a that.
And so
I'll tell you the secret of it all. Save
you 500 lifetimes.
That'll be a dollar each lifetime. Thank
you.
And and so listen to this and and don't
even think about it. Just know that it's
true. I'm karmically responsible for
saying this to you. And I'm fully aware
of that responsibility.
There is no cause for anything.
Nothing is causing anything else at all.
It's not even a possibility.
Then
how do things come about? Hey, if
there's nothing causing them,
there's nothing causing this talkingness
which is going on now.
It's coming out spontaneously.
So we'll have to explain the universe a
bit.
If we look at
divinity
as a field of infinite power
with no limitations and no dimensions.
This infinite field of power.
Power contrasts with force.
Force is linear.
Understandable through Newtonian
physics.
The differential calculus
power is beyond that realm.
Power is nonlinear. Has no beginning.
Has no end. Does not go from here to
there. Is not measurable.
Power is more like gravity.
Power just stands there.
Power influences all within its realm,
uses up no energy, doesn't go anywhere,
and everything within its field
is influenced by the quality of the
power.
So
that which is within its field we're
familiar with in the linear Newtonian
world, measurable,
identifiable,
time, space, and location.
And so the human consciousness as it
evolves then
through its own spiritual decision
brings about its own you might say
configuration or energy level.
You might picture we're like infinitely
small
molecules or little microns little tiny
but we have a polarity and we have a
figure. So every spiritual decision we
make, spiritual will then send sets up
you might say our karmic vibration, our
karmic vibrational pattern
which goes on beyond time
and within the infinite power
of the presence of God as
all that is.
Then each karmic
corpusle
you might say
goes automatically to where it would go
in such a powerful field.
We see then that the justice of God is
absolute
and that every iron filing is exactly
in the right place in this infinite
field of power
and it could cannot be in any other
doesn't require a judgmental arbitrary
dualistic kind of a conception of
divinity.
who gets angry, mad, judgmental,
punishes, rewards.
You can see
that the justice of God is absolute and
that each comes into his own exactly
depending on his own vibrational level.
And as it leaves the physical body at
what the world calls physical depth, it
automatically is in its perfect
position. Huh.
Because in anger you can protest, man.
The barricades.
You man something better for yourself.
Protest. You got enough energy at least
to come out of apathy. Apathy which
characterizes
good parts of Africa.
People children seldom live beyond the
age five. They live dead because they're
dead by 21.
AIDS and disease and poverty and
starvation, the vitaminos
ravages.
And if you manage to survive,
then the internal civil wars which form
for decades,
you manage to live adulthood, you
probably get slaughtered anyway.
Life is
not too good.
anger.
You can see that above anger, pride now
has to do with accomplishment.
So first your despair, your apathy, then
hope arises.
You can see that even fear brings a
person out of the bottom of the box.
The poor old lady rocking in the rocking
chair doesn't even experience fear.
She's beyond it. She's too apathetic.
Fear has a lot of energy. You can run
like the devil in fear. You can really
move a lot with anger and fear.
You begin to do a few things and move up
to pride.
From pride you then move above the level
of to the level of integrity.
Level of 200 which is courage.
Courage is for the first time a real
spiritual dimension. Those below are not
spiritual dimensions. They're really
animal dimensions.
The level of 200, a person now has the
capacity to tell the truth about
themsself.
Yes, I am lazy.
Yes, I am greedy.
Yes, I am addicted to alcohol and drugs.
Yes, I am ruining the lives of my
family.
Instead of denial and projection, one
now has power.
So 200 is the beginning of power.
It's characteristic of the first step in
the 12step groups from which millions of
people have recovered from all kinds of
grave and curable illnesses. The first
step is owning the truth about yourself.
Left to your own devices, your condition
is hopeless and undoubtedly fatal.
That without the help of some higher
power. So that's an honest statement. An
honest statement. So the recovery from
many conditions
and I've witnessed recovery from all
this every possible human ailment
through spiritual means of course of
miracles 12 steps whatever
the beginning is the admission that in
and of oneself lacks the power
that calibrates at 200. So 200 and up
are the beginnings of spiritual power
and integrity.
We see
some courage and move up is letting go
of consequences. Neutrality.
You you stop living out of the anxiety
of the solar plexus and in neutral you
become an easygoing person. people
in the conscious level neutral
are comfortable. So the these people are
the first comfortable people. You're not
really comfortable to get up to neutral.
In neutral if you get the job it's
terrific and if you don't you'll get
another one.
Right? So neutral is comfortable.
They're easy people to be with. They're
not trying to prove anything. They don't
want to sell your belief systems.
They're not prositizing.
They're not into war. They're not into
conflict.
They're easygoing people in neutral.
The next step up is willingness.
Willingness is very important.
Willingness now is more than just being
neutral.
The waitress in neutral says, "What do
you have?" She doesn't really care that
much if you leave a tip or not. If you
do, it's great. And if you don't, but
she probably doesn't look you in the
eye. She takes your order and she says,
"Uh, what do you have?" She does her job
and she's in neutral.
The next step up is friendliness and
willingness.
The waitress in willingness makes a good
deal more money than the waitress in
neutral because the waitress in neutral
is somewhat flat. In willingness, there
is more of the personal presence. You
smile at the customer. You say, "Can I
have the same thing as usual, George? He
feels at home with you. She makes twice
as much money.
It's twice the pip."
Her customers come back to her and want
to sit at her table. She's friendly and
nice. She remembers her name. She
becomes Georgette or whatever her name
is. You know, you look forward to seeing
her. So you see how new energy has the
beginning of love is beginning to show
up as this willingness
and acceptance is
now where you begin to realize that you
are the source of the
details of your own life. You stop
blaming it on others. Down below people
blame everything. You slip on the ice is
Gimble's fault.
>> As you get a little bit higher, you
realize you you're careless in where you
put your feet. Frankly,
so you begin to accept responsibility
and it's the beginning of real power.
Uh
if we calibrate companies and uh we we
recently we calibrate thousands of
things you know and uh recently we did
all the giant the biggest corporations
in the world you know biggest
corporations in the world biggest
corporations in America and Fortune
magazine
we've done all the departments of all
the various governments etc. And rather
amazing facts begin to reveal themselves
that almost all the giant corporations
in the world uh calibrate maybe 205.
Fierce you find anything. What does that
mean? Reliable, dependable. You paid
$20,000 for a car, you get a car. You
get a guaranteed car. You don't get a
fake car.
You get what you paid for. So there's
integrity, honesty. Most government
agencies calibrate around 205. You see,
that's not airy fairy. It's not lovey.
It's not romantic.
But that isn't what you're paying for.
Invest your money in a stock. Say, "I
want profit." So
you get higher than that, then you have
to add a new element.
friendliness, integrity,
willing to stand by your product, give
you back your money smilingly, no
questions asked. That's how I got
corresponding with Cam Sam Walton.
Yeah, here was Sam Walden
establishing a business based on certain
premises which are generally considered
spiritual, you know, and so we
corresponded back and forth. And in the
book, Harvard versus Forest, you know, I
calibrated Walmart at 385 or 365, I
forget what it was.
That's not staggeringly high when you
compare it to a saint, but Walmart is
not doesn't claim to be a saint.
But at 365 and it's gone down somewhat
since Saman died, but still it's way up
there. There's nothing in its class. You
know, all the corporations in the world,
nothing is in the 300. Nothing is really
in high 200. Only Walmart.
So what does that demonstrate to us? I
don't care anything about Walmart
personally. Is that integrity that
integrity then shows up in every area of
life.
So here was a corporation
whose integrity was remarkable. That's
why I remarked about it in power versus
force. And now we see what integrity has
brought about that integrity. It is now
the largest corporation in the entire
world. The largest corporation in the
entire world
and also the highest calibrated level of
consciousness of an enterprise of a
corporate nature.
demonstrating that that the power of
integrity shows up on the bottom line.
It is not some kind of airy fairy
doer
goody two shoes kind of fantasy.
You see the hardboiled businessman a lot
of spiritual concept sounds a little
airy fairy touchy feely. Don't give me
any touchy feely. Please give me a
break.
Now, caringness, consideration,
friendliness, and what does the jacket
say when you walk into Walmart? Says,
"How can I help?" Right out of the book,
helpfulness, willingness.
All right. So, then we finally get to
reason and logic. This is where
Northern Europe, the United States,
advanced civilized countries calibrated
in the 400s. This is the power of the
intellect.
The great benefit of the intellect of
course we witness every day as the
advances of science.
Few of us would be alive. We'd all be
dead of various diseases. And because of
science, all the diseases I treated when
I first started in medicine some 50
years ago no longer even exist.
The infectious disease hospital,
all the people sick and dying of various
diseases, there no antibiotics, no way
to cure them.
Nowadays all those people would be
living you know. So the 400s is the
world of the intellect, the university,
the college professor. The 400s are
presidents,
statesmen,
Supreme Court justices,
professors, Nobel Prize winners,
usually the high 400s.
To be president of a huge
country then requires
intellectual fortitude, vers.
So they almost all do. All the
presidents throughout time have been in
the high 400
from 500.
From 500 up from 500 up, a person
wouldn't be interested in being
president.
500 and up then is the opening of the
heart chakra
and the energy field of love starts
calibrating at 500.
At 540
is the level of unconditional love.
The level 500 and up in itself is rare.
4% of the population ever calibrates at
500.
0.4
calibrates at 540.
Unconditional love.
We'll show the distribution of the
levels of consciousness in the
population in the next slide.
Love becomes then progressively
unconditional,
finally saintly and at the level 600 the
personal self
dissolves into a oneness and that is the
state of enlightenment. The states of
enlightenment begin at 600. What the
world calls enlightenment happens one in
10 million lifetimes. One in 10 million
ever reaches 600. And of those who do,
only half will stay in the world.
In that condition,
there's no need to breathe or to eat or
to move. It is absolutely perfect,
complete, and still.
It's beyond time, beyond description.
There's no thinkingness, no thought, no
desire for anything.
People
do strange things. They want you to eat
and all kinds of oddities
which to them seem important. They see
it's important to them. They eat because
it's important to them because otherwise
the body falls over which is irrelevant
by the way.
Good ridden.
As love becomes more perfected. And one
comes into
various progressive states which are
familiar to saintthood.
There's a state of
at about 540.
One falls in love with everything and
everyone. The beauty of everything and
its perfection shines forth. Everyone is
both either handsome or beautiful as the
case may be or both
handsome and beautiful and beautifully
handsome.
One falls in love with everyone and
everything all of life. And you see what
is emerging then is the awareness of the
divinity of all of life.
And porn develops a certain reverence
The kind of love we're speaking of is
not what the world calls love. What the
world calls love is an emotion, an
emotionality
which goes from here to there. I love
you. You love me. Okay? Which is the
setup for murder and suicide as you can
see.
And if I love you and you love me, I
will kill you or kill myself. So murder
and suicide is the downside of that kind
of love which is also conditional.
All right. The kind of love we're
talking about then is a way of being in
the world.
At 540 that calibrated level,
love is what one is, what one has
become.
And there's no love that goes from here
to there.
It's the condition in which you
experience the world.
And therefore, there's a reverence for
and a respect for all of life in all of
its expressions.
As the love advances, it comes to a
state
which can only be called ecstasy.
In the higher level of love to even look
at two people who are affectionate
towards the each other, you can break
out in tears.
You break out in tears. So there's a
period in which you cry at everything.
Every kind gesture mother reaches over,
touch your crying child, and comfort it.
And you break out in tears. Everything
makes you break out in tears.
It's hard to listen to beautiful music
because you cry all the time.
Beyond that there's a level of love
which can only be described as ecstatic
described by Rama Krishna
experienced in this lifetime
one of absolute ecstasy beyond
description
in which it's impossible almost not to
dance physically
or psychically One is in
ecstasy at the re revelation of the
presence of God is all existence
ecstatic when it first reveals itself.
It's impossible to function in that
state of ecstasy.
And
by divine inspiration one may surrender
it to God.
One surrenders the ecstasy to God
and then in its place
is a profound and infinite peace with no
beginning and no end.
Peace of God
this day.
Go to the next one.
Yeah. Thank you.
This is the distribution of the levels
of consciousness.
You see, your expectations of humanity
have never been tailored by any kind of
realistic expectations.
You see, this is the distribution of the
levels of consciousness throughout all
of humanity.
And now one can revise one's
expectations.
At the time of the Neanderthal man
consciousness level was about 75.
How many kept evolving off the tree?
Finally, it got up into the low 400s. At
the time of the birth of the Buddha,
the consciousness level of all of
mankind stood at 90.
At the time of the birth of Jesus
Christ, the consciousness level of all
mankind stood at 100.
Throughout the ensuing centuries, the
consciousness level of man crept up. and
then for the last thousand years stood
at 190
stalled out at 190.
If we ask what was it in the 1400s,
we'll get 190. What was it in the 1500s?
What was it in the 1600s?
The time which some of these many of
these buildings here were built in the
1600s.
The consciousness level of mankind was
190.
That's below truth, below integrity.
You know, and so the history of mankind
is bloody and savage.
The history of Europe is bloody
savagery.
First, this side wars and butchers them.
This side wars and butchers that. Then
they get busy beheading each other. It's
a bloody and horrible history. Look at
it.
In the last century,
10 million people have died of this war.
100 million rather. Sorry, forgot one.
Zero.
100 million. Right.
Then in the late 1980s,
for unknown reasons,
the consciousness level of mankind went
from 190 to 207.
The most important phenomena in human
history. really
to go from non- integrity that which is
destructive. At 190 eventually mankind
would have destroyed himself.
The Russians were prepared to do it,
weren't they? The great mega bomb that
would kill all of life on the planet
forever. Radioactivity
death to humanity by radioactivity.
Not too kindly a thought.
I believe we escaped.
So in the late 1980s the consciousness
level of mankind went up to 207.
Critical critical because 207 you go
strong with kines theology. At 190 you
go weak.
At 207 there's hope. At 190 the fate of
mankind would be eventually its own
obliteration.
The only reason mankind didn't
obliterate itself until now it didn't
have anything capable big enough to kill
everybody all at once.
So the Russians were busy working on it.
We would have eventually done it. All
right. So here we see the distribution
of mankind. We see that 78% of the
world's population at this time 78%
calibrates below 200. to see if that's
still affect
um we have permission to ask it to you.
And approximately 78% of those
population covers below 200 at this
time.
Frankly,
you know the implications of that alone.
78% of the world's population
is not integrate
believes in falsehood
and will kill you if you don't believe
in it falsehood.
All right? So that's where mankind has
evolved to at the present time.
You might say the collective good karma
of mankind has brought about a
progression of the consciousness level
and now it's at a hopeful 207.
Maybe we could have the next slide.
Uh
the big difficulty in the evolution of
consciousness is called duality. The
pathway I teach is devotional
nonduality.
devotion to God, to the truth of God,
and transcending the dualistic nature of
the ego, at which point the mind goes
silent.
The idea of duality is that there are
two opposite things. You see, there's
heat and cold. There's goodness and
badness.
Political left, political right,
everything gets into a polarized
duality. Consequently, conflict and war.
H the right versus the wrong.
One day I'm right, you're wrong. Next
day we trade off. Right?
You look at time, the right and the
wrong. If there are two different lights
and you look at the map of the world as
it evolves over the centuries, you see
right and wrong, right and wrong, right
and wrong. See it all flashing on at
all. This side's right, this side's
wrong. Now two years later, this side's
wrong. This side's right. Right?
I was in World War II. So they were our
enemies. We hated them. We was to kill
their terrible Japs, etc. Show them a
gleaming teeth. Evil.
Now
after the war, see the veterans on both
sides are great buddies. We love each
other.
I salute his bravery. He salutes my
bravery. We both realize we did it for
the sake of what we believed in.
The commitment was to integrity. What we
thought of as integrity at the time.
Huh? So that heals the disparity. We
don't hate anybody anymore. They don't
hate us. And veterans of both sides pray
together, meet together, embrace each
other, and we realize the dignity
of the commitment to something greater
than oneself.
One may be mistaken at the time, but
you'll find that a kamicazi pilot
calibrates quite high.
He did what he did because of his belief
in the divinity of his emperor.
All right?
So you see from an arbitrary viewpoint,
we think there's hot and cold. Actually,
there's only the presence of heat.
There's either heat present or not.
There's only one variable, not two
variables. Heat is either present or not
present.
Next we can look at another scale
example two in which you see to want a
thing or not want a thing. Then you
perceive a projected value which you
project upon the thing. It's either
precious and worthwhile or it's useless.
If you love gold, you'll kill for it. If
you think it's just sort of a, you know,
pretty and useful, you won't be bothered
because it's just sort of okay. It's
neutral. Gold means neut neutral. It's
either good or bad. It's sort of it's
useful. You stick things in it. Okay,
let's have the next one.
Again, another examples of duality. See,
goodness versus badness
are all perceptual. Well, they say
perceptual. The difficulty with the
dualistic mind is that it
has these belief systems which it then
projects upon the world and says and
thinks it sees it out there. It exists
only within your mind. Doesn't exist in
the world. Just as causality is an
explanation made up by the mind.
Actually, evolution and creation are one
and the same thing. If things don't come
about by virtue of cause, then how do
they come about?
Because of the existence of God, because
of the source of existence itself
in the great infinite power, then
the potentiality of each thing
to manifest its own actuality
unfolds.
There's nothing causing it to unfold.
The source of that which one witnesses
is a is the presence of divinity as the
source of existence.
The power
to bring forth your own existence
cannot be found within the conceptual
world.
The potentiality then by its karmic
propensity unfolds as an actuality.
Nothing is causing it to do so.
The idea of cause is a mentation in your
mind.
There's nothing causing this to happen
whatsoever.
The potentiality to use the body to
explain
a dialogue
does this of its own. I have nothing to
do with it.
I'm as surprised by what the hand does
as you are. I don't know what it's doing
there. It's trying to explain something.
The potentiality
is karmically balanced under the right
condition becomes has the possibility
then to become an actuality.
And so what seems to be sequential.
The only thing that's sequential is
perception. Because your perception goes
from here to there. You think things are
happening sequentially.
The witnessing is what is sequential.
The actuality is outside of time to
begin with.
If this were not so,
no one here would exist.
Let's see if that's
sometimes composity.
Yes, what we said is a fact that things
come into actuality out of their
potentiality
because of the presence of the infinite
divinity.
The infinite power of divinity is the
only possible source of existence.
All right, so we just got rid of
duality.
And we'll move to the next exciting.
Ah
people say well I can't get rid of my
mind. I meditate. I'm a Buddhist. I'm
this. I'm that. I want to transcend the
mind.
Well we have lots of good news this
morning. The other good news is that 98%
of your mind is silent at all times.
In fact, right this moment, every single
mind in this realm is silent.
All you have to do is fall back into the
silence. You see that the silence is
already in existence just prior to the
thought.
I was telling somebody this morning, the
Buddha and I often have arguments about
things.
And the Buddha believes that reality be
can can be glimpsed between two
thoughts.
No, it's not between two thoughts. It's
just prior to the thought.
Just prior to the thought
is a space of infinite silence out of
which thinking arises.
That which out of which it arises is
silent.
In fact, your mind right now is silent.
The mind of everyone in this room is
currently silent.
There is a focus. It's like a huge
coliseum. Everybody's gone. It's
completely empty. And over in the corner
of the coliseum, there's a 4x5 in black
and white TV set. And you're focused on
this. You think the coliseum is busy and
noisy. It's empty and silent just
because you're focused on this little
screen over in the corner of the
coliseum.
So we what we discovered is that your
mind is silent. 98% of the work you need
to become a enlightened is already done.
You've only got 2% left.
Snap. Right. Anybody can have 2%.
Letting go. Wanting to think, wanting to
go. So, we see that one is addicted to
thinking this. And the real secret, the
real secret
is that you become hypnotized by the 1%
that's talking
one or 2%.
You are in a state of self hypnosis.
There is a secret out of which a lot of
you will move rapidly. There's only one
or 2% is busy.
It's in a hypnotic state.
The only thing that is needed then is to
realize that and once you realize it,
it's not that difficult to let go of the
desire for the thinkingness and all
that's derived out of it. What is the
payoff that you get from the ego
to let go of the ego and have a silence
replace it? It is only necessary to see
what the ego is up to and be willing to
surrender its payoff.
The ego because it is not based on
reality or love has managed to juice
pain and suffering.
So the ego lives off the non-lo
non-reality
then of pain, suffering, guilt, feeling
right, feeling righteous.
And you see what it does? It I it
polarizes everything. It politicizes
everything.
So you can be contentious and feel so
good and so right and see how wrong the
other people are and feel innocent as
you plunge a dagger into their heart.
Because they're evil because you
moralize
because they're they're evil. And why
are they evil? Because you idealize
and you hypothesize that they could be
better. And then we romanticize. Oh,
what a wonderful world if everybody
would just see things the way I see it.
And they don't, of course. So that's why
we criticize and we feel upset about
that. So we emotionalize. We have a
parade. We dramatize it. We make movies.
We have parades. It's catastrophic.
Catastrophic.
You can look at any point in history,
including the present time, and discover
that it's catastrophic.
It's catastrophic right now.
Just you haven't noticed.
So we theorize that it could be
differently. Could be different. We
rationalize why it's not different.
Well, we don't have the time. We don't
have the tax money. We fantasize how it
could be.
We go on, we infantalize things,
intellectualize it. And of course,
basically what we're doing is
mentalizing it. We idealize it and then
we glamorize the whole thing. Aren't our
ideas wonderful? We dramat make a drama.
and make a huge movie, $45 million, so
that you can see how I think or feel
about something. The egoentricity of all
is just staggering. All of this is
egoentricity and nothing but
who cares what your views are. I don't.
Does anybody else? No.
Next time you get into a discussion with
somebody, take a moment and notice that
they really don't give a rap what you're
thinking or what your opinions are. They
really don't care. You see, if you
present them with a platform,
if you present them with a platform from
which their ego can grandstand, they can
pontificate,
then they love you. If you don't give
them a platform upon which to
pontificate, they consider you boring
and they will demonize you on top of
that as being bad and evil and ignorant.
And of course, we prize many things out
of the solar plexus. We're willing to
sacrifice a great deal for materialism.
And the latest craze in society is to be
the victim.
The competition in victimhood is
tremendous.
There's no aspect of human life that
can't be portrayed as some kind of
victimization,
which means there are evil people out
there victimizing you.
People victimize me all the time.
They do it all day, every day.
You don't think you're being victimized.
You just haven't noticed.
Every move you're being a victim of
something or someone,
the government, of course.
Next, we're going to be through in about
2 minutes. We will end abruptly. The
speaker will turn quickly on his heel
and walk away. Then you'll know that's
the end.
We want to just compare. Reality is
viewed from the from the
viewpoint of causality. The Newtonian
characteristic world of science, the
intellect and logic which is on the left
hand side. Everything is logical,
limitable, limited, provable
to a greater closer to reality. In
quantum mechanics, things are
likelihood. They're not certainty.
Provability is a figment of your own
imagination. I'll tell you nothing can
be proven. Nothing is proof of all is
not capacity. Why is that so? Because
the ultimate reality is subjectivity.
Nothing can be true. And in the
Newtonian paradigm,
it can only be realized
subjectively
as the sense of the source of one's own
existence.
You cannot prove the existence of God.
It's ridiculous.
The person who lives the scientific
objective intellectual world says that
that is the only world.
And you know why they say that? Because
subjectively that's the truth to them.
The absolute truth then as you go beyond
theology, epistemology, all of it. You
end up with the radical truth is subject
subjective.
It is the sense of awareness of your
existence that is listening to the voice
at the moment. The sense of reality, the
source of one's own existence is the
presence of God within.
And when you say I, it's
by permission of the divinity within.
You might say permission.
Not the right word. By virtue of the
presence
of God within, one knows that one's
exists.
One is aware of one's existence.
And to know that that source of one's
existence is the truth of who one is
is what is meant by self-realization.
And I thank you.