So today we're going to discuss um how
to live your life like a prayer. Um we
have done other uh one lecture about it.
Um but I there were some things that
were missing and I wanted to touch on
certain um
characteristics that of prayer. So um my
first question is when you say live your
life like a prayer
uh what is your
interpretation of that? It means to to
dedicate your uh life to lovingness and
uh the acknowledgment of the divinity of
our creator
and uh to love your fellow man as
yourself
and to be willing to forgive
uh any seeming shortcomings
and uh to forgive the past especially
because if you think of it every
resentment that you have or anger or
dismay or something is always about the
past.
People never realize it. Every negative
feeling you have is about the past.
Whatever you're upset about happened
already and it's over.
So the big news is get over it.
And even if somebody shot your foot off,
that was just a few seconds ago.
It's not now. It was already the past.
So
stop clinging to the past
allows us a much greater freedom
uh to be who we really are and to
discover the presence of God as as
lovingness within us.
So we by letting go of the past we
uh give dominion to the lovingness which
it prevails in the present which is the
characteristic of the presence of God.
So we acknowledge God's presence by our
willingness to let go of the past and to
be loving and receptive in the present.
>> So should we live in the present? You
don't have any choice.
>> You live in the present whether you like
it or not,
>> you know, as far as the reality of the
physicality goes.
>> Psychologically, many people cling to
the past.
I know lots of people that haven't grown
up since they were maybe 12 or 14.
>> Well, the new book that we have written
is about letting go.
Oh yes.
>> of um resentments and
um different
u positionalities that we have about who
we are and what we are.
>> Yes. Those are all all remnants of the
past.
>> Mhm. our definition of our self
and our emotional opinions about
everything up to the
a couple of seconds ago
are are all belong to the past.
>> Um
>> what I just said is already in the past.
I don't even care about it now.
>> So So when you pray
>> and um how should you pray?
Well, you can't tell people how to pray.
It's it's an attitude. Prayer to me is a
reverential attitude.
And um because it's an attitude, it can
prevail anywhere, anytime, any place in
an airplane and in Alaska or wherever it
may be.
The same reverence for life,
the awareness that divinity is the
source of this life
and the reverence for that divinity
prevails over all else.
What I said is already the past.
>> Um
for instance um when you pray uh you
have often said don't do not outline.
>> Yes. So what do you mean outline?
>> What that means is not to tell God how
to do a thing or what his business is.
Uh
people try to tell God what you know
what they need when they need it and
with whom and under what circumstances
and uh that of course limits uh that
limits everything. So when we say I ask
God for knowledge of his will for me and
the power to carry that out
that's a very common prayer. I ask for
God's will for me and the power to carry
that out. And you do that one day at a
time every morning. I pray for knowledge
of your will for me this Lord this day
this Lord and ask for the power to carry
it out.
And that's a very common prayer. It's
common to all the 12step groups. They
all follow the same 12 steps. Yes.
>> Okay. Um
I'm trying to think of a example. Um
when you pray and you say, "Well, let's
just do this." All right. I want to win
the lottery. Now, you know as well as I
do that a lot of people that win the
lottery are miserable,
but um you know a lot of people think
that money is going to solve all their
problems.
>> That's just expressing a wish. That's
not really prayer.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Prayer would be uh where you ask
God to make sure that you win the
lottery. Asking God to vote in your
favor. Mhm.
>> Uh so that's a different kind of a
opinion to have about God
>> and your expectations of divinity.
Uh
I was brought up to to surrender
everything to God as as surrender
everything to God's will.
Express your wishes and then surrender
them to God's will. Mhm.
>> And if you were meant to be rich and
famous, you will be and if you weren't,
you won't.
So it's sort of an implication of karmic
propensities in a way.
>> Mhm.
>> Which is not a common common
uh notion in Christianity karma that
arises more in the eastern religions
that we don't speak about Christian
karma.
So
when is prayer useful? I mean they've
done all kind of studies about people
who are ill and um if they were had a
group of people praying for them that
they recovered quicker than other people
who are not who
>> Yes. There's been sort of a scientific
documentation
of the beneficial effects of prayer
>> by oneself and others and hopefully by
both oneself and others.
So that prayer has been scientifically
documented to be of benefit.
And what if it wasn't
and then you stop praying, right?
So, it's beneficial to have these prayer
lists or pray for people that um are
going through times of challenges
health-wise. And
>> I I think so definitely because uh not
only for their benefit, but actually for
your own even if their life doesn't
improve, you've appealed to God uh uh to
assist you in the human condition. So it
certainly has affected your own life
>> and then hopefully also the life of
others.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. What about um for instance we
always bless our food before we consume
it. So what is can you give me an why we
do that? Why do we bless our food before
we eat it? Does it change it that?
>> Well, we bless it because uh of thanks
for one thing that we have enough to
eat.
>> Many people in the world do not have
enough to eat. So, I give thanks to the
Lord for this wonderful meal and it's an
expression of God's love that I my needs
are provided for.
So I express my gratitude, my
thankfulness
and u that completes the circle.
>> Okay.
Um
what would you say would be a useful
prayer? I mean when would you use prayer
to in helping others?
Um
>> well I think in a way
uh prayer is useful all the time.
Um there is an admonition
pray constantly.
So you pray for yourself. You pray for
others. You pray for the human
condition.
You pray for little little animals who
depend on you for their life.
You pray for the ones you love.
And in the meantime, you thank God for
all of the above.
>> Okay?
>> So I thank God that you are sitting next
to me and giving me these questions to
puzzle with.
Well, when we have obstacles, would it
be appropriate to um either see the
obstacles to pray uh to see the
obstacles differently or do we pray to
learn from those obstacles?
>> Well, it depends uh how sophisticated
the person is praying.
>> Well, we're trying to get better. That's
why I want I want you to specify this. I
mean, I'm trying to get better at my
prayer
because, you know, it's I mean, more
sophisticated.
>> Well, you can see that the prayer is a
personal thing of yourself.
It also implies that divinity is
listening and capable of respond
responding. Mhm.
>> You include your environment and all the
people and that you love
and that the well-being of the world and
all of life within that world.
Mhm.
>> Well, there's been research that says
that I think it's is it the Japanese man
that did that whole book study on uh the
water and you pray over it and it
changes
>> Oh, it changes the surface tension. Yes.
>> It changes the actual
structure of the water.
>> Yeah. So, I'm not familiar with that
study, although I've heard of it. Yes.
Mhm. And so it prayer obviously is
capable of doing marvelous things.
>> Well, of course the the mind wants it to
be proven,
>> right?
>> And faith doesn't require that it be
proven.
um
whether it can be proven that God
responds to my prayers or not, you know,
is irrelevant to me because I'm um
presenting my view of myself and
divinity and my relationship to divinity
and uh I'm not responsible for the
results.
I'm only uh responsible for my own
attitude.
So I thank God for everything in advance
and whether there's a response or not is
actually quite irrelevant. Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> You know, you you you pray to get to
school on time and then you and then you
know you know that old joke the kids
prays that he's late for school. play p
prays to God to help me get to school on
time. And then he gets to the curb and
he trips and he says, "But I didn't ask
you to push me."
>> I hadn't heard that one. That's good.
>> Yeah.
Didn't ask you to push me.
Well,
um, when you pray a lot of times, I
mean, I find that my prayers are usually
for other people a lot of the time,
>> for the people.
>> For other people, you know.
>> Yes.
>> Um, and so
is it pro appropriate to ask prayers for
yourself?
>> Well, I think so. Right?
>> I mean, if you're all alone out in the
woods, who else is going to pray for
you?
You could say, "Dear God, I'm lost in
these woods.
Don't know where I am. I've lost my
compass
and the animals have run off with my
food.
It's just you and God."
Well, could be God's way of telling you
this is your last day on Earth. See,
>> so so when you outline
>> Yeah.
>> Is that saying that you want this
outcome because you're praying to God?
>> The outline is, you know, like telling
God his business
like uh you need that so much money and
you need it by Monday.
Outlining is telling God how how to how
to provide for you according to your
will
>> instead of asking for God's will.
>> So your your will may be to get it and
his will may be that you don't get it
right.
>> If you get more rich or more famous,
you're going to be in worse shape than
you are already. So
everybody wants to be rich and famous.
>> Of course it's deadly.
The daily news will tell you how how
much good it does you.
Uh
but again that all depends on personal
car. You can't say it's due to success
and fame.
Some people it benefits them
tremendously
and other people it sort of ends their
life.
>> Well, like some people do good with what
they have.
>> They do accumulate.
>> Yes.
>> Accumulated. They do all types of
wonderful things for people.
>> They really do.
>> And there's other people that would not
do that if they had it.
>> So, in some cases, it's beneficial. Mhm.
>> In other cases, it it brings their life
to an end almost.
>> Mhm.
>> Get hooked up on fame and money.
>> So, is the ego a little bit in there?
You know, when you
>> more than a little bit, it's all there.
Money and fame.
>> I was trying to be nice.
That's the old Zen in there, you know,
>> right?
>> Just give me a little money in fame.
>> Yeah.
>> Like a million or two.
To a lot of people, a million or two
would be a small change,
>> right? I knew people back in the east
they would consider that small change
>> but also you know I mean
you've also talked about karma and how
karmically you have to earn that quality
too
>> that's
not a familiar concept in the west of
karma
>> right
>> but karmically you have to be able to
handle it because a lot of people when
they hit the lottery they just can't
handle any of that.
>> Yes. It said routinely destroys people,
>> right?
>> Uh the unexpected.
>> Mhm.
>> And uh
they just go under very fast.
>> Yes. The history of people who win the
lottery
is pretty grim,
>> right?
>> High divorce, high suicide,
alcohol and drugs.
>> Their family quit talking to them. You
know, there's lots of I mean, I know a
few. There's lots of them that their
family, you know, they no longer will
talk to them.
>> Oh, yes.
>> They, you know, because they they want
money from them and
>> Yes, that's true.
>> You need to help all of us and because
we're family and,
>> you know, so there's a lot of things
that go are attached to it that
>> the little greeneyed monster
>> and I don't think other people realize
that until they
>> are there.
>> The greeneyed monster. Mhm.
>> Right.
>> Yeah. So prayer is useful in our
everyday lives and
in order to
use it in our everyday lives. Let's say
that we we're going to do a whole day in
our life. So we start off with prayer in
the morning asking God to give us a
wonderful day. Or what do we say when we
start off in the morning?
>> Well, we dedicate this day that I
service, oh Lord, and I ask how I can be
beneficial
uh to your
intention for others.
I I try to serve God and I try to serve
my fellow man.
And by serving my fellow man, I serve
God. God doesn't need my service.
But I'm very cooperative with God.
>> And then we pray over our food and bless
it. You know,
>> we acknowledge
we acknowledge the sovereignty of
divinity. Mhm.
>> I mean, we don't have to make a big
production over it. You can say it
silently before you eat. And
>> that's what you can do. Yes.
>> You don't have to do a big production
out of it.
>> Yes, that's correct. Yes.
Mhm.
>> Especially in public places, you know,
and I Well, I've always felt that prayer
was more personal on a personal level,
>> you know, and that was my communication.
>> Yes.
>> You know, with a a a special higher
being.
>> So, I always took it to more of a
personal level level than a public.
>> Yes. Yes. It's sort of a family feeling
to it,
>> right? As dinner is served, you all uh
thank give thanks for this meal and
>> bless it in God's name
with gratitude.
>> Mhm.
>> You know, you live life one day at a
time. Uh grateful for God's gifts
and the benefits that your life can have
in others.
>> Well, what would you say to someone who
doesn't believe in God or prayer?
I would say um
um not to worry about it.
>> Okay. That's I mean there's plenty of
people out there in in structured
religions that would not agree with you,
but
>> Well,
the faster trail to God is
theoretically through prayer and
divi divine service. Mhm.
>> But also the miraculous occurs out out
of unexpectedness.
>> Okay.
>> And um I've seen people go from atheist
to a profound believer in a matter of
seconds.
Wham. and all of a sudden you're hit by
a bolt of lightning and uh
during World War II. I remember that for
instance
guys and atheists but as the kamicazi
pilots came down and the bullets started
flying they suddenly found God.
>> Yeah.
Well, you've off often said that, you
know, to
um
go to the bullets
uh knowing the outcome
is a very high uh state.
>> That is a state of uh surrender.
And in that particular culture, the
divinity includes uh
what we would call more the governmental
uh power structure.
So in that particular
um
society I respected their devotion to
God and their willingness to surrender
their life
>> to the good of their country which they
understood to be the way to serve God.
It also made them very dangerous
because if they're doing it for God, you
know, they're willing to take any risk,
including taking your life with them.
>> Mhm.
>> So,
>> I respected their devotion and their
belief system.
>> Is there any um repercussion for taking
another human being's life? I mean, do
you can you answer that question or am I
asking something that I shouldn't?
>> Well, that that could take the next hour
to answer.
>> That's what I thought.
That's what I thought. I mean, what are
the, you know, karma is in that?
>> Well, you have the overall uh context.
>> Mhm.
>> And then you have the intention.
Then you have the person's capability
for comprehension.
>> And then you have the duty in there. If
you're doing
>> and then if you're in the service,
you've got a duty. That's right.
>> So what are the complications?
>> Obligation to your obligation to your
fellow man.
>> So there's several it's it's layered
then the complications are layered in
that
>> multiplicities. Uhuh. Layer upon layer.
You do a thing out of devotion.
That means you believe in God. And uh so
that depends on your background and your
background may prelude such kind of
attitudes
or it may require it. So it depends on
the culture in which you grow up.
>> Depends on the culture
>> because many times you know people say
well you know what kind of person would
take another person's life and it weighs
very heavily on our servicemen.
Indeed it does
>> that they you know because I hear so
many times you know you being in the
service uh say I'm so glad I did not
have to kill someone.
>> I I was personally
>> you were you were on the ship but you
almost got blown up yourself but I mean
we you often say I'm so glad I did not
have to take another person's life.
>> Well that way I would otherwise I would
spend the rest of my life thinking about
that what that person could have been
like. that I have the right to take
their life.
>> But out of duty, don't you think that
that
>> that is forgiven because you were doing
it out of what had to be done at that
time?
>> Well, it isn't just a matter of
forgiveness. It's a matter of personal
responsibility.
>> Okay?
>> You know, it's like you run over a
pedestrian.
You know, you weren't malicious. You
didn't intend to kill them, but you ran
over some little six-year-old in the
intersection. And so that weighs heavily
on you.
>> Mhm.
>> That little child, what that child could
have been
>> and um
of course all of these occasions bring
up, you know, the concept of karma. What
was that little child's karmic
>> background? And uh so self forgiveness
is difficult.
under certain circumstances
in which you cannot see the innocence.
You could say that in in one one respect
everyone is innocent all the time for
everything.
If you knew divine will, you wouldn't be
doing what you're doing. But you don't
know divine will. So to what degree are
is anyone responsible for their behavior
and under what conditions?
Under certain conditions, everybody's
responsible for everything, and under
others, you're not responsible for
anything.
>> So, let's say you're driving down the
street and all of a sudden, uh, you
hit someone.
>> Mhm.
>> And they and and you killed them. So
karmically
you were there at that time
>> the responsibility.
>> Yeah.
>> But not necessarily the guilt.
>> Okay.
>> The average person would feel guilty. Of
course.
>> Yes.
>> Even if it was the pedestrian's uh
fault, you would still feel guilty that
it was your car that killed them. And
of course, death has grave consequences.
But do you think that but do you think
that um God or the higher
uh awareness would know that
you could handle that? I mean do you
think that they that God only gives us
things that we can handle?
um
I haven't
spent any time thinking about
>> okay
>> whether God um goes through that kind of
a process with each and every one of us
and to me it's more that God sets the
setting in which the things are
>> matters of dominion
>> and then within that dominion you have a
certain degree of freedom
>> but it's only a matter of degree of
freedom
Uh, none of us are totally free.
>> You know, I can't decide to be six feet
tall.
I'm a few inches too short.
When I went in service, I had the I was
undersized and underweight, you know.
So, he says, "Uh, he he helped me up
there. He says, "Stand there." He says,
"Shorty," and I forget how old tall I
was. I don't know, 5 foot seven, really.
He says, "Stand, you don't quite make
it. Just stand on your toes." He says,
"Okay, now you make it." He says, "You
pass."
Then he told me to get on the scale. And
uh I didn't pass. So he said, "I want
you to go out and eat bananas and come
back in a month." So I went out and I'd
stuff myself with bananas around the
clock.
And I came back and and uh and I sit on
the scale and and he put his thumb on
the scale and he says, "Oh, you just
make it.
I wasn't really tall enough. I didn't
weigh enough
and I wasn't turned really quite
physically strong enough either,
but I wanted to be in the service.
So, I was and I uh I'm very grateful for
the opportunity I had
and serve the country and be with my
shipmates.
And uh we we sent Christmas cards to
each other after the World War was over
for many years every year. But each year
the number of Christmas cards I got
would diminish.
And now I don't get any more Christmas
cards. So I'm the last survivor from the
ship.
The last survivors
46.
Well, you often talk about how all of
you that served together were um you had
this certain camaraderie,
you know, among you. And I mean, this is
years ago and you still were sending
cards, you know, every Christmas. So,
>> Oh, yes. That's true.
>> You never forgot that.
>> Serving together in that wartime
>> uh situation.
>> Oh, yeah. We were bonded for a lifetime.
Yeah, we were bonded together for the
rest of our lives.
And I'm the last remaining member of the
crew.
>> Well, I think you were the youngest,
weren't you?
>> I don't remember. I was the smallest,
the lightest.
They called me shorty. And uh
yeah,
I was the smallest member of the crew.
Yeah.
So prayer plays a um if we use it daily
in our lives
um
do you think that betters our life?
>> Well the the prayer is uh is several
different kinds of prayer. One is a
prayer for the general welfare of
others.
Then there's specific prayers for
specific events.
Then there's prayers that are more
personal for yourself and your family
and your relatives and you know your
mother and your mother-in-law and your
sister and your daughter and all. Um and
then there's the more general prayer
which I I consider to be reverence.
uh to me to be reverent is a style of
praying in which your life becomes the
prayer.
>> Your whole life is one of acknowledgment
of the divinity as the source and
value of life.
It's not a matter of win or lose. You
know, people think of
praying as winning. You know, you win
with God. If you can pray good enough,
God will grant you the wish.
>> Yeah.
>> That's sort of the way a child prays,
you know, dear Lord, please don't let me
be late for class.
And then the kid crimps on the curb and
he says, "But I didn't ask you to push
me." I love that joke.
>> Yeah.
Well, sometimes, you know, I mean, I
myself, I have prayed for things that I
thought that I really needed or wanted
or wanted to happen or whatever. And
yet, when it didn't happen, I saw uh I
it was a different picture and it was
the way it was better that my that my
prayer wasn't answered.
>> You know, I've had that happen.
>> Yes. to where you you think, you know,
oh, I really want to want this this to
happen. This is just got to happen for
me. And yet, when that prayer isn't
answered, it's much better the way it
turned out.
>> That's the way it reveals itself, the
truth behind it.
>> So, you know, it just amazes me.
I think it's very nice that we uh have
sufficient humility that
we can acknowledge the gift whether we
it's granted or not granted.
>> Either way there's a gift
for it not to be granted opens up
certain doorways and for it to be
granted opens up other doorways.
>> So in a way you might say you always win
with prayer. You either get it or you
don't. And either way, it's beneficial.
>> You pray for a million dollars and you
don't get it. You say, "Well, God felt
that that would have been harmful to my
life."
>> Mhm.
>> And you you pray for a million dollars
and you get it. You say, "God had
confidence in my ability to to handle
this for the good of others." Because
now the million dollars gives you an
obligation to be helpful to others with
that million dollars.
>> Yeah. We talked about stewardship.
>> Yes.
>> The stewardship that is involved in
serving others.
>> You never really own anything or nothing
is really yours. You're you're only the
steward of it for a certain period of
time
>> and then it passes on to others.
>> Well, I've always had that, you know, I
like antiques.
>> Uhu.
So, I've always had it in mind that I'm
just a keeper of those for that time in
my life and then it passes on to someone
else because some of the antiques are
hundreds of years old.
>> That's right.
>> So, it just, you know, I enjoy it from
that time in my life and then it goes on
to someone else who's going to enjoy it
>> willing to share the beauty of it and
the treasure of it,
>> the value of it. Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> So, you know, when you look at it from
that point of view, it's the same with
everything in your life basically that
everything can be looked at like that.
>> That's what makes your life turns your
life into a prayer.
>> Mhm. where you see everything as a gift
or a lesson
uh and you see the benefit that it
brings to yourself and to others and you
pray to be helpful to the life of those
you love.
>> Okay. So if speaking that we're talking
about lottery and everything, if we
wanted to bring uh prosperity into our
lives,
>> I have found that the quickest way that
happens to me is when I
try and do good for others in their
life,
>> then I'm rewarded not only for that, but
from my own aspects. I mean,
emotionally,
um, spiritually, it it does so much more
for me to give to others than it does
to,
um,
just want. That's right.
>> And want.
>> So, we get we get uh by giving.
>> Well, this day and age, everybody's, you
know, financially, everybody's com, you
know, talking about this. So that's why
I'm bringing this up
>> and they are financially.
>> Oh yeah, there's
>> about it.
All the people on the television.
>> Yeah, I see.
>> Where Well,
>> well, it's because it's the holidays are
>> right
>> close by. And that always brings up the
whole subject,
>> right? for greater intensity. Prayer and
devotion and church and religion and
holiness. All these aspects
um come up for reinforcement and
re-examination with every holiday.
>> Well, Thanksgiving is coming up pretty
shortly, is it not?
>> Yes.
>> Mhm.
>> So, if we were to give, what would you
what would you say we should do as a
thanksgiving prayer? What should we do
to be to let God know that we're
thankful for what we have?
>> Just pray up a storm.
>> Rattle the dishes.
>> Yeah.
Now the way we live our life is is uh
depends on how we view divinity. If
divinity is ever present,
this lovingness is a field in which we
operate and thrive.
So this lovingness to me, God is
lovingness. Lovingness
and um
the propensity for love to go to love.
The propensity is for love to go to
love.
We recently had a lecture on love,
didn't we? It went on love. Yes. And it
had to do with the propensity of love to
go to love.
So, it's kind of weird that here we have
this Thanksgiving holiday, you know,
that involves bounty, you know, because
we celebrate.
>> We have, you know, the harvest basically
is how it all started. But, um, we're
thankful for
our family, friends,
um,
the food that we eat. Um, so we, you
know, our holidays should, the
Thanksgiving holiday is a chance to
really be thankful for the gifts that
have been granted us.
>> We're surrounded by gifts.
>> Yeah.
>> Mhm. The fact that we are still alive. I
say, "Well, thank you, God, that I'm
still alive."
Uh, and I
can you, you know, devote my life to the
usefulness to others.
>> So, that gives it some value.
Because just having things doesn't
increase value.
U
it increases fun and pleasure, but it
doesn't really increase value.
>> And it could be that certain lifetimes
you spend more lifetimes in service,
would you say, to others rather than um
>> Yes. I think if you go into the
historical background of many people,
you'll find uh a certain pattern to
their
>> recurrent recurrent emergence another
human life
to be of service or to make up for
having not been of service.
Okay.
So if you were to sum everything up as
um live your life like a prayer, what
message would you give us?
>> To be grateful for the opportunity for
your own existence. I always say dear
God I'm very grateful that I exist
and I consider this a gift which I
treasure and I will try to use this gift
to the best of my ability
to spread that love to and gratitude to
others. Yes.
So the way I express my gratitude to God
is by being loving towards others to the
greatest extent I could do so
>> even when they pull out in front of you.
Well, that's just a childish annoyance
that somebody's
>> has gotten in your way. It's a little
scary. That's right. As you're racing
down the highway, suddenly a car pulls
out
from the side of the road right in front
of you.
>> It's just very hard to to say take what
you're saying and put it into every day.
>> Well, it's an it's an attitude. And
because it's an attitude, it prevails
and covers all the conditions.
So if a car is going too slow,
uh you have one kind of response. If the
car is pulling out too fast, you have
another response.
But all of them are being governed by
your great gratitude
that you have the opportunity to save
people's lives to serve other people and
to be alive for the benefit of yourself
and others. Amen. Mhm.
>> So live your life like a prayer every
day and in every way
>> to be grateful for your own existence
and to share your appreciation to God
that you exist
and the opportunity to express your love
towards others
uh is a gift from God. And I give thanks
to thee, oh Lord, for the gift of being
able to be here with you right now and
and record this event.
>> Thank you, dear Lord, for the chance to
record this event. And after you and I
are long gone, that this recording will
still be available if anybody's
interested.
Way back in the olden times
when old Doc Hawkins and old Susan
Hawkins
were still kicking around and alive, you
know, way way back then.
We'll be old, old old folks before you
know it. Okay.
>> All right. Thank you.