I wrote this question down to Yes. Good.
I wrote this question down to Yes. Good. And uh I've also provided your wife
And uh I've also provided your wife
And uh I've also provided your wife Susan a copy of this question.
Susan a copy of this question.
Susan a copy of this question. It seems to me that the basic needs of
It seems to me that the basic needs of
It seems to me that the basic needs of food, clothing, and shelter and
food, clothing, and shelter and
food, clothing, and shelter and selfactualization
selfactualization
selfactualization must be achieved by 80% of the world's
must be achieved by 80% of the world's
must be achieved by 80% of the world's population
population
population before humanity could calculate between
before humanity could calculate between
before humanity could calculate between five and 600.
five and 600.
five and 600. This would still require the mind and
This would still require the mind and
This would still require the mind and ego to achieve these basic needs in the
ego to achieve these basic needs in the
ego to achieve these basic needs in the daily lives of human beings.
daily lives of human beings.
daily lives of human beings. A spiritual level of consciousness where
A spiritual level of consciousness where
A spiritual level of consciousness where love is the essence of human behavior
love is the essence of human behavior
love is the essence of human behavior could provide the paradigm shift into
could provide the paradigm shift into
could provide the paradigm shift into the 500s.
the 500s.
the 500s. Which comes first, the chicken or the
Which comes first, the chicken or the
Which comes first, the chicken or the egg? And how does humanity reach a
egg? And how does humanity reach a
egg? And how does humanity reach a balance between basic needs and
balance between basic needs and
balance between basic needs and spiritual enlightenment?
the optimum opportunity.
the optimum opportunity. Instant by instant we make choices.
Instant by instant we make choices.
Instant by instant we make choices. By so doing we transcend past karma
By so doing we transcend past karma
By so doing we transcend past karma and move into out of force
and move into out of force
and move into out of force into power.
into power.
into power. So whereas at one level we have to kill
So whereas at one level we have to kill
So whereas at one level we have to kill somebody to get his wife and his crop
somebody to get his wife and his crop
somebody to get his wife and his crop and his money and tear off his jewelry.
and his money and tear off his jewelry.
and his money and tear off his jewelry. Now all that comes to us with no energy
Now all that comes to us with no energy
Now all that comes to us with no energy and no effort.
and no effort.
and no effort. You have a loving life.
You have a loving life.
You have a loving life. People give you gifts right and left.
People give you gifts right and left.
People give you gifts right and left. You suffer from the problem of
You suffer from the problem of
You suffer from the problem of abundance.
It's the automatic consequence of that
It's the automatic consequence of that which you have become. And that's the
which you have become. And that's the
which you have become. And that's the way the field reacts to what you have
way the field reacts to what you have
way the field reacts to what you have become.
become.
become. What you have become then is magnetic to
What you have become then is magnetic to
What you have become then is magnetic to the field. And the field can't do enough
the field. And the field can't do enough
the field. And the field can't do enough for you. I have to be careful not to say
for you. I have to be careful not to say
for you. I have to be careful not to say anything I like.
anything I like.
anything I like. If I mention that I like licorice,
If I mention that I like licorice,
If I mention that I like licorice, within a week I'll get tons of licorice,
within a week I'll get tons of licorice,
within a week I'll get tons of licorice, packages of licorice, licorice stuff by
packages of licorice, licorice stuff by
packages of licorice, licorice stuff by the door.
At a lower level of consciousness,
At a lower level of consciousness, you're wanting, but because of your
you're wanting, but because of your
you're wanting, but because of your wantingness, you deny it to yourself.
wantingness, you deny it to yourself.
wantingness, you deny it to yourself. It's when you let go of wantingness that
It's when you let go of wantingness that
It's when you let go of wantingness that abundance happens. So there are many
abundance happens. So there are many
abundance happens. So there are many workshops on how to increase prosperity
workshops on how to increase prosperity
workshops on how to increase prosperity and such things
and such things
and such things and I say wanting prosperity is the very
and I say wanting prosperity is the very
and I say wanting prosperity is the very thing that keeps it from you. The thing
thing that keeps it from you. The thing
thing that keeps it from you. The thing to do is to find satisfaction in being
to do is to find satisfaction in being
to do is to find satisfaction in being that which you are
that which you are
that which you are to the best that you can be what you
to the best that you can be what you
to the best that you can be what you are. To me that's what's class. Class is
are. To me that's what's class. Class is
are. To me that's what's class. Class is being what you are to the fullest.
being what you are to the fullest.
being what you are to the fullest. class to me is the waiter that serves
class to me is the waiter that serves
class to me is the waiter that serves with style, you know? I mean, that is a
with style, you know? I mean, that is a
with style, you know? I mean, that is a waiter. The chef who does it with
waiter. The chef who does it with
waiter. The chef who does it with finesse,
finesse,
finesse, the cook, the cleaning lady, the taxi
the cook, the cleaning lady, the taxi
the cook, the cleaning lady, the taxi cab driver who's friendly as all get
cab driver who's friendly as all get
cab driver who's friendly as all get out, goes out of his way.
out, goes out of his way.
out, goes out of his way. Class is being what you are to the
Class is being what you are to the
Class is being what you are to the fullest. Huh? And then you pull to
fullest. Huh? And then you pull to
fullest. Huh? And then you pull to yourself abundance. A classy cab driver
yourself abundance. A classy cab driver
yourself abundance. A classy cab driver gets heavy tips all the time, doesn't
gets heavy tips all the time, doesn't
gets heavy tips all the time, doesn't he?
he?
he? >> The great waitress, you say, "Hi,
>> The great waitress, you say, "Hi,
>> The great waitress, you say, "Hi, Gertude. I want to sit in Gertude's side
Gertude. I want to sit in Gertude's side
Gertude. I want to sit in Gertude's side of the restaurant."
of the restaurant."
of the restaurant." So, the world seeks you out because of
So, the world seeks you out because of
So, the world seeks you out because of what you have become.
what you have become.
what you have become. And what you've become, we just covered
And what you've become, we just covered
And what you've become, we just covered on one of those slides. Gracious, you
on one of those slides. Gracious, you
on one of those slides. Gracious, you know, saying, "Gee, thanks. That was
know, saying, "Gee, thanks. That was
know, saying, "Gee, thanks. That was terrific."
terrific."
terrific." It doesn't take a great deal to turn
It doesn't take a great deal to turn
It doesn't take a great deal to turn your life from wantingness
your life from wantingness
your life from wantingness to plenty to. And as I say, the problem
to plenty to. And as I say, the problem
to plenty to. And as I say, the problem of abundance. I give workshops on how to
of abundance. I give workshops on how to
of abundance. I give workshops on how to handle the problem of abundance.
handle the problem of abundance.
handle the problem of abundance. Where do you put it all?
Where do you put it all?
Where do you put it all? So
So
So this is the a world that offers us the
this is the a world that offers us the
this is the a world that offers us the maximum opportunity to grow and become
maximum opportunity to grow and become
maximum opportunity to grow and become that
that
that and that which we become attracts to it
and that which we become attracts to it
and that which we become attracts to it all the good things and at the other end
all the good things and at the other end
all the good things and at the other end of the scale we repel all the good
of the scale we repel all the good
of the scale we repel all the good things. We repel all the good things. A
things. We repel all the good things. A
things. We repel all the good things. A decent couple goes to look at an
decent couple goes to look at an
decent couple goes to look at an apartment in a neighborhood covered with
apartment in a neighborhood covered with
apartment in a neighborhood covered with filth and says no thank you
filth and says no thank you
filth and says no thank you repelled by the negative.
So we become our potentiality and as a
So we become our potentiality and as a consequence the field responds to us.
consequence the field responds to us.
consequence the field responds to us. We find fulfillment then in every moment
We find fulfillment then in every moment
We find fulfillment then in every moment of everything that we do.
of everything that we do.
of everything that we do. Everything that we do. When I was a cab
Everything that we do. When I was a cab
Everything that we do. When I was a cab driver, I made more money than any cab
driver, I made more money than any cab
driver, I made more money than any cab driver per mile in the company.
driver per mile in the company.
driver per mile in the company. When I was a bartender, I doubled the
When I was a bartender, I doubled the
When I was a bartender, I doubled the business. Everything I did, I did with I
business. Everything I did, I did with I
business. Everything I did, I did with I love doing it. And I'm right.
love doing it. And I'm right.
love doing it. And I'm right. I knew every address, which side of the
I knew every address, which side of the
I knew every address, which side of the street, 2262 North, so and so. I knew
street, 2262 North, so and so. I knew
street, 2262 North, so and so. I knew was left side or the right side. I knew
was left side or the right side. I knew
was left side or the right side. I knew all the oneway streets, so you could
all the oneway streets, so you could
all the oneway streets, so you could come around this way. You know what I
come around this way. You know what I
come around this way. You know what I mean? You just try to be the best you
mean? You just try to be the best you
mean? You just try to be the best you can at everything you do. So, how do we
can at everything you do. So, how do we
can at everything you do. So, how do we get 80% of the world's population to be
get 80% of the world's population to be
get 80% of the world's population to be that way? I don't want to get 80% of the
that way? I don't want to get 80% of the
that way? I don't want to get 80% of the world anyway.
world anyway.
world anyway. Why? Because this is the optimum
Why? Because this is the optimum
Why? Because this is the optimum environment. See, a lot of people want
environment. See, a lot of people want
environment. See, a lot of people want to turn this into a celestial realm.
to turn this into a celestial realm.
to turn this into a celestial realm. This is not a celestial realm. Not
This is not a celestial realm. Not
This is not a celestial realm. Not supposed to be a celestial realm. This
supposed to be a celestial realm. This
supposed to be a celestial realm. This is supposed to be where you have the
is supposed to be where you have the
is supposed to be where you have the choices all the way from the cutthroat
choices all the way from the cutthroat
choices all the way from the cutthroat at the bottom to a Christlike figure at
at the bottom to a Christlike figure at
at the bottom to a Christlike figure at the top.
the top.
the top. This is purgatorial in a way because it
This is purgatorial in a way because it
This is purgatorial in a way because it covers the whole spectrum. If you go to
covers the whole spectrum. If you go to
covers the whole spectrum. If you go to a celestial realm, you're talking about
a celestial realm, you're talking about
a celestial realm, you're talking about 500 and up, 540 and up. You don't have
500 and up, 540 and up. You don't have
500 and up, 540 and up. You don't have any choices there. You're not you don't
any choices there. You're not you don't
any choices there. You're not you don't have a choice between falling for this
have a choice between falling for this
have a choice between falling for this and falling for that.
So this is a world of maximum
So this is a world of maximum opportunity. I have no desire to change
opportunity. I have no desire to change
opportunity. I have no desire to change it. It's perfectly fine the way it is.
it. It's perfectly fine the way it is.
it. It's perfectly fine the way it is. because it offers us somebody who
because it offers us somebody who
because it offers us somebody who calibrates 120 or well let's say 120.
calibrates 120 or well let's say 120.
calibrates 120 or well let's say 120. Where is he going to get reborn and move
Where is he going to get reborn and move
Where is he going to get reborn and move from 120 up to 350?
from 120 up to 350?
from 120 up to 350? Where you going to get born? Not in the
Where you going to get born? Not in the
Where you going to get born? Not in the celestial realm.
celestial realm.
celestial realm. Not in hell either. You know, you can't
Not in hell either. You know, you can't
Not in hell either. You know, you can't move out. You know, you've got to be in
move out. You know, you've got to be in
move out. You know, you've got to be in a place with absolute opportunity and
a place with absolute opportunity and
a place with absolute opportunity and freedom
freedom
freedom here. You can curse the guy who pulls in
here. You can curse the guy who pulls in
here. You can curse the guy who pulls in front of you in traffic or say, "I'll
front of you in traffic or say, "I'll
front of you in traffic or say, "I'll give the guy a break. Why not?"
give the guy a break. Why not?"
give the guy a break. Why not?" >> Sure.
>> Sure.
>> Sure. >> You got that whole choice. In heaven,
>> You got that whole choice. In heaven,
>> You got that whole choice. In heaven, you don't have that choice.
It's all flowers and celestial things,
It's all flowers and celestial things, you
a golden fairy floss in front of you and
a golden fairy floss in front of you and you swinging your celestial gondola.
you swinging your celestial gondola.
you swinging your celestial gondola. Now you got to have the opportunity to
Now you got to have the opportunity to
Now you got to have the opportunity to curse him or give him the okay. So this
curse him or give him the okay. So this
curse him or give him the okay. So this is the to me the world of maximum
is the to me the world of maximum
is the to me the world of maximum spiritual opportunity.
spiritual opportunity.
spiritual opportunity. >> So we value the diversity here. We value
>> So we value the diversity here. We value
>> So we value the diversity here. We value the diversity because of the tremendous
the diversity because of the tremendous
the diversity because of the tremendous opportunity here. You can jump 100. I've
opportunity here. You can jump 100. I've
opportunity here. You can jump 100. I've had people in class, you know, in a
had people in class, you know, in a
had people in class, you know, in a group like this jump 150 right during a
group like this jump 150 right during a
group like this jump 150 right during a lecture. You 150 points.
lecture. You 150 points.
lecture. You 150 points. It's the equivalent of 25 terms.
It's the equivalent of 25 terms.
It's the equivalent of 25 terms. >> Yeah. Thank you for that distinction.
>> Yeah. Thank you for that distinction.
>> Yeah. Thank you for that distinction. Okay.
>> If you have if if you have questions, if
>> If you have if if you have questions, if you would line up over here and then
you would line up over here and then
you would line up over here and then we'll take those one at a time. And if
we'll take those one at a time. And if
we'll take those one at a time. And if you have books to sign, if you'd also
you have books to sign, if you'd also
you have books to sign, if you'd also queue up over there, please.
queue up over there, please.
queue up over there, please. >> Yeah. If you have books to sign, I'll be
>> Yeah. If you have books to sign, I'll be
>> Yeah. If you have books to sign, I'll be happy to sign them.
No, I didn't think I was going to hang
No, I didn't think I was going to hang on last.
on last.
on last. >> I have no books to sign and I have a
>> I have no books to sign and I have a
>> I have no books to sign and I have a simple technical question.
simple technical question.
simple technical question. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Thanks to your works, I've been
>> Thanks to your works, I've been
>> Thanks to your works, I've been meditating for the past nine months by
meditating for the past nine months by
meditating for the past nine months by surrendering up my thoughts and it's
surrendering up my thoughts and it's
surrendering up my thoughts and it's worked extraordinarily well, I think.
worked extraordinarily well, I think.
worked extraordinarily well, I think. Um, I'm pleased so far. And I've been
Um, I'm pleased so far. And I've been
Um, I'm pleased so far. And I've been doing it on two basis. one uh silently
doing it on two basis. one uh silently
doing it on two basis. one uh silently and the other with listening to some
and the other with listening to some
and the other with listening to some meditation CDs where they put one tone
meditation CDs where they put one tone
meditation CDs where they put one tone in one ear and one in the other
in one ear and one in the other
in one ear and one in the other >> and it sort of brings things up to help
>> and it sort of brings things up to help
>> and it sort of brings things up to help clear them.
clear them.
clear them. >> Yeah, that's the uh
>> Yeah, that's the uh
>> Yeah, that's the uh >> Yeah,
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, >> kind of like the Monroe Institute, but
>> kind of like the Monroe Institute, but
>> kind of like the Monroe Institute, but >> Monroe sort of like Monroe. Yeah, the
>> Monroe sort of like Monroe. Yeah, the
>> Monroe sort of like Monroe. Yeah, the same idea. Yeah,
same idea. Yeah,
same idea. Yeah, >> this thing is like a 10-year program
>> this thing is like a 10-year program
>> this thing is like a 10-year program about two years into it.
about two years into it.
about two years into it. >> Yeah. In any event, I find that after I
>> Yeah. In any event, I find that after I
>> Yeah. In any event, I find that after I do the simple ones silently, it's just a
do the simple ones silently, it's just a
do the simple ones silently, it's just a lot more refreshing and easier. When I
lot more refreshing and easier. When I
lot more refreshing and easier. When I listen to the CDs, it seems to bring out
listen to the CDs, it seems to bring out
listen to the CDs, it seems to bring out more stuff. So, I'm wondering which is
more stuff. So, I'm wondering which is
more stuff. So, I'm wondering which is the most advantageous to do. Should I
the most advantageous to do. Should I
the most advantageous to do. Should I stick to the silent, stick to the sort
stick to the silent, stick to the sort
stick to the silent, stick to the sort of listening to the CDs, or is it best
of listening to the CDs, or is it best
of listening to the CDs, or is it best to do a combination of both?
to do a combination of both?
to do a combination of both? >> Well, which is more fruitful? Yes,
>> Well, which is more fruitful? Yes,
>> Well, which is more fruitful? Yes, that's uh my question to you.
I thought they had a pot.
I thought they had a pot. >> Which is the more fruitful for you?
>> Which is the more fruitful for you?
>> Which is the more fruitful for you? >> Well, in the long term, I can't tell.
>> Well, in the long term, I can't tell.
>> Well, in the long term, I can't tell. Some I think the silent ones are nice,
Some I think the silent ones are nice,
Some I think the silent ones are nice, but
but
but >> I think you should do both of them
>> I think you should do both of them
>> I think you should do both of them because they seem to serve two different
because they seem to serve two different
because they seem to serve two different purposes.
purposes.
purposes. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> You ought to come up, Sus, and sit where
>> You ought to come up, Sus, and sit where
>> You ought to come up, Sus, and sit where we grab you. Uh
we grab you. Uh
we grab you. Uh my feeling is that they're equal in
my feeling is that they're equal in
my feeling is that they're equal in value. We have permission to ask this.
value. We have permission to ask this.
value. We have permission to ask this. Uh they're equal in value. Resist. Yeah.
Uh they're equal in value. Resist. Yeah.
Uh they're equal in value. Resist. Yeah. Because the value you get out of out of
Because the value you get out of out of
Because the value you get out of out of it is the consequent of your intention.
it is the consequent of your intention.
it is the consequent of your intention. So your intention is the same in both
So your intention is the same in both
So your intention is the same in both directions. You see if you do prayer
directions. You see if you do prayer
directions. You see if you do prayer wheels you would say well isn't that
wheels you would say well isn't that
wheels you would say well isn't that ignorant? Shake that thing around and
ignorant? Shake that thing around and
ignorant? Shake that thing around and your prayers are going up to heaven.
your prayers are going up to heaven.
your prayers are going up to heaven. When you calibrate prayer wheels they
When you calibrate prayer wheels they
When you calibrate prayer wheels they calibrate over 500. See the intention of
one is like devoting oneself to
one is like devoting oneself to divinity.
divinity.
divinity. So then the technique becomes merely the
So then the technique becomes merely the
So then the technique becomes merely the manifestation of the intention but it's
manifestation of the intention but it's
manifestation of the intention but it's the intention that gives it the 520 10
the intention that gives it the 520 10
the intention that gives it the 520 10 or 20
or 20
or 20 >> right
>> right
>> right >> you know like the Ganges river did I
>> you know like the Ganges river did I
>> you know like the Ganges river did I tell you about the Ganges river today
tell you about the Ganges river today
tell you about the Ganges river today >> not today
>> not today
>> not today >> not today well you know the Ganges river
>> not today well you know the Ganges river
>> not today well you know the Ganges river has a uh a good hundred cities dump
has a uh a good hundred cities dump
has a uh a good hundred cities dump their garbage in the Ganges the dead
their garbage in the Ganges the dead
their garbage in the Ganges the dead bodies and feces and I've been in that
bodies and feces and I've been in that
bodies and feces and I've been in that part of the world and dead bodies are
part of the world and dead bodies are
part of the world and dead bodies are actually floating right by you and feces
actually floating right by you and feces
actually floating right by you and feces etc. So when I calibrated the Ganges
etc. So when I calibrated the Ganges
etc. So when I calibrated the Ganges it's over 500.
it's over 500.
it's over 500. You say how could a filthy river like
You say how could a filthy river like
You say how could a filthy river like that? People drink the Ganges water and
that? People drink the Ganges water and
that? People drink the Ganges water and they don't die of typhoid or anything.
they don't die of typhoid or anything.
they don't die of typhoid or anything. The millions of devotees Hindus over the
The millions of devotees Hindus over the
The millions of devotees Hindus over the centuries
centuries
centuries have sanctified the water of the Ganges
have sanctified the water of the Ganges
have sanctified the water of the Ganges and the Ganges is now over 500.
and the Ganges is now over 500.
and the Ganges is now over 500. Gajji Zor 500 505 510 I think it was
Gajji Zor 500 505 510 I think it was
Gajji Zor 500 505 510 I think it was around 505 510 the Gajis river so from a
around 505 510 the Gajis river so from a
around 505 510 the Gajis river so from a mechanical chemical viewpoint you'd say
mechanical chemical viewpoint you'd say
mechanical chemical viewpoint you'd say it's repulsive disgusting and probably
it's repulsive disgusting and probably
it's repulsive disgusting and probably give you a typhoid fever
give you a typhoid fever
give you a typhoid fever just like food you know food jumps 15
just like food you know food jumps 15
just like food you know food jumps 15 calibrates about 10 or 15 even 20 points
calibrates about 10 or 15 even 20 points
calibrates about 10 or 15 even 20 points higher once you bless it blessed food
higher once you bless it blessed food
higher once you bless it blessed food calibrates higher than ordinary food
calibrates higher than ordinary food
calibrates higher than ordinary food starting at the bottom you have
starting at the bottom you have
starting at the bottom you have mechanical food which calibrates usually
mechanical food which calibrates usually
mechanical food which calibrates usually a little bit less than 200 tastes dead
a little bit less than 200 tastes dead
a little bit less than 200 tastes dead in your mouth. Then food made by human
in your mouth. Then food made by human
in your mouth. Then food made by human energy jumps over 200 to 210. Then
energy jumps over 200 to 210. Then
energy jumps over 200 to 210. Then blessed food jumps up to 220.
blessed food jumps up to 220.
blessed food jumps up to 220. So the mo the the the cook in the house,
So the mo the the the cook in the house,
So the mo the the the cook in the house, man or woman, it does it out of love.
man or woman, it does it out of love.
man or woman, it does it out of love. And then the family blesses it. That's
And then the family blesses it. That's
And then the family blesses it. That's the highest energy food there is.
the highest energy food there is.
the highest energy food there is. So we always bless our kiddies food for
So we always bless our kiddies food for
So we always bless our kiddies food for the same reason. What you plus the
the same reason. What you plus the
the same reason. What you plus the kitty's food or the doggy's food is that
kitty's food or the doggy's food is that
kitty's food or the doggy's food is that energy actually goes up and there are
energy actually goes up and there are
energy actually goes up and there are certain brands of cat food that
certain brands of cat food that
certain brands of cat food that calibrate below 200 and my cat won't eat
calibrate below 200 and my cat won't eat
calibrate below 200 and my cat won't eat them
>> actually caliber below 200 I don't know
>> actually caliber below 200 I don't know what they do with that food but the cat
what they do with that food but the cat
what they do with that food but the cat won't eat it and so I said what is that
won't eat it and so I said what is that
won't eat it and so I said what is that stuff calibrated with 190 or something
stuff calibrated with 190 or something
stuff calibrated with 190 or something >> okay well I I think you've answered my
>> okay well I I think you've answered my
>> okay well I I think you've answered my question because in that on that basis
question because in that on that basis
question because in that on that basis then I could Do I could dispense of the
then I could Do I could dispense of the
then I could Do I could dispense of the CDs because it doesn't make any
CDs because it doesn't make any
CDs because it doesn't make any difference or alternatively they have
difference or alternatively they have
difference or alternatively they have some technical merit to them that is
some technical merit to them that is
some technical merit to them that is beneficial.
beneficial.
beneficial. >> They may serve a certain purpose at a
>> They may serve a certain purpose at a
>> They may serve a certain purpose at a certain time. Right. Second that makes
certain time. Right. Second that makes
certain time. Right. Second that makes sense.
sense.
sense. >> Yeah. Because everybody who gets evolved
>> Yeah. Because everybody who gets evolved
>> Yeah. Because everybody who gets evolved you know checks this out checks that out
you know checks this out checks that out
you know checks this out checks that out checks out new aism chatting channeling
checks out new aism chatting channeling
checks out new aism chatting channeling psychic readings
psychic readings
psychic readings the tarot cards dream dream
the tarot cards dream dream
the tarot cards dream dream interpretation
interpretation
interpretation all
all
all >> got to check it out. See? And I say,
>> got to check it out. See? And I say,
>> got to check it out. See? And I say, "Check it out and then leave."
"Check it out and then leave."
"Check it out and then leave." >> Okay,
>> Okay,
>> Okay, >> now you know what it is. Leave it. Yeah.
>> now you know what it is. Leave it. Yeah.
>> now you know what it is. Leave it. Yeah. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> You're doing well. Just, you know,
>> You're doing well. Just, you know,
>> You're doing well. Just, you know, you're checking it all out.
you're checking it all out.
you're checking it all out. >> I think I'm sure. Yes.
>> I think I'm sure. Yes.
>> I think I'm sure. Yes. >> Thanks.
>> Thanks.
>> Thanks. >> You can't become a master until you're
>> You can't become a master until you're
>> You can't become a master until you're educated. And an educated master is
educated. And an educated master is
educated. And an educated master is probably been everywhere and tried it
probably been everywhere and tried it
probably been everywhere and tried it out. He got his foot caught in the bear
out. He got his foot caught in the bear
out. He got his foot caught in the bear trap. And that's why he knows not to put
trap. And that's why he knows not to put
trap. And that's why he knows not to put it there.
it there.
it there. That's it.
That's it.
That's it. >> Dr. I've been u trying my hand at muscle
>> Dr. I've been u trying my hand at muscle
>> Dr. I've been u trying my hand at muscle testing since listening to your tapes
testing since listening to your tapes
testing since listening to your tapes and going to some
and going to some
and going to some >> some of your seminars. And uh one
>> some of your seminars. And uh one
>> some of your seminars. And uh one curious thing I picked up that I haven't
curious thing I picked up that I haven't
curious thing I picked up that I haven't heard of and I don't know whether I'm
heard of and I don't know whether I'm
heard of and I don't know whether I'm just making it up or not is uh in
just making it up or not is uh in
just making it up or not is uh in calibrating people I have um found that
calibrating people I have um found that
calibrating people I have um found that with people deeply immersed in a
with people deeply immersed in a
with people deeply immersed in a spiritual practice
spiritual practice
spiritual practice that I get uh different um readings um
that I get uh different um readings um
that I get uh different um readings um that I would call the uh spiritual
that I would call the uh spiritual
that I would call the uh spiritual tailwind effect. In other words, um the
tailwind effect. In other words, um the
tailwind effect. In other words, um the the deep immersion in the spiritual
the deep immersion in the spiritual
the deep immersion in the spiritual practice seems to create a higher level
practice seems to create a higher level
practice seems to create a higher level of consciousness in that person than is
of consciousness in that person than is
of consciousness in that person than is rooted in the person. And at times I I
rooted in the person. And at times I I
rooted in the person. And at times I I see the behavior of the person at the
see the behavior of the person at the
see the behavior of the person at the lower level and at the higher level.
lower level and at the higher level.
lower level and at the higher level. Wondering if that makes any sense at
Wondering if that makes any sense at
Wondering if that makes any sense at all.
all.
all. >> No.
>> All right. When you do kinesiology,
>> All right. When you do kinesiology, you have to be very specific about what
you have to be very specific about what
you have to be very specific about what you're holding in mind.
you're holding in mind.
you're holding in mind. Uh you have to be careful with the
Uh you have to be careful with the
Uh you have to be careful with the technique.
technique.
technique. You have to be very specific in what
You have to be very specific in what
You have to be very specific in what you're asking. In other words, I've
you're asking. In other words, I've
you're asking. In other words, I've calibrated monkeys and elephants to a
calibrated monkeys and elephants to a
calibrated monkeys and elephants to a couple at a couple different energies.
couple at a couple different energies.
couple at a couple different energies. And uh one time I was holding in mind
And uh one time I was holding in mind
And uh one time I was holding in mind the monkeys in Monkey Island who were
the monkeys in Monkey Island who were
the monkeys in Monkey Island who were having a good time and playing. Another
having a good time and playing. Another
having a good time and playing. Another time I was picturing monkeys out in
time I was picturing monkeys out in
time I was picturing monkeys out in South America.
South America.
South America. Uh, one time I was picturing an elephant
Uh, one time I was picturing an elephant
Uh, one time I was picturing an elephant with a how to on the back. So I learned
with a how to on the back. So I learned
with a how to on the back. So I learned I must use if I'm going to do image then
I must use if I'm going to do image then
I must use if I'm going to do image then I got to keep the same image
I got to keep the same image
I got to keep the same image comparatively
comparatively
comparatively and I have to be careful how I phrase
and I have to be careful how I phrase
and I have to be careful how I phrase the the question. If this person's level
the the question. If this person's level
the the question. If this person's level of consciousness is over so and so. So
of consciousness is over so and so. So
of consciousness is over so and so. So for consistency you have to keep
for consistency you have to keep
for consistency you have to keep consistent methodology.
consistent methodology.
consistent methodology. Now people process information
Now people process information
Now people process information differently. Some people are more
differently. Some people are more
differently. Some people are more visual, some are more auditory, some are
visual, some are more auditory, some are
visual, some are more auditory, some are more feeling people. So when I say uh
more feeling people. So when I say uh
more feeling people. So when I say uh calibrate your mother, they could be
calibrate your mother, they could be
calibrate your mother, they could be picturing mother holding homebaked
picturing mother holding homebaked
picturing mother holding homebaked bread. That's ideal mother. They could
bread. That's ideal mother. They could
bread. That's ideal mother. They could be picture mother when uh in a different
be picture mother when uh in a different
be picture mother when uh in a different mood when mother was angry at them. They
mood when mother was angry at them. They
mood when mother was angry at them. They could be picturing the ideal of
could be picturing the ideal of
could be picturing the ideal of motherism.
motherism.
motherism. So you have to be how mother felt,
So you have to be how mother felt,
So you have to be how mother felt, thought, felt, you know. So you've got
thought, felt, you know. So you've got
thought, felt, you know. So you've got to pretty much use the same modality
to pretty much use the same modality
to pretty much use the same modality predominantly.
predominantly.
predominantly. So I'm using today like conceptually
So I'm using today like conceptually
So I'm using today like conceptually conceptually where is the class of
conceptually where is the class of
conceptually where is the class of hippopotamus?
hippopotamus?
hippopotamus? Conceptually
Conceptually
Conceptually and I'm not picturing a hippopotamus.
and I'm not picturing a hippopotamus.
and I'm not picturing a hippopotamus. See now if I picture hippopotamus like
See now if I picture hippopotamus like
See now if I picture hippopotamus like this I might get a different calibration
this I might get a different calibration
this I might get a different calibration than if I'm picturing the hippopotamus
than if I'm picturing the hippopotamus
than if I'm picturing the hippopotamus in the zoo.
in the zoo.
in the zoo. So when you do it try to stick to the
So when you do it try to stick to the
So when you do it try to stick to the same prevailing modality
If you make it too complicated you won't
If you make it too complicated you won't get specific answers.
get specific answers.
get specific answers. You try to keep it simple. SP's not
You try to keep it simple. SP's not
You try to keep it simple. SP's not working too good.
working too good.
working too good. Okay.
Okay.
Okay. She use her own pen. Nobody use her own
She use her own pen. Nobody use her own
She use her own pen. Nobody use her own pen. Okie do. Thank you. I got one.
pen. Okie do. Thank you. I got one.
pen. Okie do. Thank you. I got one. Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. >> Yeah. No, I'm going to use this word.
>> Yeah. No, I'm going to use this word.
>> Yeah. No, I'm going to use this word. >> Question.
>> Question.
>> Question. >> Yes. some notes.
>> Yes. some notes.
>> Yes. some notes. >> So, while I'm answering it, I'll, you
>> So, while I'm answering it, I'll, you
>> So, while I'm answering it, I'll, you know, be happy to say thank
know, be happy to say thank
know, be happy to say thank >> Larry
>> Larry
>> Larry >> question on what's we've been what we've
>> question on what's we've been what we've
>> question on what's we've been what we've been hearing a lot about over the last
been hearing a lot about over the last
been hearing a lot about over the last few months is
few months is
few months is the Passion of the Christ, the movie.
the Passion of the Christ, the movie.
the Passion of the Christ, the movie. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Just out of curiosity, where would you
>> Just out of curiosity, where would you
>> Just out of curiosity, where would you think that would fall in as far as
think that would fall in as far as
think that would fall in as far as consciousness level?
consciousness level?
consciousness level? >> Um, did you say the movie?
>> Um, did you say the movie?
>> Um, did you say the movie? >> Yeah, the movie.
>> Yeah, the movie.
>> Yeah, the movie. >> All right. The intention. The intention
>> All right. The intention. The intention
>> All right. The intention. The intention behind it is at 490.
behind it is at 490.
behind it is at 490. His intention was 490. The product
His intention was 490. The product
His intention was 490. The product because of extensive
because of extensive
because of extensive overexposure I think to the downside the
overexposure I think to the downside the
overexposure I think to the downside the negative torture and all that. We all
negative torture and all that. We all
negative torture and all that. We all know that torture goes on in prisons. We
know that torture goes on in prisons. We
know that torture goes on in prisons. We don't have to witness it brought it down
don't have to witness it brought it down
don't have to witness it brought it down below 200. If you remove the torture
below 200. If you remove the torture
below 200. If you remove the torture then you've got a different thing. I
then you've got a different thing. I
then you've got a different thing. I never asked the we asked that. If the 10
never asked the we asked that. If the 10
never asked the we asked that. If the 10 minutes of torture is removed from uh
minutes of torture is removed from uh
minutes of torture is removed from uh the passion of the Christ, it jumps over
the passion of the Christ, it jumps over
the passion of the Christ, it jumps over 260, 300, 350, 380, 400,
260, 300, 350, 380, 400,
260, 300, 350, 380, 400, 395,
395,
395, 400. Okay. With the with the torture
400. Okay. With the with the torture
400. Okay. With the with the torture scene in it, it calibrates over 190,
scene in it, it calibrates over 190,
scene in it, it calibrates over 190, 195. See, so artistically,
but his intention was 490. is in he he
but his intention was 490. is in he he was integrous in his intention
was integrous in his intention
was integrous in his intention and then the artistic side came in
and then the artistic side came in
and then the artistic side came in and
and
and I think has too much of a traumatic
I think has too much of a traumatic
I think has too much of a traumatic impact
impact
impact traumatic impact.
traumatic impact.
traumatic impact. >> I agree. Thank you.
>> But his intention was certainly
>> But his intention was certainly at 490. Very good. Yes.
at 490. Very good. Yes.
at 490. Very good. Yes. Okay.
Okay.
Okay. >> Oh, no problem. We can sign and talk at
>> Oh, no problem. We can sign and talk at
>> Oh, no problem. We can sign and talk at the same time and ride a bicycle.
>> I afraid this is going to get out of the
>> I afraid this is going to get out of the way. I'm going to sign you in one
way. I'm going to sign you in one
way. I'm going to sign you in one second.
second.
second. >> Dr. Hawkins, when you test when you do
>> Dr. Hawkins, when you test when you do
>> Dr. Hawkins, when you test when you do kinesiology testing, are you testing the
kinesiology testing, are you testing the
kinesiology testing, are you testing the consciousness?
consciousness?
consciousness? >> I've asking a calibrated level of
>> I've asking a calibrated level of
>> I've asking a calibrated level of consciousness. Yes.
consciousness. Yes.
consciousness. Yes. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> I'm asking true or false.
>> I'm asking true or false.
>> I'm asking true or false. I'm saying true or not true or I'm
I'm saying true or not true or I'm
I'm saying true or not true or I'm holding a number in mind and I say this
holding a number in mind and I say this
holding a number in mind and I say this calibrates over like I just did you know
calibrates over like I just did you know
calibrates over like I just did you know >> right
>> right
>> right how how can you be sure that the the
how how can you be sure that the the
how how can you be sure that the the thoughts and the emotions aren't
thoughts and the emotions aren't
thoughts and the emotions aren't interfering
interfering
interfering >> how do you know that what
>> how do you know that what
>> how do you know that what >> how can you be sure the thoughts and the
>> how can you be sure the thoughts and the
>> how can you be sure the thoughts and the emotions of the person aren't
emotions of the person aren't
emotions of the person aren't interfering with or your thoughts and
interfering with or your thoughts and
interfering with or your thoughts and emotions aren't
emotions aren't
emotions aren't >> uh well that has nothing to do with it
>> uh well that has nothing to do with it
>> uh well that has nothing to do with it >> why
>> why
>> why You asked the fatal question.
You asked the fatal question.
You asked the fatal question. She said why?
She said why?
She said why? >> Yeah.
>> There is no answer to the question why
>> There is no answer to the question why >> it has. So thoughts and emotions don't
>> it has. So thoughts and emotions don't
>> it has. So thoughts and emotions don't change.
change.
change. >> It is that way. Why does a quirk float?
>> It is that way. Why does a quirk float?
>> It is that way. Why does a quirk float? Because it is that way.
Because it is that way.
Because it is that way. If I hold
If I hold
If I hold the actually the the explanation of
the actually the the explanation of
the actually the the explanation of advanced theoretical physics which I
advanced theoretical physics which I
advanced theoretical physics which I gave this morning answers it.
gave this morning answers it.
gave this morning answers it. We we go from the training or equations
We we go from the training or equations
We we go from the training or equations the potentiality
the potentiality
the potentiality of the wave function. We collapse it
of the wave function. We collapse it
of the wave function. We collapse it through the question
through the question
through the question to with who state in the universe. Say
to with who state in the universe. Say
to with who state in the universe. Say by collapsing the wave function then
by collapsing the wave function then
by collapsing the wave function then we go from potentiality into the
we go from potentiality into the
we go from potentiality into the actuality.
actuality.
actuality. So the consequence then depends on
So the consequence then depends on
So the consequence then depends on whether or not it has a reality.
whether or not it has a reality.
whether or not it has a reality. The kinesiologic test is not between yes
The kinesiologic test is not between yes
The kinesiologic test is not between yes and no. It's between yes and not yes. So
and no. It's between yes and not yes. So
and no. It's between yes and not yes. So I say this calibrates over 460. Yes.
I say this calibrates over 460. Yes.
I say this calibrates over 460. Yes. This calibrates over 465 with mil.
This calibrates over 465 with mil.
This calibrates over 465 with mil. Now, she doesn't have to know what I'm
Now, she doesn't have to know what I'm
Now, she doesn't have to know what I'm holding in mind because I have an
holding in mind because I have an
holding in mind because I have an audience. I verbalize it. All right.
audience. I verbalize it. All right.
audience. I verbalize it. All right. What I'm holding in mind calibrates over
What I'm holding in mind calibrates over
What I'm holding in mind calibrates over 485.
485.
485. 490.
490.
490. Well, mine calibrates at 490. I didn't
Well, mine calibrates at 490. I didn't
Well, mine calibrates at 490. I didn't tell her what that was.
tell her what that was.
tell her what that was. Bill 490 495.
Bill 490 495.
Bill 490 495. I didn't tell her what it was.
Do you know what it was? What it was?
Do you know what it was? What it was? No. Nobody knows what it was. I was only
No. Nobody knows what it was. I was only
No. Nobody knows what it was. I was only holding it silently in mind.
holding it silently in mind.
holding it silently in mind. I was holding the intention of the guy
I was holding the intention of the guy
I was holding the intention of the guy who created Passion of the Christ.
who created Passion of the Christ.
who created Passion of the Christ. Intention. What's his name?
Intention. What's his name?
Intention. What's his name? >> Mel Gibson.
>> Mel Gibson.
>> Mel Gibson. >> Huh?
>> Huh?
>> Huh? >> Mel Gibson.
>> Mel Gibson.
>> Mel Gibson. >> Mel. Yeah. Now, holy, what is this man's
>> Mel. Yeah. Now, holy, what is this man's
>> Mel. Yeah. Now, holy, what is this man's intent? This man's attention is over
intent? This man's attention is over
intent? This man's attention is over 480, 485, 490. It's right in there. She
480, 485, 490. It's right in there. She
480, 485, 490. It's right in there. She doesn't know what I'm holding.
>> So, would it be better not to have a
>> So, would it be better not to have a person not know what you're
person not know what you're
person not know what you're >> It doesn't make any difference whether
>> It doesn't make any difference whether
>> It doesn't make any difference whether they know or they don't know.
they know or they don't know.
they know or they don't know. Sometimes, because I like to share
Sometimes, because I like to share
Sometimes, because I like to share information with her, I'll say it out
information with her, I'll say it out
information with her, I'll say it out loud because she gets to know the answer
loud because she gets to know the answer
loud because she gets to know the answer the same time I do. At other times if
the same time I do. At other times if
the same time I do. At other times if it's something very very critical I may
it's something very very critical I may
it's something very very critical I may check it out silently first to make sure
check it out silently first to make sure
check it out silently first to make sure that there's absolutely no influence.
that there's absolutely no influence.
that there's absolutely no influence. >> Would you suggest
>> Would you suggest
>> Would you suggest >> it doesn't change but I want to make
>> it doesn't change but I want to make
>> it doesn't change but I want to make sure like I say
sure like I say
sure like I say no one can possibly experience their own
no one can possibly experience their own
no one can possibly experience their own death not possible
death not possible
death not possible though I may not tell her that first see
though I may not tell her that first see
though I may not tell her that first see I'm going to say what I'm holding in
I'm going to say what I'm holding in
I'm going to say what I'm holding in mind is true I get true then she'll say
mind is true I get true then she'll say
mind is true I get true then she'll say what was that and
Okay, thank you.
Okay, thank you. >> You can't experience your own death
>> You can't experience your own death
>> You can't experience your own death because you're not there to experience
because you're not there to experience
because you're not there to experience it, you know? It's ridiculous.
it, you know? It's ridiculous.
it, you know? It's ridiculous. Like you left the theater, how would you
Like you left the theater, how would you
Like you left the theater, how would you know it's playing on the screen, you
know it's playing on the screen, you
know it's playing on the screen, you know?
>> Yeah. Actually, uh, is this your book?
>> Yeah. Actually, uh, is this your book? Oh, okay. That's you just answered my
Oh, okay. That's you just answered my
Oh, okay. That's you just answered my question and I had a few, but I come up
question and I had a few, but I come up
question and I had a few, but I come up with another one that I'm here.
with another one that I'm here.
with another one that I'm here. Um
Um
Um in your
in your
in your uh practices is there anything uh
uh practices is there anything uh
uh practices is there anything uh exercise technique method of meditation
exercise technique method of meditation
exercise technique method of meditation that you found particularly helpful for
that you found particularly helpful for
that you found particularly helpful for specifically working on raising one's
specifically working on raising one's
specifically working on raising one's consciousness
consciousness
consciousness more effective than
more effective than
more effective than others are
others are
others are >> well um
>> well um
>> well um meditation is a whole subject in itself
meditation is a whole subject in itself
meditation is a whole subject in itself I'll give you a very
I'll give you a very
I'll give you a very >> simple Simple one.
>> simple Simple one.
>> simple Simple one. I'm suspicious of alder styles of
I'm suspicious of alder styles of
I'm suspicious of alder styles of breathing and physiologic manipulation.
breathing and physiologic manipulation.
breathing and physiologic manipulation. Hyperventilation,
Hyperventilation,
Hyperventilation, one nostril, the other nostril. To me,
one nostril, the other nostril. To me,
one nostril, the other nostril. To me, those are all distortions.
those are all distortions.
those are all distortions. What are those are? Are attempts at an
What are those are? Are attempts at an
What are those are? Are attempts at an altered state of consciousness. An
altered state of consciousness. An
altered state of consciousness. An altered state is not the same as a
altered state is not the same as a
altered state is not the same as a spiritual state. Alpha training is not
spiritual state. Alpha training is not
spiritual state. Alpha training is not the same as a spontaneous spiritual
the same as a spontaneous spiritual
the same as a spontaneous spiritual eulgence. Those are altered states of
eulgence. Those are altered states of
eulgence. Those are altered states of consciousness. You can train it with bow
consciousness. You can train it with bow
consciousness. You can train it with bow feedback.
feedback.
feedback. And some yoga techniques are really just
And some yoga techniques are really just
And some yoga techniques are really just attempts at altered states of
attempts at altered states of
attempts at altered states of consciousness.
A very simple way to meditate is to
A very simple way to meditate is to close your eyes, look straight ahead.
close your eyes, look straight ahead.
close your eyes, look straight ahead. And if you close your eyes and look
And if you close your eyes and look
And if you close your eyes and look straight ahead, you'll see tiny little
straight ahead, you'll see tiny little
straight ahead, you'll see tiny little specks of light on the inside of the
specks of light on the inside of the
specks of light on the inside of the eyelids. If I look, if I close them
eyelids. If I look, if I close them
eyelids. If I look, if I close them right now, it's like you see
right now, it's like you see
right now, it's like you see multicolored very tiny little specks.
multicolored very tiny little specks.
multicolored very tiny little specks. Those are called fos jeans.
If you just look ahead into the field,
If you just look ahead into the field, which you could do anytime except when
which you could do anytime except when
which you could do anytime except when you're driving,
you're driving,
you're driving, although some people do it when they're
although some people do it when they're
although some people do it when they're driving,
and merely focus ahead on those lights
and merely focus ahead on those lights in front of you. Okay? If you want, you
in front of you. Okay? If you want, you
in front of you. Okay? If you want, you can watch your breathing. All right.
can watch your breathing. All right.
can watch your breathing. All right. Now, as you do this, I already told you
Now, as you do this, I already told you
Now, as you do this, I already told you this morning, the mind is 99% silent.
this morning, the mind is 99% silent.
this morning, the mind is 99% silent. So, you watch images and thoughts, and
So, you watch images and thoughts, and
So, you watch images and thoughts, and you let go.
You let go the intention that's
You let go the intention that's propagating them. As soon as you discern
propagating them. As soon as you discern
propagating them. As soon as you discern what it is,
You watch as the thought arises and you
You watch as the thought arises and you see that it arises out of nothing. All
see that it arises out of nothing. All
see that it arises out of nothing. All right? So let's say if you want to
right? So let's say if you want to
right? So let's say if you want to visualize how it happens,
visualize how it happens,
visualize how it happens, thoughts are like flying fish coming
thoughts are like flying fish coming
thoughts are like flying fish coming right shooting out of the sea. If you've
right shooting out of the sea. If you've
right shooting out of the sea. If you've ever been in the Saraso sea or I forget
ever been in the Saraso sea or I forget
ever been in the Saraso sea or I forget what sea it was in where you're in and
what sea it was in where you're in and
what sea it was in where you're in and the fish fly out of the water and then
the fish fly out of the water and then
the fish fly out of the water and then landing on the deck. Yeah. Well, this
landing on the deck. Yeah. Well, this
landing on the deck. Yeah. Well, this fish is not causing this fish to fly out
fish is not causing this fish to fly out
fish is not causing this fish to fly out of the water.
of the water.
of the water. The water is still unclear and clear,
The water is still unclear and clear,
The water is still unclear and clear, but out of it comes here a fish and here
but out of it comes here a fish and here
but out of it comes here a fish and here a fish and here a fish. And that's the
a fish and here a fish. And that's the
a fish and here a fish. And that's the way thoughts are. Till instead of
way thoughts are. Till instead of
way thoughts are. Till instead of focusing on the fish, you focus on the
focusing on the fish, you focus on the
focusing on the fish, you focus on the water.
water.
water. Just prior to the beginning of of a
Just prior to the beginning of of a
Just prior to the beginning of of a thought is a silent sea out of which the
thought is a silent sea out of which the
thought is a silent sea out of which the thought arises. You can
thought arises. You can
thought arises. You can you can catch the thought earlier and
you can catch the thought earlier and
you can catch the thought earlier and earlier in the process of formation. And
earlier in the process of formation. And
earlier in the process of formation. And I'll tell you a little exercise that
I'll tell you a little exercise that
I'll tell you a little exercise that shows how it works. Ordinarily, when
shows how it works. Ordinarily, when
shows how it works. Ordinarily, when you're riding in a car, your eyes,
you're riding in a car, your eyes,
you're riding in a car, your eyes, you'll watch. If you're a passenger,
you'll watch. If you're a passenger,
you'll watch. If you're a passenger, your eye shoots the head to the
your eye shoots the head to the
your eye shoots the head to the telephone pole, tracks the telephone
telephone pole, tracks the telephone
telephone pole, tracks the telephone pole, then it shoots the head to a tree,
pole, then it shoots the head to a tree,
pole, then it shoots the head to a tree, tracks the tree, then it shoots the head
tracks the tree, then it shoots the head
tracks the tree, then it shoots the head to a house, tracks the house, then it
to a house, tracks the house, then it
to a house, tracks the house, then it shoots the head to a billboard, tracks
shoots the head to a billboard, tracks
shoots the head to a billboard, tracks the billboard. There's another way of
the billboard. There's another way of
the billboard. There's another way of doing it. Draw a circle in the pedi in
doing it. Draw a circle in the pedi in
doing it. Draw a circle in the pedi in the uh
the uh
the uh right front window. What do you call it?
right front window. What do you call it?
right front window. What do you call it? Pedestrian seat. No, the drast seat. And
Pedestrian seat. No, the drast seat. And
Pedestrian seat. No, the drast seat. And you watch through the this port hole.
you watch through the this port hole.
you watch through the this port hole. Now you see the things flicking by. You
Now you see the things flicking by. You
Now you see the things flicking by. You see how those are flicking by? You're
see how those are flicking by? You're
see how those are flicking by? You're not tracking anything. You can't track
not tracking anything. You can't track
not tracking anything. You can't track it. It's just foaming by here. You
it. It's just foaming by here. You
it. It's just foaming by here. You become attached to it. You juice it for
become attached to it. You juice it for
become attached to it. You juice it for interest. Here you get attached to it.
interest. Here you get attached to it.
interest. Here you get attached to it. You juice it. Now it's like in a squeeze
You juice it. Now it's like in a squeeze
You juice it. Now it's like in a squeeze lemon. and you let it go, it's not
lemon. and you let it go, it's not
lemon. and you let it go, it's not interesting anymore. Now you see a dog
interesting anymore. Now you see a dog
interesting anymore. Now you see a dog house up there. You're constantly
house up there. You're constantly
house up there. You're constantly squeezing interest out of everything.
squeezing interest out of everything.
squeezing interest out of everything. If you focus just through this the side
If you focus just through this the side
If you focus just through this the side window now, you can't juice anything.
window now, you can't juice anything.
window now, you can't juice anything. You have to let it go as fast as it
You have to let it go as fast as it
You have to let it go as fast as it arises. So you learn to witness without
arises. So you learn to witness without
arises. So you learn to witness without becoming attached, without beginning to
becoming attached, without beginning to
becoming attached, without beginning to seek and clutch and pull and juice out
seek and clutch and pull and juice out
seek and clutch and pull and juice out of it interest, excitement, novelty.
of it interest, excitement, novelty.
of it interest, excitement, novelty. And you'll see that your mind is
And you'll see that your mind is
And you'll see that your mind is addicted to novelty and entertainment.
addicted to novelty and entertainment.
addicted to novelty and entertainment. That your thoughts are a form of
That your thoughts are a form of
That your thoughts are a form of entertainment. Your little private TV
entertainment. Your little private TV
entertainment. Your little private TV set in your head.
All right. So, as you do this, you see
All right. So, as you do this, you see you're constantly surrendering it to
you're constantly surrendering it to
you're constantly surrendering it to God.
God.
God. Could would I be willing to surrender
Could would I be willing to surrender
Could would I be willing to surrender this to God? Could I let go my
this to God? Could I let go my
this to God? Could I let go my carnivorous interest in eating up all
carnivorous interest in eating up all
carnivorous interest in eating up all these little morsels of juicy interest
these little morsels of juicy interest
these little morsels of juicy interest and novelty and self- amusement, self a
and novelty and self- amusement, self a
and novelty and self- amusement, self a grandisman
grandisman
grandisman and scaring myself about the future and
and scaring myself about the future and
and scaring myself about the future and squeezing anguish and guilt and remorse
squeezing anguish and guilt and remorse
squeezing anguish and guilt and remorse out of the past.
out of the past.
out of the past. Poor old Rover and how he got run over
Poor old Rover and how he got run over
Poor old Rover and how he got run over and how we all cried and we couldn't eat
and how we all cried and we couldn't eat
and how we all cried and we couldn't eat our dinner and
our dinner and
our dinner and give up already. You know what I mean?
You begin to get the feelingness of
You begin to get the feelingness of surrenderingness, not as a specific
surrenderingness, not as a specific
surrenderingness, not as a specific conceptual
conceptual
conceptual form, but the feelingness of letting go.
form, but the feelingness of letting go.
form, but the feelingness of letting go. And you be you merge with the
And you be you merge with the
And you be you merge with the you merge with the context. You become
you merge with the context. You become
you merge with the context. You become the context in which all of this is
the context in which all of this is
the context in which all of this is happening. And as you merge with the
happening. And as you merge with the
happening. And as you merge with the context, you'll feel
context, you'll feel
context, you'll feel as though your mind is expanded out into
as though your mind is expanded out into
as though your mind is expanded out into space.
At first, it's like your mind is in your
At first, it's like your mind is in your head, but then your mind will go out and
head, but then your mind will go out and
head, but then your mind will go out and merge with the totality of the context.
Then knowingness begins to present to
Then knowingness begins to present to you belief systems
you belief systems
you belief systems that you have to be willing to let go.
So it's a presentation then one thing
So it's a presentation then one thing after another. Would I be willing to
after another. Would I be willing to
after another. Would I be willing to surrender how I'm seeing this and let
surrender how I'm seeing this and let
surrender how I'm seeing this and let God show me how it is? You know, so
God show me how it is? You know, so
God show me how it is? You know, so in the end uh meditation I say is like a
in the end uh meditation I say is like a
in the end uh meditation I say is like a mudra. Actually,
mudra. Actually,
mudra. Actually, I don't believe in meditation
I don't believe in meditation
I don't believe in meditation specifically much because it takes you
specifically much because it takes you
specifically much because it takes you out of the world. And I said, well, I
out of the world. And I said, well, I
out of the world. And I said, well, I didn't have time to meditate today. No,
didn't have time to meditate today. No,
didn't have time to meditate today. No, I didn't have time to meditate today.
I didn't have time to meditate today.
I didn't have time to meditate today. So, what happens with meditation, except
So, what happens with meditation, except
So, what happens with meditation, except unless you're very dedicated and do it,
unless you're very dedicated and do it,
unless you're very dedicated and do it, you know, an hour in the morning, an
you know, an hour in the morning, an
you know, an hour in the morning, an hour at night for 20 years like some
hour at night for 20 years like some
hour at night for 20 years like some people I know, but the average person
people I know, but the average person
people I know, but the average person will do it, you know, interestedly, they
will do it, you know, interestedly, they
will do it, you know, interestedly, they do a workshop on it. They'll do it, you
do a workshop on it. They'll do it, you
do a workshop on it. They'll do it, you know, for a couple months and then it'll
know, for a couple months and then it'll
know, for a couple months and then it'll fall by the wayside. You say uh you
fall by the wayside. You say uh you
fall by the wayside. You say uh you started doing the course of miracles
started doing the course of miracles
started doing the course of miracles last year. Uh how you how's it going? I
last year. Uh how you how's it going? I
last year. Uh how you how's it going? I don't know. I got the 130 and I quit.
don't know. I got the 130 and I quit.
don't know. I got the 130 and I quit. It hasn't become part of you. So you try
It hasn't become part of you. So you try
It hasn't become part of you. So you try to adopt the style that is part of you.
to adopt the style that is part of you.
to adopt the style that is part of you. The real meditation is
The real meditation is
The real meditation is is the more like a mudra. Now real
is the more like a mudra. Now real
is the more like a mudra. Now real meditation is like a posture of
meditation is like a posture of
meditation is like a posture of supplication to God.
supplication to God.
supplication to God. This is how I am. This is how I witness.
This is how I am. This is how I witness.
This is how I am. This is how I witness. This is how I experience.
This is how I experience.
This is how I experience. But it's like
But it's like
But it's like it's like a supplication to the Holy
it's like a supplication to the Holy
it's like a supplication to the Holy Spirit to recontextualize
Spirit to recontextualize
Spirit to recontextualize and show it back to you how it is.
with your hands are up asking, "Yes, but
with your hands are up asking, "Yes, but how is it in reality? I know how you see
how is it in reality? I know how you see
how is it in reality? I know how you see it." Hey,
it." Hey,
it." Hey, so a mudra is a hand position. You know,
so a mudra is a hand position. You know,
so a mudra is a hand position. You know, in classic uh spirituality,
in classic uh spirituality,
in classic uh spirituality, uh it's a way of being of presenting of
uh it's a way of being of presenting of
uh it's a way of being of presenting of presenting your existence to divinity.
presenting your existence to divinity.
presenting your existence to divinity. It's a way of being with divinity at all
It's a way of being with divinity at all
It's a way of being with divinity at all times to always be in a state of
times to always be in a state of
times to always be in a state of supplication.
supplication.
supplication. To thee, oh Lord,
To thee, oh Lord,
To thee, oh Lord, I present what I am now, what I think I
I present what I am now, what I think I
I present what I am now, what I think I am now. But it's always with a slight
am now. But it's always with a slight
am now. But it's always with a slight question mark. And then the spirit
question mark. And then the spirit
question mark. And then the spirit answers you and reveals to you and you
answers you and reveals to you and you
answers you and reveals to you and you say, "Oh, I see. So, so and you may walk
say, "Oh, I see. So, so and you may walk
say, "Oh, I see. So, so and you may walk around with it for a couple days and
around with it for a couple days and
around with it for a couple days and then suddenly and then you say the heck
then suddenly and then you say the heck
then suddenly and then you say the heck with it. God's not going to give me an
with it. God's not going to give me an
with it. God's not going to give me an answer anyway."
answer anyway."
answer anyway." >> And then instantly you got the answer.
That you're holding a negative view of
That you're holding a negative view of God is the great stingy. Oh yeah. The
God is the great stingy. Oh yeah. The
God is the great stingy. Oh yeah. The great stingy one.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Well, give me what I want when I want
>> Well, give me what I want when I want
>> Well, give me what I want when I want it.
it.
it. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Thank you for the opportunity.
>> Thank you for the opportunity.
>> Thank you for the opportunity. It's a way of being. You see, when your
It's a way of being. You see, when your
It's a way of being. You see, when your life is a prayer, then your life becomes
life is a prayer, then your life becomes
life is a prayer, then your life becomes a supplication.
a supplication.
a supplication. You know, like your life becomes the
You know, like your life becomes the
You know, like your life becomes the prayer of St. Francis of Aisi.
prayer of St. Francis of Aisi.
prayer of St. Francis of Aisi. He's saying, "Lord, let me be a channel
He's saying, "Lord, let me be a channel
He's saying, "Lord, let me be a channel of thy knowingness, thy will, thy love,
of thy knowingness, thy will, thy love,
of thy knowingness, thy will, thy love, thy healing, all the attributes of
thy healing, all the attributes of
thy healing, all the attributes of divinity. Let me be thy reflection, oh
divinity. Let me be thy reflection, oh
divinity. Let me be thy reflection, oh Lord, for I am thy servant."
Lord, for I am thy servant."
Lord, for I am thy servant." To be a servant of the Lord is
>> Are you ready for me, Dr. Hawkins?
>> Are you ready for me, Dr. Hawkins? >> Uh, may I ask you a question?
>> Uh, may I ask you a question?
>> Uh, may I ask you a question? >> Yes. Okay.
>> Yes. Okay.
>> Yes. Okay. >> Thanks for the honor of sitting with
>> Thanks for the honor of sitting with
>> Thanks for the honor of sitting with you. um have a question regarding um the
you. um have a question regarding um the
you. um have a question regarding um the I guess the rise of terrorist activity u
I guess the rise of terrorist activity u
I guess the rise of terrorist activity u projected on I guess many western
projected on I guess many western
projected on I guess many western nations
nations
nations particularly the US the terrorist
particularly the US the terrorist
particularly the US the terrorist activity and the uh
activity and the uh
activity and the uh >> yes
>> yes
>> yes >> the range of responses that have been
>> the range of responses that have been
>> the range of responses that have been taken and then are being I guess um
taken and then are being I guess um
taken and then are being I guess um developed to counter the terrorist
developed to counter the terrorist
developed to counter the terrorist activity
activity
activity >> uh aside from
>> uh aside from
>> uh aside from us There's a
us There's a
us There's a mass human consciousness elevating our
mass human consciousness elevating our
mass human consciousness elevating our overall consciousness to kind of counter
overall consciousness to kind of counter
overall consciousness to kind of counter that to bring everybody up as you
that to bring everybody up as you
that to bring everybody up as you mentioned and bring the whole sea up.
mentioned and bring the whole sea up.
mentioned and bring the whole sea up. There's been a range of military
There's been a range of military
There's been a range of military responses and other I guess survival
responses and other I guess survival
responses and other I guess survival protective measures.
protective measures.
protective measures. >> Yeah. what's really appropriate here
>> Yeah. what's really appropriate here
>> Yeah. what's really appropriate here with poor mankind's consciousness is now
with poor mankind's consciousness is now
with poor mankind's consciousness is now to ensure that we survive um you know as
to ensure that we survive um you know as
to ensure that we survive um you know as a US and another western nation
a US and another western nation
a US and another western nation >> well you use kinesiology and you check
>> well you use kinesiology and you check
>> well you use kinesiology and you check out all the possible responses and see
out all the possible responses and see
out all the possible responses and see which one is the highest
which one is the highest
which one is the highest >> I mean that's the way I do it as a
>> I mean that's the way I do it as a
>> I mean that's the way I do it as a research project
research project
research project >> right
>> right
>> right >> see the downside of spirituality is
>> see the downside of spirituality is
>> see the downside of spirituality is denial
denial
denial uh it's a spiritual error to be stupid
uh it's a spiritual error to be stupid
uh it's a spiritual error to be stupid and blindsided,
and blindsided,
and blindsided, >> right?
>> right?
>> right? >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Yes, it is.
>> Yes, it is.
>> Yes, it is. >> You can't say because I'm spiritual, I'm
>> You can't say because I'm spiritual, I'm
>> You can't say because I'm spiritual, I'm not responsible for, you know, not
not responsible for, you know, not
not responsible for, you know, not protecting my family and they're now
protecting my family and they're now
protecting my family and they're now dead,
dead,
dead, >> right?
>> right?
>> right? >> And now that's not an excuse. Ignorance
>> And now that's not an excuse. Ignorance
>> And now that's not an excuse. Ignorance of the law is no excuse even on the
of the law is no excuse even on the
of the law is no excuse even on the level of the law. Ignorance of the law
level of the law. Ignorance of the law
level of the law. Ignorance of the law is no excuse. People tend to get into a
is no excuse. People tend to get into a
is no excuse. People tend to get into a sentimentalizing
sentimentalizing
sentimentalizing and fantasizing and imaginative
and fantasizing and imaginative
and fantasizing and imaginative spirituality
spirituality
spirituality that you have to be walking around with
that you have to be walking around with
that you have to be walking around with your hands folded, singing hsms, not eat
your hands folded, singing hsms, not eat
your hands folded, singing hsms, not eat meat, etc., not have sex, etc.
meat, etc., not have sex, etc.
meat, etc., not have sex, etc. No, you have to be a real life human
No, you have to be a real life human
No, you have to be a real life human being and you have to be all use all
being and you have to be all use all
being and you have to be all use all your faculties
your faculties
your faculties because truth is um quite a requirement.
because truth is um quite a requirement.
because truth is um quite a requirement. Truth to live a life of truth is
Truth to live a life of truth is
Truth to live a life of truth is demanding demanding and cowardliness no
demanding demanding and cowardliness no
demanding demanding and cowardliness no matter how pious you make it sound is
matter how pious you make it sound is
matter how pious you make it sound is still cowardice. Mhm.
still cowardice. Mhm.
still cowardice. Mhm. >> Z,
>> could you uh calibrate the current US
>> could you uh calibrate the current US administration's response to the
administration's response to the
administration's response to the terrorist activities?
terrorist activities?
terrorist activities? >> You're going to be disappointed.
>> You're going to be disappointed.
>> You're going to be disappointed. Unfortunately,
Unfortunately,
Unfortunately, >> are you prepared to be disappointed?
>> are you prepared to be disappointed?
>> are you prepared to be disappointed? >> Yeah, let's hear
>> Yeah, let's hear
>> Yeah, let's hear >> about 460.
>> about 460.
>> about 460. >> I'm not disappointed. That's kind of
>> I'm not disappointed. That's kind of
>> I'm not disappointed. That's kind of what I thought.
what I thought.
what I thought. >> The calibration level of the presidency
>> The calibration level of the presidency
>> The calibration level of the presidency of the United States has consistently
of the United States has consistently
of the United States has consistently been around 460.
been around 460.
been around 460. You can't really handle the office
You can't really handle the office
You can't really handle the office unless you're 450 or 460. So the office
unless you're 450 or 460. So the office
unless you're 450 or 460. So the office has certain requirements
has certain requirements
has certain requirements >> to fulfill that office. Don't forget you
>> to fulfill that office. Don't forget you
>> to fulfill that office. Don't forget you then take an oath
then take an oath
then take an oath >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> on the Bible. You swear by God that you
>> on the Bible. You swear by God that you
>> on the Bible. You swear by God that you will protect the people of the United
will protect the people of the United
will protect the people of the United States from all aggressors. So help me
States from all aggressors. So help me
States from all aggressors. So help me God.
God.
God. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> You say this in front of the Chief
>> You say this in front of the Chief
>> You say this in front of the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court and put
Justice of the Supreme Court and put
Justice of the Supreme Court and put your hand in the Bible.
your hand in the Bible.
your hand in the Bible. That's quite an oath.
That's quite an oath.
That's quite an oath. And it doesn't mean that you can't be
And it doesn't mean that you can't be
And it doesn't mean that you can't be mistaken. You can be mistaken. See, 460
mistaken. You can be mistaken. See, 460
mistaken. You can be mistaken. See, 460 is not saintthood,
is not saintthood,
is not saintthood, nor is it Einstein. 460 means to be able
nor is it Einstein. 460 means to be able
nor is it Einstein. 460 means to be able to fulfill the obligation to your oath
to fulfill the obligation to your oath
to fulfill the obligation to your oath to the highest degree. So
to the highest degree. So
to the highest degree. So people in the Supreme Court do the same
people in the Supreme Court do the same
people in the Supreme Court do the same thing. You see, now people in the
thing. You see, now people in the
thing. You see, now people in the Supreme Court generally calibrates
Supreme Court generally calibrates
Supreme Court generally calibrates around fore.
around fore.
around fore. But as we what as we were saying this
But as we what as we were saying this
But as we what as we were saying this morning, how could the Supreme Court
morning, how could the Supreme Court
morning, how could the Supreme Court rule on this taking God out of the or
rule on this taking God out of the or
rule on this taking God out of the or religious or whatever when they don't
religious or whatever when they don't
religious or whatever when they don't understand the difference between
understand the difference between
understand the difference between religion and spirituality and that's the
religion and spirituality and that's the
religion and spirituality and that's the crux of the whole argument. Mhm.
crux of the whole argument. Mhm.
crux of the whole argument. Mhm. >> You got a Supreme Court at 460. You got
>> You got a Supreme Court at 460. You got
>> You got a Supreme Court at 460. You got a smart guy at 400 as something. And
a smart guy at 400 as something. And
a smart guy at 400 as something. And neither one of knows the critical issue
neither one of knows the critical issue
neither one of knows the critical issue that's even central to the decision.
that's even central to the decision.
that's even central to the decision. The constitution protects us from
The constitution protects us from
The constitution protects us from religion and by so doing allows us the
religion and by so doing allows us the
religion and by so doing allows us the freedom of spirituality.
freedom of spirituality.
freedom of spirituality. So if our rights come by divine
So if our rights come by divine
So if our rights come by divine by virtue of the divinity of our
by virtue of the divinity of our
by virtue of the divinity of our creation, they cannot be removed.
creation, they cannot be removed.
creation, they cannot be removed. They're irrefutable.
They're irrefutable.
They're irrefutable. If in a secular government they don't
If in a secular government they don't
If in a secular government they don't come from
come from
come from the source of existence itself, then
the source of existence itself, then
the source of existence itself, then they only come by vote of your fellow
they only come by vote of your fellow
they only come by vote of your fellow man. You can remove many times.
man. You can remove many times.
man. You can remove many times. I'd rather have my rights come by virtue
I'd rather have my rights come by virtue
I'd rather have my rights come by virtue of the divinity of my creator
of the divinity of my creator
of the divinity of my creator where they can never be refuted rather
where they can never be refuted rather
where they can never be refuted rather than by the vote of a fellow man. They
than by the vote of a fellow man. They
than by the vote of a fellow man. They elect somebody new and I'm voted out of
elect somebody new and I'm voted out of
elect somebody new and I'm voted out of office. All my rights are voted out of
office. All my rights are voted out of
office. All my rights are voted out of office.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> So it calls upon the highest. Now there
>> So it calls upon the highest. Now there
>> So it calls upon the highest. Now there are dilemas in the world that you cannot
are dilemas in the world that you cannot
are dilemas in the world that you cannot handle at 460.
handle at 460.
handle at 460. 460 will get you through the great books
460 will get you through the great books
460 will get you through the great books of the western world.
of the western world.
of the western world. But there are other things other than
But there are other things other than
But there are other things other than the integrity of the government. So what
the integrity of the government. So what
the integrity of the government. So what the what's being revealed now is that
the what's being revealed now is that
the what's being revealed now is that not only this administration but the
not only this administration but the
not only this administration but the previous administration hands were tied.
You remember the Taurus Valley principal
You remember the Taurus Valley principal when it became law. You remember the
when it became law. You remember the
when it became law. You remember the Church Pike Committee hearings?
Church Pike Committee hearings?
Church Pike Committee hearings? So the intelligence department was
So the intelligence department was
So the intelligence department was crippled 20 years ago. Yeah.
crippled 20 years ago. Yeah.
crippled 20 years ago. Yeah. And it lost funding. It lost We're the
And it lost funding. It lost We're the
And it lost funding. It lost We're the only country in the world that doesn't
only country in the world that doesn't
only country in the world that doesn't have an elaborate espionage system even
have an elaborate espionage system even
have an elaborate espionage system even during peace time. Countries like
during peace time. Countries like
during peace time. Countries like France, Spain, they they've got a
France, Spain, they they've got a
France, Spain, they they've got a million spies out there. Are you going
million spies out there. Are you going
million spies out there. Are you going to blindside them? Not likely.
Huh?
Huh? Our country calibrates at 421.
Our country calibrates at 421.
Our country calibrates at 421. The UN calibrates by intention at 204
The UN calibrates by intention at 204
The UN calibrates by intention at 204 operationally about 195.
operationally about 195.
operationally about 195. So you want to turn a country at 421
So you want to turn a country at 421
So you want to turn a country at 421 to the governance of a committee that
to the governance of a committee that
to the governance of a committee that calibrates at 195? I don't think so.
calibrates at 195? I don't think so.
calibrates at 195? I don't think so. >> Well, that's what I'd felt. I just
>> Well, that's what I'd felt. I just
>> Well, that's what I'd felt. I just wondered what your perceptions were on
wondered what your perceptions were on
wondered what your perceptions were on what the truth. Well, the way you the
what the truth. Well, the way you the
what the truth. Well, the way you the way you kill a thing is you turn it over
way you kill a thing is you turn it over
way you kill a thing is you turn it over to committee. Everybody any businessman
to committee. Everybody any businessman
to committee. Everybody any businessman knows that.
To me, the UN is the ultimate committee.
To me, the UN is the ultimate committee. >> No, you you're you pretty much
with sovereignty goes rights, but with
with sovereignty goes rights, but with sovereignty also goes obligations.
sovereignty also goes obligations.
sovereignty also goes obligations. I think that all the presidents frankly
I think that all the presidents frankly
I think that all the presidents frankly have done what they could do,
have done what they could do,
have done what they could do, but
but
but They're not saints. They're not Mother
They're not saints. They're not Mother
They're not saints. They're not Mother Teresa. Mother Teresa didn't end war on
Teresa. Mother Teresa didn't end war on
Teresa. Mother Teresa didn't end war on this planet either, did she?
this planet either, did she?
this planet either, did she? >> No happening.
>> No happening.
>> No happening. God bless her.
God bless her.
God bless her. >> So, Monday morning quarterbacking.
>> So, Monday morning quarterbacking.
>> So, Monday morning quarterbacking. You see, it's compassion for the
You see, it's compassion for the
You see, it's compassion for the limitations of the human mind. The human
limitations of the human mind. The human
limitations of the human mind. The human ego by its structure is unable to tell
ego by its structure is unable to tell
ego by its structure is unable to tell truth from falsehood.
truth from falsehood.
truth from falsehood. The human ego is like the hardware of a
The human ego is like the hardware of a
The human ego is like the hardware of a computer. Society then puts in the
computer. Society then puts in the
computer. Society then puts in the software,
software,
software, but the hardware can't protect itself
but the hardware can't protect itself
but the hardware can't protect itself against whatever it's being programmed
against whatever it's being programmed
against whatever it's being programmed with.
You know, Socrates,
You know, Socrates, Socrates didn't believe, you know,
Socrates didn't believe, you know,
Socrates didn't believe, you know, criticized democracy.
criticized democracy.
criticized democracy. >> Socrates said that the difficulty with
>> Socrates said that the difficulty with
>> Socrates said that the difficulty with democracy is every idiot will not have a
democracy is every idiot will not have a
democracy is every idiot will not have a vote.
vote.
vote. Well, the uninformed, the unintelligent,
Well, the uninformed, the unintelligent,
Well, the uninformed, the unintelligent, and those who do not value or know the
and those who do not value or know the
and those who do not value or know the truth will have equal rights with those
truth will have equal rights with those
truth will have equal rights with those who do.
who do.
who do. >> Therefore, he believed in oligarchy.
>> Therefore, he believed in oligarchy.
>> Therefore, he believed in oligarchy. And oligarchy is rule by the few who are
And oligarchy is rule by the few who are
And oligarchy is rule by the few who are picked by virtue of their education,
picked by virtue of their education,
picked by virtue of their education, their wisdom, their integrity, and we'd
their wisdom, their integrity, and we'd
their wisdom, their integrity, and we'd calibrate their level of consciousness.
So, you'd only have the best cooks, the
So, you'd only have the best cooks, the best cooks in the kitchen.
best cooks in the kitchen.
best cooks in the kitchen. >> Now, anybody who's persuasive can get in
>> Now, anybody who's persuasive can get in
>> Now, anybody who's persuasive can get in the kitchen. But it takes more than
the kitchen. But it takes more than
the kitchen. But it takes more than persuasiveness and getting votes. It
persuasiveness and getting votes. It
persuasiveness and getting votes. It takes a profound integrity.
takes a profound integrity.
takes a profound integrity. >> Well, we saw that with President Truman.
>> Well, we saw that with President Truman.
>> Well, we saw that with President Truman. Remember the terrible, terrible problem
Remember the terrible, terrible problem
Remember the terrible, terrible problem he had?
he had?
he had? I don't envy any any of the presidents,
I don't envy any any of the presidents,
I don't envy any any of the presidents, but Truman I felt dissorious for
but Truman I felt dissorious for
but Truman I felt dissorious for >> because he had the problem of triage.
>> because he had the problem of triage.
>> because he had the problem of triage. You're going to allow six they estimated
You're going to allow six they estimated
You're going to allow six they estimated 7 million people will die if we invade
7 million people will die if we invade
7 million people will die if we invade Japan. They will fight to the last men.
Japan. They will fight to the last men.
Japan. They will fight to the last men. >> 7 million die. Or or
>> 7 million die. Or or
>> 7 million die. Or or you can pick out a population of
you can pick out a population of
you can pick out a population of 180,000.
180,000.
180,000. By killing 180,000, you save 7 million.
By killing 180,000, you save 7 million.
By killing 180,000, you save 7 million. That's called triage. Every physician
That's called triage. Every physician
That's called triage. Every physician faces this all the time.
faces this all the time.
faces this all the time. >> Yeah,
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, >> we faced it in the military. World War
>> we faced it in the military. World War
>> we faced it in the military. World War II.
II.
II. Two guys overboard. Are you going to
Two guys overboard. Are you going to
Two guys overboard. Are you going to turn back the ship right out of the
turn back the ship right out of the
turn back the ship right out of the middle of the fleet and pick up these
middle of the fleet and pick up these
middle of the fleet and pick up these two guys and risk the fleet?
two guys and risk the fleet?
two guys and risk the fleet? Can't.
Can't.
Can't. Unless you've been through war, you
Unless you've been through war, you
Unless you've been through war, you don't really understand triage. Unless
don't really understand triage. Unless
don't really understand triage. Unless you've been in the emergency room at the
you've been in the emergency room at the
you've been in the emergency room at the hospital at midnight on a Saturday night
hospital at midnight on a Saturday night
hospital at midnight on a Saturday night where they come in with ice picks in
where they come in with ice picks in
where they come in with ice picks in their head.
their head.
their head. Guy walks in. He's got an ice pick. I'm
Guy walks in. He's got an ice pick. I'm
Guy walks in. He's got an ice pick. I'm on duty on Saturday night in New York
on duty on Saturday night in New York
on duty on Saturday night in New York City. Belleville. Here's a guy with an
City. Belleville. Here's a guy with an
City. Belleville. Here's a guy with an ice pick in his head and it's coming out
ice pick in his head and it's coming out
ice pick in his head and it's coming out his other eye. You know what I'm saying?
Another guy was just in a subway
Another guy was just in a subway accident and his brain is squashed and
accident and his brain is squashed and
accident and his brain is squashed and the ER is already full to the top.
the ER is already full to the top.
the ER is already full to the top. So, which one are you going to let go?
So, which one are you going to let go?
So, which one are you going to let go? you do the ice pick guy, the other
you do the ice pick guy, the other
you do the ice pick guy, the other brain's
brain's
brain's going to swell up, hemorrhage, and he'll
going to swell up, hemorrhage, and he'll
going to swell up, hemorrhage, and he'll be dead. And if you do him, the guy with
be dead. And if you do him, the guy with
be dead. And if you do him, the guy with the ice pick, I'll have a sephilitis and
the ice pick, I'll have a sephilitis and
the ice pick, I'll have a sephilitis and affected brain and so and so tomorrow.
affected brain and so and so tomorrow.
affected brain and so and so tomorrow. So triage is something the American
So triage is something the American
So triage is something the American public doesn't understand.
public doesn't understand.
public doesn't understand. So people who criticize Truman's
So people who criticize Truman's
So people who criticize Truman's decision, they have no heart.
decision, they have no heart.
decision, they have no heart. They may come from smart smart but they
They may come from smart smart but they
They may come from smart smart but they have no heart because can you imagine
have no heart because can you imagine
have no heart because can you imagine the crushing horror that he went
the crushing horror that he went
the crushing horror that he went through? I always admired Truman that
through? I always admired Truman that
through? I always admired Truman that did that he ever he said boy that's a
did that he ever he said boy that's a
did that he ever he said boy that's a son of a but I made that decision
son of a but I made that decision
son of a but I made that decision and we all agonized with him. So I think
and we all agonized with him. So I think
and we all agonized with him. So I think what
what
what public officials and presidents and
public officials and presidents and
public officials and presidents and congressmen and all need is less
congressmen and all need is less
congressmen and all need is less criticism and more support.
criticism and more support.
criticism and more support. We say, you know, we know you got a hard
We say, you know, we know you got a hard
We say, you know, we know you got a hard job. This is how we all feel. You ought
job. This is how we all feel. You ought
job. This is how we all feel. You ought to see it.
to see it.
to see it. >> If we got behind these guys and
>> If we got behind these guys and
>> If we got behind these guys and supported them, we wouldn't push them
supported them, we wouldn't push them
supported them, we wouldn't push them into the terrible.
into the terrible.
into the terrible. See, politicians get pushed into this
See, politicians get pushed into this
See, politicians get pushed into this mutual vuperation. Who pushes them
mutual vuperation. Who pushes them
mutual vuperation. Who pushes them there? I'll tell you who pushes them
there? I'll tell you who pushes them
there? I'll tell you who pushes them there. The voter pushes them there.
there. The voter pushes them there.
there. The voter pushes them there. If we supported their integrity, said,
If we supported their integrity, said,
If we supported their integrity, said, you know, we want a wonderful person
you know, we want a wonderful person
you know, we want a wonderful person that we can love and care about and
that we can love and care about and
that we can love and care about and respect.
Do you ever hear people compliment the
Do you ever hear people compliment the the the people in charge?
the the people in charge?
the the people in charge? Dear Governor, you did a great job.
Dear Governor, you did a great job.
Dear Governor, you did a great job. Chief President, you did a great Did
Chief President, you did a great Did
Chief President, you did a great Did you? Yep.
you? Yep.
you? Yep. >> No, they're too busy.
>> No, they're too busy.
>> No, they're too busy. >> They take the heat.
>> They take the heat.
>> They take the heat. >> So the critic the critic is too busy.
>> So the critic the critic is too busy.
>> So the critic the critic is too busy. You see? Yeah. You can't become Walmarts
You see? Yeah. You can't become Walmarts
You see? Yeah. You can't become Walmarts without everybody hating you. Why is
without everybody hating you. Why is
without everybody hating you. Why is that? Huh?
that? Huh?
that? Huh? I know why Walmart became
I know why Walmart became
I know why Walmart became successful. because I you know I was a
successful. because I you know I was a
successful. because I you know I was a friend of Sams and we calibrated back
friend of Sams and we calibrated back
friend of Sams and we calibrated back and forth and I calibrated his level and
and forth and I calibrated his level and
and forth and I calibrated his level and I said what you know what attracted me
I said what you know what attracted me
I said what you know what attracted me was that you're going to run a big
was that you're going to run a big
was that you're going to run a big company based on integrity the
company based on integrity the
company based on integrity the principles of integrity I calibrated Sam
principles of integrity I calibrated Sam
principles of integrity I calibrated Sam and principles of integrity
and principles of integrity
and principles of integrity >> at the time they calibrated about 380
>> at the time they calibrated about 380
>> at the time they calibrated about 380 when Sam was alive you know
when Sam was alive you know
when Sam was alive you know what are what other companies going to
what are what other companies going to
what are what other companies going to give you your money back and operate on
give you your money back and operate on
give you your money back and operate on the lowest possible profit margin I mean
the lowest possible profit margin I mean
the lowest possible profit margin I mean Santa Claus other than Santa Claus I
Santa Claus other than Santa Claus I
Santa Claus other than Santa Claus I don't know who you know no sooner does
don't know who you know no sooner does
don't know who you know no sooner does it become successful because of its
it become successful because of its
it become successful because of its integrity that it starts becoming
integrity that it starts becoming
integrity that it starts becoming vilified. Yeah.
vilified. Yeah.
vilified. Yeah. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Who made Walmart successful?
>> People that bought our products.
>> People that bought our products. >> That's right. You and I.
>> That's right. You and I.
>> That's right. You and I. >> That's right.
>> That's right.
>> That's right. >> Well, you've got the integrity of the
>> Well, you've got the integrity of the
>> Well, you've got the integrity of the intention, but then you got the support
intention, but then you got the support
intention, but then you got the support of the people. S say what our
of the people. S say what our
of the people. S say what our politicians need is less vilification
politicians need is less vilification
politicians need is less vilification and more support, more compassion. It's
and more support, more compassion. It's
and more support, more compassion. It's a son of a gun of a job being a governor
a son of a gun of a job being a governor
a son of a gun of a job being a governor or being a mayor or
or being a mayor or
or being a mayor or >> or president.
>> or president.
>> or president. >> President any whose books are
>> President any whose books are
>> President any whose books are >> these are mine.
>> these are mine.
>> these are mine. >> Oh, those are yours.
>> Oh, those are yours.
>> Oh, those are yours. >> These are these are going to be my
>> These are these are going to be my
>> These are these are going to be my letter.
letter.
letter. >> And I think we should give them our
>> And I think we should give them our
>> And I think we should give them our compassion, our support, and our help.
compassion, our support, and our help.
compassion, our support, and our help. If we have helpful suggestions,
If we have helpful suggestions,
If we have helpful suggestions, you know, we send them helpful
you know, we send them helpful
you know, we send them helpful suggestions.
suggestions.
suggestions. >> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much. >> To make their job more successful.
>> To make their job more successful.
>> To make their job more successful. >> Yeah. Well, I think we should, you know,
>> Yeah. Well, I think we should, you know,
>> Yeah. Well, I think we should, you know, give more of our appreciation to these
give more of our appreciation to these
give more of our appreciation to these people unless of our vilification.
people unless of our vilification.
people unless of our vilification. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> What is it, you know, what it takes to
>> What is it, you know, what it takes to
>> What is it, you know, what it takes to be a critic? Nothing. Any idiot can be a
be a critic? Nothing. Any idiot can be a
be a critic? Nothing. Any idiot can be a critic.
critic.
critic. >> That takes no brains at all to be a
>> That takes no brains at all to be a
>> That takes no brains at all to be a critic.
critic.
critic. >> To be a supporter and say, you know, I
>> To be a supporter and say, you know, I
>> To be a supporter and say, you know, I appreciate the the risk and the energy
appreciate the the risk and the energy
appreciate the the risk and the energy you put into all this, you know.
you put into all this, you know.
you put into all this, you know. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Regarding the current presidential uh
Regarding the current presidential uh
Regarding the current presidential uh candidates uh Kerry and Nater and Bush,
candidates uh Kerry and Nater and Bush,
candidates uh Kerry and Nater and Bush, you were the calibration of Bush around
you were the calibration of Bush around
you were the calibration of Bush around 460. Do you have the calibrations of the
460. Do you have the calibrations of the
460. Do you have the calibrations of the other gentlemen?
other gentlemen?
other gentlemen? >> I didn't do them. Uh the other the
>> I didn't do them. Uh the other the
>> I didn't do them. Uh the other the others that were in the race I wasn't
others that were in the race I wasn't
others that were in the race I wasn't too enthused with one or two of them
too enthused with one or two of them
too enthused with one or two of them seemed pretty rattlerain to me.
seemed pretty rattlerain to me.
seemed pretty rattlerain to me. >> Yeah. Possible to do the calibration.
>> Yeah. Possible to do the calibration.
>> Yeah. Possible to do the calibration. And then there was one that I I think he
And then there was one that I I think he
And then there was one that I I think he dropped out really cuz he thought being
dropped out really cuz he thought being
dropped out really cuz he thought being Jewish he wouldn't get the vote. But he
Jewish he wouldn't get the vote. But he
Jewish he wouldn't get the vote. But he was integ.
>> Yeah. Another one. Got one seems sort of
>> Yeah. Another one. Got one seems sort of emotionally unstable. I thought he too
emotionally unstable. I thought he too
emotionally unstable. I thought he too wild a man. I don't want him at the
wild a man. I don't want him at the
wild a man. I don't want him at the tiller.
tiller.
tiller. >> Doctor Dr. Ding.
>> Doctor Dr. Ding.
>> Doctor Dr. Ding. >> I wouldn't want him at the tiller of my
>> I wouldn't want him at the tiller of my
>> I wouldn't want him at the tiller of my sailboat. You know what I mean?
sailboat. You know what I mean?
sailboat. You know what I mean? >> Sees a breeze coming hard over on the
>> Sees a breeze coming hard over on the
>> Sees a breeze coming hard over on the tiller. No thanks.
tiller. No thanks.
tiller. No thanks. Okay.
Okay.
Okay. >> Yeah, those are just come see come saw.
>> Yeah, those are just come see come saw.
>> Yeah, those are just come see come saw. >> Well, thank you very much.
>> Well, thank you very much.
>> Well, thank you very much. >> Yeah,
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, >> thank you. What I'd like to know is
>> thank you. What I'd like to know is
>> thank you. What I'd like to know is there's different it seems to be
there's different it seems to be
there's different it seems to be different like I don't know what to call
different like I don't know what to call
different like I don't know what to call them boundaries of sets of levels of
them boundaries of sets of levels of
them boundaries of sets of levels of consciousness like between 300 and 400
consciousness like between 300 and 400
consciousness like between 300 and 400 and 400 and 500 and things like that
and 400 and 500 and things like that
and 400 and 500 and things like that that can be difficult to
that can be difficult to
that can be difficult to penetrate I'll say um and I'm wondering
penetrate I'll say um and I'm wondering
penetrate I'll say um and I'm wondering about you know in in general growing
about you know in in general growing
about you know in in general growing from these levels of consciousness and
from these levels of consciousness and
from these levels of consciousness and methodologies.
That's the question. Well, like like for
That's the question. Well, like like for example, transitioning between
example, transitioning between
example, transitioning between like being like the 300s and 400s. Yes.
like being like the 300s and 400s. Yes.
like being like the 300s and 400s. Yes. This something I'm interested in looking
This something I'm interested in looking
This something I'm interested in looking at. And um
at. And um
at. And um All right. The 300s. Uh
All right. The 300s. Uh
All right. The 300s. Uh what?
what?
what? Yeah. But I mean, yes, the the upside of
Yeah. But I mean, yes, the the upside of
Yeah. But I mean, yes, the the upside of the 300s is uh enthusiasm, service, re
the 300s is uh enthusiasm, service, re
the 300s is uh enthusiasm, service, re uh beginning to really own your own
uh beginning to really own your own
uh beginning to really own your own power instead of projecting it out
power instead of projecting it out
power instead of projecting it out there. You stop playing victim.
there. You stop playing victim.
there. You stop playing victim. Uh
Uh
Uh the 300's are also more
the 300's are also more
the 300's are also more emotional than the 400s.
emotional than the 400s.
emotional than the 400s. The 400s tend to be non-emotional.
The 400s tend to be non-emotional.
The 400s tend to be non-emotional. They follow the rules of logic.
Not by how people feel,
Not by how people feel, but what's logical.
but what's logical.
but what's logical. Begin to track what is the truth of the
Begin to track what is the truth of the
Begin to track what is the truth of the thing. Not how do people feel about the
thing. Not how do people feel about the
thing. Not how do people feel about the truth, but what is the truth.
truth, but what is the truth.
truth, but what is the truth. So the people in the 400s, their actions
So the people in the 400s, their actions
So the people in the 400s, their actions are dominated by reason.
In the 300s and 200s, they're dominated
In the 300s and 200s, they're dominated more by
more by
more by they give more
they give more
they give more credence to emotion. How do you feel
credence to emotion. How do you feel
credence to emotion. How do you feel about it? In the 400s, nobody's
about it? In the 400s, nobody's
about it? In the 400s, nobody's interested in how you feel about it. In
interested in how you feel about it. In
interested in how you feel about it. In the operating room, I don't care how
the operating room, I don't care how
the operating room, I don't care how anybody feels about it.
That's uninteresting. I don't care how
That's uninteresting. I don't care how the nurse feels about it. Feelings have
the nurse feels about it. Feelings have
the nurse feels about it. Feelings have no place in the operating room. You got
no place in the operating room. You got
no place in the operating room. You got a stereotactic instrument. You better be
a stereotactic instrument. You better be
a stereotactic instrument. You better be pretty exact.
pretty exact.
pretty exact. One/tenth of a millimeter off and
One/tenth of a millimeter off and
One/tenth of a millimeter off and they're dead.
they're dead.
they're dead. T of a millimeter this side, they live.
T of a millimeter this side, they live.
T of a millimeter this side, they live. This is not when you're interested in
This is not when you're interested in
This is not when you're interested in people's solar plexus.
people's solar plexus.
people's solar plexus. You're not interested in their emotions.
You're not interested in their emotions.
You're not interested in their emotions. So everybody tends to hold their breath.
So everybody tends to hold their breath.
So everybody tends to hold their breath. One way to control emotions,
One way to control emotions,
One way to control emotions, people tend to hold their breath in the
people tend to hold their breath in the
people tend to hold their breath in the O and let the emotions out later, but
O and let the emotions out later, but
O and let the emotions out later, but the middle of the surgery is not what I
the middle of the surgery is not what I
the middle of the surgery is not what I want to hear what people feel like in
want to hear what people feel like in
want to hear what people feel like in the middle of war when you're the
the middle of war when you're the
the middle of war when you're the skipper. I don't care how they feel. I
skipper. I don't care how they feel. I
skipper. I don't care how they feel. I say 30 degrees port. I don't care how he
say 30 degrees port. I don't care how he
say 30 degrees port. I don't care how he feels about that.
feels about that.
feels about that. He can tell his buddies when he gets
He can tell his buddies when he gets
He can tell his buddies when he gets back to port over a couple beers. See,
back to port over a couple beers. See,
back to port over a couple beers. See, so what is when you're given a choice
so what is when you're given a choice
so what is when you're given a choice what's going to dominate the intellect,
what's going to dominate the intellect,
what's going to dominate the intellect, however, as it gets sophisticated takes
however, as it gets sophisticated takes
however, as it gets sophisticated takes feelings into account. So the more
feelings into account. So the more
feelings into account. So the more sophisticated surgeon, I'm aware of how
sophisticated surgeon, I'm aware of how
sophisticated surgeon, I'm aware of how everybody feels in the O, including the
everybody feels in the O, including the
everybody feels in the O, including the family, and how the patient was before
family, and how the patient was before
family, and how the patient was before and the likelihood exists and how
and the likelihood exists and how
and the likelihood exists and how they're going to respond if I make a
they're going to respond if I make a
they're going to respond if I make a mistake, etc.
mistake, etc.
mistake, etc. So the intellect takes as part of the
So the intellect takes as part of the
So the intellect takes as part of the equation the feelingness of everybody
equation the feelingness of everybody
equation the feelingness of everybody involved too and their stated
involved too and their stated
involved too and their stated intentions.
intentions.
intentions. If I'm going to be paralyzed, doc, I
If I'm going to be paralyzed, doc, I
If I'm going to be paralyzed, doc, I just should not make it. You got it.
just should not make it. You got it.
just should not make it. You got it. That's just between you and me. But
That's just between you and me. But
That's just between you and me. But don't tell the wife.
If it's life or paralysis, I'm not
If it's life or paralysis, I'm not interested in life with paralysis.
interested in life with paralysis.
interested in life with paralysis. I don't wish to be a burden the rest of
I don't wish to be a burden the rest of
I don't wish to be a burden the rest of my life on my wife So I know
my life on my wife So I know
my life on my wife So I know that's what the patient's telling me. I
that's what the patient's telling me. I
that's what the patient's telling me. I can't convey that to her. That's part of
can't convey that to her. That's part of
can't convey that to her. That's part of the equation. You understand how people
the equation. You understand how people
the equation. You understand how people feel that becomes part of the equation
feel that becomes part of the equation
feel that becomes part of the equation which the intellect finally puts it all
which the intellect finally puts it all
which the intellect finally puts it all together.
Yeah.
Yeah. >> I I I see. But I it's also wondering you
>> I I I see. But I it's also wondering you
>> I I I see. But I it's also wondering you know in terms of working with
know in terms of working with
know in terms of working with let's say I'm in the 300 then working
let's say I'm in the 300 then working
let's say I'm in the 300 then working with intellect versus working with love
with intellect versus working with love
with intellect versus working with love versus working with
versus working with
versus working with >> No it's not it's not versus no
>> No it's not it's not versus no
>> No it's not it's not versus no >> okay
>> okay
>> okay >> not versus
it's not necessary to go through the
it's not necessary to go through the 400s
400s
400s you see these numbers don't actually
you see these numbers don't actually
you see these numbers don't actually exist those are calibrations
exist those are calibrations
exist those are calibrations They're an abstraction. They're an
They're an abstraction. They're an
They're an abstraction. They're an abstraction.
abstraction.
abstraction. The holograph is the world is
The holograph is the world is
The holograph is the world is holographic. So it's how you look at it
holographic. So it's how you look at it
holographic. So it's how you look at it from here. This is not better than that.
from here. This is not better than that.
from here. This is not better than that. It's just different than that. This is
It's just different than that. This is
It's just different than that. This is how it looks through the intellect. This
how it looks through the intellect. This
how it looks through the intellect. This is how it looks through feeling.
It's not better than, it's different
It's not better than, it's different than.
So are you saying then I mean I
So are you saying then I mean I for me there's an attraction towards
for me there's an attraction towards
for me there's an attraction towards working to become more conscious.
working to become more conscious.
working to become more conscious. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> And
>> And
>> And although once isn't necessarily
although once isn't necessarily
although once isn't necessarily intrinsically better than another. Is is
intrinsically better than another. Is is
intrinsically better than another. Is is that something to pursue? You can jump
that something to pursue? You can jump
that something to pursue? You can jump the intellect all together. You can go
the intellect all together. You can go
the intellect all together. You can go from the 300s right to the 500s
from the 300s right to the 500s
from the 300s right to the 500s through simple faith through compassion
through simple faith through compassion
through simple faith through compassion love. simple faith, simplicity. Mother
love. simple faith, simplicity. Mother
love. simple faith, simplicity. Mother Teresa represents that pathway
Teresa represents that pathway
Teresa represents that pathway through selfless service, compassion,
through selfless service, compassion,
through selfless service, compassion, and love. You jump the 400s. She doesn't
and love. You jump the 400s. She doesn't
and love. You jump the 400s. She doesn't even go into the 400s.
even go into the 400s.
even go into the 400s. I don't think Mother Patrices was ever
I don't think Mother Patrices was ever
I don't think Mother Patrices was ever in the 400s.
in the 400s.
in the 400s. You probably went from the 300s right
You probably went from the 300s right
You probably went from the 300s right right into the 500s. She was 700 and
right into the 500s. She was 700 and
right into the 500s. She was 700 and something when she left here.
Yes. I'll finish him.
Yes. I'll finish him. Bringing enough ammunition. We'll finish
Bringing enough ammunition. We'll finish
Bringing enough ammunition. We'll finish him off.
>> Yeah. I don't think Mother Teresa ever
>> Yeah. I don't think Mother Teresa ever fooled around with the 400s.
fooled around with the 400s.
fooled around with the 400s. She wasn't Mother Teresa PhD.
She She had her choice. Do it this
She She had her choice. Do it this lifetime or come back and get a PhD. She
lifetime or come back and get a PhD. She
lifetime or come back and get a PhD. She said, "I'll do it this lifetime.
I think she jumped to 400. She went
I think she jumped to 400. She went right probably from the 300 selfless
right probably from the 300 selfless
right probably from the 300 selfless service and then surrendered completely
service and then surrendered completely
service and then surrendered completely to God to Jesus Christ cuz she was a
to God to Jesus Christ cuz she was a
to God to Jesus Christ cuz she was a real Christian, you know. She
real Christian, you know. She
real Christian, you know. She surrendered everything to Jesus Christ
surrendered everything to Jesus Christ
surrendered everything to Jesus Christ and maybe in a matter of a few seconds
and maybe in a matter of a few seconds
and maybe in a matter of a few seconds went right into 700.
went right into 700.
went right into 700. Okay. Okay. Go with the Mother Teresa
Okay. Okay. Go with the Mother Teresa
Okay. Okay. Go with the Mother Teresa group trouble.
group trouble.
group trouble. you won't have to read all the dumb
you won't have to read all the dumb
you won't have to read all the dumb books.
>> My question follows logically on his in
>> My question follows logically on his in a way. Um I was wondering
a way. Um I was wondering
a way. Um I was wondering I feel like I and you've alluded to
I feel like I and you've alluded to
I feel like I and you've alluded to quite a few people get stuck in the 400s
quite a few people get stuck in the 400s
quite a few people get stuck in the 400s and it's hard for them to make that
and it's hard for them to make that
and it's hard for them to make that transition to a positionality of love
transition to a positionality of love
transition to a positionality of love and coming from that. And I wondered the
and coming from that. And I wondered the
and coming from that. And I wondered the best way to to
best way to to
best way to to make that make that transition.
make that make that transition.
make that make that transition. And along with that uh my only
And along with that uh my only
And along with that uh my only experience of of God as love is a
experience of of God as love is a
experience of of God as love is a feeling of love coming through me
feeling of love coming through me
feeling of love coming through me towards others.
towards others.
towards others. And that's the only experience I've ever
And that's the only experience I've ever
And that's the only experience I've ever had that gives me some hint that that
had that gives me some hint that that
had that gives me some hint that that that is part of God. And I wondered if
that is part of God. And I wondered if
that is part of God. And I wondered if there's some way that I can be more
there's some way that I can be more
there's some way that I can be more attuned to
attuned to
attuned to uh to perceiving
uh to perceiving
uh to perceiving the love of God.
the love of God.
the love of God. >> Did you ever do the course of miracles?
>> Did you ever do the course of miracles?
>> Did you ever do the course of miracles? >> No.
>> No.
>> No. >> Do it.
>> I'll tell you why. The the course hit me
>> I'll tell you why. The the course hit me right off the bat when I read, you know,
right off the bat when I read, you know,
right off the bat when I read, you know, not the workbook. I mean, not the
not the workbook. I mean, not the
not the workbook. I mean, not the textbook, but the workbook. Okay. The
textbook, but the workbook. Okay. The
textbook, but the workbook. Okay. The workbook calibrates at 600.
workbook calibrates at 600.
workbook calibrates at 600. The workbook calibrates at 600. The
The workbook calibrates at 600. The
The workbook calibrates at 600. The textbook calibrates at 550.
textbook calibrates at 550.
textbook calibrates at 550. Um why? Because it tends to polarize the
Um why? Because it tends to polarize the
Um why? Because it tends to polarize the ego. It's really coming from another
ego. It's really coming from another
ego. It's really coming from another voice than the other side, different
voice than the other side, different
voice than the other side, different author.
author.
author. Because it handles the ego completely
Because it handles the ego completely
Because it handles the ego completely differently between the two. If you do
differently between the two. If you do
differently between the two. If you do the workbook, which is one sentence a
the workbook, which is one sentence a
the workbook, which is one sentence a day, it bypasses the intellect. The
day, it bypasses the intellect. The
day, it bypasses the intellect. The thing that this struck me about the
thing that this struck me about the
thing that this struck me about the genius of the course,
genius of the course,
genius of the course, most spirituality
most spirituality
most spirituality addresses
addresses
addresses a person as they are with the truth. But
a person as they are with the truth. But
a person as they are with the truth. But that person as they are is extremely
that person as they are is extremely
that person as they are is extremely welldefended by the ego.
welldefended by the ego.
welldefended by the ego. So, you're presenting spiritual truth to
So, you're presenting spiritual truth to
So, you're presenting spiritual truth to a person dominated by the ego and
a person dominated by the ego and
a person dominated by the ego and they're going to shake it off like a dog
they're going to shake it off like a dog
they're going to shake it off like a dog does water.
What the course of miracles does, the
What the course of miracles does, the workbook,
workbook,
workbook, it begins to take the ego apart first
it begins to take the ego apart first
it begins to take the ego apart first before it hits you with truth. Doesn't
before it hits you with truth. Doesn't
before it hits you with truth. Doesn't tell you God is love
tell you God is love
tell you God is love in lesson 20.
in lesson 20.
in lesson 20. You know that already. So what?
You know that already. So what?
You know that already. So what? No,
No,
No, I remember the lesson that bulled me
I remember the lesson that bulled me
I remember the lesson that bulled me over and I said, "This is spiritual
over and I said, "This is spiritual
over and I said, "This is spiritual genius. I can recognize spiritual
genius. I can recognize spiritual
genius. I can recognize spiritual genius." It says, "Your thoughts don't
genius." It says, "Your thoughts don't
genius." It says, "Your thoughts don't mean anything." I uhoh,
mean anything." I uhoh,
mean anything." I uhoh, this I got to read.
this I got to read.
this I got to read. >> That is very far advanced because they
>> That is very far advanced because they
>> That is very far advanced because they only mean what meaning you give them to
only mean what meaning you give them to
only mean what meaning you give them to mean. Of course, you're the author of
mean. Of course, you're the author of
mean. Of course, you're the author of meaning.
meaning.
meaning. So, I thought, "Wow, this is a great
So, I thought, "Wow, this is a great
So, I thought, "Wow, this is a great course." And of course what it does is
course." And of course what it does is
course." And of course what it does is take the ego apart. Then once the ego is
take the ego apart. Then once the ego is
take the ego apart. Then once the ego is disassembled and weakened then it comes
disassembled and weakened then it comes
disassembled and weakened then it comes up with spiritual truth. But that
up with spiritual truth. But that
up with spiritual truth. But that spiritual truth is not rejected by the
spiritual truth is not rejected by the
spiritual truth is not rejected by the intellect anymore. So to bypass the
intellect anymore. So to bypass the
intellect anymore. So to bypass the intellect then I think the course of
intellect then I think the course of
intellect then I think the course of miracles is very helpful.
miracles is very helpful.
miracles is very helpful. >> And is that something that you would
>> And is that something that you would
>> And is that something that you would pursue by obtaining the workbook or is
pursue by obtaining the workbook or is
pursue by obtaining the workbook or is it something that you would join a
it something that you would join a
it something that you would join a >> Well, you can do the workbook on your
>> Well, you can do the workbook on your
>> Well, you can do the workbook on your own. And you don't need to join a group.
own. And you don't need to join a group.
own. And you don't need to join a group. Some people do, but I think they tend to
Some people do, but I think they tend to
Some people do, but I think they tend to intellectualize sometimes, you know, and
intellectualize sometimes, you know, and
intellectualize sometimes, you know, and they start telling you sea stories
they start telling you sea stories
they start telling you sea stories about, you know, when they saw Guru so
about, you know, when they saw Guru so
about, you know, when they saw Guru so and so and then the thing that appeared
and so and then the thing that appeared
and so and then the thing that appeared in the sky and give me a break. So
in the sky and give me a break. So
in the sky and give me a break. So they tend to wander off. Just if you do
they tend to wander off. Just if you do
they tend to wander off. Just if you do the workbook by yourself, seriously,
the workbook by yourself, seriously,
the workbook by yourself, seriously, it's transformative.
it's transformative.
it's transformative. You know, we tested people with
You know, we tested people with
You know, we tested people with kinesiology
kinesiology
kinesiology and the way I ran across it was I was
and the way I ran across it was I was
and the way I ran across it was I was using it. I was going to teach a course
using it. I was going to teach a course
using it. I was going to teach a course in it. I was giving a class in
in it. I was giving a class in
in it. I was giving a class in kinesiology. So, I wanted some students.
kinesiology. So, I wanted some students.
kinesiology. So, I wanted some students. Well, we had students hanging around the
Well, we had students hanging around the
Well, we had students hanging around the clinic
clinic
clinic and I said, "Come over here. Give me
and I said, "Come over here. Give me
and I said, "Come over here. Give me your arm a second." And look at this
your arm a second." And look at this
your arm a second." And look at this fluorescent light. And these people arm
fluorescent light. And these people arm
fluorescent light. And these people arm didn't go down. Everybody's arm goes
didn't go down. Everybody's arm goes
didn't go down. Everybody's arm goes down when you look at fluorescent
down when you look at fluorescent
down when you look at fluorescent lights. I said, "What have you been up
lights. I said, "What have you been up
lights. I said, "What have you been up to?" I said, "We did the course of
to?" I said, "We did the course of
to?" I said, "We did the course of miracles." Whoa.
miracles." Whoa.
miracles." Whoa. >> So then we ran some test pupils through.
>> So then we ran some test pupils through.
>> So then we ran some test pupils through. We tested them before they did the
We tested them before they did the
We tested them before they did the course of miracles. Fluorescent lights
course of miracles. Fluorescent lights
course of miracles. Fluorescent lights make everybody go weak. Sweet and low
make everybody go weak. Sweet and low
make everybody go weak. Sweet and low makes everybody go weak.
makes everybody go weak.
makes everybody go weak. Certain things make everybody go weak.
Certain things make everybody go weak.
Certain things make everybody go weak. We tracked these students as they went
We tracked these students as they went
We tracked these students as they went through the course of miracles. And by
through the course of miracles. And by
through the course of miracles. And by the time they got to about less than 80,
the time they got to about less than 80,
the time they got to about less than 80, 75, 80, 95 around in there, they'd look
75, 80, 95 around in there, they'd look
75, 80, 95 around in there, they'd look at look at the fluescent lights on their
at look at the fluescent lights on their
at look at the fluescent lights on their arm did not go weak.
arm did not go weak.
arm did not go weak. Now they were passed. Now they realized
Now they were passed. Now they realized
Now they were passed. Now they realized I'm only subject to what I hold in mind.
I'm only subject to what I hold in mind.
I'm only subject to what I hold in mind. Nothing out there's nothing out there
Nothing out there's nothing out there
Nothing out there's nothing out there that has any power over me.
that has any power over me.
that has any power over me. Something had incredibly changed.
Something had incredibly changed.
Something had incredibly changed. And you cannot change your kinesiologic
And you cannot change your kinesiologic
And you cannot change your kinesiologic responses or your acupuncture energy
responses or your acupuncture energy
responses or your acupuncture energy rhythms voluntarily. So some force or
rhythms voluntarily. So some force or
rhythms voluntarily. So some force or energy or transformation had taken
energy or transformation had taken
energy or transformation had taken place.
place.
place. So I'd say bypass the intellect. Try the
So I'd say bypass the intellect. Try the
So I'd say bypass the intellect. Try the course of miracles.
course of miracles.
course of miracles. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Doesn't work. I'll give you your money
>> Doesn't work. I'll give you your money
>> Doesn't work. I'll give you your money back.
back.
back. Buy the paperback edition.
I'm having uh trouble grasping the
I'm having uh trouble grasping the source of my own valition and of myself
source of my own valition and of myself
source of my own valition and of myself for uh exercising free will, making
for uh exercising free will, making
for uh exercising free will, making choices, having intentions.
choices, having intentions.
choices, having intentions. >> So what your question has to do with is
>> So what your question has to do with is
>> So what your question has to do with is the spiritual will.
the spiritual will.
the spiritual will. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> All right.
Well, it's calibrated level of
Well, it's calibrated level of consciousness is actually a consequence
consciousness is actually a consequence
consciousness is actually a consequence of the spiritual will.
People were asking me about meditation
People were asking me about meditation and I forgot to mention it. Uh the
and I forgot to mention it. Uh the
and I forgot to mention it. Uh the spiritual will doesn't change from
spiritual will doesn't change from
spiritual will doesn't change from instant to instant. The content of
instant to instant. The content of
instant to instant. The content of consciousness constantly shifts. But
consciousness constantly shifts. But
consciousness constantly shifts. But your spiritual will which is your
your spiritual will which is your
your spiritual will which is your committed intention that does not change
committed intention that does not change
committed intention that does not change from moment to moment.
from moment to moment.
from moment to moment. Your spiritual will does not shift
Your spiritual will does not shift
Your spiritual will does not shift instant by instant. Choice shifts
instant by instant. Choice shifts
instant by instant. Choice shifts instant by instant. But your intention,
instant by instant. But your intention,
instant by instant. But your intention, your spiritual will, which is the way
your spiritual will, which is the way
your spiritual will, which is the way you set the rudder,
you set the rudder,
you set the rudder, the way you set your course on the
the way you set your course on the
the way you set your course on the compass, that doesn't shift from second
compass, that doesn't shift from second
compass, that doesn't shift from second to second. You go up a little bit on the
to second. You go up a little bit on the
to second. You go up a little bit on the wave this way, you go up a little bit of
wave this way, you go up a little bit of
wave this way, you go up a little bit of the wave this way, but the compass is
the wave this way, but the compass is
the wave this way, but the compass is already set. So, it's your spiritual
already set. So, it's your spiritual
already set. So, it's your spiritual will, your intention, your commitment.
will, your intention, your commitment.
will, your intention, your commitment. That's what makes the spiritual pathway
That's what makes the spiritual pathway
That's what makes the spiritual pathway work. That's why there's 10,000 ways to
work. That's why there's 10,000 ways to
work. That's why there's 10,000 ways to God because intention is so powerful.
God because intention is so powerful.
God because intention is so powerful. Rotating prayer wheels, burning candles,
Rotating prayer wheels, burning candles,
Rotating prayer wheels, burning candles, sitting cross-legged, breathing in funny
sitting cross-legged, breathing in funny
sitting cross-legged, breathing in funny ways,
ways,
ways, all of that helps because of the
all of that helps because of the
all of that helps because of the spiritual will. In a deep meditation, I
spiritual will. In a deep meditation, I
spiritual will. In a deep meditation, I experience what your spiritual will.
experience what your spiritual will.
experience what your spiritual will. There are other times I experience and
There are other times I experience and
There are other times I experience and witness reactions within myself from
witness reactions within myself from
witness reactions within myself from lower states of consciousness.
lower states of consciousness.
lower states of consciousness. >> From what?
>> From what?
>> From what? >> Lower states of consciousness. I
>> Lower states of consciousness. I
>> Lower states of consciousness. I >> Yeah, sure.
>> Yeah, sure.
>> Yeah, sure. >> Frustration. I I'm I struggle with where
>> Frustration. I I'm I struggle with where
>> Frustration. I I'm I struggle with where the valition is in me to to change to
the valition is in me to to change to
the valition is in me to to change to make a different choice to raise that.
make a different choice to raise that.
make a different choice to raise that. >> Well, you want to transcend it. See we
>> Well, you want to transcend it. See we
>> Well, you want to transcend it. See we don't have enough
don't have enough
don't have enough uh time today to go into the details of
uh time today to go into the details of
uh time today to go into the details of transcending the ego.
transcending the ego.
transcending the ego. Now the positionalities the
Now the positionalities the
Now the positionalities the positionalities
positionalities
positionalities uh the the the things that arise in the
uh the the the things that arise in the
uh the the the things that arise in the ego like you say anger or dismay or
ego like you say anger or dismay or
ego like you say anger or dismay or whatever
whatever
whatever uh are all the automatic consequence of
uh are all the automatic consequence of
uh are all the automatic consequence of perception.
perception.
perception. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> It's because of how you're seeing it. So
>> It's because of how you're seeing it. So
>> It's because of how you're seeing it. So your problem is not anger. Your problem
your problem is not anger. Your problem
your problem is not anger. Your problem is how you're seeing it.
is how you're seeing it.
is how you're seeing it. So that's why the course of miracles you
So that's why the course of miracles you
So that's why the course of miracles you ask the miracle. What is the miracle? A
ask the miracle. What is the miracle? A
ask the miracle. What is the miracle? A miracle is asking the Holy Spirit to
miracle is asking the Holy Spirit to
miracle is asking the Holy Spirit to reconextualize
reconextualize
reconextualize reconextualize it to you. And now that
reconextualize it to you. And now that
reconextualize it to you. And now that you see it differently, you see there
you see it differently, you see there
you see it differently, you see there isn't a problem.
isn't a problem.
isn't a problem. >> It's only once I observe
>> It's only once I observe
>> It's only once I observe >> how you were seeing it
>> how you were seeing it
>> how you were seeing it >> problematic per right and wrong. Right.
>> problematic per right and wrong. Right.
>> problematic per right and wrong. Right. Then I asked for that to be released and
Then I asked for that to be released and
Then I asked for that to be released and it is.
it is.
it is. >> He asked for a transformation of p of uh
>> He asked for a transformation of p of uh
>> He asked for a transformation of p of uh yes the holy spirit to replace your
yes the holy spirit to replace your
yes the holy spirit to replace your perception
perception
perception uh with truth which means you want god
uh with truth which means you want god
uh with truth which means you want god to in the form of the holy spirit to
to in the form of the holy spirit to
to in the form of the holy spirit to recontextualize it so you see it
recontextualize it so you see it
recontextualize it so you see it differently. Once you see it differently
differently. Once you see it differently
differently. Once you see it differently there isn't a problem.
there isn't a problem.
there isn't a problem. >> Yes. So I ask for that. I can't just
>> Yes. So I ask for that. I can't just
>> Yes. So I ask for that. I can't just choose that or have the intention. If
choose that or have the intention. If
choose that or have the intention. If you can get more sophisticated your
you can get more sophisticated your
you can get more sophisticated your spiritual work, you see that's the
spiritual work, you see that's the
spiritual work, you see that's the problem. And you can begin to do that
problem. And you can begin to do that
problem. And you can begin to do that yourself.
But when you hit a blind spot, you say,
But when you hit a blind spot, you say, "I don't I don't see why why I'm see I
"I don't I don't see why why I'm see I
"I don't I don't see why why I'm see I just hate this guy and I don't know. I
just hate this guy and I don't know. I
just hate this guy and I don't know. I can't get off it. It's because the way
can't get off it. It's because the way
can't get off it. It's because the way I'm seeing it."
I'm seeing it."
I'm seeing it." So you ask God for help to see it
So you ask God for help to see it
So you ask God for help to see it differently.
differently.
differently. Okay. Thank you. Yeah.
Okay. Thank you. Yeah.
Okay. Thank you. Yeah. You see,
You see,
You see, like I say, right and wrong, people get
like I say, right and wrong, people get
like I say, right and wrong, people get indignant, moralistic,
indignant, moralistic,
indignant, moralistic, and politics and all that. It's because
and politics and all that. It's because
and politics and all that. It's because of how you're seeing it. So that's why I
of how you're seeing it. So that's why I
of how you're seeing it. So that's why I started out today with the scale of
started out today with the scale of
started out today with the scale of consciousness. I said everything there
consciousness. I said everything there
consciousness. I said everything there is serving something below it and at the
is serving something below it and at the
is serving something below it and at the same time serving something above it. So
same time serving something above it. So
same time serving something above it. So that
that
that learning how to be a good thief is a
learning how to be a good thief is a
learning how to be a good thief is a step up from starving to death in
step up from starving to death in
step up from starving to death in poverty. When I was a pickpock at Paris,
poverty. When I was a pickpock at Paris,
poverty. When I was a pickpock at Paris, I was a good one. The other people lay
I was a good one. The other people lay
I was a good one. The other people lay around in poverty, not me.
around in poverty, not me.
around in poverty, not me. Then when you get further ahead, you can
Then when you get further ahead, you can
Then when you get further ahead, you can let that go.
let that go.
let that go. So you can start out for survival
So you can start out for survival
So you can start out for survival cutting corners, but then your intention
cutting corners, but then your intention
cutting corners, but then your intention is to transcend that. So each one
is to transcend that. So each one
is to transcend that. So each one inspires that which is below it and
inspires that which is below it and
inspires that which is below it and serves as example.
In order to survive, you first have to
In order to survive, you first have to get off the floor. So
the so-called gangster robsters,
the so-called gangster robsters, rosters, rosters, what are they?
rosters, rosters, what are they?
rosters, rosters, what are they? Rapsters.
Rapsters.
Rapsters. Gangster rapsters.
Gangster rapsters.
Gangster rapsters. From ethics and morality, we say, "Isn't
From ethics and morality, we say, "Isn't
From ethics and morality, we say, "Isn't that awful?
that awful?
that awful? And what they're saying to you is if you
And what they're saying to you is if you
And what they're saying to you is if you folks starve to death and lay there in
folks starve to death and lay there in
folks starve to death and lay there in apathy. Well, I'm going to be a
apathy. Well, I'm going to be a
apathy. Well, I'm going to be a millionaire and show you how to do it.
millionaire and show you how to do it.
millionaire and show you how to do it. All right? So, he's selling
All right? So, he's selling
All right? So, he's selling non-integrity, but in a way for an
non-integrity, but in a way for an
non-integrity, but in a way for an integrous purpose. Well, you say it's
integrous purpose. Well, you say it's
integrous purpose. Well, you say it's just greed. No, it's just more than
just greed. No, it's just more than
just greed. No, it's just more than greed. Now, he's got the energy of
greed. Now, he's got the energy of
greed. Now, he's got the energy of pride.
pride.
pride. Now, he's coming up.
Now, he's coming up.
Now, he's coming up. Next thing he becomes integrous. He
Next thing he becomes integrous. He
Next thing he becomes integrous. He starts his own company. Now you see some
starts his own company. Now you see some
starts his own company. Now you see some of these rap stars that started out with
of these rap stars that started out with
of these rap stars that started out with nothing but vulgarity and obscity.
nothing but vulgarity and obscity.
nothing but vulgarity and obscity. Now they got their own record company.
Now they got their own record company.
Now they got their own record company. Now they're signing contracts like and
Now they're signing contracts like and
Now they're signing contracts like and they're becoming ordinary businessmen.
they're becoming ordinary businessmen.
they're becoming ordinary businessmen. So they rise out of the gutter and they
So they rise out of the gutter and they
So they rise out of the gutter and they say, "Look, be like me. Make a few
say, "Look, be like me. Make a few
say, "Look, be like me. Make a few bucks. Don't wallow there in self-pity.
bucks. Don't wallow there in self-pity.
bucks. Don't wallow there in self-pity. Stop being the weak
Stop being the weak
Stop being the weak uh victim.
uh victim.
uh victim. Get the hell up and fight for it." So we
Get the hell up and fight for it." So we
Get the hell up and fight for it." So we can put them down, say they're vulgar
can put them down, say they're vulgar
can put them down, say they're vulgar and obscene, but to the people below
and obscene, but to the people below
and obscene, but to the people below them, they're inspirational. See, so
them, they're inspirational. See, so
them, they're inspirational. See, so what we put down is inspirational to
what we put down is inspirational to
what we put down is inspirational to somebody that's really at the bottom.
somebody that's really at the bottom.
somebody that's really at the bottom. This whole country is if you could get
This whole country is if you could get
This whole country is if you could get them up to the level of a rap star, we
them up to the level of a rap star, we
them up to the level of a rap star, we wouldn't have any worry about them.
wouldn't have any worry about them.
wouldn't have any worry about them. They don't have the energy to feed
They don't have the energy to feed
They don't have the energy to feed themselves. The food is right there and
themselves. The food is right there and
themselves. The food is right there and they can't lift their arm. Look at their
they can't lift their arm. Look at their
they can't lift their arm. Look at their arm. It's all wasted. It's all gone.
arm. It's all wasted. It's all gone.
arm. It's all wasted. It's all gone. and their brain is deteriorated with
and their brain is deteriorated with
and their brain is deteriorated with age. They don't even know where their
age. They don't even know where their
age. They don't even know where their mouth is anymore. You better to be a rap
mouth is anymore. You better to be a rap
mouth is anymore. You better to be a rap star, you know.
star, you know.
star, you know. So each one of us then serves in some
So each one of us then serves in some
So each one of us then serves in some way and and that gets off gets us off
way and and that gets off gets us off
way and and that gets off gets us off the polarity of judgmentalism. See, so
the polarity of judgmentalism. See, so
the polarity of judgmentalism. See, so that's what the course of miracles does
that's what the course of miracles does
that's what the course of miracles does is it recontextualizes
is it recontextualizes
is it recontextualizes and you say, you think he's a bad man.
and you say, you think he's a bad man.
and you say, you think he's a bad man. Let me show you where he was. Now I'll
Let me show you where he was. Now I'll
Let me show you where he was. Now I'll show you where he is now. And now I'll
show you where he is now. And now I'll
show you where he is now. And now I'll show you where he'll be in the future.
show you where he'll be in the future.
show you where he'll be in the future. Chris, here's Christmas past. Here's
Chris, here's Christmas past. Here's
Chris, here's Christmas past. Here's Christmas Christmas present. And there's
Christmas Christmas present. And there's
Christmas Christmas present. And there's going to be Christmas future. So my
going to be Christmas future. So my
going to be Christmas future. So my prediction is that today's vulgar rap
prediction is that today's vulgar rap
prediction is that today's vulgar rap star if he doesn't go down the toes
star if he doesn't go down the toes
star if he doesn't go down the toes completely with drugs will become
completely with drugs will become
completely with drugs will become tomorrow's businessman. You know, he
tomorrow's businessman. You know, he
tomorrow's businessman. You know, he will become progressively integrous. I
will become progressively integrous. I
will become progressively integrous. I think because the consciousness level of
think because the consciousness level of
think because the consciousness level of mankind keeps going up and it has to
mankind keeps going up and it has to
mankind keeps going up and it has to pull us all up.
pull us all up.
pull us all up. And now your reps are saying, "Look, I
And now your reps are saying, "Look, I
And now your reps are saying, "Look, I did what I had to do to get where I am."
did what I had to do to get where I am."
did what I had to do to get where I am." Uh, look where I am, though.
Uh, look where I am, though.
Uh, look where I am, though. Got to respect me for what I did.