Today we're going to talk about what is
inner peace and how does one achieve it
in uh and live with it in their
lifetime. So when I hold in mind
um inner peace
um I think of my um inner spiritual
uh body that is um always with me. Um,
is that
correct that the inner peace is
something that you always carry with
you?
>> Well, that that's your your definition
of it.
>> Everybody has their own definition.
>> Okay.
>> Of what they would mean by spiritual
peace.
>> Mhm.
>> You know, how closely they fulfill their
their own uh
um ambitions about it.
To me, uh, inner peace is, uh, the the
acceptance of what is from instant to
instant
with, uh, so if the bird is singing as
you walk through the woods, you're happy
the bird is singing. If the bird is not
singing, you're quiet. You're happy the
bird is not singing because you can hear
every little twig.
uh so to be happy with the experience of
life as you experience it.
However, I'm experiencing it right now.
If I accept that I have some wonderment
of where we're going to go next with
conversation,
well, that's a normal experience to
wonder what is the next question going
to be.
So I accept that I have some mild not
apprehension but wonder. Yeah. Yeah. A
little apprehension.
What will the next question be? And will
I be able to adequately fulfill my own
inner definition of adequacy of
explanation?
>> Mhm.
>> Will I live up to my own inner
expectations?
So the only fulfillment I have to worry
about then is whether I'm fulfilling my
own inner expectations.
The awareness of presence of God is just
one of them,
you know, but it's more inclusive than
just that. There's also our
physical performance as human beings and
our intellectual performance
and our emotional compatibility
and our
I would like to ser serve some practical
uh purpose for the people who will be
seeing this uh this film as we as we
finish it. Mhm. that I can stimulate
them to ask themselves what to me is
inner peace? What to me is the full
meaning of life?
What part does the awareness of God play
in my own inner experience and
expectation?
And you may have no uh understanding of
God or or even
uh wondering about it,
which is fine too because if it was up
to God for you to think about God now,
you'd be thinking about God now. So if
you're not, it's probably because
doesn't God God doesn't want you
thinking about God now.
The way to make God happy is don't think
about God when God doesn't want you
thinking about God. How does that grab
you
if you're thinking about it? It must be
the expectation unconsciously
to include God in one's definition of
fulfillment of happiness
and uh but not to be uh
consciously aware of it from moment to
moment because that stirs up an inner
expectation. Mhm.
>> You know, we all have an idea of God has
having something to do with piety.
Piety. So people,
>> you mentioned God, they expect the
expectation of piety.
And um but the presence of God is more
than just piety. P one B of one mode of
expression of it.
um and going beyond piety.
The spontaneity of how this very moment
is unfolding
just this moment right now that I'm
speaking of is unfolding of its own
inner
potentiality
to become the reality of our experience.
Whether we experience that reality or
not is irrelevant to the presence of
that reality.
So my acceptance of the the presence of
God at this very moment is so complete
and total that I don't have to think
about it
that if God wants me to serve wants us
to serve others through our
communication
through what we're doing this morning
then I feel we've uh fulfilled our uh
potentiality as
my gift to other human beings is to
express myself to the fullest capacity
that I can of my own realization of the
presence of God as I have experienced it
throughout life
and in at different periods of life that
experience has been quite different.
Sometimes it was overpoweringly present
other times I was oblivious of it
consciously.
because I was too busy laughing and
having a good time.
So at that time God was present as the
experience of the joy of the moment of
being an adult human being.
When I was younger it was the expression
of the presence of God as the experience
of being a child, a happy child.
Right now I'm very very happy right this
moment with you.
uh this moment I have no further
expectation other than we are being who
we are with each other at this moment
and and I love you very much and I want
you to know the degree to which I love
you
and that fulfills uh
um
some inner need on my part that I should
not only feel what I feel about you but
share with you how I feel about you.
Uh
the thankfulness
uh so I'm very thankful for your love
and your presence
because with your love and your presence
I become
u the greater fulfillment of my inner
divine potential.
that you help me fulfill the awareness
and the conscious awareness of the
presence of God within me
as existence because out of the
existence of of being with you comes
that joy and the joy tells me that God
is here now present.
So, I experience God as the happiness
that I feel when I'm with you and
chatting away with you. And at the same
time, the back of my mind is saying,
"You could be doing it better." But
that's BS. If I could be doing it
better, I would. I would be.
Well, when when I experience
>> inner peace, it's like a it's like a
calm I think of it as a being a calm
presence that is always within my aura,
>> but sometimes, you know, the worldly
>> Yeah.
>> things take over. And so it's always
there, but there's
daily activities and tasks that have to
be accomplished.
>> Distraction.
>> So there's Yeah. So, but it's always
there. Inner peace is always there. And
you know it's there.
>> You know, um you get a kind of a inner
peace when you do a job well done. You
know that God helped you do that. um you
get an inner peace when um you know you
see a a child being born because you
know that without God that would not
have happened.
>> So I just feel like um inner peace is
something that's always within your
aura. It's just that you have to take
the time to recognize it that a lot of
people you know because of the daily
activities and things you know even just
planting a tree there's a certain piece
of
>> times in my life when I lost the inner
peace u the suffering of other I lose my
inner peace when I witnessed the
suffering of others the suffering of
other beings humans or animals
uh bird u the witnessing a suffering I
lose I lose that feeling of inner peace.
>> Mhm.
>> Uh I don't know how to overcome that.
U
to witness the suffering of others.
>> Well, if that's more of the compassion
that's in you that that takes over the
inner peace is always there though. But
isn't that wouldn't that be the
compassion to
>> Well, peace is more the achievement of
the goal. you know as a physician one of
the reason I became a physician is uh to
relieve the suffering of others
and uh so to to witness the ongoingness
of suffering in someone else brings in a
suffering within me which can I can only
eliminate by relieving their suffering.
So
uh
in a way I guess if you define it oddly
enough it's always selfish then to
relieve the suffering of others because
then I feel better that they're feeling
better.
>> But also it's also kind of fulfilling
because you know that you use the go the
gifts that God gave you to help that
another human being. that that's what I
feel I I I do best
>> is uh how to relieve the suffering of
others
uh by their you know whatever that
suffering might be could be guilt it
could be physical pain could be fear of
the future it could be regret over the
past
>> it could be wor over their pets and
animals you say I worry too much about
the dog I will stop worrying about the
dog instead I'll worry about the bird
we got a talking parrot
who chatters away. Yes, she does.
>> Oh, it's hysterically funny.
So, in the meantime, I like all my
animals. So, there's the doggy sitting
there. Then there's the kitty sitting
there. And then there's the birdie
chirping and talking away. And there's
you and I talking about the birds and
the cats and the dogs all at the same
time. So, it's sort of ciruitous.
Their happiness makes us happy. And
because we're happy, they become happy
that we're happy.
>> Right? That's true.
>> As the
presence of God is really the uh
expression of the uh potentiality of the
moment.
So our happiness and our gladness at the
presence of all the things we love
uh is an expression of the fulfillment
of God.
>> Well, if you had to describe
>> Yeah.
>> What would you inner peace in yourself?
If you had to describe inner peace,
could you give me a time that you really
feel inner peace uh within yourself?
What at what times do you feel that
strong inner peace?
>> When I'm fulfilling my potential to the
best of my capacity
like right now, I feel peaceful that I
am expressing myself as well as I can
under these circumstances.
this couch, this camera, this time, this
temperature, this room.
Hypothetically, I might be more
eloquent. But in reality, I'm being as
eloquent as I can be right at this
moment. And the love I feel from you
tends to charge it up. And then when we
took a break, we went in and checked out
all the the all the animals were happy.
So everybody's hunky dory. Everybody's
happy. And
so the fulfillment of that potential
uh brings brings a state of joy. Uhhuh.
And and uh and I'm I'm happy that you're
sitting next to me and we're discussing
such a subject.
Um, would you consider inner peace an
emotional
state or is it more of a physical
state?
>> I I I understand as a state of
consciousness.
>> Okay.
>> The entire state of consciousness which
includes the emotion and the
expectation.
And what I just said, I've already
remembered. I just remembered that I've
already just said what I just said. So
the immediate past. So there's the
immediate past.
What's going to be said in the next
moment? There's the immediate past.
There's the immediate future. There's
the immediate present. Uh all
simultaneously. Past, present, and
future become melded into one
overall experience.
melt melted into one overall experience.
>> It's not it's not an emotional it's and
it's not physical. So it's just
>> state.
>> No, it's all of them.
>> It's all of them.
>> Yeah. You can't say it's not that. It's
not exclusively that.
>> Okay.
>> It's all of them. Uh physical comfort
that we're comfortable here that our
conversation is unfolding spontaneously.
uh that it's been correctly recorded and
that we can see each other as visually
well
>> that our facial expressions are
appropriate.
>> Okay.
>> It is a little bit on the darker side,
is it? Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> So,
>> that's be fine.
>> Um peace is
>> all it feels like.
>> Yeah.
It is.
>> Yeah. Um peace is it fulfilling um
interex expectations?
Do we have uh like a inter do we
recognize when we really feel uh inner
peace? Do we recognize that uh as a
state?
>> I think we experience it without
actually defining it. Right?
uh when asked to define it, I think it's
easy enough to define
except that it's difficult.
>> Okay.
>> Well, we we know what generally talk
about peace, we're talking about
external peace,
>> peaceful situation, surroundings.
um
you can be at peace with a emotional
state that is not peaceful.
So by that meaning of peace we mean
total acceptance.
I can totally accept that at a certain
time I be may be stricken with guilt or
at a second certain time I might be
stricken with anger or anger you know
that it might be a non
during the war uh
you know
I was at on the one hand at peace all
the time
uh I was on a mind sweeper you can get
blown up any instant
So there I am living with we live I
learned to live at peace with the
possibility of instant death.
Instant death and and a couple times it
almost happened. The ship came
and the horn sticking out of the
mine, you know, actually began to bump
the edge of the ship.
So admittedly, I was prepared to go to
God right then. that any moment you're
going to explode into a million pieces.
So you have to be at peace
with the possibility of imminent death
at any second.
And and the ship would would just touch,
you know, there's this mine and it's got
these horns sticking out and the wave
would come like this and the ship would
come like this and it would just touch
the horn, touch the edge of the horn of
this mine.
And curiously enough, I was at inner
peace that any instant
I may suddenly go to thee, oh Lord.
Amen.
And uh
taking taking the ship through a
typhoon, you know, at any second we the
inclinometer hit actually 90° which is
horizontal.
So, I'm standing on the wall, standing
on the bulkhead, steering the ship, and
at any moment we may explode from
hitting this mo mine or drown from the
typhoon going on. And so, I'm living
with the possibility of instant death.
And yet, I was completely at peace with
it. Completely surrendered. If you
explode, you explode.
>> If you drown, you drowned. If the ship
goes over, the ship goes over.
>> Do you remember when we were traveling
and we were going back to New York and
um the plane at the time the it never
gained altitude and we flew to
Albuquerque, New Mexico and when we had
a forced landing and there were uh fire
trucks lining the the runway and
everything and the Yeah. Do you remember
that? Anyway, there it was one of those
times and I can remember when the pilot
when the pilot came on and says we're
going to have to land in Albuquerque and
we and we just looked at each other
>> your seat belts.
>> Yeah. And we just looked at each other
and we had the most it was just like
okay if we go we go.
>> That's right. We're starting now's our
time to go. We're going to die. If
you're going to die now you die,
>> right?
>> So you accept the imminence and
possibility. In fact, even the
likelihood of sudden death. And yet,
you're completely at peace about it.
>> And we looked over at each other and we
grabbed each other's hands and you know,
the plane came down.
>> That's right. If we crash, we crash. And
if we don't don't, we don't.
>> So, there was peace, right? Oh, I see
what the point you're making.
Peace is possible right in the middle of
extreme danger.
>> Exactly. I mean, we were both we were
exposed to the imminence of likelihood
in fact of sudden death at any instant
>> and yet we were both at peace with it.
We looked at each other and said, "Well,
>> okay,
>> if we're going now, we're going now."
>> And that was it.
>> And there was no problem. So what's the
problem?
>> They both die, we die now.
And of course, we were dying together.
So that made it even more more, you
know, easy.
But uh during the war where I didn't
have a part partner, I accepted the fact
that we could blow up at any instant
>> and I felt a piece about it.
We came very close to close to exploding
and you was a piece about it. And I I
was at the wheel during the great
Okanawa typhoon which is a very famous
typhoon went on for three days and 90
ships 90 ships went down in the typhoon
and I was at the wheel for three days
and uh
and I would sleep for like 10 10 minutes
and then go back to the wheel for an
hour or two because I wasn't seasick.
Everybody was seasick and I uh I was
never seasick.
>> Yeah, you said it was. And uh so I just
kept going.
As I say, the ship was sideways. I was
standing on the bulkhead at 90 degrees.
Uh so you can be in the middle of
absolute extreme danger and be at peace.
And I was at totally at inner peace
about it. If you blow up, you blow up.
And if you do, you don't. And if you
don't, you don't. So
complete and total acceptance of the
totality of the experience
>> sudden death was not only possible it
was very likely
>> but you know in that in that uh in that
setting that I'm talking about on the
plane and we were sitting there I mean
>> you think about everyone going oh no oh
no in the plane and everybody was dead
silence it was just like eerie
>> I think everybody was praying too.
>> Yes, they had to. But everyone was It
was just dead silence.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Because they came around
said, "Prepare for a crash landing,
didn't they?"
>> Yes. And they told us that we'd have to
We had to bend over and put our head
between our legs.
>> Yes. At the buck of your seat belt.
>> Yeah.
>> You had to put your pillow on your lap,
>> right?
>> And put your head on your pillow,
>> And prepare for prepared to die. Really?
>> So, we looked at each other and held
each other. And we thought if we go and
we go and if we don't we don't.
>> So, and uh we didn't. Did we?
>> No.
>> I guess we did.
>> I guess we not. We're not. We're still
here.
>> But we were prepared.
>> Yeah.
>> But that was that's a very nice example.
And the plane tells you we're prepared
for a crash landing. Put your head on
your pillow.
And uh strangely enough,
profound state of peace comes to you
when you totally accept it. If you
resist it, you become frightened.
>> Mhm.
>> But when you totally accept the fear, it
disappears it. That's a very good
example. Yeah. The example between fear
and anxiety and life and death
>> and inner peace.
>> Yeah. And inner peace. Yeah.
We looked at each other and said, "If we
leave now, we're leaving now." So
If you live, you live. And if you die,
you die. That's it.
Total acceptance of the possibility of
the realities of existence brings about
an inner peace.
>> So even though there could be even
though there is chaos around you, um
there's still this inner peace that
prevails.
>> That's interesting. That's true. Just
like you in the ship, you know, this
horn was going to bump the ship and you
were gonna it was going to explode this
mine right next to the ship and you grab
the whatever gaffle or whatever it was
and say, "Okay, let's push it away.
You pushed it away."
>> That's I thought you Well, if we blow
up, we blow up and if we don't, we
don't.
>> Yeah. Absolutely.
>> So, I guess the fastest road to peace is
total acceptance
of the of the reality of how you're
experienc how however you're
experiencing reality at that moment.
The total acceptance of it brings peace
because every time we were near a plane
crash, they would say, "Put your head on
your pillow.
Um, you know, do this, that, and the
other." And we felt at peace. I wasn't
nervous. Were you?
>> No. Neither one of us. I looked at you
and thought, well, if we go, we go, and
if we don't, we don't.
>> Also, also though, I mean, we were we
were doing spiritual work, we were uh
speaking, you know, and um it was like,
okay, if if this is what God has for us,
it was acceptance, too,
>> you know,
>> but it doesn't necessarily have to be
couched in spiritual terms. No,
>> because during the war, I mean, you
know, when when it almost got exploded
off of mine, I I think I was an atheist
at the time.
>> I don't remember if I can anybody can we
use the arm?
>> No, you weren't an atheist at the time
of the war. It was after that, I think.
>> I said, can we use the arm or not?
During the six at the time, I believed
in God.
>> Oh, I did believe in God. Oh,
>> it was later.
>> Oh,
>> I think.
>> Mhm. But I'm just saying that um inner
peace is something that's there. You
just have to
>> discover that it's already present.
>> Um at least that's my understanding.
>> So you don't discover until you need it
and then you finally
>> experience that it's always been there.
>> Right.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Because it seems like it's there in
times of crisis when you really need it.
That inner peace and knowing is always
there.
Yeah, that's right. And the other
passengers were the same. They said,
"Put your head on your pillow. Prepare
for a crash landing."
>> I think they said, "Put a your head on
your lap." There wasn't any
>> Well, whatever it was, uh there wasn't
any widespread panic at all.
>> In fact, peace prevailed in the whole
cabin of that that airplane.
>> Mhm.
>> Nobody started to scream, "Help! Help!
Help!" There was no hysteria, no
screaming.
There was absolute peace and quiet.
Everybody put their head on their pillow
and prepared to die.
It was a very profound moment. Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> Mhm.
>> Um
do you think that um you can obtain an
inner peace by fulfilling a a goal or a
um task?
>> Is that inner peace or is that something
else? I no I think that's inner peace
where you set a goal for yourself and
then fulfill that goal
because it leaves nothing uh undone.
>> Inner peace is I have a certain
expectation in myself that as we sit
here you and I I will spontaneously be
honest to the my greatest capacity.
I may not be the most fluent. I I've
probably been more fluent at other
times,
but I um my inner expectation is that I
will feel completely secure, at ease,
and at one with you as we answer these
questions. And that I know I will be
doing the best that I possibly can do
under the circumstance.
>> Mh.
>> And that if I was capable of being more
uh eloquent or fluent, I would be. So I
how however whatever the potentiality I
have of being at this moment is being
fulfilled at this very moment. So I am
already becoming and have become the
complete fulfillment of my highest
expectations of myself that I will be
fluent and eloquent when I ask to to be
so or maybe useful to others
when making something useful with others
always adds value to me. you know, I do
a better job
>> I do a better job of something
>> if I know it's going to serve some other
purpose, you know.
>> So,
is there a certain amount of inner peace
when you donate your life to God?
>> Oh, I think to any
>> I think it brings a profound sense of
peace. Yes.
uh what I do now I ask God to help me do
it to the best of my ability
that I may thereby be serving God.
Uh
my obligation to divinity is to be the
fulfillment of
my own potentiality to the best of my
capacity.
>> Mhm.
>> To be as fluent as I can be
so that other other people's
understanding of it will be uh
aided and embedded by our discussing. So
our dis are discussing what this means
to us
brings the same question up in others.
What does my existence mean to me? What
does my existence mean to my wife? What
does my existence mean to my family
and to mankind? Am I being all that I
can be for the sake of mankind?
A lot of times I think of my own
existence as serving
a multitude of purposes simultaneously.
Mhm.
>> Um when in the eastern religions we have
meditative states and a lot of people
refer to that meditative state as their
inner peace.
>> Oh yes
>> state.
>> Yeah. So um would you say that
meditation is a form of inner peace or
is it just the
vessel that inner peace is brought forth
for us to recognize? Well, I think it's
both s is both simultaneously.
U
inner peace is a is a profound state.
>> Mhm.
>> Uh
true inner peace cannot be uh disturbed
by disturbance. As paradoxical as that
may sound,
>> uh, right now I feel I'm fulfilling what
I'm supposed to be doing with you to the
best of my ability
and nothing deserves that peace because
I know what that intention is.
>> Now, if I fail to achieve that
intention, I'm still going to stay at
peace because I did the best I could at
the time.
If I could have done better, I would
have. So I'm being as eloquent as I can
be at this moment under these
circumstances.
That doesn't mean that hypothetically I
couldn't be more eloquent at other
moments
uh or other other circumstances.
All right. So our overall intention
I think tends to dominate the quality of
the experience.
Um, my overall intention is to express
love for God, for you, for my fellow
human being, for the people here in the
room all simultaneously.
>> I love the photographer. I love the
witnesses. I love the people who help
move the furniture.
I I love the all that is at this moment
equally, you might say.
I don't love this wall more than I do
this window. There's like a totality
of um the love of that which exists.
The love of all that exists. So that to
me divinity is all that exists.
How however you may see it or experience
it is something else. again.
Mhm. Not but that does not influence the
absolute reality of it.
So you think I worry too much about the
doggy. So I say well worrying too much
about the doggy is the fulfillment of my
perfection.
The kind of person who worries too much
about the doggy.
That's perfectly who I am.
I worry about the kitties too and the
beauty.
>> Yeah.
>> And I worry about you
>> and I worry about our friends
>> and I worry about everybody sitting in
this room right this moment that each
one is
um being fulfilled in their expectations
and however
they might be benefited or uh by what we
say. So would you say that the state
that you feel when you are in a when
you're meditating that state that you
feel when you're meditating you know
it's very difficult to quiet the mind
but once you have that you have this
kind of peacefulness that comes over you
>> oh yeah that's a profound state of
>> that's a profound state all right so
this profound state of consciousness is
always there it's just we have to
recognize it within our own aura or
within our own being
>> yes to have it dominate in other words
Yeah.
>> Right.
>> Uhhuh.
>> You know, well, a lot of people want to
be in that state all the time. And I
think it's impossible to be in a
complete state of inner peace. I mean,
there's just it's unless you are a monk
or
>> no, you can be in that state of inner
peace every moment.
>> You can
>> once you're aware that it's there. Like
right now as I'm speaking to you, I'm
aware the cameras are grinding, that
there's a crew watching this, that it's
being recorded, etc. So you might say on
the surface that disturbs the piece.
>> Right?
>> On the other hand, within myself
is the reality that all of that is
irrelevant
and that my overall intention is the is
the reality of the moment. Okay? Whether
it's achieved or not is irre you know
not irrelevant but secondary.
>> So you talk about riding the quest the
crest of the wave.
>> Yeah that's it.
>> So what it is is not to expect
this or that to just be in that moment.
>> It's a way of being you know so it's not
a state from which you go from one thing
to another.
Yeah. Uh to me it's an overall intention
>> that colors everything
that I'll be as real as I can be about
the reality as I experience it from
moment to moment. So when we were in
that plane preparing to die, we put our
head on the pillow, we looked at each
other and there was a profound state of
peace.
>> Mhm.
>> If we die, we die. And if we don't, we
don't. And uh
so there we are facing sudden death and
at a state of profound peace at the very
moment that they're facing the
likelihood. It was it was a likelihood.
It wasn't just a remote possibility. It
was pretty much a likelihood.
>> Yeah. To pull out the fire engines along
the runway. I would say that might be
true.
>> It was a likelihood.
A likelihood of sudden death. And he
isn't. And yet we were at profound peace
with it.
>> I was very peaceful with you. It was
like our spirits were
became one.
>> And I suppose during such states the
presence of God is all that exists and
every aspect of one's own consciousness.
>> It's really just the awareness of the
presence of God that is
>> that is uh creating the overall effect.
So,
>> well, I look at that situation and I I
look at, you know, we could have
panicked, you know, you know, you could
have panicked, you could have done a lot
of things. Um, yet
we were, you know, at one with if this
happens, it happens. And if it's
supposed to be, it's supposed to be.
>> Mhm.
>> So,
that is a form of inner peace.
>> It was profound inner peace.
>> Yeah. Whether you live or die was
irrelevant.
>> Yeah.
>> So the experience of reality transcended
even the presence of life itself you
might say.
>> As paradoxical as that may sound
but you live or die whether we die this
instant or we don't die this instant all
became irrelevant.
Our experience of the reality of the
present moment was overwhelming.
>> So we were basically riding the crest of
that wave. That's where we were
>> where we were. Uh because we weren't
concerned with this or that. We were
just in that moment.
>> So we were so much with the the reality
of the moment it was almost
disappointing when we landed safely
>> and back to the usual anxieties.
>> How we going to catch my collar
straight?
>> Yeah. Or how we going to catch the next
plane out of here? You know, because we
had to switch right
>> planes and all this to catch the next
flight. had the piece of possibility of
sudden death and now you got the
anxieties of
>> normal life, you know,
>> everybody was crowding around trying to
get the next flight out. It was really
kind of wild.
>> Yeah.
So does permanent um how does one
uh
uh bring to life uh in them the the how
does one
um
live in permanent inner peace at all
times?
>> Just bringing up the question already
starts it going.
>> Okay. Um people it never crosses their
mind that you can be at peace
uh much less all of all the time. Uh
there are many people who don't know
what peace is never experienced it
except just as they go to sleep.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. And I have many patients lived in
24 247 anxiety you know about they're
always anxious upset depressed
regretful or fearful. Mhm.
>> And they never knew what inner peace
was. Therefore, tranquilizers did serve
a certain purpose
that because they began to experience
what it is to feel peace.
So tranquilizers I think u
pharmacolog you know ph pharmacologic
tranquilizers
um do serve a certain very practical
pragmatic use youthfulness
and you say oh this is what it feels
like to feel peaceful yes and you tell
people you know with a little inner
training and experience you can achieve
that state all the time.
>> Mhm. You know, just like if if this talk
goes well, it goes well. And if it
doesn't go well, then it doesn't go
well. And can I be peaceful if it
doesn't go well? No.
>> That's terrible.
>> Why not? Because it means I got to
repeat it until I get it to be to be the
way I want it to be. That's all mainly.
So inner peace is a state of mind or
presence that is with us at all times
and actually all of us have the ability
to tap into that whenever we really need
to if we are spiritual.
Um
>> well I would say is the potentiality is
there at all times.
>> Okay.
>> The experience of it is not there at all
times.
All right, that is true. Okay,
>> but when you become sophisticated,
you begin to recognize that that
profound sense of peacefulness is even
there is is there even when you're not
experiencing it consciously. Okay.
>> Even when you're upset, I was upset, but
that didn't really change the reality
that within myself there is that which
was not upsettable because
>> it can't be upset cuz it's not
upsettable,
>> right?
>> You know, just like I can't upset the
uh the space that we're sitting on on
the couch, you know, the space itself is
cannot be upset. that can merely obscure
it. But the space itself is is
immutable. It's
cannot be altered.
And then the fact that your
questions are going to bring up some
moment of temporary
uh apprehension or anxiety or god
concern I guess concern that I'm
answering the question as adequately as
I could.
Do you think that meditating
helps to make um your inner spirituality
more aware of that inner peace?
>> Do you think meditative states help to
um allow one to experience that inner
peace? I think I think the doing so as a
formality for instance brings it to your
conscious awareness
then you become aware that
you didn't realize it but that that is
really there at all times.
So right now what happens right now
would would disturb the emotional
uh
externalism of it.
>> Mhm.
>> But it wouldn't really affect the
internal peacefulness of it. The
internal peacefulness cannot be
disturbed
because that's an expression of the
presence of God within me as the
awareness of my own existence which
doesn't fluctuate from moment to moment.
But its expression would fluctuate. I
could say well I could have answered
that more eloquently
but that's thinkingness.
So thinkingness is has to be
differentiated
>> from uh peace of mind.
>> Thinkingness is the quickest way to
destroy peace of mind.
It takes years of practice to be able to
indulge in thinking this and maintain
peace of mind simultaneously.
So
most of the time I can do it. I can be
aware that I'm trying to be as eloquent
as I can be with you.
And um you know I say on a superficial
level apprehensive that I'm not being
but on an inner level it's not
disturbing any peace at all because the
reality of my existence and my intention
is not being altered by anything that
goes on in this room or anything that's
being said. So is um when we have say
compassion
for another person that's in you know
and um that's entirely different than
inner peace.
>> Yeah.
>> Um compassion is is a
>> it's not entirely different but it's a
different
>> it's a different example.
>> Well yeah you're good. You're right.
You're right. Um so I would classify as
inner pieces in a whole structure
of itself.
>> Oh yeah. Okay.
>> Um compassion is you know compassion you
feel for another one's hurt. It's a
different whole different thing.
>> But um that was a question someone had.
Is inner peace the same as compassion
which I feel that since we've talked
that it is not.
>> Compassion's in a whole different
category.
Well, you can feel compassion for
yourself as a human being.
I think everybody should have compassion
for themsel as a human being to realize
that being a human being is difficult.
>> Okay?
>> That you're deserving of uh certain love
and forgiveness
out of compassion for your own existence
as a human being.
I don't remember consciously asking to
be
or be born
>> or to be a child. I don't remember
consciously asking any of that. That all
occurred of itself spontaneously
without asking me about it.
>> I don't remember being asked, do you
want to do want to exist?
>> Do you want to be
do you want to experience life? I don't
know. Nobody ever asked me that. So
through
>> it was superimposed.
>> So through meditation we awaken the
inner peace but it could also be through
contemplation couldn't it?
>> Yes indeed.
>> Uh I mean it doesn't have to be
meditation. It could be
>> you know you're contemplating
uh a
a problem or a situation and
>> when the answer comes you have this
profound knowingness that is more or
less an inner peace.
>> Oh yeah.
In fact, you can be at pe at at inner,
you know, peaceful even when you're not
at peace.
>> You know, you can be very accepting of
whatever your state of consciousness is.
So overall, you're at peace with the
fact that you're upset. You know what
I'm saying? The par it may sound
paradoxical, right?
But when we're landing in a plane and it
may crash at any moment, the fact that
you feel fear come up at your solar
plexus
did not really affect your overall peace
because your overall peace accepted that
fearfulness of dying is coming up
because you're about about to crash and
about to die.
So there was on the one hand fear, there
was on the other hand a peace. If it
happens, it happens. If it doesn't, it
doesn't.
>> Mhm.
>> And I'm just being a human being.
>> A normal human being would feel fear as
they're about to crash. So you at peace
with that fearfulness was okay.
Uhhuh.
Okayesseness. H.
So, if you had something to say to
our people uh that are watching this um
about inner peace, what would your words
be?
to accept the
the the reality of one's level of
consciousness
at all times no matter what it might be.
To just accept whatever one's level of
consciousness is
accepting then not the content of
consciousness
but consciousness itself.
Uh so experientially and by looking at
it I'm aware of how consciousness
functions,
how it is, how it's experienced,
>> how it's perceived and I accept the
totality of that. So I can be at peace
with upsetness because I accept that
upsetness is appropriate at this moment.
Just like when we were afraid the plane
was about to crash. Mhm.
>> Um, we all accepted the fear, but nobody
felt upset that they were fearful,
>> right?
>> They just accepted that, yeah,
everybody's afraid they're about to
crash.
>> Mhm.
>> Because we were
few moments from death. Everybody was
facing a few moments from death
>> together. And there was a profound peace
in the plane. It was peculiar.
>> Quiet.
>> Whole plane full of people were about to
die. Everybody puts their head in their
lap and everybody's at peace with the
fact that we're about to die.
>> It was paradoxical. Wasn't that very
interesting phenomena?
>> Anybody who's looking at this has ever
been in that experience will know what
we're saying.
>> The stewardist comes around and says,
"Put your pillow on your lap. Put your
head on your pillow and stay there and
I'll tell you when it's safe to come
up." And somehow some kind of strange
peace prevails. Mhm.
>> Mhm.
Something in an inner knowingness or the
inner knowingness
within consciousness.
>> Mhm.
>> Which is really an expression of
divinity
as conscious awareness without
articulating it or thinkingness.
Uh so peace really comes when you
eliminate and transcend thinkingness.
Uh have no thoughts about it. So as I
talk to you right now, I have no
thoughts about it. If I stop and think
about it, then I'll create anxiety. Am I
saying what I want to say? Am I doing it
eloquently? Am I speaking clearly
enough? Is it being recorded properly?
The minute I stop and start asking
questions, I've I've lost the very thing
I was looking for.
So peace to me means accepting however
it is right now is however it is right
now. the fact that I might be more
eloquent. I might speak more loudly,
more clearly, better articulation.
Uh, I accept that that's all part of the
reality of human existence. And I don't
feel upset about it. I'm at peace with
the fact that I'm uh that peacefulness
is not a 100% all the time
uh prevailing dominant state of
consciousness.
It is and it isn't.
The fact that I accept it eliminates it
as real anxiety. So I can be at peace
with the fact that I feel anxiety. How's
that grab you?
That's a winner, baby. Hey, I can be at
peace with the fact that I'm not at
peace at all. There you go. Of course
you're upset, baby. Why not? You know,
you could stumble and make a fool of
yourself and sound like an idiot. Uh, so
I accept that.
And that's fine with me. That's true.
>> Okay.
>> Everybody, anybody who's ever spoken in
public knows what I we're talking about.
>> Yeah. Uhhuh.
>> Well, thank you. Thank you so much for
your thoughts on that.
>> Thank you for asking me.