I have two questions. Yep.
I have two questions. Yep. >> First one is uh my feel is of is the
>> First one is uh my feel is of is the
>> First one is uh my feel is of is the field of addictions. And many times I've
field of addictions. And many times I've
field of addictions. And many times I've heard over the years that people who get
heard over the years that people who get
heard over the years that people who get into drugs and alcohol and become
into drugs and alcohol and become
into drugs and alcohol and become addicted are on a negative path looking
addicted are on a negative path looking
addicted are on a negative path looking for spirituality.
for spirituality.
for spirituality. Um that's the first question. The second
Um that's the first question. The second
Um that's the first question. The second one I run a program called bridging the
one I run a program called bridging the
one I run a program called bridging the gaps and we
gaps and we
gaps and we >> yeah wait the first one was it's a
>> yeah wait the first one was it's a
>> yeah wait the first one was it's a negative pathway that's positionality
if it leads to God is hardly negative I
if it leads to God is hardly negative I would say it's the hard way to God
>> but you do you see it also as a as a
>> but you do you see it also as a as a spiritual path but uh the the slow route
spiritual path but uh the the slow route
spiritual path but uh the the slow route the slowboat
the slowboat
the slowboat >> addiction is the way of desperation It's
>> addiction is the way of desperation It's
>> addiction is the way of desperation It's choosing.
choosing.
choosing. See, with addiction, you got two
See, with addiction, you got two
See, with addiction, you got two choices. You either surrender to God or
choices. You either surrender to God or
choices. You either surrender to God or die.
die.
die. It's a oneway. You can't change your
It's a oneway. You can't change your
It's a oneway. You can't change your mind, get off the boat. It's a
mind, get off the boat. It's a
mind, get off the boat. It's a progressive disease. It takes you down
progressive disease. It takes you down
progressive disease. It takes you down to finally suicide, dementia.
to finally suicide, dementia.
to finally suicide, dementia. You don't have any choice. So, you
You don't have any choice. So, you
You don't have any choice. So, you either surrender to God or you die. Very
either surrender to God or you die. Very
either surrender to God or you die. Very strict pathway.
Second question is that ever since I
Second question is that ever since I discovered your book, I been trying to
discovered your book, I been trying to
discovered your book, I been trying to figure out how to incorporate
figure out how to incorporate
figure out how to incorporate the material into the program because we
the material into the program because we
the material into the program because we are holistically based and we're looking
are holistically based and we're looking
are holistically based and we're looking at a lot of different things. Acu detox
at a lot of different things. Acu detox
at a lot of different things. Acu detox and yoga and
and yoga and
and yoga and >> exercise. We've really focused on the
>> exercise. We've really focused on the
>> exercise. We've really focused on the physiology of addiction or
physiology of addiction or
physiology of addiction or >> what kind of addiction?
>> what kind of addiction?
>> what kind of addiction? >> Physiology or the biochemical aspect. So
>> Physiology or the biochemical aspect. So
>> Physiology or the biochemical aspect. So we're more in the the physical along
we're more in the the physical along
we're more in the the physical along with the 12step model and so forth. But
with the 12step model and so forth. But
with the 12step model and so forth. But I trying to and then then you said a few
I trying to and then then you said a few
I trying to and then then you said a few minutes ago that half the population is
minutes ago that half the population is
minutes ago that half the population is below 200. So you can't use that as far
below 200. So you can't use that as far
below 200. So you can't use that as far as kinesiology. So uh
as kinesiology. So uh
as kinesiology. So uh >> although I my experience has been
>> although I my experience has been
>> although I my experience has been overall that drug addicts and alcoholics
overall that drug addicts and alcoholics
overall that drug addicts and alcoholics at least the ones that get to treatment
at least the ones that get to treatment
at least the ones that get to treatment are usually above average at least the
are usually above average at least the
are usually above average at least the ones we treat. The disease uh is
ones we treat. The disease uh is
ones we treat. The disease uh is physical, mental and spiritual. And I
physical, mental and spiritual. And I
physical, mental and spiritual. And I believe you have to approach all three
believe you have to approach all three
believe you have to approach all three including nutrition,
including nutrition,
including nutrition, >> making sure they don't go into
>> making sure they don't go into
>> making sure they don't go into hypoglycemic uh relapse.
hypoglycemic uh relapse.
hypoglycemic uh relapse. I used to take them off sugar and sweets
I used to take them off sugar and sweets
I used to take them off sugar and sweets and put them on big doses of vitamins
and put them on big doses of vitamins
and put them on big doses of vitamins and send them to AA.
You done what you can.
You done what you can. >> But how would you specifically use what
>> But how would you specifically use what
>> But how would you specifically use what you speak of in in a program? Do you
you speak of in in a program? Do you
you speak of in in a program? Do you have any thoughts on that? I don't I
have any thoughts on that? I don't I
have any thoughts on that? I don't I send them day a they don't need
send them day a they don't need
send them day a they don't need >> we do also
>> we do also
>> we do also >> they don't need they don't need anything
>> they don't need they don't need anything
>> they don't need they don't need anything that I've got to say if they do the
that I've got to say if they do the
that I've got to say if they do the program
program
program >> because the third step you're
>> because the third step you're
>> because the third step you're surrendering everything to God as it
surrendering everything to God as it
surrendering everything to God as it arises
arises
arises including resisting the admitting the
including resisting the admitting the
including resisting the admitting the fact that you have an addiction
fact that you have an addiction
fact that you have an addiction >> well we have our difficulty we have one
>> well we have our difficulty we have one
>> well we have our difficulty we have one program that specializes in
program that specializes in
program that specializes in professionals so we get doctors lawyers
professionals so we get doctors lawyers
professionals so we get doctors lawyers and and they don't tend I mean we have a
and and they don't tend I mean we have a
and and they don't tend I mean we have a mixture but Many of them will not go to
mixture but Many of them will not go to
mixture but Many of them will not go to or will not
or will not
or will not do not want to incorporate anything to
do not want to incorporate anything to
do not want to incorporate anything to do with AA in their program.
do with AA in their program.
do with AA in their program. >> That's pridefulness.
>> That's pridefulness.
>> That's pridefulness. >> I definitely agree with that.
>> I definitely agree with that.
>> I definitely agree with that. >> So I tell them you got
>> So I tell them you got
>> So I tell them you got humility in life or pride in death. I
humility in life or pride in death. I
humility in life or pride in death. I don't care which choice you make.
don't care which choice you make.
don't care which choice you make. >> I like that.
>> I like that.
>> I like that. >> I mean I don't give a damn whether you
>> I mean I don't give a damn whether you
>> I mean I don't give a damn whether you live or die. You know what I mean? It's
live or die. You know what I mean? It's
live or die. You know what I mean? It's something to you. to me. You don't mean
something to you. to me. You don't mean
something to you. to me. You don't mean nickels.
nickels.
nickels. >> I like that answer. Thank you.
Uh
Uh >> thank you for this opportunity.
>> thank you for this opportunity.
>> thank you for this opportunity. >> That's the zen of it.
>> We've spoken of intentions here today.
>> We've spoken of intentions here today. Can you explain the difference between
Can you explain the difference between
Can you explain the difference between goals and intentions and whether or not
goals and intentions and whether or not
goals and intentions and whether or not the visualization process or how
the visualization process or how
the visualization process or how important the visualization process is
important the visualization process is
important the visualization process is to the fulfillment of goals?
to the fulfillment of goals?
to the fulfillment of goals? >> Visualization has to do with form.
>> Visualization has to do with form.
>> Visualization has to do with form. Uh form is not uh you know necessarily a
Uh form is not uh you know necessarily a
Uh form is not uh you know necessarily a spiritual goal. That's a worldly goal.
A goal is a ending place.
A goal is a ending place. I go from here. I've reached my goal.
I go from here. I've reached my goal.
I go from here. I've reached my goal. I'm done.
Intention is a direction of life. And
Intention is a direction of life. And you can't achieve any goal. There isn't
you can't achieve any goal. There isn't
you can't achieve any goal. There isn't any goal. It's like you decided to keep
any goal. It's like you decided to keep
any goal. It's like you decided to keep going east. So long as you keep going
going east. So long as you keep going
going east. So long as you keep going east,
east,
east, your goal is already fulfilled.
your goal is already fulfilled.
your goal is already fulfilled. I say, are you going east? Yep. Well,
I say, are you going east? Yep. Well,
I say, are you going east? Yep. Well, that was your intention. So you've
that was your intention. So you've
that was your intention. So you've already achieved your goal to go east.
already achieved your goal to go east.
already achieved your goal to go east. If your decision is to go the spiritual
If your decision is to go the spiritual
If your decision is to go the spiritual pathway, then you've already achieved
pathway, then you've already achieved
pathway, then you've already achieved that.
that.
that. What you mean is it's ultimate. You
What you mean is it's ultimate. You
What you mean is it's ultimate. You know, it's ultimate
know, it's ultimate
know, it's ultimate is what you're really talking about,
is what you're really talking about,
is what you're really talking about, right?
right?
right? Yeah. It's al ultimate.
All God asks of you is that you set the
All God asks of you is that you set the compass in a spiritually integrous
compass in a spiritually integrous
compass in a spiritually integrous direction. That's the only thing he
direction. That's the only thing he
direction. That's the only thing he asks.
asks.
asks. Nothing else is asked.
Nothing else is asked.
Nothing else is asked. >> Is it not beneficial to have
>> Is it not beneficial to have
>> Is it not beneficial to have in in this worldly form in in the world
in in this worldly form in in the world
in in this worldly form in in the world a a I want to say a direction yes an
a a I want to say a direction yes an
a a I want to say a direction yes an intention but but that which we want we
intention but but that which we want we
intention but but that which we want we want to attain that which we want to go
want to attain that which we want to go
want to attain that which we want to go to not just
to not just
to not just >> if you what you hold in mind tends to
>> if you what you hold in mind tends to
>> if you what you hold in mind tends to actualize that's a fact.
actualize that's a fact.
actualize that's a fact. You just hold in mind a picture of what
You just hold in mind a picture of what
You just hold in mind a picture of what you feel would be the fulfillment
you feel would be the fulfillment
you feel would be the fulfillment without desiring it
without desiring it
without desiring it without trying to make it happen.
without trying to make it happen.
without trying to make it happen. You you picture every place I've ever
You you picture every place I've ever
You you picture every place I've ever lived, I would picture what I picture
lived, I would picture what I picture
lived, I would picture what I picture would be ideal, but not crave it or want
would be ideal, but not crave it or want
would be ideal, but not crave it or want it or desire it.
it or desire it.
it or desire it. And each time
And each time
And each time there would be a phone call and it would
there would be a phone call and it would
there would be a phone call and it would say, "Hey, place next to me right along
say, "Hey, place next to me right along
say, "Hey, place next to me right along the creek is up for sale."
the creek is up for sale."
the creek is up for sale." And you're the only one I want to live
And you're the only one I want to live
And you're the only one I want to live next to me. Anyway, so I came and looked
next to me. Anyway, so I came and looked
next to me. Anyway, so I came and looked at it. I was thinking of a little a
at it. I was thinking of a little a
at it. I was thinking of a little a little place out in the woods next to
little place out in the woods next to
little place out in the woods next to the creek. See, same thing happened back
the creek. See, same thing happened back
the creek. See, same thing happened back east. I was thinking, you know, of acres
east. I was thinking, you know, of acres
east. I was thinking, you know, of acres of woods, you know,
of woods, you know,
of woods, you know, building a certain kind of house in the
building a certain kind of house in the
building a certain kind of house in the middle of it. So you just picture it.
middle of it. So you just picture it.
middle of it. So you just picture it. What you hold in mind tends to
What you hold in mind tends to
What you hold in mind tends to actualize.
actualize.
actualize. But it's up to many karmic
But it's up to many karmic
But it's up to many karmic propensities and other things whether
propensities and other things whether
propensities and other things whether you unconsciously feel that you deserve
you unconsciously feel that you deserve
you unconsciously feel that you deserve this. Many things have to be resolved.
this. Many things have to be resolved.
this. Many things have to be resolved. But it tends to come about as you
But it tends to come about as you
But it tends to come about as you picture it.
picture it.
picture it. >> Okay?
>> Okay?
>> Okay? But without trying to force it or or
But without trying to force it or or
But without trying to force it or or make it happen,
>> let it go.
>> let it go. >> It's more like you. Yes. It's more like
>> It's more like you. Yes. It's more like
>> It's more like you. Yes. It's more like you picture
you picture
you picture that's for you. You know what I mean?
that's for you. You know what I mean?
that's for you. You know what I mean? You hold it as a loving picture in your
You hold it as a loving picture in your
You hold it as a loving picture in your mind that what you admire or cherish and
mind that what you admire or cherish and
mind that what you admire or cherish and try to let go the solar plexus
try to let go the solar plexus
try to let go the solar plexus wantingness of it.
wantingness of it.
wantingness of it. Thank you, sir.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you, sir. >> The other is to drive it with greed and
>> The other is to drive it with greed and
>> The other is to drive it with greed and kill everybody in your way.
>> Um, once we have once we have become
>> Um, once we have once we have become enlightened, are we free from suffering
enlightened, are we free from suffering
enlightened, are we free from suffering for all eternity? Are we done?
You don't have to worry about all of
You don't have to worry about all of eternity.
The Buddha said,
The Buddha said, "Human life is sickness, old age,
"Human life is sickness, old age,
"Human life is sickness, old age, suffering, and death." And it's due to
suffering, and death." And it's due to
suffering, and death." And it's due to constantly recycling back and forth by
constantly recycling back and forth by
constantly recycling back and forth by identifying the self as mind and body.
identifying the self as mind and body.
identifying the self as mind and body. To transcend that illusion that you are
To transcend that illusion that you are
To transcend that illusion that you are the mind or that you are the body. to
the mind or that you are the body. to
the mind or that you are the body. to let go of cravingness and wantingness
let go of cravingness and wantingness
let go of cravingness and wantingness which binds you to the wheel of rebirth
which binds you to the wheel of rebirth
which binds you to the wheel of rebirth and reincarnation.
and reincarnation.
and reincarnation. If you let that go, you need not be
If you let that go, you need not be
If you let that go, you need not be reborn again and physicality.
That good enough?
That good enough? >> But I never argued with I think Okay.
>> But I never argued with I think Okay.
>> But I never argued with I think Okay. >> After you've escaped after you've
>> After you've escaped after you've
>> After you've escaped after you've escaped the birth death cycle.
escaped the birth death cycle.
escaped the birth death cycle. >> Yes. Um, do you ever suffer again after
>> Yes. Um, do you ever suffer again after
>> Yes. Um, do you ever suffer again after that? I mean, because Jesus I thought
that? I mean, because Jesus I thought
that? I mean, because Jesus I thought after you became enlightened and escaped
after you became enlightened and escaped
after you became enlightened and escaped the karmic cycle that life was eternal
the karmic cycle that life was eternal
the karmic cycle that life was eternal paradise or you didn't have any more
paradise or you didn't have any more
paradise or you didn't have any more work to do.
work to do.
work to do. >> I don't quite get the gist of the
>> I don't quite get the gist of the
>> I don't quite get the gist of the question. What happens to you after
question. What happens to you after
question. What happens to you after you're enlightened?
you're enlightened?
you're enlightened? >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> There isn't any one for thing something
>> There isn't any one for thing something
>> There isn't any one for thing something to happen to. You see, you're begging
to happen to. You see, you're begging
to happen to. You see, you're begging the question after you are you you are
the question after you are you you are
the question after you are you you are not anyone anymore. What happens to that
not anyone anymore. What happens to that
not anyone anymore. What happens to that one that is no more? He doesn't exist.
one that is no more? He doesn't exist.
one that is no more? He doesn't exist. End the problem.
End the problem.
End the problem. Thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you. After sugar dissolves in water
After sugar dissolves in water
After sugar dissolves in water doesn't have any problem with sugar
doesn't have any problem with sugar
doesn't have any problem with sugar anymore.
Uh
Uh I've been getting the impression I guess
I've been getting the impression I guess
I've been getting the impression I guess by reading partly Omar
by reading partly Omar
by reading partly Omar Sharif Abdullah is is one person that
Sharif Abdullah is is one person that
Sharif Abdullah is is one person that wrote a book recently that kind of
wrote a book recently that kind of
wrote a book recently that kind of states it very well that that there's a
states it very well that that there's a
states it very well that that there's a definite threat to the biosphere from
definite threat to the biosphere from
definite threat to the biosphere from our over production and and then not
our over production and and then not
our over production and and then not watching out what's going on and
watching out what's going on and
watching out what's going on and also that the part of the solution
also that the part of the solution
also that the part of the solution is a shift in myth.
is a shift in myth.
is a shift in myth. to where we see that we're one family on
to where we see that we're one family on
to where we see that we're one family on one world away from the the perception
one world away from the the perception
one world away from the the perception that we're all these separate nations
that we're all these separate nations
that we're all these separate nations and are against each other and and and
and are against each other and and and
and are against each other and and and do you uh have found any resonance with
do you uh have found any resonance with
do you uh have found any resonance with this or is that something that's in your
this or is that something that's in your
this or is that something that's in your concerns or
concerns or
concerns or do you get you get the gist of it?
do you get you get the gist of it?
do you get you get the gist of it? What's the gist?
>> Oh, well,
>> Oh, well, >> it's the other way around.
>> it's the other way around.
>> it's the other way around. >> Yeah. that that uh we see a coming uh a
>> Yeah. that that uh we see a coming uh a
>> Yeah. that that uh we see a coming uh a problem with the earth and that that the
problem with the earth and that that the
problem with the earth and that that the solution is in in a shift in the in the
solution is in in a shift in the in the
solution is in in a shift in the in the uh myth.
uh myth.
uh myth. >> You see that the the way to be as a
>> You see that the the way to be as a
>> You see that the the way to be as a spiritual person
spiritual person
spiritual person is respectful of the sacredness of all
is respectful of the sacredness of all
is respectful of the sacredness of all of life.
of life.
of life. And then from that respect for the
And then from that respect for the
And then from that respect for the sacredness of all of life, certain
sacredness of all of life, certain
sacredness of all of life, certain actions automatically follow that are
actions automatically follow that are
actions automatically follow that are aligned with that intention.
Yes.
Yes. Uh
Uh
Uh it just seems that there's a crisis
it just seems that there's a crisis
it just seems that there's a crisis right now and if we don't have a certain
right now and if we don't have a certain
right now and if we don't have a certain amount of increased spiritual
amount of increased spiritual
amount of increased spiritual perception of of honoring the sacredness
perception of of honoring the sacredness
perception of of honoring the sacredness that we'll really have a bad mess up.
that we'll really have a bad mess up.
that we'll really have a bad mess up. You see the distribution of the
You see the distribution of the
You see the distribution of the consciousness level of mankind
consciousness level of mankind
consciousness level of mankind goes from
goes from
goes from let's take the green river pillar
let's take the green river pillar
let's take the green river pillar probably around 30 calibrated
probably around 30 calibrated
probably around 30 calibrated consciousness of about 30
consciousness of about 30
consciousness of about 30 and it goes all the way up to a
and it goes all the way up to a
and it goes all the way up to a thousand.
So
So included in that immense straddle
All possibility.
All possibility. I think I sort of answered your question
I think I sort of answered your question
I think I sort of answered your question earlier. If this was meant to be a
earlier. If this was meant to be a
earlier. If this was meant to be a celestial realm, it would be.
celestial realm, it would be.
celestial realm, it would be. Neither one of us would probably be
Neither one of us would probably be
Neither one of us would probably be here.
It's not a celestial realm.
It's not a celestial realm. Not supposed to be a celestial realm.
Not supposed to be a celestial realm.
Not supposed to be a celestial realm. Everybody who tries to impose their will
Everybody who tries to impose their will
Everybody who tries to impose their will on it and force it into being a
on it and force it into being a
on it and force it into being a celestial realm is following some kind
celestial realm is following some kind
celestial realm is following some kind of a spiritual illusion.
of a spiritual illusion.
of a spiritual illusion. That's a fact. Resist.
That's a fact. Resist.
That's a fact. Resist. >> That's true. The the damage could be
>> That's true. The the damage could be
>> That's true. The the damage could be repaired in several more of millennia.
repaired in several more of millennia.
repaired in several more of millennia. So we have we have a whole stratified
So we have we have a whole stratified
So we have we have a whole stratified set of choices
set of choices
set of choices and that's how we work out our karma. So
and that's how we work out our karma. So
and that's how we work out our karma. So this is a gymnasium a school
a purgatorial opportunity
a purgatorial opportunity >> and the class as a whole race can go
>> and the class as a whole race can go
>> and the class as a whole race can go boom boom boom several steps back and
boom boom boom several steps back and
boom boom boom several steps back and have a long way back or the class as a
have a long way back or the class as a
have a long way back or the class as a whole race can go squeeze through to the
whole race can go squeeze through to the
whole race can go squeeze through to the next level. That's where I think we are.
next level. That's where I think we are.
next level. That's where I think we are. take different forms. Yeah.
>> Dr. Hawkins, I had an experience much
>> Dr. Hawkins, I had an experience much like the one you talked about in the
like the one you talked about in the
like the one you talked about in the snowbank and um following that
snowbank and um following that
snowbank and um following that experience for three days, I felt
experience for three days, I felt
experience for three days, I felt somewhat assaulted by uh
somewhat assaulted by uh
somewhat assaulted by uh darker entities and
darker entities and
darker entities and felt looking back that I needed to stay
felt looking back that I needed to stay
felt looking back that I needed to stay in that physical space within that
in that physical space within that
in that physical space within that eternal space in order to achieve the
eternal space in order to achieve the
eternal space in order to achieve the goal that I've been seeking. and left
goal that I've been seeking. and left
goal that I've been seeking. and left that physical space for reasons that I
that physical space for reasons that I
that physical space for reasons that I wasn't really aware of just kind of
wasn't really aware of just kind of
wasn't really aware of just kind of happened. Um,
since then the although I've had a
since then the although I've had a pretty significant shift of my sense of
pretty significant shift of my sense of
pretty significant shift of my sense of identity, there still is a definite
identity, there still is a definite
identity, there still is a definite sense of ego. My question is once
sense of ego. My question is once
sense of ego. My question is once that space is or that state of
that space is or that state of
that space is or that state of consciousness is experienced, is it just
consciousness is experienced, is it just
consciousness is experienced, is it just a matter of remaining there? Uh cuz it
a matter of remaining there? Uh cuz it
a matter of remaining there? Uh cuz it seemed like there was a complete
seemed like there was a complete
seemed like there was a complete >> No, it usually doesn't stay. It usually
>> No, it usually doesn't stay. It usually
>> No, it usually doesn't stay. It usually doesn't stay. Uh near-death experiences,
doesn't stay. Uh near-death experiences,
doesn't stay. Uh near-death experiences, transitory states of illumination,
transitory states of illumination,
transitory states of illumination, uh are usually not permanent. They
uh are usually not permanent. They
uh are usually not permanent. They usually come and go,
but they inspire you. It's like you get
but they inspire you. It's like you get a a glimpse of a a glimpse ahead.
a a glimpse of a a glimpse ahead.
a a glimpse of a a glimpse ahead. >> You see what's possible
>> You see what's possible
>> You see what's possible and they be they become inspirational.
and they be they become inspirational.
and they be they become inspirational. But I think Ramana Maharash is a gadana
But I think Ramana Maharash is a gadana
But I think Ramana Maharash is a gadana maharaj. All those will agree that in
maharaj. All those will agree that in
maharaj. All those will agree that in the beginning they may come as a state
the beginning they may come as a state
the beginning they may come as a state of illumination and then leave. The
of illumination and then leave. The
of illumination and then leave. The Christian literature of the saints is
Christian literature of the saints is
Christian literature of the saints is also full of that.
also full of that.
also full of that. Oh my beloved, how could thou have left
Oh my beloved, how could thou have left
Oh my beloved, how could thou have left me? The angels I mean you know the dove
me? The angels I mean you know the dove
me? The angels I mean you know the dove soaring and then uh down now down near
soaring and then uh down now down near
soaring and then uh down now down near the earth feeling Chris fallen.
the earth feeling Chris fallen.
the earth feeling Chris fallen. It's like you rise above your karma and
It's like you rise above your karma and
It's like you rise above your karma and go into a botific state, but then your
go into a botific state, but then your
go into a botific state, but then your negative karma catches up with you
negative karma catches up with you
negative karma catches up with you again.
Therefore, one works harder and let's go
Therefore, one works harder and let's go wanting to return to that state.
wanting to return to that state.
wanting to return to that state. Forget returning to that state
Forget returning to that state
Forget returning to that state because it cannot be brought back. It's
because it cannot be brought back. It's
because it cannot be brought back. It's not valitional. It's not within the
not valitional. It's not within the
not valitional. It's not within the province of will.
Lead the most spiritually pure life you
Lead the most spiritually pure life you can. And if providenc
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Yeah. You rise above your bed. That's
>> Yeah. You rise above your bed. That's
>> Yeah. You rise above your bed. That's what I
>> Hi. Um earlier today you mentioned in
>> Hi. Um earlier today you mentioned in your lecture that um over 200 we come
your lecture that um over 200 we come
your lecture that um over 200 we come into this life with a particular karmic
into this life with a particular karmic
into this life with a particular karmic identification and there's also a
identification and there's also a
identification and there's also a predetermined exit moment. So we really
predetermined exit moment. So we really
predetermined exit moment. So we really don't need to have fear about that
don't need to have fear about that
don't need to have fear about that moment of death. But you also talked
moment of death. But you also talked
moment of death. But you also talked about a few instances in your life when
about a few instances in your life when
about a few instances in your life when you were kind of at the a turning point
you were kind of at the a turning point
you were kind of at the a turning point where it seemed like you could or when
where it seemed like you could or when
where it seemed like you could or when you were 14, you talked about possibly
you were 14, you talked about possibly
you were 14, you talked about possibly choosing to stay or to leave.
choosing to stay or to leave.
choosing to stay or to leave. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> And I've heard other people, you know,
>> And I've heard other people, you know,
>> And I've heard other people, you know, who had near-death experiences talk
who had near-death experiences talk
who had near-death experiences talk about they felt like
about they felt like
about they felt like >> you don't hear from them again.
>> you don't hear from them again.
>> you don't hear from them again. >> That's true. That's true. So, I mean, is
>> That's true. That's true. So, I mean, is
>> That's true. That's true. So, I mean, is is it really completely predetermined?
is it really completely predetermined?
is it really completely predetermined? Are are there instances where you
Are are there instances where you
Are are there instances where you actually do have a choice sometimes?
actually do have a choice sometimes?
actually do have a choice sometimes? >> A choice about what?
>> A choice about what?
>> A choice about what? >> About whether to leave or to stay
>> About whether to leave or to stay
>> About whether to leave or to stay >> if our work is finished.
>> if our work is finished.
>> if our work is finished. >> Leave or stay.
>> Leave or stay.
>> Leave or stay. >> Yeah. Stay. As it seemed like you did
>> Yeah. Stay. As it seemed like you did
>> Yeah. Stay. As it seemed like you did when you were 14 and and felt that your
when you were 14 and and felt that your
when you were 14 and and felt that your father wasn't ready to have you leave.
father wasn't ready to have you leave.
father wasn't ready to have you leave. >> Well, you see, uh you you you neither
>> Well, you see, uh you you you neither
>> Well, you see, uh you you you neither win nor lose. No matter which decision
win nor lose. No matter which decision
win nor lose. No matter which decision you make,
you make,
you make, >> it doesn't really matter.
>> it doesn't really matter.
>> it doesn't really matter. >> Mhm. They're really both the same,
>> Mhm. They're really both the same,
>> Mhm. They're really both the same, although that's very hard to see
>> in terms of um whether a person's time
>> in terms of um whether a person's time of exit is predetermined.
of exit is predetermined.
of exit is predetermined. Is that then I guess it doesn't matter.
Is that then I guess it doesn't matter.
Is that then I guess it doesn't matter. And you're saying
And you're saying
And you're saying >> the time is
>> the time is
>> the time is >> well it has to do with the intention at
>> well it has to do with the intention at
>> well it has to do with the intention at the time and the karmic propensities and
the time and the karmic propensities and
the time and the karmic propensities and whether that was one of your purposes in
whether that was one of your purposes in
whether that was one of your purposes in this reincarnation
this reincarnation
this reincarnation etc.
etc.
etc. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> So it's a rather complicated issue. It
>> So it's a rather complicated issue. It
>> So it's a rather complicated issue. It would take some research.
would take some research.
would take some research. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> And past life recall and all to get what
>> And past life recall and all to get what
>> And past life recall and all to get what the significance was. Mhm.
the significance was. Mhm.
the significance was. Mhm. >> The choosing this was
>> The choosing this was
>> The choosing this was each time in the interest of love as
each time in the interest of love as
each time in the interest of love as love was understood at that time.
love was understood at that time.
love was understood at that time. >> So the understanding of love to a
>> So the understanding of love to a
>> So the understanding of love to a 14year-old boy would be somewhat
14year-old boy would be somewhat
14year-old boy would be somewhat different than at age 75.
different than at age 75.
different than at age 75. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> See?
>> See?
>> See? >> Right.
>> Right.
>> Right. So the comprehension the way it's
So the comprehension the way it's
So the comprehension the way it's contextualized would be different
contextualized would be different
contextualized would be different therefore different karmic consequences.
If one case to say is sacrificial
If one case to say is sacrificial another case to leave is sacrificial.
another case to leave is sacrificial.
another case to leave is sacrificial. >> Right.
>> Right.
>> Right. >> See
>> See
>> See >> right. So do we have a choice of whether
>> right. So do we have a choice of whether
>> right. So do we have a choice of whether or not
or not
or not >> Oh yeah choice
>> Oh yeah choice
>> Oh yeah choice >> the choice of sacrifice.
>> the choice of sacrifice.
>> the choice of sacrifice. >> You have a choice.
>> You have a choice.
>> You have a choice. >> You can either breathe or not breathe.
>> You can either breathe or not breathe.
>> You can either breathe or not breathe. >> You don't have to breathe. That state
>> You don't have to breathe. That state
>> You don't have to breathe. That state it's not necessary to breathe.
it's not necessary to breathe.
it's not necessary to breathe. Everything stops. Don't have to eat.
Everything stops. Don't have to eat.
Everything stops. Don't have to eat. Don't have to go to the bathroom. Don't
Don't have to go to the bathroom. Don't
Don't have to go to the bathroom. Don't have to breathe. Nothing.
>> to you know retain the body or not
>> to you know retain the body or not >> and because your mind is silent you
>> and because your mind is silent you
>> and because your mind is silent you can't think about it
can't think about it
can't think about it doesn't think about it
doesn't think about it
doesn't think about it therefore
therefore
therefore >> I ask
>> I ask
>> I ask >> the choosingness
>> the choosingness
>> the choosingness oops
oops
oops >> the choosingness
>> the choosingness
>> the choosingness comes out of nothingness
Because there's nothing but silence. The
Because there's nothing but silence. The choosingness happens of its own.
choosingness happens of its own.
choosingness happens of its own. It isn't I that chose to breathe. The
It isn't I that chose to breathe. The
It isn't I that chose to breathe. The choosing this chose to breathe.
Um
Um this book is for a friend of mine who's
this book is for a friend of mine who's
this book is for a friend of mine who's turning 60 and he's on the faculty and
turning 60 and he's on the faculty and
turning 60 and he's on the faculty and the board of directors of the Gestalt
the board of directors of the Gestalt
the board of directors of the Gestalt Institute in Cleveland. And when he read
Institute in Cleveland. And when he read
Institute in Cleveland. And when he read your book the first time, he was so
your book the first time, he was so
your book the first time, he was so moved by it, he bought a case and
moved by it, he bought a case and
moved by it, he bought a case and invited all the faculty to to read this
invited all the faculty to to read this
invited all the faculty to to read this book. And
book. And
book. And >> what's his name? I should say to so and
>> what's his name? I should say to so and
>> what's his name? I should say to so and so.
so.
so. >> His name is Yeah.
>> His name is Yeah.
>> His name is Yeah. >> to my dear friend Josh. What's his name?
>> to my dear friend Josh. What's his name?
>> to my dear friend Josh. What's his name? >> That's close. It's um John Carter.
>> That's close. It's um John Carter.
>> That's close. It's um John Carter. >> Huh?
>> Huh?
>> Huh? >> John Carter.
>> John Carter.
>> John Carter. >> John Carter.
>> John Carter. >> Carter.
>> Carter.
>> Carter. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Like president.
>> Like president.
>> Like president. Like President
Like President
Like President >> Yes. How about
>> Yes. How about
>> Yes. How about >> only John Carter? Yeah.
>> only John Carter? Yeah.
>> only John Carter? Yeah. >> Carter.
>> Carter.
>> Carter. >> Like Cartier.
>> Oh, you mean the Cartier? Oh, of course
>> Oh, you mean the Cartier? Oh, of course I know what you mean.
I know what you mean.
I know what you mean. >> Thank you.
>> Well,
>> Well, >> hi. Um, you state in your book that uh
>> hi. Um, you state in your book that uh
>> hi. Um, you state in your book that uh the Buddha taught enlightenment and that
the Buddha taught enlightenment and that
the Buddha taught enlightenment and that Christ taught salvation. Is there a
Christ taught salvation. Is there a
Christ taught salvation. Is there a distinction between the two?
distinction between the two?
distinction between the two? >> And what?
salvation
salvation is the celestial realm.
is the celestial realm.
is the celestial realm. Love is 500. Calibrates 500.
Love is 500. Calibrates 500.
Love is 500. Calibrates 500. Unconditional love calibrates at 540.
Unconditional love calibrates at 540.
Unconditional love calibrates at 540. No. Enlightenment calibrates at 600 and
No. Enlightenment calibrates at 600 and
No. Enlightenment calibrates at 600 and over.
over.
over. So it's like u
So it's like u
So it's like u more advanced destination
more advanced destination
more advanced destination to shoot for. It's also far more arduous
to shoot for. It's also far more arduous
to shoot for. It's also far more arduous and far less likely to be accomplished.
Lotus land Buddhism and Christianity are
Lotus land Buddhism and Christianity are both like practical. It's like the
both like practical. It's like the
both like practical. It's like the negativity, the gravitation of the
negativity, the gravitation of the
negativity, the gravitation of the negativity on this planet is so intense.
negativity on this planet is so intense.
negativity on this planet is so intense. The provocation is so continuous. I
The provocation is so continuous. I
The provocation is so continuous. I mean, the media hit you with it
mean, the media hit you with it
mean, the media hit you with it constantly. Fallacy, rhetoric,
constantly. Fallacy, rhetoric,
constantly. Fallacy, rhetoric, distortion, positionality, emotional
distortion, positionality, emotional
distortion, positionality, emotional manipulation, glamorization.
manipulation, glamorization.
manipulation, glamorization. It's a ceaseless barrage
It's a ceaseless barrage
It's a ceaseless barrage that the likelihood of also leading an
that the likelihood of also leading an
that the likelihood of also leading an ordinary life is staying alive as a
ordinary life is staying alive as a
ordinary life is staying alive as a human being and becoming a light that's
human being and becoming a light that's
human being and becoming a light that's practically zilch. So
practically zilch. So
practically zilch. So Jesus says get real and Islam Buddhism
Jesus says get real and Islam Buddhism
Jesus says get real and Islam Buddhism says get real
says get real
says get real become as pure a human being as you can
become as pure a human being as you can
become as pure a human being as you can and still live like a family life and
and still live like a family life and
and still live like a family life and living so and so.
living so and so.
living so and so. And if you're it's because of your
And if you're it's because of your
And if you're it's because of your alignment, your intention, devotion to
alignment, your intention, devotion to
alignment, your intention, devotion to Jesus Christ as your savior, he then
Jesus Christ as your savior, he then
Jesus Christ as your savior, he then becomes your advocate.
becomes your advocate.
becomes your advocate. And you might say the judges of justice
And you might say the judges of justice
And you might say the judges of justice hold
hold
hold on the scale, huh? The weight of what
on the scale, huh? The weight of what
on the scale, huh? The weight of what you've done. And the Christ speaks for
you've done. And the Christ speaks for
you've done. And the Christ speaks for you and says, "But in my name did she
you and says, "But in my name did she
you and says, "But in my name did she ask for your help, oh Lord."
ask for your help, oh Lord."
ask for your help, oh Lord." So by that
So by that
So by that one is the benefit of grace. The grace
one is the benefit of grace. The grace
one is the benefit of grace. The grace of the savior then is that he is the
of the savior then is that he is the
of the savior then is that he is the advocate for your intention.
advocate for your intention.
advocate for your intention. So as you left this lifetime she may not
So as you left this lifetime she may not
So as you left this lifetime she may not have accomplished her ultimate goal but
have accomplished her ultimate goal but
have accomplished her ultimate goal but she has made a stated intention and
she has made a stated intention and
she has made a stated intention and therefore you merit admission to this
therefore you merit admission to this
therefore you merit admission to this celestial realm called heaven.
celestial realm called heaven.
celestial realm called heaven. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. enlightenment there would be nobody
enlightenment there would be nobody
enlightenment there would be nobody there to be spoken for.
I have two questions. The first question
I have two questions. The first question has to do with the chakras and I'm
has to do with the chakras and I'm
has to do with the chakras and I'm wondering if they how they or if they um
wondering if they how they or if they um
wondering if they how they or if they um can be found on the in the levels of
can be found on the in the levels of
can be found on the in the levels of consciousness where they
consciousness where they
consciousness where they >> preferably roughly comparable. The base
>> preferably roughly comparable. The base
>> preferably roughly comparable. The base chakra, as I say, if you get down to the
chakra, as I say, if you get down to the
chakra, as I say, if you get down to the bottom of apathy, the energy has left
bottom of apathy, the energy has left
bottom of apathy, the energy has left the base chakra and you just lay there
the base chakra and you just lay there
the base chakra and you just lay there in apathy, you don't even have the
in apathy, you don't even have the
in apathy, you don't even have the energy to feed yourself. That's apathy.
energy to feed yourself. That's apathy.
energy to feed yourself. That's apathy. The base chakra is blown out.
The base chakra is blown out.
The base chakra is blown out. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> You get up to higher levels, you get up
>> You get up to higher levels, you get up
>> You get up to higher levels, you get up to the
to the
to the spleen. Uh you get to hatred.
spleen. Uh you get to hatred.
spleen. Uh you get to hatred. The
The
The al-Qaeda operates out of the spleen. Out
al-Qaeda operates out of the spleen. Out
al-Qaeda operates out of the spleen. Out of the spleen.
of the spleen.
of the spleen. Hamas, all those operate out of the
Hamas, all those operate out of the
Hamas, all those operate out of the splain. Hatred and uh in the name of God
splain. Hatred and uh in the name of God
splain. Hatred and uh in the name of God they kill which is blasphemy really is
they kill which is blasphemy really is
they kill which is blasphemy really is actual blasphemy.
actual blasphemy.
actual blasphemy. Um to use the words of God against God
Um to use the words of God against God
Um to use the words of God against God and therefore that which hates divinity
and therefore that which hates divinity
and therefore that which hates divinity masquerades that they are doing so in
masquerades that they are doing so in
masquerades that they are doing so in the name of divinity which is the
the name of divinity which is the
the name of divinity which is the ultimate blasphemy. That's why they
ultimate blasphemy. That's why they
ultimate blasphemy. That's why they calibrated 35.
>> So
>> So >> that's the spleen. The solar plexus is
>> that's the spleen. The solar plexus is
>> that's the spleen. The solar plexus is wantingness.
wantingness.
wantingness. The let's say uh you know wantingness,
The let's say uh you know wantingness,
The let's say uh you know wantingness, aggressiveness, doingness, the capacity
aggressiveness, doingness, the capacity
aggressiveness, doingness, the capacity to do that's in the 200s, the 300s.
to do that's in the 200s, the 300s.
to do that's in the 200s, the 300s. The heart of course is the heart chakra
The heart of course is the heart chakra
The heart of course is the heart chakra the 500. The third eye, the opening of
the 500. The third eye, the opening of
the 500. The third eye, the opening of third eye would be like 600.
third eye would be like 600.
third eye would be like 600. Spiritual discernment. Without
Spiritual discernment. Without
Spiritual discernment. Without kinesiology, people don't have spiritual
kinesiology, people don't have spiritual
kinesiology, people don't have spiritual discernment. They can't tell appearance
discernment. They can't tell appearance
discernment. They can't tell appearance from essence.
from essence.
from essence. They can't tell the sheep's clothing
They can't tell the sheep's clothing
They can't tell the sheep's clothing from the wolf in the sheep's clothing.
from the wolf in the sheep's clothing.
from the wolf in the sheep's clothing. So Jesus Christ sent me here. He says,
So Jesus Christ sent me here. He says,
So Jesus Christ sent me here. He says, "I want you to teach kinesiology."
So people can tell whether it's a sheep
So people can tell whether it's a sheep or is it a wolf in sheep's clothing?
or is it a wolf in sheep's clothing?
or is it a wolf in sheep's clothing? >> Because other than by their fruits you
>> Because other than by their fruits you
>> Because other than by their fruits you shall know them, there's no way of
shall know them, there's no way of
shall know them, there's no way of telling, is there?
How can you tell a sheep from a wolf in
How can you tell a sheep from a wolf in sheep's clothing?
>> I'm a sheep with wolf's clothing.
>> I'm a sheep with wolf's clothing. >> Ah,
>> I scare people away so they won't find
>> I scare people away so they won't find that I'm a sheep underneath. Uh
that I'm a sheep underneath. Uh
that I'm a sheep underneath. Uh and uh the other question has to do with
and uh the other question has to do with
and uh the other question has to do with um with vibrational levels. Um and I
um with vibrational levels. Um and I
um with vibrational levels. Um and I wonder there's been a lot of work done
wonder there's been a lot of work done
wonder there's been a lot of work done around um the organs of the body when
around um the organs of the body when
around um the organs of the body when they're running perfectly. They run at
they're running perfectly. They run at
they're running perfectly. They run at 77 megahertz. I'm talking about
77 megahertz. I'm talking about
77 megahertz. I'm talking about frequency levels and things like that.
frequency levels and things like that.
frequency levels and things like that. Um and that when you pursue a spiritual
Um and that when you pursue a spiritual
Um and that when you pursue a spiritual path you are there's a lot of talk about
path you are there's a lot of talk about
path you are there's a lot of talk about vibrate bringing your vibration up
vibrate bringing your vibration up
vibrate bringing your vibration up bringing your frequency up and so do you
bringing your frequency up and so do you
bringing your frequency up and so do you have is there any correlation
have is there any correlation
have is there any correlation is there a correlation or a bridge
is there a correlation or a bridge
is there a correlation or a bridge between that work and the work that of
between that work and the work that of
between that work and the work that of the levels of consciousness?
the levels of consciousness?
the levels of consciousness? >> I don't think so. I think they're
>> I don't think so. I think they're
>> I don't think so. I think they're talking about different scales of
talking about different scales of
talking about different scales of vibration. See we're talking about
vibration. See we're talking about
vibration. See we're talking about spiritual energy
spiritual energy
spiritual energy >> uh and balance. So if you're spiritually
>> uh and balance. So if you're spiritually
>> uh and balance. So if you're spiritually aligned,
aligned,
aligned, spiritually aligned and your
spiritually aligned and your
spiritually aligned and your intentionality is uh integris
intentionality is uh integris
intentionality is uh integris the chakra system and the acupuncture
the chakra system and the acupuncture
the chakra system and the acupuncture system will balance itself out.
system will balance itself out.
system will balance itself out. Unless you have an impairment in some
Unless you have an impairment in some
Unless you have an impairment in some particular attitude, that's why John
particular attitude, that's why John
particular attitude, that's why John Diamond did such excellent work. you
Diamond did such excellent work. you
Diamond did such excellent work. you know, he found the acupuncture points
know, he found the acupuncture points
know, he found the acupuncture points that relate to certain attitudes and he
that relate to certain attitudes and he
that relate to certain attitudes and he would give you
would give you
would give you um
um
um a what what do you call it where you say
a what what do you call it where you say
a what what do you call it where you say positive I forgive my enemies. Huh?
positive I forgive my enemies. Huh?
positive I forgive my enemies. Huh? >> An affirmation.
>> An affirmation.
>> An affirmation. >> Yeah. An affirmation at the same time
>> Yeah. An affirmation at the same time
>> Yeah. An affirmation at the same time you stimulate those specific acupuncture
you stimulate those specific acupuncture
you stimulate those specific acupuncture points. So those things that are related
points. So those things that are related
points. So those things that are related to body work and consciousness and
to body work and consciousness and
to body work and consciousness and attitudes
attitudes
attitudes are like a step between the physical.
are like a step between the physical.
are like a step between the physical. You know body work is like a step
You know body work is like a step
You know body work is like a step between the physical and then the chakra
between the physical and then the chakra
between the physical and then the chakra system and then the pure spiritual work
system and then the pure spiritual work
system and then the pure spiritual work which doesn't pay attention to chakra
which doesn't pay attention to chakra
which doesn't pay attention to chakra systems.
systems.
systems. Pure spiritual work doesn't pay
Pure spiritual work doesn't pay
Pure spiritual work doesn't pay attention to them. You know as I mean
attention to them. You know as I mean
attention to them. You know as I mean esoterically you can describe them but
esoterically you can describe them but
esoterically you can describe them but they're irrelevant.
they're irrelevant.
they're irrelevant. You know the daggers at the point of
You know the daggers at the point of
You know the daggers at the point of your enemy's heart. You can either push
your enemy's heart. You can either push
your enemy's heart. You can either push it in or not. You haven't got time to do
it in or not. You haven't got time to do
it in or not. You haven't got time to do kinesiology
kinesiology
kinesiology >> right? You just have time to choose.
>> right? You just have time to choose.
>> right? You just have time to choose. >> In one lifetime you lose if you push it
>> In one lifetime you lose if you push it
>> In one lifetime you lose if you push it in and another lifetime you lose if you
in and another lifetime you lose if you
in and another lifetime you lose if you don't. Depends on the context. I said
don't. Depends on the context. I said
don't. Depends on the context. I said you can't know truth unless you know
you can't know truth unless you know
you can't know truth unless you know context.
Integrity means crossing over 200 for
Integrity means crossing over 200 for integrity reasons.
integrity reasons.
integrity reasons. So, as I've told other groups, one
So, as I've told other groups, one
So, as I've told other groups, one lifetime I failed to kill a warrior that
lifetime I failed to kill a warrior that
lifetime I failed to kill a warrior that I'd wound wounded
I'd wound wounded
I'd wound wounded and I came back and had to go through
and I came back and had to go through
and I came back and had to go through painful surgery with no anesthesia. In
painful surgery with no anesthesia. In
painful surgery with no anesthesia. In the middle of it, I remembered the exact
the middle of it, I remembered the exact
the middle of it, I remembered the exact thing.
thing.
thing. I put a sword right through his groin
I put a sword right through his groin
I put a sword right through his groin and did not give him the food
and did not give him the food
and did not give him the food the kudigra
the kudigra
the kudigra cartis.
cartis.
cartis. I couldn't bring myself to kill him. So
I couldn't bring myself to kill him. So
I couldn't bring myself to kill him. So I left him to die of his wounds which
I left him to die of his wounds which
I left him to die of his wounds which took him weeks of agony and fever and I
took him weeks of agony and fever and I
took him weeks of agony and fever and I should have one warrior to another put
should have one warrior to another put
should have one warrior to another put him out of his misery.
him out of his misery.
him out of his misery. So I had to suffer the guilt of that for
So I had to suffer the guilt of that for
So I had to suffer the guilt of that for a long time agonizing that I had lacked
a long time agonizing that I had lacked
a long time agonizing that I had lacked the courage
the courage
the courage one warrior to another.
In this war you leave a pistol with one
In this war you leave a pistol with one bullet left in the by his hand. and you
bullet left in the by his hand. and you
bullet left in the by his hand. and you walk away. Now it's his choice but
walk away. Now it's his choice but
walk away. Now it's his choice but that's your obligation warrior to
that's your obligation warrior to
that's your obligation warrior to warrior.
warrior.
warrior. So in this lifetime I did that karma and
So in this lifetime I did that karma and
So in this lifetime I did that karma and I apologized to him
Now I would have the courage
Now I would have the courage to grow
to grow
to grow >> out of my love for him I kill him. See,
>> out of my love for him I kill him. See,
>> out of my love for him I kill him. See, so it's intention, not the act. So in
so it's intention, not the act. So in
so it's intention, not the act. So in one lifetime to run the dagger home
one lifetime to run the dagger home
one lifetime to run the dagger home would be cowardly and negative and
would be cowardly and negative and
would be cowardly and negative and another not to would be cowardly and
another not to would be cowardly and
another not to would be cowardly and negative. So context makes the whole
negative. So context makes the whole
negative. So context makes the whole difference.
Yeah.
Yeah. And I just have one other thing which is
And I just have one other thing which is
And I just have one other thing which is um
um
um I am so grateful for some of the things
I am so grateful for some of the things
I am so grateful for some of the things you said today about when you're born
you said today about when you're born
you said today about when you're born and when you die and you these things
and when you die and you these things
and when you die and you these things are all set up. I had a I had my first
are all set up. I had a I had my first
are all set up. I had a I had my first child in December and she was only with
child in December and she was only with
child in December and she was only with us for 10 days and um I really can your
us for 10 days and um I really can your
us for 10 days and um I really can your work has really helped with that to know
work has really helped with that to know
work has really helped with that to know that
that
that these are things are chosen you know
these are things are chosen you know
these are things are chosen you know >> karmically destined to come in and out
>> karmically destined to come in and out
>> karmically destined to come in and out >> right
>> right
>> right >> to experience the birth process for some
>> to experience the birth process for some
>> to experience the birth process for some reason
reason
reason >> and having accomplished it left end of
>> and having accomplished it left end of
>> and having accomplished it left end of karmic
karmic
karmic >> purpose
>> purpose
>> purpose >> so thank you for that
>> so thank you for that
>> so thank you for that >> yeah another interesting Fact
>> yeah another interesting Fact
>> yeah another interesting Fact uh I like things that relieve guilt and
uh I like things that relieve guilt and
uh I like things that relieve guilt and anxiety you know is that the spirit
anxiety you know is that the spirit
anxiety you know is that the spirit human spirit doesn't enter the embryo
human spirit doesn't enter the embryo
human spirit doesn't enter the embryo until the third month. Isn't that
until the third month. Isn't that
until the third month. Isn't that interesting?
interesting?
interesting? >> Not till the third month. Spirit waits
>> Not till the third month. Spirit waits
>> Not till the third month. Spirit waits to make sure I guess embryo is going to
to make sure I guess embryo is going to
to make sure I guess embryo is going to survive. Doesn't enter the human embryo
survive. Doesn't enter the human embryo
survive. Doesn't enter the human embryo till the third month. I just think
till the third month. I just think
till the third month. I just think that's interesting.
that's interesting.
that's interesting. I don't know what it means but
Yeah. Third month, huh?
Yeah. Third month, huh? >> Dr. Hawkins, if I understood you
>> Dr. Hawkins, if I understood you
>> Dr. Hawkins, if I understood you correctly this morning, you had said
correctly this morning, you had said
correctly this morning, you had said that Christ came in in one lifetime and
that Christ came in in one lifetime and
that Christ came in in one lifetime and Edgar Casey says he cames that he was
Edgar Casey says he cames that he was
Edgar Casey says he cames that he was here 33 lifetimes. And I just wondered
here 33 lifetimes. And I just wondered
here 33 lifetimes. And I just wondered why the discrepancy
why the discrepancy
why the discrepancy >> because Casey didn't know any better.
Casey was into the esoteric Christ
Casey was into the esoteric Christ >> which means what?
>> which means what?
>> which means what? >> Yes. Well, it takes you have to be
>> Yes. Well, it takes you have to be
>> Yes. Well, it takes you have to be educated in esotericism.
educated in esotericism.
educated in esotericism. There is the esoteric Christ and then
There is the esoteric Christ and then
There is the esoteric Christ and then there's the physical material Christ.
there's the physical material Christ.
there's the physical material Christ. Okay.
Okay.
Okay. Mr. Esis Casey was talking about the
Mr. Esis Casey was talking about the
Mr. Esis Casey was talking about the esoteric Christ. Yes. He was speaking of
esoteric Christ. Yes. He was speaking of
esoteric Christ. Yes. He was speaking of the esoteric Christ and not the actual
the esoteric Christ and not the actual
the esoteric Christ and not the actual physical Christ.
physical Christ.
physical Christ. Does that mean she's the man?
Does that mean she's the man?
Does that mean she's the man? >> You'll have to study
>> You'll have to study
>> You'll have to study uh what's her name that uh channel the
uh what's her name that uh channel the
uh what's her name that uh channel the white brotherhood.
white brotherhood.
white brotherhood. >> If you read the Alice Bailey books
>> If you read the Alice Bailey books
>> If you read the Alice Bailey books that'll sort of answer it.
that'll sort of answer it.
that'll sort of answer it. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> And Manley's books which get more into
>> And Manley's books which get more into
>> And Manley's books which get more into esotericism.
esotericism.
esotericism. And there are different levels of
And there are different levels of
And there are different levels of existence other than the physical and
existence other than the physical and
existence other than the physical and the strictly spiritual esoteric levels.
the strictly spiritual esoteric levels.
the strictly spiritual esoteric levels. So I think Casey was talking about the
So I think Casey was talking about the
So I think Casey was talking about the esoteric Christ.
esoteric Christ.
esoteric Christ. >> Okay. Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you. >> Who you might say was reborn again in
>> Who you might say was reborn again in
>> Who you might say was reborn again in the late 80s when the consciousness
the late 80s when the consciousness
the late 80s when the consciousness level went from 190 to 205. That's the
level went from 190 to 205. That's the
level went from 190 to 205. That's the re reemergence of the Christ
re reemergence of the Christ
re reemergence of the Christ consciousness. The second coming, isn't
consciousness. The second coming, isn't
consciousness. The second coming, isn't it? Where do they think another human
it? Where do they think another human
it? Where do they think another human beings should come up and say I'm reborn
beings should come up and say I'm reborn
beings should come up and say I'm reborn Jesus? I mean get up. There's no way.
Jesus? I mean get up. There's no way.
Jesus? I mean get up. There's no way. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> No. The Christ consciousness prevails.
>> No. The Christ consciousness prevails.
>> No. The Christ consciousness prevails. Then another wave of the Christ
Then another wave of the Christ
Then another wave of the Christ consciousness come came in in October
consciousness come came in in October
consciousness come came in in October 14th at 5 in the afternoon. It went from
14th at 5 in the afternoon. It went from
14th at 5 in the afternoon. It went from 205 to 207.
205 to 207.
205 to 207. It seems to me like the Christ
It seems to me like the Christ
It seems to me like the Christ consciousness prevails then it then it
consciousness prevails then it then it
consciousness prevails then it then it increases then it increases. What do you
increases then it increases. What do you
increases then it increases. What do you think would happen to the people on this
think would happen to the people on this
think would happen to the people on this planet if it went from 200 up to a
planet if it went from 200 up to a
planet if it went from 200 up to a thousand all of a sudden?
thousand all of a sudden?
thousand all of a sudden? >> They blow up.
>> They blow up.
>> They blow up. >> It brings sudden death to most people on
>> It brings sudden death to most people on
>> It brings sudden death to most people on the planet. You know that?
the planet. You know that?
the planet. You know that? >> No. You raise the level of the sea this
>> No. You raise the level of the sea this
>> No. You raise the level of the sea this much. Then you raise the level of sea
much. Then you raise the level of sea
much. Then you raise the level of sea this much because the whole world has to
this much because the whole world has to
this much because the whole world has to adjust to that.
adjust to that.
adjust to that. So spiritual advancement is not supposed
So spiritual advancement is not supposed
So spiritual advancement is not supposed to be brutal to force everybody to jump
to be brutal to force everybody to jump
to be brutal to force everybody to jump to 2,000 or thousand. I mean to even go
to 2,000 or thousand. I mean to even go
to 2,000 or thousand. I mean to even go from 800 to 900 like fries your whole
from 800 to 900 like fries your whole
from 800 to 900 like fries your whole nervous system like it die a thousand
nervous system like it die a thousand
nervous system like it die a thousand deaths. So what are you going to do? Fry
deaths. So what are you going to do? Fry
deaths. So what are you going to do? Fry everybody on the planet and force them
everybody on the planet and force them
everybody on the planet and force them to jump to a thousand? No. I think the
to jump to a thousand? No. I think the
to jump to a thousand? No. I think the Christ consciousness
Christ consciousness
Christ consciousness as it becomes acceptable moves in we may
as it becomes acceptable moves in we may
as it becomes acceptable moves in we may see another decade or a few decades it
see another decade or a few decades it
see another decade or a few decades it moves another two. Look at the upset
moves another two. Look at the upset
moves another two. Look at the upset that even a few points has caused all
that even a few points has caused all
that even a few points has caused all the giant corporations have fallen.
the giant corporations have fallen.
the giant corporations have fallen. All kinds of things heads have been
All kinds of things heads have been
All kinds of things heads have been rolling. Those heads would not have
rolling. Those heads would not have
rolling. Those heads would not have rolled at 190.
rolled at 190.
rolled at 190. >> Mhm. and Ron would be profitable at 190.
>> Mhm. and Ron would be profitable at 190.
>> Mhm. and Ron would be profitable at 190. We'll come. We'll quit.
We'll come. We'll quit.
We'll come. We'll quit. >> Okay, I'm going to see them right now.
>> Okay, I'm going to see them right now.
>> Okay, I'm going to see them right now. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> I'm not catching a train. All right.
>> I'm not catching a train. All right.
>> I'm not catching a train. All right. >> Oh. Oh, I'm moving.
>> Oh. Oh, I'm moving.
>> Oh. Oh, I'm moving. Okay. I know we're not running the
Okay. I know we're not running the
Okay. I know we're not running the space. Is there a church?
space. Is there a church?
space. Is there a church? >> Thanks for coming.
>> Thanks for coming.
>> Thanks for coming. >> Uh, are you familiar with the term
>> Uh, are you familiar with the term
>> Uh, are you familiar with the term psychic vampires or people who steal
psychic vampires or people who steal
psychic vampires or people who steal others energy?
others energy?
others energy? Not really.
Not really.
Not really. >> Uh,
>> Uh,
>> Uh, no. No.
no. No.
no. No. Um,
Um,
Um, can somebody go from a um calibrated at
can somebody go from a um calibrated at
can somebody go from a um calibrated at a 400 uh by one bad choice drop to below
a 400 uh by one bad choice drop to below
a 400 uh by one bad choice drop to below 200 without
200 without
200 without >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> And uh would that also be a shock to the
>> And uh would that also be a shock to the
>> And uh would that also be a shock to the system as it is in reverse from say 190
system as it is in reverse from say 190
system as it is in reverse from say 190 to
to
to >> or can or do we do that all the time? I
>> or can or do we do that all the time? I
>> or can or do we do that all the time? I mean,
mean,
mean, >> I don't know if it'd be a shock to the
>> I don't know if it'd be a shock to the
>> I don't know if it'd be a shock to the system or not. I don't historically
system or not. I don't historically
system or not. I don't historically remember that being said.
remember that being said.
remember that being said. >> Do we do that? Uh, I mean, do we bounce
>> Do we do that? Uh, I mean, do we bounce
>> Do we do that? Uh, I mean, do we bounce up and down daily just by choice?
up and down daily just by choice?
up and down daily just by choice? >> Not much. No. No. We fluctuate a little
>> Not much. No. No. We fluctuate a little
>> Not much. No. No. We fluctuate a little bit like this.
bit like this.
bit like this. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> But I say your your spiritual will is
>> But I say your your spiritual will is
>> But I say your your spiritual will is what your spiritual intention, your
what your spiritual intention, your
what your spiritual intention, your will, your commitment.
will, your commitment.
will, your commitment. >> So the spiritual will doesn't fluctuate
>> So the spiritual will doesn't fluctuate
>> So the spiritual will doesn't fluctuate from moment to moment. No.
And the miraculous does occur as a
And the miraculous does occur as a consequence of the condolini energy
because the person will sit down there
because the person will sit down there with a problem and
with a problem and
with a problem and you don't know why they're there and
you don't know why they're there and
you don't know why they're there and then you get oh I get what yeah and walk
then you get oh I get what yeah and walk
then you get oh I get what yeah and walk away well and you had nothing to do with
away well and you had nothing to do with
away well and you had nothing to do with that.
that.
that. The healing capacity then is a
The healing capacity then is a
The healing capacity then is a consequence of spiritual commitment. You
consequence of spiritual commitment. You
consequence of spiritual commitment. You can't do it for its own sake.
The condolini energy, the miraculous,
The condolini energy, the miraculous, the so-called cities si d his s are a
the so-called cities si d his s are a
the so-called cities si d his s are a consequence.
consequence.
consequence. But you can't seek them for themselves.
The cities,
The cities, you know, do perform the miraculous.
and they're exquisite to experience,
and they're exquisite to experience, but you can't hang on to them for their
but you can't hang on to them for their
but you can't hang on to them for their own sake. And the spiritually advanced
own sake. And the spiritually advanced
own sake. And the spiritually advanced teachings are
teachings are
teachings are uh not to uh claim them, not to hang on
uh not to uh claim them, not to hang on
uh not to uh claim them, not to hang on to them to merely witness them because
to them to merely witness them because
to them to merely witness them because the condalini energy does what it does
the condalini energy does what it does
the condalini energy does what it does of its own.
Yes.
Yes. >> Thank you, Dr. Hawkins. Um, question
>> Thank you, Dr. Hawkins. Um, question
>> Thank you, Dr. Hawkins. Um, question about fluorescent lights. Have you
about fluorescent lights. Have you
about fluorescent lights. Have you tested full spectrum fluorescent lights
tested full spectrum fluorescent lights
tested full spectrum fluorescent lights as well as ordinary ones?
as well as ordinary ones?
as well as ordinary ones? >> No, we didn't bother. We those were the
>> No, we didn't bother. We those were the
>> No, we didn't bother. We those were the days we they I don't know. We just had
days we they I don't know. We just had
days we they I don't know. We just had fluorescent lights.
fluorescent lights.
fluorescent lights. >> Thank you. Um,
>> Thank you. Um,
>> Thank you. Um, and
and
and >> can you comment on the level of
>> can you comment on the level of
>> can you comment on the level of consciousness of any entity or entities
consciousness of any entity or entities
consciousness of any entity or entities that inhabit the sun?
that inhabit the sun?
that inhabit the sun? >> That what?
>> That what?
>> That what? >> Inhabit the sun.
>> Inhabit the sun.
>> Inhabit the sun. >> The sun.
>> The sun.
>> The sun. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> No.
>> No.
>> No. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Whose sun?
>> The cosmic sun. No, I never thought of
>> The cosmic sun. No, I never thought of the question.
the question.
the question. >> Dr. Hawkins. Uh, my question has to do
>> Dr. Hawkins. Uh, my question has to do
>> Dr. Hawkins. Uh, my question has to do with spiritual intention. If your
with spiritual intention. If your
with spiritual intention. If your intention is to surrender to God and
intention is to surrender to God and
intention is to surrender to God and that is what you're making the purpose
that is what you're making the purpose
that is what you're making the purpose of your life are intentions such as
of your life are intentions such as
of your life are intentions such as prayer for healing for oneself or loved
prayer for healing for oneself or loved
prayer for healing for oneself or loved ones or actually any preferences
ones or actually any preferences
ones or actually any preferences whatsoever if you put any intention into
whatsoever if you put any intention into
whatsoever if you put any intention into those thoughts are they integrous
those thoughts are they integrous
those thoughts are they integrous because really when you do that it's
because really when you do that it's
because really when you do that it's >> depends on what level of consciousness
>> depends on what level of consciousness
>> depends on what level of consciousness you're at at the time. On one level
you're at at the time. On one level
you're at at the time. On one level would be it would be something you've
would be it would be something you've
would be it would be something you've got to get over.
got to get over.
got to get over. At another level it would be something
At another level it would be something
At another level it would be something that you're just approaching and
that you're just approaching and
that you're just approaching and learning. At another you would say in
learning. At another you would say in
learning. At another you would say in the name of the highest good because you
the name of the highest good because you
the name of the highest good because you don't know if healing somebody or
don't know if healing somebody or
don't know if healing somebody or they're getting better is in the
they're getting better is in the
they're getting better is in the interest of the highest good anyway.
interest of the highest good anyway.
interest of the highest good anyway. Better they leave. You know what I'm
Better they leave. You know what I'm
Better they leave. You know what I'm saying?
saying?
saying? >> So therefore
>> So therefore
>> So therefore >> serve the highest good by getting out of
>> serve the highest good by getting out of
>> serve the highest good by getting out of here frankly.
here frankly.
here frankly. And so really just surrendering it to
And so really just surrendering it to
And so really just surrendering it to God and saying whatever is in the
God and saying whatever is in the
God and saying whatever is in the highest good is it in which case um
highest good is it in which case um
highest good is it in which case um certain prayers any prayers for anything
certain prayers any prayers for anything
certain prayers any prayers for anything else are really not necessary.
else are really not necessary.
else are really not necessary. >> Well it's well-intentioned. It's well
>> Well it's well-intentioned. It's well
>> Well it's well-intentioned. It's well intentioned.
intentioned.
intentioned. >> So it's a form of love.
>> So it's a form of love.
>> So it's a form of love. >> Oh the prayer you mean?
>> Oh the prayer you mean?
>> Oh the prayer you mean? >> Yeah. In a way it's sort of ambiguous
>> Yeah. In a way it's sort of ambiguous
>> Yeah. In a way it's sort of ambiguous because you're asking God to do what
because you're asking God to do what
because you're asking God to do what God's will is for the person and he
God's will is for the person and he
God's will is for the person and he really doesn't need to be reminded.
Exactly. And what if it's one's own self
Exactly. And what if it's one's own self and you feel that um you know you're
and you feel that um you know you're
and you feel that um you know you're asking or making an intention let's say
asking or making an intention let's say
asking or making an intention let's say for a certain kind of healing process
for a certain kind of healing process
for a certain kind of healing process which I think you maybe can effect but
which I think you maybe can effect but
which I think you maybe can effect but >> but what you do is you hold in mind as I
>> but what you do is you hold in mind as I
>> but what you do is you hold in mind as I say what you hold in mind tends to
say what you hold in mind tends to
say what you hold in mind tends to actualize you saw the physics of it this
actualize you saw the physics of it this
actualize you saw the physics of it this morning through the Heisenberg
morning through the Heisenberg
morning through the Heisenberg principles. So the intentionality
principles. So the intentionality
principles. So the intentionality of their health and wellness if you're
of their health and wellness if you're
of their health and wellness if you're just holding it in mind you don't have
just holding it in mind you don't have
just holding it in mind you don't have to go through in treaty
to go through in treaty
to go through in treaty which is a dualistic process there's a
which is a dualistic process there's a
which is a dualistic process there's a me asking a god there
me asking a god there
me asking a god there you're seeing all three separated you
you're seeing all three separated you
you're seeing all three separated you the person you're praying for and god
the person you're praying for and god
the person you're praying for and god see
see
see >> right
>> right
>> right >> and you're trying to close the triangle
>> and you're trying to close the triangle
>> and you're trying to close the triangle where there isn't any triangle so by
where there isn't any triangle so by
where there isn't any triangle so by intentionality you picture the
intentionality you picture the
intentionality you picture the resolution that from your limited
resolution that from your limited
resolution that from your limited viewpoint
viewpoint
viewpoint you feel would be the most desirable and
you feel would be the most desirable and
you feel would be the most desirable and most loving resolution
most loving resolution
most loving resolution may not be but at least in your
may not be but at least in your
may not be but at least in your viewpoint
viewpoint
viewpoint >> and that's not contradicting
>> and that's not contradicting
>> and that's not contradicting let's say the will of God or your
let's say the will of God or your
let's say the will of God or your intention to
intention to
intention to >> well that's why you do it in align with
>> well that's why you do it in align with
>> well that's why you do it in align with God's will
>> you know Medicare keeps their people
>> you know Medicare keeps their people alive you know in the nursing homes I
alive you know in the nursing homes I
alive you know in the nursing homes I was the only doctor would go to the
was the only doctor would go to the
was the only doctor would go to the nursing homes in the old county and I'd
nursing homes in the old county and I'd
nursing homes in the old county and I'd go there and some old thing and be all
go there and some old thing and be all
go there and some old thing and be all there crippled up in a wheelchair. Help.
What do you want? Let me out of here.
What do you want? Let me out of here. Medicare won't let you allow allow you
Medicare won't let you allow allow you
Medicare won't let you allow allow you to let people die. It's against the law.
to let people die. It's against the law.
to let people die. It's against the law. All these tubes and plugs and
All these tubes and plugs and
All these tubes and plugs and ghastly gastly gastly. Help help. What
ghastly gastly gastly. Help help. What
ghastly gastly gastly. Help help. What does she want? Help. Help me get out of
does she want? Help. Help me get out of
does she want? Help. Help me get out of here. They won't let me get out of here.
So, should I pray for her to stay alive
So, should I pray for her to stay alive or pull the plug?
or pull the plug?
or pull the plug? She's begging me. Please let me out of
She's begging me. Please let me out of
She's begging me. Please let me out of here. I'm in agony. All this is keeping
here. I'm in agony. All this is keeping
here. I'm in agony. All this is keeping me in endless agony. Can't you help me?
me in endless agony. Can't you help me?
me in endless agony. Can't you help me? That's what she's asking me.
That's what she's asking me.
That's what she's asking me. Doctor, doctor, can't you let me go? And
Doctor, doctor, can't you let me go? And
Doctor, doctor, can't you let me go? And I tell her it's against the law.
Against the law. That appears to die. He
Against the law. That appears to die. He there begging.
there begging.
there begging. Right.
Please let me go.
Please let me go. No.
No.
No. Got to stay here.
The vadic system talks about the u the
The vadic system talks about the u the cycle of yogas or ages and uh the
cycle of yogas or ages and uh the
cycle of yogas or ages and uh the current age we're in being known as the
current age we're in being known as the
current age we're in being known as the kaw yoga the dark ages the aay
kaw yoga the dark ages the aay
kaw yoga the dark ages the aay and
and
and in your books
in your books
in your books you talk about the progression of
you talk about the progression of
you talk about the progression of consciousness
consciousness
consciousness from well around a 100 2,000 years ago
from well around a 100 2,000 years ago
from well around a 100 2,000 years ago 207 currently and it suggests that if
207 currently and it suggests that if
207 currently and it suggests that if the vdic model is accurate that we're
the vdic model is accurate that we're
the vdic model is accurate that we're moving out of that darker age into the
moving out of that darker age into the
moving out of that darker age into the next
next
next >> what's the question
>> what's the question
>> what's the question >> this cycle is this cycle something
>> this cycle is this cycle something
>> this cycle is this cycle something you've examined with the the calibration
you've examined with the the calibration
you've examined with the the calibration scale as to validate is this something
scale as to validate is this something
scale as to validate is this something that actually is uh occurs on this
that actually is uh occurs on this
that actually is uh occurs on this planet sort of winking in and out of uh
planet sort of winking in and out of uh
planet sort of winking in and out of uh of of
of of
of of let's say human manifestation or
let's say human manifestation or
let's say human manifestation or spiritual manifestation human form.
>> When India in Indra breathes in universe
>> When India in Indra breathes in universe disappear when Indra breathes out
disappear when Indra breathes out
disappear when Indra breathes out universes appear every breath is a
universes appear every breath is a
universes appear every breath is a kaluga. Did that answer your question?
kaluga. Did that answer your question?
kaluga. Did that answer your question? >> Yep.
>> Yep.
>> Yep. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. You said that uh
You said that uh
You said that uh life is consciousness entering matter.
life is consciousness entering matter.
life is consciousness entering matter. And I wondered what is matter without
And I wondered what is matter without
And I wondered what is matter without consciousness?
consciousness?
consciousness? >> Dead.
>> Dead.
>> Dead. >> Dead.
>> Well, what is matter then? I guess I
>> Well, what is matter then? I guess I wonder.
wonder.
wonder. >> Energy. E= MC².
>> Energy. E= MC².
>> Energy. E= MC². >> It's energy. Yeah.
>> It's energy. Yeah.
>> It's energy. Yeah. >> Energy.
>> Energy.
>> Energy. >> Energy. Oh, so
>> Energy. Oh, so
>> Energy. Oh, so >> and plus speed. MC^ squ. So
>> and plus speed. MC^ squ. So
>> and plus speed. MC^ squ. So consciousness makes it have a form. No.
consciousness makes it have a form. No.
consciousness makes it have a form. No. Because algae doesn't have
Because algae doesn't have
Because algae doesn't have consciousness.
consciousness.
consciousness. >> No.
>> No.
>> No. >> So what's it? I don't
>> So what's it? I don't
>> So what's it? I don't >> The energy of life then is the energy of
>> The energy of life then is the energy of
>> The energy of life then is the energy of consciousness.
What's the question?
What's the question? >> Well, I'm I don't know. This is one of
>> Well, I'm I don't know. This is one of
>> Well, I'm I don't know. This is one of those things the brain can't just is
those things the brain can't just is
those things the brain can't just is puzzled with that what is well matter is
puzzled with that what is well matter is
puzzled with that what is well matter is energy.
energy.
energy. >> Matter is not energy it's matter.
>> Matter is not energy it's matter.
>> Matter is not energy it's matter. >> Well then there's no that's
>> Well then there's no that's
>> Well then there's no that's >> E doesn't equal E equals MC².
>> E doesn't equal E equals MC².
>> E doesn't equal E equals MC². >> Well matter
>> Well matter
>> Well matter >> light
>> light
>> light >> is.
>> is.
>> is. >> So energy then is convertible into
>> So energy then is convertible into
>> So energy then is convertible into matter
matter
matter >> under the appropriate conditions. Okay,
>> under the appropriate conditions. Okay,
>> under the appropriate conditions. Okay, >> energy can be converted to matter.
>> energy can be converted to matter.
>> energy can be converted to matter. >> So
>> So
>> So >> there's the law of conservation of
>> there's the law of conservation of
>> there's the law of conservation of energy, the law law of conservation of
energy, the law law of conservation of
energy, the law law of conservation of matter. And then there's one we forgot
matter. And then there's one we forgot
matter. And then there's one we forgot to mention day one today that's more
to mention day one today that's more
to mention day one today that's more important than all of them. The law of
important than all of them. The law of
important than all of them. The law of conservation of energy of life. You
conservation of energy of life. You
conservation of energy of life. You cannot kill life.
cannot kill life.
cannot kill life. It's not possible to kill life. Not
It's not possible to kill life. Not
It's not possible to kill life. Not within the realm of the destroyable.
within the realm of the destroyable.
within the realm of the destroyable. It can only change form. So E= MC² means
It can only change form. So E= MC² means
It can only change form. So E= MC² means that energy and its physicality can take
that energy and its physicality can take
that energy and its physicality can take different dimensions. Of course the
different dimensions. Of course the
different dimensions. Of course the discovery of dark matter, dark energy
discovery of dark matter, dark energy
discovery of dark matter, dark energy and all such things and string theory of
and all such things and string theory of
and all such things and string theory of uh you know complicated advanced
uh you know complicated advanced
uh you know complicated advanced theoretical physics. My own view of it
theoretical physics. My own view of it
theoretical physics. My own view of it there's only one physicality in the
there's only one physicality in the
there's only one physicality in the whole universe and that's pure energy
whole universe and that's pure energy
whole universe and that's pure energy itself.
itself.
itself. The vibrational frequency of which can
The vibrational frequency of which can
The vibrational frequency of which can then take the form of matter, fire,
then take the form of matter, fire,
then take the form of matter, fire, heat, electricity,
heat, electricity,
heat, electricity, telephone, electricity. But there's only
telephone, electricity. But there's only
telephone, electricity. But there's only one basic primary primordial energy out
one basic primary primordial energy out
one basic primary primordial energy out of which all of these expressions arise.
of which all of these expressions arise.
of which all of these expressions arise. >> Is consciousness then an expression of
>> Is consciousness then an expression of
>> Is consciousness then an expression of energy, a certain kind of expression? I
energy, a certain kind of expression? I
energy, a certain kind of expression? I mean, this is just a mental question,
mean, this is just a mental question,
mean, this is just a mental question, but it comes up.
but it comes up.
but it comes up. >> It's the infinite energy, you might say,
>> It's the infinite energy, you might say,
>> It's the infinite energy, you might say, is comparable to gravity.
is comparable to gravity.
is comparable to gravity. It's a primordial the primordial energy
It's a primordial the primordial energy
It's a primordial the primordial energy out of which all of existence arises.
If divinity is primordial infinite
If divinity is primordial infinite formless energy,
formless energy,
formless energy, it can it it then manifests as all of
it can it it then manifests as all of
it can it it then manifests as all of creation. Yes, creation then is
creation. Yes, creation then is
creation. Yes, creation then is expressed in different vibrational
expressed in different vibrational
expressed in different vibrational frequencies.
frequencies.
frequencies. heat, light,
heat, light,
heat, light, dark matter, light matter, dark hole,
dark matter, light matter, dark hole,
dark matter, light matter, dark hole, dark holes, dark galaxies, dark holes in
dark holes, dark galaxies, dark holes in
dark holes, dark galaxies, dark holes in the galaxies. So the gravitation is so
the galaxies. So the gravitation is so
the galaxies. So the gravitation is so intense, the gravitation in a dark hole
intense, the gravitation in a dark hole
intense, the gravitation in a dark hole is so intense that even light cannot
is so intense that even light cannot
is so intense that even light cannot escape.
escape.
escape. >> That's gravity for you.
>> That's gravity for you.
>> That's gravity for you. That's enough. Okay,
That's enough. Okay,
That's enough. Okay, >> get the answer.
>> I have to rescue her.
>> I have to rescue her. >> Yeah, Dr. Hawkins, um your your book has
>> Yeah, Dr. Hawkins, um your your book has
>> Yeah, Dr. Hawkins, um your your book has been u very instrumental in a in a book
been u very instrumental in a in a book
been u very instrumental in a in a book that I'm writing right now um called the
that I'm writing right now um called the
that I'm writing right now um called the science of personal fulfillment. I've
science of personal fulfillment. I've
science of personal fulfillment. I've been pursuing this for quite a while.
been pursuing this for quite a while.
been pursuing this for quite a while. Um
Um
Um but a question I want to ask is uh
but a question I want to ask is uh
but a question I want to ask is uh do you consider yourself a me um of the
do you consider yourself a me um of the
do you consider yourself a me um of the order of Melkisedc?
order of Melkisedc?
order of Melkisedc? >> Do I consider myself what?
>> Do I consider myself what?
>> Do I consider myself what? >> Of the order of Melkisedc.
>> Well, no.
>> Well, no. >> I asked that question because
>> I asked that question because
>> I asked that question because you know Jesus was of the order and he
you know Jesus was of the order and he
you know Jesus was of the order and he was a healer.
was a healer.
was a healer. um which you are also and when I say he
um which you are also and when I say he
um which you are also and when I say he was a healer I mean the energy field
was a healer I mean the energy field
was a healer I mean the energy field that surrounded him and um I never
that surrounded him and um I never
that surrounded him and um I never contextualized it in that way cuz I
contextualized it in that way cuz I
contextualized it in that way cuz I didn't contextualize Jesus Christ either
didn't contextualize Jesus Christ either
didn't contextualize Jesus Christ either but I think I know what you're talking
but I think I know what you're talking
but I think I know what you're talking about it's a it's a spiritual
about it's a it's a spiritual
about it's a it's a spiritual contextualization one what I'm not
contextualization one what I'm not
contextualization one what I'm not familiar with yeah I understand what
familiar with yeah I understand what
familiar with yeah I understand what you're saying now yeah
you're saying now yeah
you're saying now yeah >> I see all right just one more thing Um,
I'm wrestling with
I'm wrestling with one of my base instincts that is anger
one of my base instincts that is anger
one of my base instincts that is anger that I'm
that I'm
that I'm seeking to subdue. And my uh fiance,
seeking to subdue. And my uh fiance,
seeking to subdue. And my uh fiance, well aware of that, she does things to
well aware of that, she does things to
well aware of that, she does things to bring it out and elevate it.
Now when I tell her I say well look
Now when I tell her I say well look a man and a woman supposed to be one and
a man and a woman supposed to be one and
a man and a woman supposed to be one and there are certain thoughts that I
there are certain thoughts that I
there are certain thoughts that I wouldn't even think knowing what it
wouldn't even think knowing what it
wouldn't even think knowing what it would do to me and you who's supposed to
would do to me and you who's supposed to
would do to me and you who's supposed to be part of me doing these things to
be part of me doing these things to
be part of me doing these things to bring these things out of me that I'm
bring these things out of me that I'm
bring these things out of me that I'm trying to subdue and on the other hand
trying to subdue and on the other hand
trying to subdue and on the other hand she's telling me well if you're studying
she's telling me well if you're studying
she's telling me well if you're studying that you're supposed to be able to do
that you're supposed to be able to do
that you're supposed to be able to do better and I'm um you know I sit
better and I'm um you know I sit
better and I'm um you know I sit thinking about it. I'm saying
thinking about it. I'm saying
thinking about it. I'm saying >> she's giving you all these golden
>> she's giving you all these golden
>> she's giving you all these golden opportunities in other words.
opportunities in other words.
opportunities in other words. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Thank you, sweetheart. Out of your love.
>> Thank you, sweetheart. Out of your love.
>> Thank you, sweetheart. Out of your love. You have given me the opportunity to
You have given me the opportunity to
You have given me the opportunity to forgive you. But but I I
take the other way.
take the other way. >> Sweetheart,
>> Sweetheart,
>> Sweetheart, >> I I said, "Look, no. I I see I I don't
>> I I said, "Look, no. I I see I I don't
>> I I said, "Look, no. I I see I I don't think you know you you you are being
think you know you you you are being
think you know you you you are being part of me. I don't think you should be
part of me. I don't think you should be
part of me. I don't think you should be doing this.
doing this.
doing this. >> Yeah, right.
>> Yeah, right.
>> Yeah, right. >> Oh,
>> Oh,
>> Oh, >> right. She's part of you, but with
>> right. She's part of you, but with
>> right. She's part of you, but with limitations. With reservations.
limitations. With reservations.
limitations. With reservations. >> H
>> H
>> H I think
I think
I think >> if God meant for there to be one sex,
>> if God meant for there to be one sex,
>> if God meant for there to be one sex, there'd only be one sex.
A butterfly has two wings to fly with.
A butterfly has two wings to fly with. See life.
See life.
See life. >> It's a pleasure to be here.
>> It's a pleasure to be here.
>> It's a pleasure to be here. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> My question is um you spoke about how
>> My question is um you spoke about how
>> My question is um you spoke about how when we're born um we're already at a
when we're born um we're already at a
when we're born um we're already at a level of consciousness.
level of consciousness.
level of consciousness. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Which also means we're already at a
>> Which also means we're already at a
>> Which also means we're already at a particular karmic level.
particular karmic level.
particular karmic level. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> So um as our life progresses and we make
>> So um as our life progresses and we make
>> So um as our life progresses and we make choices and sometimes people make
choices and sometimes people make
choices and sometimes people make negative choices, people
negative choices, people
negative choices, people Um what is our life kind of like a yo-yo
Um what is our life kind of like a yo-yo
Um what is our life kind of like a yo-yo in terms of spiritual growth do we not
in terms of spiritual growth do we not
in terms of spiritual growth do we not everyone's life is not an upward
everyone's life is not an upward
everyone's life is not an upward progression is it okay
progression is it okay
progression is it okay >> many people in this lifetime have fallen
>> many people in this lifetime have fallen
>> many people in this lifetime have fallen considerably
considerably
considerably if you do Napoleon
if you do Napoleon
if you do Napoleon Napoleon was about 450 460 and he became
Napoleon was about 450 460 and he became
Napoleon was about 450 460 and he became emperor crowned himself emperor his
emperor crowned himself emperor his
emperor crowned himself emperor his calibration then dropped to about 130 or
calibration then dropped to about 130 or
calibration then dropped to about 130 or 160 or something. The time of the battle
160 or something. The time of the battle
160 or something. The time of the battle of Waterloo,
the Duke of
the Duke of huh
huh
huh the Duke of Wellington calibrated around
the Duke of Wellington calibrated around
the Duke of Wellington calibrated around I forget 420 or something but by that
I forget 420 or something but by that
I forget 420 or something but by that time Napoleon had crashed and was like
time Napoleon had crashed and was like
time Napoleon had crashed and was like about 170.
about 170.
about 170. Adolf Hitler also calibrated in the
Adolf Hitler also calibrated in the
Adolf Hitler also calibrated in the reasonably good 400s early in his career
reasonably good 400s early in his career
reasonably good 400s early in his career and when you can with klesiology track
and when you can with klesiology track
and when you can with klesiology track historically when these events happened
historically when these events happened
historically when these events happened with Napoleon it was when he crowned
with Napoleon it was when he crowned
with Napoleon it was when he crowned himself emperor. See to crown the
himself emperor. See to crown the
himself emperor. See to crown the sovereign head of a European state was
sovereign head of a European state was
sovereign head of a European state was done by the pope. So he usurped the pope
done by the pope. So he usurped the pope
done by the pope. So he usurped the pope and crowned himself emperor
and crowned himself emperor
and crowned himself emperor and in that moment he crashed into
and in that moment he crashed into
and in that moment he crashed into megalomania.
megalomania.
megalomania. Hitler did the same thing when he became
Hitler did the same thing when he became
Hitler did the same thing when he became head of all the departments of
head of all the departments of
head of all the departments of government. He was
government. He was
government. He was the head of the army, the head of the
the head of the army, the head of the
the head of the army, the head of the military, the head of the government,
military, the head of the government,
military, the head of the government, the head of everything. And in that
the head of everything. And in that
the head of everything. And in that moment, Hitler crashed from 440 or
moment, Hitler crashed from 440 or
moment, Hitler crashed from 440 or wherever he was down to 1 whatever it
wherever he was down to 1 whatever it
wherever he was down to 1 whatever it was when he finally gave up. So that
was when he finally gave up. So that
was when he finally gave up. So that narcissistic megalomania lies in weight
narcissistic megalomania lies in weight
narcissistic megalomania lies in weight lies and wait. And the grandiosity then
lies and wait. And the grandiosity then
lies and wait. And the grandiosity then destroys what could have been great.
destroys what could have been great.
destroys what could have been great. Winston Churchill did not succumb to the
Winston Churchill did not succumb to the
Winston Churchill did not succumb to the same same temptation. You see? So power
same same temptation. You see? So power
same same temptation. You see? So power then worthly power differentiates the
then worthly power differentiates the
then worthly power differentiates the sheep from the goats. You either become
sheep from the goats. You either become
sheep from the goats. You either become a statesman or you become
a statesman or you become
a statesman or you become um megalamaniac.
>> Um I don't know if other
>> Um I don't know if other >> you ask me.
>> you ask me.
>> you ask me. >> Yeah, I think so. I think well one one
>> Yeah, I think so. I think well one one
>> Yeah, I think so. I think well one one of the things that's has happened to me
of the things that's has happened to me
of the things that's has happened to me since I've been reading your book is I'm
since I've been reading your book is I'm
since I've been reading your book is I'm constantly looking at the numbers and
constantly looking at the numbers and
constantly looking at the numbers and saying, "Oh gee, where would I fall?"
saying, "Oh gee, where would I fall?"
saying, "Oh gee, where would I fall?" you know, and I don't know if other
you know, and I don't know if other
you know, and I don't know if other people are doing this.
people are doing this.
people are doing this. >> You don't have to worry about where you
>> You don't have to worry about where you
>> You don't have to worry about where you fall.
fall.
fall. >> Well, in other words, it's a kind of a
>> Well, in other words, it's a kind of a
>> Well, in other words, it's a kind of a you already are what you are saying
you already are what you are saying
you already are what you are saying >> because unless you were spiritually
>> because unless you were spiritually
>> because unless you were spiritually uh integrous, you wouldn't be on a
uh integrous, you wouldn't be on a
uh integrous, you wouldn't be on a spiritual pathway to begin with. I was
spiritual pathway to begin with. I was
spiritual pathway to begin with. I was telling if you're on a spiritual
telling if you're on a spiritual
telling if you're on a spiritual pathway, don't worry about it. Let God
pathway, don't worry about it. Let God
pathway, don't worry about it. Let God worry about it. Let Jesus worry about
worry about it. Let Jesus worry about
worry about it. Let Jesus worry about it. That's what he's there for. And you
it. That's what he's there for. And you
it. That's what he's there for. And you spoke of G you spoke of
spoke of G you spoke of
spoke of G you spoke of and and in when you were talking about
and and in when you were talking about
and and in when you were talking about Jesus were you saying Jesus was an
Jesus were you saying Jesus was an
Jesus were you saying Jesus was an advocate? You used the word advocate.
advocate? You used the word advocate.
advocate? You used the word advocate. >> Yes. Spokesman for on your behalf.
I will stand before the father
I will stand before the father in your behalf because you have aligned
in your behalf because you have aligned
in your behalf because you have aligned yourself
yourself
yourself with me and
with me and
with me and in my name in the name of Jesus Christ
in my name in the name of Jesus Christ
in my name in the name of Jesus Christ that's all it takes in the name of the
that's all it takes in the name of the
that's all it takes in the name of the Lord Jesus
Lord Jesus
Lord Jesus and I will look after these are my
and I will look after these are my
and I will look after these are my because these are my sheep they have
because these are my sheep they have
because these are my sheep they have committed to me karmically
committed to me karmically
committed to me karmically they are now my sheep and I speak for
they are now my sheep and I speak for
they are now my sheep and I speak for them on their behalf enough that I will
them on their behalf enough that I will
them on their behalf enough that I will look after them, oh Lord.
look after them, oh Lord.
look after them, oh Lord. And the Lord says, "Pass hopefully."
And the Lord says, "Pass hopefully."
And the Lord says, "Pass hopefully." >> Then where does grace, one last
>> Then where does grace, one last
>> Then where does grace, one last question. Yeah.
question. Yeah.
question. Yeah. >> Where does grace come in?
>> Where does grace come in?
>> Where does grace come in? >> Grace.
>> Grace.
>> Grace. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Grace is a very sophisticated
>> Grace is a very sophisticated
>> Grace is a very sophisticated understanding.
It is by grace that you exist.
It is by grace that you exist. It is by grace that you are allowed to
It is by grace that you are allowed to
It is by grace that you are allowed to suffer the consequences of wrong
suffer the consequences of wrong
suffer the consequences of wrong decisions.
decisions.
decisions. It is by grace that you can earn karmic
It is by grace that you can earn karmic
It is by grace that you can earn karmic merit.
merit.
merit. >> Karmic what? Karmic
>> Karmic what? Karmic
>> Karmic what? Karmic >> merit.
>> merit.
>> merit. >> Merit is by grace that you can undo the
>> Merit is by grace that you can undo the
>> Merit is by grace that you can undo the errors of the past.
errors of the past.
errors of the past. It is by grace that you have existence
It is by grace that you have existence
It is by grace that you have existence in the first place.
>> Dr.
>> Dr. Yes,
Yes,
Yes, >> I think uh Grace probably answered my
>> I think uh Grace probably answered my
>> I think uh Grace probably answered my question, but my question was about uh
question, but my question was about uh
question, but my question was about uh karmic consequences for choosing uh to
karmic consequences for choosing uh to
karmic consequences for choosing uh to have an abortion.
have an abortion.
have an abortion. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> And um I just I wanted to ask you about
>> And um I just I wanted to ask you about
>> And um I just I wanted to ask you about that.
that.
that. >> That would depend on the individual and
>> That would depend on the individual and
>> That would depend on the individual and the and the context in which it
the and the context in which it
the and the context in which it happened. We mentioned before that the
happened. We mentioned before that the
happened. We mentioned before that the spirit doesn't come into the embryo to
spirit doesn't come into the embryo to
spirit doesn't come into the embryo to the third month.
the third month.
the third month. >> Yes. So if it's an abortion within the
>> Yes. So if it's an abortion within the
>> Yes. So if it's an abortion within the first 3 months, I don't think a person
first 3 months, I don't think a person
first 3 months, I don't think a person is technically guilty of anything.
is technically guilty of anything.
is technically guilty of anything. There's no spirit there yet.
There's no spirit there yet.
There's no spirit there yet. It's only the primordial
It's only the primordial
It's only the primordial embryionic animalness
embryionic animalness
embryionic animalness that is going to be inherited by a human
that is going to be inherited by a human
that is going to be inherited by a human spirit.
spirit.
spirit. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> So it depend on all the on many factors,
>> So it depend on all the on many factors,
>> So it depend on all the on many factors, intentionality.
intentionality.
intentionality. >> Okay. Um, that was the first I I'd ever
>> Okay. Um, that was the first I I'd ever
>> Okay. Um, that was the first I I'd ever heard of that, the uh human spirit not
heard of that, the uh human spirit not
heard of that, the uh human spirit not coming into the human embryo till the
coming into the human embryo till the
coming into the human embryo till the third month when you said that today.
third month when you said that today.
third month when you said that today. And
And
And wow. Um, because you know, I've carried
wow. Um, because you know, I've carried
wow. Um, because you know, I've carried uh a lot of guilt and pain and uh so I
uh a lot of guilt and pain and uh so I
uh a lot of guilt and pain and uh so I hope to God it was before 3 months.
hope to God it was before 3 months.
hope to God it was before 3 months. >> Well, you know,
>> spontaneous abortions are so frequent
>> spontaneous abortions are so frequent that people don't even know they happen
that people don't even know they happen
that people don't even know they happen that often. They think it's a mis
that often. They think it's a mis
that often. They think it's a mis period.
period.
period. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Yep. Probably 10% of all pregnancies end
>> Yep. Probably 10% of all pregnancies end
>> Yep. Probably 10% of all pregnancies end up with spontaneous abortion and maybe
up with spontaneous abortion and maybe
up with spontaneous abortion and maybe more maybe closer to a third. I think
more maybe closer to a third. I think
more maybe closer to a third. I think they skipped a period actually that was
they skipped a period actually that was
they skipped a period actually that was spontaneous miscarriage.
spontaneous miscarriage.
spontaneous miscarriage. >> So um
>> So um
>> So um would they have to do with also like the
would they have to do with also like the
would they have to do with also like the soul coming in that that was that soul's
soul coming in that that was that soul's
soul coming in that that was that soul's purpose?
purpose?
purpose? It's very complicated. If you knew how
It's very complicated. If you knew how
It's very complicated. If you knew how to do kinesiology very well and if you
to do kinesiology very well and if you
to do kinesiology very well and if you get permission, you could ask many
get permission, you could ask many
get permission, you could ask many questions.
questions.
questions. >> Did this spirit only mean to come in and
>> Did this spirit only mean to come in and
>> Did this spirit only mean to come in and leave right away? You may have
leave right away? You may have
leave right away? You may have accomplished that spirit's purpose. You
accomplished that spirit's purpose. You
accomplished that spirit's purpose. You see, and you're feeling guilty about
see, and you're feeling guilty about
see, and you're feeling guilty about nothing when actually that was the
nothing when actually that was the
nothing when actually that was the spirit's purpose. Anyhow,
spirit's purpose. Anyhow,
spirit's purpose. Anyhow, >> I don't know. It's a complicated
>> I don't know. It's a complicated
>> I don't know. It's a complicated research it
research it
research it >> just yeah a question for so long. So um
>> just yeah a question for so long. So um
>> just yeah a question for so long. So um but also
but also
but also if I mean I think it was before 3 months
if I mean I think it was before 3 months
if I mean I think it was before 3 months but if it wasn't so that karmically
but if it wasn't so that karmically
but if it wasn't so that karmically you're con you know is that like you
you're con you know is that like you
you're con you know is that like you most likely play that out in another
most likely play that out in another
most likely play that out in another lifetime the consequences.
lifetime the consequences.
lifetime the consequences. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Mhm. Or maybe
>> Mhm. Or maybe
>> Mhm. Or maybe >> next time you might come in get aborted
>> next time you might come in get aborted
>> next time you might come in get aborted too much.
>> Well though that's what I was thinking.
>> Well though that's what I was thinking. uh or
uh or
uh or you know to have that experience. Uh so
you know to have that experience. Uh so
you know to have that experience. Uh so anyways that was
anyways that was
anyways that was >> it's complex.
>> it's complex.
>> it's complex. >> Uhhuh.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Uhhuh. >> You just have to have faith that it all
>> You just have to have faith that it all
>> You just have to have faith that it all works out in the end. God's will
works out in the end. God's will
works out in the end. God's will prevails. In the end God's will
prevails. In the end God's will
prevails. In the end God's will prevails.
prevails.
prevails. Therefore
>> if you feel guilt about it, you ask for
>> if you feel guilt about it, you ask for forgiveness. I've made a mistake. Then I
forgiveness. I've made a mistake. Then I
forgiveness. I've made a mistake. Then I I pray for forgiveness of mistake.
I pray for forgiveness of mistake.
I pray for forgiveness of mistake. >> Mhm. And I you know so in the end God's
>> Mhm. And I you know so in the end God's
>> Mhm. And I you know so in the end God's goodness prevails. So
goodness prevails. So
goodness prevails. So >> you haven't held up the progress of
>> you haven't held up the progress of
>> you haven't held up the progress of divinity.
divinity.
divinity. >> Okay. Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you. >> We don't want to exaggerate the
>> We don't want to exaggerate the
>> We don't want to exaggerate the importance of our mistakes either
>> in the overall course of the evolution
>> in the overall course of the evolution of the universe.
It's trivial.
It's trivial. Yes. Thanks for taking my question, Dr.
Yes. Thanks for taking my question, Dr.
Yes. Thanks for taking my question, Dr. Hawkins. If if I understand what you're
Hawkins. If if I understand what you're
Hawkins. If if I understand what you're saying, uh it would seem as though the
saying, uh it would seem as though the
saying, uh it would seem as though the time of our death is predetermined from
time of our death is predetermined from
time of our death is predetermined from the time that we hit here.
the time that we hit here.
the time that we hit here. >> At the moment you're born, the moment of
>> At the moment you're born, the moment of
>> At the moment you're born, the moment of your death is already preset.
your death is already preset.
your death is already preset. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> That's where we go kinesiology. You
>> That's where we go kinesiology. You
>> That's where we go kinesiology. You know, I'm not putting money there, but
know, I'm not putting money there, but
know, I'm not putting money there, but >> that
>> that
>> that >> that's what I learned. Yeah. Well, that
>> that's what I learned. Yeah. Well, that
>> that's what I learned. Yeah. Well, that being the case, um what does that say
being the case, um what does that say
being the case, um what does that say about safety concerns or you alluded to
about safety concerns or you alluded to
about safety concerns or you alluded to skydiving or or even uh free will, the
skydiving or or even uh free will, the
skydiving or or even uh free will, the choice to um take one's own life if
choice to um take one's own life if
choice to um take one's own life if there was a severe illness or something
there was a severe illness or something
there was a severe illness or something like that?
like that?
like that? >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Is uh
>> Is uh
>> Is uh is there free will in that matter?
is there free will in that matter?
is there free will in that matter? >> Yeah, there's free will.
>> Choose to die or not to die, that's not
>> Choose to die or not to die, that's not going to determine what happens, but you
going to determine what happens, but you
going to determine what happens, but you get your you get to vote.
I'm not sure I understand that that it's
I'm not sure I understand that that it's predetermined, but I still get to vote.
predetermined, but I still get to vote.
predetermined, but I still get to vote. >> You get to vote
>> You get to vote
>> You get to vote >> the time you you can't control
>> the time you you can't control
>> the time you you can't control the however you do have the capacity to
the however you do have the capacity to
the however you do have the capacity to influence the way in which it may
influence the way in which it may
influence the way in which it may happen.
>> Okay? So that if I were a person who was
>> Okay? So that if I were a person who was in a nursing home and I was ill and
in a nursing home and I was ill and
in a nursing home and I was ill and decide, I mean, I would have that
decide, I mean, I would have that
decide, I mean, I would have that ability still.
ability still.
ability still. >> Well,
>> Well,
>> Well, >> you're going to leave the you're going
>> you're going to leave the you're going
>> you're going to leave the you're going to leave at the time that you're
to leave at the time that you're
to leave at the time that you're destined to leave. And I would presume
destined to leave. And I would presume
destined to leave. And I would presume the old lady in the wheelchair who can't
the old lady in the wheelchair who can't
the old lady in the wheelchair who can't get the hell out of here. It's because
get the hell out of here. It's because
get the hell out of here. It's because it's not time for her yet. When it's
it's not time for her yet. When it's
it's not time for her yet. When it's time, you can't stop her from getting
time, you can't stop her from getting
time, you can't stop her from getting out of here.
out of here.
out of here. >> Is there a karmic consequence to
>> Is there a karmic consequence to
>> Is there a karmic consequence to suicide?
suicide?
suicide? >> I haven't really researched the karmic
>> I haven't really researched the karmic
>> I haven't really researched the karmic consequence of suicide, but it's not as
consequence of suicide, but it's not as
consequence of suicide, but it's not as down as people think.
down as people think.
down as people think. You remember who was that lady that
You remember who was that lady that
You remember who was that lady that wrote so much the doctor about death and
wrote so much the doctor about death and
wrote so much the doctor about death and dying?
dying?
dying? >> Uh Dr. Kubler Ross.
>> Uh Dr. Kubler Ross.
>> Uh Dr. Kubler Ross. >> Kubler Ross. Right. In her research,
>> Kubler Ross. Right. In her research,
>> Kubler Ross. Right. In her research, suicide didn't appear to have any
suicide didn't appear to have any
suicide didn't appear to have any negative real negative consequence at
negative real negative consequence at
negative real negative consequence at all.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you. >> And why should God care about it? Want
>> And why should God care about it? Want
>> And why should God care about it? Want to check yourself out? Hi,
to check yourself out? Hi,
to check yourself out? Hi, can you comment on capital punishment?
>> It calibrates extremely low.
>> It calibrates extremely low. Uh, capital punishment calibrates over
Uh, capital punishment calibrates over
Uh, capital punishment calibrates over 30 35 about 30.
So
So >> that's it.
>> that's it.
>> that's it. >> Yeah. Thank you.
You were talking about spiritual will
You were talking about spiritual will doesn't and attention doesn't fluctuate
doesn't and attention doesn't fluctuate
doesn't and attention doesn't fluctuate >> and yet there seems to be an experience
>> and yet there seems to be an experience
>> and yet there seems to be an experience often called the dark night of the soul.
often called the dark night of the soul.
often called the dark night of the soul. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Feels like it's below 200.
>> Feels like it's below 200.
>> Feels like it's below 200. >> Yes. It's horrible.
>> Yes. It's horrible.
>> Yes. It's horrible. >> Can you like But you're not necessarily
>> Can you like But you're not necessarily
>> Can you like But you're not necessarily dropping to that as an overall.
dropping to that as an overall.
dropping to that as an overall. >> No. You know, you read you read all the
>> No. You know, you read you read all the
>> No. You know, you read you read all the Christian saints and many have written
Christian saints and many have written
Christian saints and many have written about the dark night of the soul.
about the dark night of the soul.
about the dark night of the soul. It seems to have been more first of all
It seems to have been more first of all
It seems to have been more first of all the Christians than others. You don't
the Christians than others. You don't
the Christians than others. You don't read so much about the dark night of the
read so much about the dark night of the
read so much about the dark night of the soul coming from India
soul coming from India
soul coming from India or Buddhism.
It's not really a familiar thing in
It's not really a familiar thing in Buddhist literature. No, in it's more in
Buddhist literature. No, in it's more in
Buddhist literature. No, in it's more in Christian literature.
Christian literature.
Christian literature. It's like you transcend all your dark
It's like you transcend all your dark
It's like you transcend all your dark karma, go into a great place, and uh now
karma, go into a great place, and uh now
karma, go into a great place, and uh now your negative karma of the undone comes
your negative karma of the undone comes
your negative karma of the undone comes up, takes you out of it. See,
up, takes you out of it. See,
up, takes you out of it. See, >> negative karma of the undone.
>> negative karma of the undone.
>> negative karma of the undone. >> The undone.
>> The undone.
>> The undone. >> Okay,
>> Okay,
>> Okay, >> you've transcended up to there, but
>> you've transcended up to there, but
>> you've transcended up to there, but there's farther to go. And now because
there's farther to go. And now because
there's farther to go. And now because you're not and now what you've brought
you're not and now what you've brought
you're not and now what you've brought up is stuff that would not have been
up is stuff that would not have been
up is stuff that would not have been brought up had you not
brought up had you not
brought up had you not uh risen to that level.
uh risen to that level.
uh risen to that level. You're not going to have a problem with
You're not going to have a problem with
You're not going to have a problem with forgiveness until you until you really
forgiveness until you until you really
forgiveness until you until you really do the course of miracles. And now
do the course of miracles. And now
do the course of miracles. And now forgiveness is the biggest problem in
forgiveness is the biggest problem in
forgiveness is the biggest problem in your life. You see you see everything in
your life. You see you see everything in
your life. You see you see everything in terms of condemnation.
terms of condemnation.
terms of condemnation. You're okay until you set a higher
You're okay until you set a higher
You're okay until you set a higher spiritual goal. Now you brought your
spiritual goal. Now you brought your
spiritual goal. Now you brought your bottom up. You brought up your bottom.
bottom up. You brought up your bottom.
bottom up. You brought up your bottom. See?
See?
See? So you used to be able to hate bad
So you used to be able to hate bad
So you used to be able to hate bad people and right
people and right
people and right >> it was no problem.
>> it was no problem.
>> it was no problem. >> Now you're guilten.
I have to see Ludicrous as an okay guy.
I have to see Ludicrous as an okay guy. Isn't that tough? How am I going to see
Isn't that tough? How am I going to see
Isn't that tough? How am I going to see Ludicrous as an okay guy? You talking
Ludicrous as an okay guy? You talking
Ludicrous as an okay guy? You talking about hollow, they call them hollow
about hollow, they call them hollow
about hollow, they call them hollow point bullets,
point bullets,
point bullets, kicking pregnant wives in the belly.
kicking pregnant wives in the belly.
kicking pregnant wives in the belly. Am I supposed to love this guy?
See what a problem I got now. Didn't
See what a problem I got now. Didn't have that problem before I did the
have that problem before I did the
have that problem before I did the course of miracles.
course of miracles.
course of miracles. I thought he was a swell guy or else I
I thought he was a swell guy or else I
I thought he was a swell guy or else I hated him. But I didn't have any
hated him. But I didn't have any
hated him. But I didn't have any problem. But once you do so, all right.
problem. But once you do so, all right.
problem. But once you do so, all right. So spiritual evolution itself will now
So spiritual evolution itself will now
So spiritual evolution itself will now keep giving you new problems that will
keep giving you new problems that will
keep giving you new problems that will take you out of euphoria.
take you out of euphoria.
take you out of euphoria. When you're over your
When you're over your
When you're over your when you're when you're um ahead of your
when you're when you're um ahead of your
when you're when you're um ahead of your karma, you feel euphoric,
karma, you feel euphoric,
karma, you feel euphoric, but then that doesn't last,
but then that doesn't last,
but then that doesn't last, >> right?
>> right?
>> right? >> Because the next lesson comes up,
>> Because the next lesson comes up,
>> Because the next lesson comes up, >> right?
>> right?
>> right? >> So, it doesn't mean you've fallen. It
>> So, it doesn't mean you've fallen. It
>> So, it doesn't mean you've fallen. It means that you're still advancing,
means that you're still advancing,
means that you're still advancing, >> right?
>> right?
>> right? >> If you stop advancing, you probably go
>> If you stop advancing, you probably go
>> If you stop advancing, you probably go back into euphoria again.
back into euphoria again.
back into euphoria again. >> Really? So, so it'll continue to feel
>> Really? So, so it'll continue to feel
>> Really? So, so it'll continue to feel >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. So long as you're ahead of your karma,
So long as you're ahead of your karma,
So long as you're ahead of your karma, see, but
see, but
see, but >> the spirit doesn't allow you to stay
>> the spirit doesn't allow you to stay
>> the spirit doesn't allow you to stay there,
there,
there, >> then the spirit says, "What about this?"
>> then the spirit says, "What about this?"
>> then the spirit says, "What about this?" >> Right?
>> Right?
>> Right? >> Well, I because I did the course of
>> Well, I because I did the course of
>> Well, I because I did the course of miracles for a really long time and it
miracles for a really long time and it
miracles for a really long time and it felt like I cut out a whole level and
felt like I cut out a whole level and
felt like I cut out a whole level and hit a point of grace for a very long
hit a point of grace for a very long
hit a point of grace for a very long time and now it's like all the
time and now it's like all the
time and now it's like all the unconscious are like
unconscious are like
unconscious are like >> that's from past lifetime or Yeah.
>> that's from past lifetime or Yeah.
>> that's from past lifetime or Yeah. >> What she's picking up is from past
>> What she's picking up is from past
>> What she's picking up is from past lifetimes. Yeah. The past lifetimes are
lifetimes. Yeah. The past lifetimes are
lifetimes. Yeah. The past lifetimes are catching up with you.
catching up with you.
catching up with you. >> Oh, good.
>> Oh, good.
>> Oh, good. >> But that's good. That I mean that's good
>> But that's good. That I mean that's good
>> But that's good. That I mean that's good because I can then move through them.
because I can then move through them.
because I can then move through them. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> You know, the Buddha said he was beset
>> You know, the Buddha said he was beset
>> You know, the Buddha said he was beset by demons, you know, beset by demons. In
by demons, you know, beset by demons. In
by demons, you know, beset by demons. In my lifetime, I've been fried by them,
my lifetime, I've been fried by them,
my lifetime, I've been fried by them, you know.
you know.
you know. Fry your nervous system. God almighty,
Fry your nervous system. God almighty,
Fry your nervous system. God almighty, you know.
you know.
you know. Well, I I understand like because it
Well, I I understand like because it
Well, I I understand like because it always felt like I'd done something
always felt like I'd done something
always felt like I'd done something wrong because I I know that as you are
wrong because I I know that as you are
wrong because I I know that as you are so you draw to you and then to suddenly
so you draw to you and then to suddenly
so you draw to you and then to suddenly hit such a bottom is like oh what did I
hit such a bottom is like oh what did I
hit such a bottom is like oh what did I do wrong?
do wrong?
do wrong? >> You become a challenge to your opposite.
>> You become a challenge to your opposite.
>> You become a challenge to your opposite. >> Say it again.
>> Say it again.
>> Say it again. >> You become a challenge. The forces that
>> You become a challenge. The forces that
>> You become a challenge. The forces that prevail due to lack of integrity. See as
prevail due to lack of integrity. See as
prevail due to lack of integrity. See as you evolve you become a threat to them.
you evolve you become a threat to them.
you evolve you become a threat to them. You can run in run the way you run in
You can run in run the way you run in
You can run in run the way you run in run, but when the integity level jumps
run, but when the integity level jumps
run, but when the integity level jumps over 205, you can't run and run the
over 205, you can't run and run the
over 205, you can't run and run the other way anymore.
other way anymore.
other way anymore. >> Yep.
>> Yep.
>> Yep. >> Okay. Very much.
>> Okay. Very much.
>> Okay. Very much. >> Ro,
>> Ro,
>> Ro, you're almost through.
you're almost through.
you're almost through. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> We're going to quit at six. Go ahead.
>> We're going to quit at six. Go ahead.
>> We're going to quit at six. Go ahead. >> Good. Dr. Hawkins, u
>> Good. Dr. Hawkins, u
>> Good. Dr. Hawkins, u Dr. Dr. Ian Stevenson, uh, University of
Dr. Dr. Ian Stevenson, uh, University of
Dr. Dr. Ian Stevenson, uh, University of Virginia, psychiatrist,
Virginia, psychiatrist,
Virginia, psychiatrist, age probably about 82 or three now. Back
age probably about 82 or three now. Back
age probably about 82 or three now. Back in the early 70s, he did he did a book
in the early 70s, he did he did a book
in the early 70s, he did he did a book called 20 cases suggestive of
called 20 cases suggestive of
called 20 cases suggestive of reincarnation. By that time, he he had
reincarnation. By that time, he he had
reincarnation. By that time, he he had >> Oh, yeah.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Oh, yeah. >> checked memories of kids
>> checked memories of kids
>> checked memories of kids >> right
>> right
>> right >> throughout the world.
>> throughout the world.
>> throughout the world. >> Uhhuh.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Uhhuh. >> By that time about a thousand. Now he's
>> By that time about a thousand. Now he's
>> By that time about a thousand. Now he's up at about 7,000. Yeah.
up at about 7,000. Yeah.
up at about 7,000. Yeah. >> A book called Old Souls written by the
>> A book called Old Souls written by the
>> A book called Old Souls written by the >> trying to document reincarnation.
>> trying to document reincarnation.
>> trying to document reincarnation. >> Now I I uh I met him some years ago when
>> Now I I uh I met him some years ago when
>> Now I I uh I met him some years ago when he had just written the book actually
he had just written the book actually
he had just written the book actually was still in manuscript form when I was
was still in manuscript form when I was
was still in manuscript form when I was uh well on the west coast and I asked
uh well on the west coast and I asked
uh well on the west coast and I asked him when does the soul usually enter the
him when does the soul usually enter the
him when does the soul usually enter the body?
body?
body? >> Uhhuh.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Uhhuh. >> He said at birth. Almost always at
>> He said at birth. Almost always at
>> He said at birth. Almost always at birth. Sometimes there's a little delay
birth. Sometimes there's a little delay
birth. Sometimes there's a little delay maybe a day or two a week. Where does
maybe a day or two a week. Where does
maybe a day or two a week. Where does the soul enter? I asked. Never forget
the soul enter? I asked. Never forget
the soul enter? I asked. Never forget the conversation and you said almost
the conversation and you said almost
the conversation and you said almost always through the soft part of the uh
always through the soft part of the uh
always through the soft part of the uh of the skull.
of the skull.
of the skull. >> Fontineel. Yeah.
>> Fontineel. Yeah.
>> Fontineel. Yeah. >> So you're coming up with three months.
>> So you're coming up with three months.
>> So you're coming up with three months. >> That's what I get with kinesiology when
>> That's what I get with kinesiology when
>> That's what I get with kinesiology when I ask the question.
I ask the question.
I ask the question. >> Okay. Do you want to try it again in
>> Okay. Do you want to try it again in
>> Okay. Do you want to try it again in light of uh in light of Ian Stevenson?
light of uh in light of Ian Stevenson?
light of uh in light of Ian Stevenson? The soul enters at birth.
The soul enters at birth.
The soul enters at birth. >> Soul enters. We have permission to ask
>> Soul enters. We have permission to ask
>> Soul enters. We have permission to ask this in front of this audience.
this in front of this audience.
this in front of this audience. the spirit enters the embryo
the spirit enters the embryo
the spirit enters the embryo uh before the third month
uh before the third month
uh before the third month after the third month. I don't know.
after the third month. I don't know.
after the third month. I don't know. Let's get the same answer.
Let's get the same answer.
Let's get the same answer. >> Well, then we have a a difference.
>> Well, then we have a a difference.
>> Well, then we have a a difference. >> No, because you see spirit bodyic body
>> No, because you see spirit bodyic body
>> No, because you see spirit bodyic body is not physical. So, it doesn't enter
is not physical. So, it doesn't enter
is not physical. So, it doesn't enter the brain in the first place.
the brain in the first place.
the brain in the first place. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Okay. It doesn't need a fontineel
>> Okay. It doesn't need a fontineel
>> Okay. It doesn't need a fontineel because it's not physical. And the soul
because it's not physical. And the soul
because it's not physical. And the soul is a much broader uh kind of part of
is a much broader uh kind of part of
is a much broader uh kind of part of oneself.
oneself.
oneself. >> Okay. So part enters early.
>> Okay. So part enters early.
>> Okay. So part enters early. >> Yeah. Stevenson thinking of it in more
>> Yeah. Stevenson thinking of it in more
>> Yeah. Stevenson thinking of it in more physical terms.
physical terms.
physical terms. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> But it's probably more like a diffuse
>> But it's probably more like a diffuse
>> But it's probably more like a diffuse field.
field.
field. >> Probably more like a diffuse field
>> Probably more like a diffuse field
>> Probably more like a diffuse field >> a minute ago.
>> a minute ago.
>> a minute ago. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. I haven't heard of this name in a long
I haven't heard of this name in a long
I haven't heard of this name in a long time. Stevenson.
time. Stevenson.
time. Stevenson. Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. like to know if you are in a situation
like to know if you are in a situation
like to know if you are in a situation that seems to be difficult where the
that seems to be difficult where the
that seems to be difficult where the environment may be at a lower
environment may be at a lower
environment may be at a lower consciousness level than you are and I'm
consciousness level than you are and I'm
consciousness level than you are and I'm thinking in particular of a job I have
thinking in particular of a job I have
thinking in particular of a job I have um is it how what's the best way to be
um is it how what's the best way to be
um is it how what's the best way to be able to hold on to your own level of
able to hold on to your own level of
able to hold on to your own level of consciousness and not be pulled down
consciousness and not be pulled down
consciousness and not be pulled down >> uh it won't pull down uh except with
>> uh it won't pull down uh except with
>> uh it won't pull down uh except with your agreement. So if it's a lower level
your agreement. So if it's a lower level
your agreement. So if it's a lower level consciousness than your own own, then
consciousness than your own own, then
consciousness than your own own, then it's a test pattern you're in.
it's a test pattern you're in.
it's a test pattern you're in. If we, you know, if we aggravate her
If we, you know, if we aggravate her
If we, you know, if we aggravate her enough, she'll finally hate us.
enough, she'll finally hate us.
enough, she'll finally hate us. >> What?
>> What?
>> What? >> After you pass the test, it'll
>> After you pass the test, it'll
>> After you pass the test, it'll disappear.
>> It's like looking for your weak spots.
>> It's like looking for your weak spots. We aggravate her enough, sooner or
We aggravate her enough, sooner or
We aggravate her enough, sooner or later, we'll get her to hate us. And she
later, we'll get her to hate us. And she
later, we'll get her to hate us. And she will no longer become an enemy of us.
will no longer become an enemy of us.
will no longer become an enemy of us. She'll enjoy the haters of the world.
She'll enjoy the haters of the world.
She'll enjoy the haters of the world. But if you resist that and make a
But if you resist that and make a
But if you resist that and make a choice, it will disappear from your
choice, it will disappear from your
choice, it will disappear from your life. It will have served a purpose
life. It will have served a purpose
life. It will have served a purpose >> which is
>> which is
>> which is >> and then you'll be surrounded with nice
>> and then you'll be surrounded with nice
>> and then you'll be surrounded with nice people
people
people >> that seems to have happened.
>> that seems to have happened.
>> that seems to have happened. >> It's like a test period in your life.
>> It's like a test period in your life.
>> It's like a test period in your life. >> Okay?
>> Okay?
>> Okay? >> If you just keep returning negativity
>> If you just keep returning negativity
>> If you just keep returning negativity with positive happiness and
with positive happiness and
with positive happiness and good and blessings etc it will disappear
good and blessings etc it will disappear
good and blessings etc it will disappear from your life. Okay, thank you.
from your life. Okay, thank you.
from your life. Okay, thank you. >> There'll be nothing to hold it in place
>> There'll be nothing to hold it in place
>> There'll be nothing to hold it in place anymore. It's being held in place by the
anymore. It's being held in place by the
anymore. It's being held in place by the test pattern.
test pattern.
test pattern. Yeah.
>> Dr. Hawkins, I wanted to ask you, what
>> Dr. Hawkins, I wanted to ask you, what is the nature of true service?
is the nature of true service?
is the nature of true service? >> Nature, what?
True service. Service to God.
True service. Service to God. uh that would take all day but briefly
uh that would take all day but briefly
uh that would take all day but briefly it is to surrender one's personal
it is to surrender one's personal
it is to surrender one's personal willfulness
willfulness
willfulness yeah
yeah
yeah in the 12 steps I think are very end
in the 12 steps I think are very end
in the 12 steps I think are very end also the course of miracles to
surrender oneself one's life to God now
surrender oneself one's life to God now you don't know what that means
and as time goes on you realize that you
and as time goes on you realize that you never did know what it means because
never did know what it means because
never did know what it means because it's revealed to you differently. It's
it's revealed to you differently. It's
it's revealed to you differently. It's comes by revelation
what is it you're supposed to surrender
what is it you're supposed to surrender to God. You know
to God. You know
to God. You know to even know what that means probably
to even know what that means probably
to even know what that means probably takes a lifetime. So the what the will
takes a lifetime. So the what the will
takes a lifetime. So the what the will of God means then is comes as a
of God means then is comes as a
of God means then is comes as a revelation. So it means one thing at
revelation. So it means one thing at
revelation. So it means one thing at this level, one thing at this level, one
this level, one thing at this level, one
this level, one thing at this level, one thing at this level, one thing at this
thing at this level, one thing at this
thing at this level, one thing at this level.
level.
level. And when it served its purpose at this
And when it served its purpose at this
And when it served its purpose at this level, it takes on a new meaning at the
level, it takes on a new meaning at the
level, it takes on a new meaning at the next level.
next level.
next level. >> Just a follow up to that, the reason I
>> Just a follow up to that, the reason I
>> Just a follow up to that, the reason I asked that sometimes it feels like
asked that sometimes it feels like
asked that sometimes it feels like there's an overwhelming sense of
there's an overwhelming sense of
there's an overwhelming sense of responsibility.
responsibility.
responsibility. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> And I'm wondering is that the
>> And I'm wondering is that the
>> And I'm wondering is that the unworthiness of the ego, the
unworthiness of the ego, the
unworthiness of the ego, the unworthiness of the ego or the
unworthiness of the ego or the
unworthiness of the ego or the aspiration of the soul?
aspiration of the soul?
aspiration of the soul? >> Yes. It's a combination of both with
>> Yes. It's a combination of both with
>> Yes. It's a combination of both with prayer uh you get the illumination of
prayer uh you get the illumination of
prayer uh you get the illumination of it.
it.
it. You you'll get illumination. You just
You you'll get illumination. You just
You you'll get illumination. You just say
say
say dear God I ask God of your kindness and
dear God I ask God of your kindness and
dear God I ask God of your kindness and beneficence for clarification of this
beneficence for clarification of this
beneficence for clarification of this understanding and I ask the Holy Spirit
understanding and I ask the Holy Spirit
understanding and I ask the Holy Spirit for a miracle
for a miracle
for a miracle and then forget it.
and then forget it.
and then forget it. Then as you're driving down the road
Then as you're driving down the road
Then as you're driving down the road it's a snap.
it's a snap.
it's a snap. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Okay.