Today, we're going to discuss what is real success.
Real?
Real.
So, that's the topic.
So, what would you say, when I think of that, what is real success,
immediately people think that money and position and personal goals are what they consider is real success.
When I ask you as a spiritual teacher what real success is, how would you interpret that?
I would, as a spiritual teacher, say it has to do with fulfilling your obligations to experience the presence of God to the fullest possible extent.
And to begin to realize that as you do this, everything reveals itself.
As divinity.
As you ask me the question, the divinity of this moment is now revealing itself to me.
It seems at first like an artificially posed thought.
Then you realize that there is no such thing as an artificially posed thought.
That thought is originating from the presence of God as the reality of you and I sitting here on this couch speaking at this moment.
That is the presence of God as existence.
From moment to moment, the existence of that which is real is nothing but the realization that God is the essence of all reality.
Thank you, Lord. Amen.
God told me to say that.
Well, you know, a lot of people think that they're successful if they have money.
Oh, yeah.
A lot of them, you know.
So you've always said that if a person, as far as it goes, is if they do the best they can at what they do.
That's it.
That success will automatically come to them.
Yes.
And I don't want to put down material success.
It's okay to be a millionaire and to be world famous and on television every day and have worshipful crowds.
I don't want to.
There's no point to make that.
That's wrong.
That's how success comes to that person.
We need famous people to hang out around and enjoy their presence.
So we get to share in the joy of their success.
So if people are joyfully successful, I say thank you.
Thank you for your success because we're all enjoying your enjoyment of it.
And we all need Bob.
Bob Hope and Bing Crosby.
That sort of dates me, doesn't it?
Who would be a current example?
Well, a lot of people, you know, they...
Can you give me a current example?
Well, like, you know, fame.
You know, they want to be famous and recognized.
Like I were.
Is there any people like that today?
What?
People.
Who is these people?
Can you name me one successful person?
Well, many come to mind.
I mean...
Like?
Jay Letterman.
Who?
Yeah, Jay Letterman.
Jay Leno.
Oh, oh, oh.
I see what you're saying.
I don't know who they are, but it sounds good to me.
All right.
Well, you know, politicians are, you know, famous.
President.
Yeah.
Who is the president of the United States?
Obama.
Oh, Michelle Obama?
No, no.
Barack.
Barack?
Barack Obama.
That's a funny name.
Is that his real first name?
Barack?
Yeah?
Barack.
Oh.
Oh, he seemed like a nice fellow.
I liked him.
And with the name of Barack, if Obama would become president, you really got to have something
on the ball.
You know what I mean?
It was John Obama.
So, Phil.
Well, my question is, real success, is it what you are in the world?
Or is it how the world sees you?
Well, the real success is its own self-fulfillment.
Real success is achieving the fulfillment and expression of your own potentialities.
The world may or may not recognize that.
So, the world's response to it.
However, real success would really include not only fulfillment of your own potentiality,
but the response of the world to it.
So, it's perfectly all right to be president of the United States.
I think it's great that he fulfilled his potentiality.
And I also enjoy the fact that the world recognizes it.
That is a name, right?
Isn't it?
Philip Obama?
I don't know.
Barack.
Barack Obama?
Mm-hmm.
That's his first name?
Yeah.
Barack?
Yeah?
Okay.
Anyway, I enjoy him when I see him speak.
I think he's very eloquent.
Very eloquent speaker.
Yes.
More eloquent than I am, he's very eloquent.
Mm-hmm.
I'm glad he's president because he's very eloquent and sort of elegant, actually.
Very elegant, yeah.
Okay, but who you are in the world versus what you are in the world.
So, how would you describe that?
Well, who is the personality?
And what?
It has to do with function.
You're a what when you sit here and talk to the camera.
Mm-hmm.
Right now, I'm being a what.
But there is a who being that what.
Mm-hmm.
So, there's both a who and a what.
And the what is the momentary expression of that who.
Who is being whatever that person is being at the moment.
Mm-hmm.
It's okay.
It's okay to be both who and what.
Okay.
In fact, you really have to be both a who and a what at the same time.
Because who is it that's being a what?
Well, do you think that the ego comes in to play when the who is there?
I think the who, yes.
The who is the...
Inter...
Is the villain, yeah.
The who.
Mm-hmm.
And the what is...
Is the external expression of it.
So, everybody is both who and what at the same time, all the time.
If you think about who, then you get sort of expanded.
Or you get embarrassed or nervous.
I don't know who's speaking right now.
Well, I guess me, yeah.
But what is it that's speaking?
Because whatever is speaking right now is happening spontaneously.
Mm-hmm.
I don't have time to give thought to what I'm going to say.
And you don't give me any time to say or to think about it.
What's it all about, baby?
Is real success how people see you or how you see yourself?
Well, real success, I think, fulfills both.
You can be really successful and keep it privately to yourself.
That's real success.
You fulfill your own goals.
You don't need public rights.
You don't need recognition.
If my goal is to chop down this tree and have it all sawed up by 4 o'clock this afternoon,
then when I do that, I'm a real success.
Mm-hmm.
And nobody knows about it except myself.
So, real success to me is then the self-fulfillment of a self-goal.
And the world may or may not even notice it.
Mm-hmm.
So, I have to make myself happy.
So, we're talking...
I'm talking this morning, and I have to make myself happy that I'm understanding the points that you are trying to stimulate me to focus on.
Mm-hmm.
So, if I'm not sure what you're wanting me to focus on, then I'm not happy.
Am I applying myself to what you want me to focus on?
Yes.
Then I'm happy.
Thank you, sweetheart.
Oh, gee, that was an easy one.
Some people are hard to hire.
You're an easy one.
When we become judgmental, do we judge people for who they are, or do we judge people for what they are?
Well, we do both.
We do both.
The mind really doesn't choose either or.
It spontaneously does them all at the same time.
The person is famous.
They should be famous.
We're glad they're famous.
Sometimes we criticize somebody because they're famous for what we consider to be the wrong reasons.
They've committed a crime or done something hideous, and so we're critical of them for being famous.
They're really not famous.
They're really infamous.
Infamous.
So, when fame reaches the height of negativity, we call it infamous.
Infamous rather than famous.
People, you know, serial killers and all.
We don't say they're famous.
We say they're infamous.
Do you think that people sometimes set goals for themselves a little high?
Like, you know, sometimes people have higher expectations than they're willing to.
Oh, yes.
Well, I think you can set the goal as high as you want.
And the expectations...
Expectation has to be then tailored to what's possible.
You know, you can set your goal to be President of the United States,
but only one person is going to achieve that every four years.
So, there's nothing wrong with setting it as a goal and hoping to be the best.
I hope that we speak in a clearly eloquent and hopeful style this morning.
That's a hope.
And I would like to...
I hope that we've achieved that goal, that we've been able to help clarify
that's an important part of human life.
Because we don't like to admit that it's a big part, but frankly, it is.
Frankly, it's a big part, whether you have friends that like you
and you're well thought of in your neighborhood
and you're successful at whatever your work is.
Those things are important.
You'd like to pretend they're not.
But even if it's shoveling the sidewalk,
when you get through shoveling all the snow off the sidewalk,
you stand back and you look at it, you feel pleased.
So, I guess just feeling pleased and satisfied is sufficient.
It's just shovel all the snow off, nobody slipped and hurt themselves,
and you feel good that you've fulfilled your responsibility as a good neighbor.
So, true success is on different levels, then, actually.
So, you have your personal success, such as chopping the tree up
and getting it done by 4 o'clock.
You have your financial success, which is the goals you set for yourself outside.
You have your spiritual success, which is your relationship with God.
And then you have, you know, family and everything else that are other successes.
So, you know...
Relationship.
A good wife, a good husband.
So, actually, success, when we lump it together, that's unfair
because there's so many different types of success.
Yeah, personal success, marital success, parental success.
When your kid gets a good mark at school and comes home with a thing on it.
I remember when I was a kid, if you got good marks, you got a little star on your collar.
So, I couldn't wait to get home and show my mom my star on my collar.
She said, what have you got there?
I said, star, Mom.
Oh, boy, oh, boy.
Didn't you tell me about a teacher you once had that you were telling...
You were very intellectual anyway, but you came home and told a story about something.
I forgot what it was.
A steamship or something like that.
And the teacher told your parents you had a very imaginative imagination, and here it was all true.
I was born with a genius.
And so I was often smarter than the teacher.
And the teacher would give a short lecture on something,
and then I would correct the teacher because I didn't understand the subtleties of such things.
So, the teacher would explain their understanding, but I, as I said, had a genius IQ.
And I knew the whole encyclopedia.
So, I would elaborate on it for the teacher's benefit and the class's benefit.
I didn't do it for my benefit.
I thought they'd like to know the facts, which I had read the encyclopedia already about.
When I was a kid, I read the encyclopedia.
Other kids are reading the funny papers.
It seems very funny now that I was reading the encyclopedia.
I remember I got up to R, and I thought, oh, whammo, I'm up to R already, you know what I mean?
I've only been at it a week.
A week?
Yeah.
It took you a week to read things?
To get up to R, yeah.
Oh, my gosh.
Well, that would be a success in itself.
I don't know if I finished X, Y, and Z in the meantime.
Zebra, Zappo.
But, I mean, those are successes in their own right.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
So, I was just...
You know, it's successes to fulfill your own goal.
Right.
I was one time digging a ditch, and I set myself as a goal to dig six feet a day.
Well, six feet a ditch depends on how deep it is.
It can be quite a chore.
It can be shallow, it's not much.
But if it's deep, six feet a day is a lot of digging.
And I can remember when I dug six feet a day of ditch, and I said, wow, that was a great day, you know?
Mm-hmm.
All stone and rock, and six feet of it was quite an accomplishment, especially when you were a small ectomorph like I was.
So, if you were to...
I was an ectomorph.
Yeah.
You know what an ectomorph is?
Yes.
Okay, well, I was a small ectomorph.
I started digging a six-foot ditch was quite an accomplishment.
So, if you were to tell people what type of goals they should set for themselves,
as far as it goes, as spiritual goals, what would you say?
You're going to divide them up?
I mean, I was going to divide them up myself.
Oh, all right.
I'll say, all right.
All right.
No, I'll do it your way.
No, that's all right.
Spiritual goals, you know, would be different for every person, I think.
Some people would only consider becoming enlightened itself.
That's the fulfillment.
Other people, they just believe in God in the first place, or to even go to church.
I know people who never even go to church.
And finally on, what do you want to call it, day?
Ash Wednesday.
Ash Wednesday, they went to church.
And so that was an achievement for them, to just go to church and to fulfill the goal of,
at least the external appearances of...
Religion, religiosity.
We went to church on...
Ash Wednesday.
Ash Wednesday, yes.
Even the name itself seemed mysterious, you know.
Ash, what do you mean?
Ashes to ashes and dust to dust.
Oh, wow.
So, you know, you can contemplate on that for a couple of years.
Ashes to ashes and dust to dust.
What does that fully signify?
Well, the intellect has a quick answer for it.
But as you begin to contemplate, ashes to ashes and dust to dust,
I look at you and I say, you and I are both going to become ashes someday, sweetheart.
Well, honey, you never saw a U-Haul following a hearse, have you?
Oh, that's a funny one.
Very funny one.
So we can't take it with us.
Can't take it with you, no.
Well, you don't want to take it with you.
It would be excess baggage in heaven, yes.
And heaven is more of a state of being rather than a state of doing.
Okay.
People say, what do you do in heaven?
Well, there's nothing to do except just be.
So just being is enough.
To do.
We went to church for some really Sunday there.
And it wasn't, it had nothing to do with what was being done.
It was all the who of and the significance of the presence and the symbolism of it all.
The symbolism of reverence for the presence of God as existence is,
is,
done at this moment.
And the hands are doing it of themselves.
And I look at the hands and I say,
hands, what are you expressing?
You're not expressing what I'm thinking because I'm not thinking anything.
I ask the hands to express the reverence of the presence of,
the awareness of the presence of God as existence.
And I thank the hands for fulfilling that obligation.
So with the mind,
uh,
it thinks the mind can then represent and therefore with a certain level of intention,
every moment is expressing the presence of God.
The divinity of the presence of God is expressing itself every second.
In fact,
it cannot be otherwise.
It can only be the failure,
the ability to recognize it as such or the inability to recognize it as such.
So as you and I sit here and speak,
I say,
I feel by using whatever talents I may have in the service of,
of the Lord,
that I'm serving God by sitting here next to you and you're doing the same thing
with me.
So you and I right now are serving God to the best of our knowledge to share our
understanding of divinity and the intention of divinity.
and how to fulfill that.
That may not be somebody else's,
but it doesn't make any difference
because I want to hear everybody's idea on it.
I want to hear everybody's thoughts
on how do I fulfill God's obligation
or my responsibility to God.
I think that's a really interesting question
to ask everybody.
I'd like to ask a whole dozen different people
doing different things in the world.
How do you feel you're fulfilling God's obligation
and get the interesting answers?
I go to work every day and I support my children
and I pay my taxes and I'm good to my wife
and I shovel the snow
and I make sure the car has gas in it.
Fulfilling one's obligation to human life
is a way of fulfilling the intention of divinity
because it is through divinity
that we experience life.
And at least it's human form.
A lot of people think that success
is actually changing the world,
making a difference in the world.
That's worldly success, yeah.
Well, yeah, but a lot of people set their goals at that.
Oh, I see, yeah.
They want to change the thought
of everyone around them.
Oh, yeah.
To make a difference.
Influence.
Yeah, they want to put their mark
on the world.
So what you're saying is
by being a better person spiritually,
you do put your mark on the world.
We do it silently.
But we do it silently.
Yes.
The fact that you're present in the room
makes what goes on in the room differently.
Let's see if that's true.
Let me have your hand.
Even if you say nothing,
the presence of a...
spiritually advanced person in a room
changes everything that happens in that room.
Resist.
Oh, wow.
So even if you just lay on the floor
and say nothing,
the energy that you emanate
is affecting everything around you.
Well, that's a nice thing to know,
that you're light.
In other words, your life has value
all the time,
even though you're not out there
doing spectacular things,
being famous, writing famous music,
appearing on stage,
or just...
Okay, so let's have the arm again.
Just being the excellence
of the possibility within yourself
of whatever it may be
is serving God.
Okay, to sing the best song you can sing,
to dance the best dance,
you and I right now
are fulfilling an obligation to each other.
You said we're going to be giving
a little talk this morning
that we're going to be recording,
and I was thinking,
I was panic-stricken.
I said, oh, my God,
I haven't thought about this.
What am I going to talk about?
And as we sat down here,
my inner mind said,
oh, my God,
what are we going to talk about?
And right now, my mind is saying,
oh, my God,
what are we going to talk about?
I have no idea
what we're going to be speaking about
this morning.
Let me have your arm.
Thank you.
I just wanted you to give me my arm
for no reason this morning.
I didn't like this.
I think it's important to ask you.
I already asked you before.
I thought if it was not God's intention
for me to be sitting here
speaking to you
in the style in which I am,
there is no other possibility
except to be doing
what God wants me to do,
which is sitting here
commenting to you
on your presence
and the effect that it has on me.
So you, as yourself,
what would you say
What would you say success looks like to you?
To me?
Mm-hmm.
Oh, okay.
Would you share that with us?
Well, to me, success means multiple things simultaneously, because you might ask it from
different areas.
Am I being successful in fulfilling your expectation of me this morning to come forth and spontaneously
answer these questions?
That's what I'm doing.
So I'm happy that I am fulfilling what I understood was your question to me.
Could we go into the studio and discuss a few of these important questions?
So I feel satisfied that I am fulfilling your expectation of me.
And so I'm hoping that my doing so makes you happy.
So your happiness is part of my intention all the time.
I mean, I always want you to be happy, and there's no moment when I ... I've never had
a wish that you should not be happy.
Never.
I never crossed my mind.
I want you to be happy all the time.
And so the only reason I'm worried about how the doggies are behaving is I want the doggies
to add to your happiness.
I don't want the doggie to have an accident, which would detract from your happiness.
So that's why we let the doggie out, to make sure that the doggie wouldn't interrupt our
fulfillment of this obligation this morning.
Is the search for enlightenment or bettering one's spiritual understanding, is that ... it's
an entirely different success than, say, worldly success?
Well, yes, spiritually, success has nothing to do with the world, really.
On one level, it has everything to do with it, but on the level at which you're asking
it, it has really nothing to do with it.
Because success is an inner goal, an inner expectation, partly based on an awareness
of what your capacities are.
So if I feel I've successfully, adequately answered your questions, then I'll feel satisfied
that I've adequately addressed them, carefully listened to them, and allowed themselves to
spontaneously answer.
So these moments that we have right this very instant are all happening spontaneously.
I have no idea of what they are.
I don't know.
I don't know what to talk about, other than that we were going to be here to speak.
So I trust, there's a certain trust, there's a certain inner trust that my inner self will
automatically adjust itself to fulfill the expectations of the moment, one of them being
that your satisfaction at the way in which I'm answering you right this moment.
So I'm feeling happy that you ... you might possibly be happy with the way I'm answering
you right this moment.
You might be happy with the way I'm being right now.
Are you being happy with the way I'm being right now?
Yes.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Okay.
You're not just saying that to make me feel good.
No, no.
But there's another ... you have to put a point down.
All right.
So a lot of people that are successful in their spiritual life do not have worldly success.
I mean, that's ...
That's true.
You know.
Because ... do you think it's because they concentrated all their ... I mean that the
Spiritual success is more important to them than worldly?
That's all it is.
And the fulfillment is of spiritual goals.
The other day we went to church for, what is it,
Happy Wednesday morning?
What do you call it?
Ash Wednesday.
Huh?
Oh, Ash Wednesday, right.
Unhappy day.
Anyway, we got there on time,
fulfilled the obligation to ourself
that we decided we wished to do that.
Not everybody goes, and we didn't always go every year.
Some years you feel like for some reason
it's important that we go this week.
It could be for unknown reasons.
I think most things happen for unknown reasons.
I think our mind gives us an explanation,
but I think the explanation may have very little to do
with the reality.
There was possibly people affected just by our physical presence
in the room itself, of which we had no comprehension.
A little doggy barking by the side of the beach.
Doesn't know he's barking to make you happy,
but that may be what keeps a little sick kid alive.
The puppy that loves the sick child keeps the child alive.
The sick puppy doesn't know it's doing it.
I mean, the puppy doesn't know it's doing it.
But there are children in hospitals whose lives are extended
by the presence of having a puppy or a dog.
And I think the study of the effect of dogs on human life
is very, very fascinating.
Not only that it extends your life ten years,
but it increases the quality.
So the quality of our life is much higher
since we got Kelsey dog.
And I don't know what Kelsey cost us, five bucks?
Yeah.
No.
Good.
Three?
No.
Fifteen?
We adopted her, so no, it wasn't that.
No?
No.
Anyway, the presence of that dog in our life makes a difference.
And even now as we speak, in the back of my mind,
I realize the dog is sitting home waiting for us to come home
from the studio.
And that as we get closer and closer, her tail will start to wag.
She will feel happier and happier and more and more excited.
Mm-hmm.
That makes life joyful.
The fact that your existence brings joy to others.
So when I approach the kitties, they start to purr.
The big orange kitty always goes purr, purr, purr, purr.
And that makes me happy.
I can hear the kitties' happiness.
And the doggie's tail is wagging.
And then we've got an African talking parrot.
Is that his name? African talking parrot?
African gray.
And the parrot starts talking up a storm.
So the kitty's purring.
The dog's tail is wagging.
And the African gray parrot is talking up a big storm there.
It's called a zoo.
All of that adds to the joy of life.
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
A joie de vivre.
I like that word, joie de vivre.
Joie de vivre.
Joie, joie de vivre.
Yeah.
So what you would say is, I mean, it's kind of common knowledge that a spiritual aspirant a lot of times is not as successful in the world as other people because that just seems to be secondary to them.
Yeah, that's pretty true.
A secondary goal.
It's okay to have money, but it's considered a detriment.
Right.
Yeah, many times.
Mm-hmm.
Enough to have, you know, your needs fulfilled.
You know, that's all you really need.
And the rest is irrelevant.
Mm-hmm.
I've got a new pair of shoes on.
I'm proud of them.
Whenever I see my...
Do you see new shoes?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, those are new shoes.
I'm very proud of these new shoes.
Well, I haven't had a new pair of shoes in, I don't know, years.
So, to me, a new pair of shoes is a big, exciting event.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
So now I have to break them in.
I've decided that.
The upside is you have a new pair of shoes.
The downside is you have to break it in.
Yeah.
Well, I think everybody should enjoy these brand new shoes, you know.
But it couldn't get simpler, really.
So, success is a name that we put on an act that, whether it's a new business or a new
business, it's a new business.
It's a new business.
So, I mean, we're, it's, and actually, the more important success is the personal success
rather than the worldly.
Yes.
I mean, to certain people that would be.
I mean, other people, worldly success is what they would.
It is worldly, yeah.
They don't divide the two.
Right.
So, to some people, they want the same thing.
To achieve worldly success.
So, for instance, what I'm trying to do right now is answer your question.
Okay.
questions to the best of my capability.
What the world thinks of it is rather irrelevant.
Well, wasn't it Carnegie, who's a big steel manufacturer, and he was very successful
and had all this money, and he gave all of it away at the end of his life?
Everything that he had accomplished his whole life, he gave away.
Well, I think that's a good idea.
What else are you going to do with it?
You can't take it with you.
So, what he did is he created these museums and...
Oh, yes.
I see what you're saying, yes.
So that other people could enjoy...
Oh, yes.
I think that's right.
Yeah.
Yes.
I think it was Carnegie.
What you're trying to do is share your success with the world.
The fact that we have people who are interested in listening to us speak with each other,
the fact that that is so makes our life successful, isn't it?
Mm-hmm.
Isn't that right?
But I mean, I know wealthy people, and that would be the last thing they would do, is
to give everything, their whole life, you know, they wouldn't want to give it all away.
Well, you can't take it with you.
What would you do with it?
I know, but I mean, there's lots of people that pass it along or whatever, you know,
to the next generation.
Oh, oh, I see what you mean.
Yeah.
Control of their wealth.
Right.
Control of it.
Mm-hmm.
Control of it, yeah.
Oh, yeah.
All right, that's just, you know, people don't have to be ashamed of normal human emotions.
Normal human emotions is to crave success, recognition, worldly goods, comfort.
Those are just normal for the human.
I don't think a person should feel guilty about it.
I mean, I hope people enjoy our discussion right now, you know.
Is that selfish, or is it just the goodwill, or it's just the fact that I care about people
and their happiness?
I want them to enjoy the moment, and that what we're speaking about with each other
stimulates a similar positive response within them, so I'm not just talking to you so that
we can play this back and enjoy ourselves talking to each other, because I've already
heard what we had to say, you know, but what you want to do is share your enjoyment.
It's the same as if you play piano or something.
Yeah.
Well, there was a great pianist, pretty well-known pianist, and in fact, we had two, we owned
two pianos in the house.
Everybody in the house played piano, and everybody played it to the best of their ability, so
we enjoyed each other's capacity and capabilities as a pianist, and then I took up the violin
instead.
Plus, I was also a singer.
Yeah.
I was also a well-known boy soprano, and so I had this incredible singing voice, plus
I could play the violin, plus I could play the piano, so, and then I enjoyed music, and
I still do listen to a great orchestra, so the enjoyment of music and all of its expressions
adds to the joy of life.
Mm-hmm.
So, on the way home, if we had to go home, we'd go home.
If we had a little music in the electric cart that we're going to go home in, I'd probably
play the music to add to the celebration of this morning.
Wouldn't I?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
So—
I just got the name of that song.
Merrily, we rolled along.
Yeah.
I like it.
so it's it's a choice that we have to make whether we want a spirit whether we
consider spiritual success more important to us or we consider financial
success yeah yeah whether we're going to divide them up that way and classify
them is that way right because you can be financially successful and also
spiritually right they don't preclude each other right and you can be rich as
all get out and not pious or you can be very pious and very poor it's better to
be rich and pious it's better to go home from church in a Cadillac than peddling
yourself in a rusty old bicycle a modicum of it so all these things come
down to balance right you know religiosity you can also become a
religious nut you know
pain in the neck so all these things is a matter of balance how much time you
and I spend with each other talking and laughing with each other how much time
we spend with our doggy and playing with her dog so it seems to me that
everything we do is a matter of balance there's a bad matter of balance of
affection of playfulness of rest of sleep of work of wash their
in the car when it needs being washed so life is a is a constant uh fluctuating diversity
over which we have no control whether it rains today or it doesn't so if if one could
balance their life between their spiritual goals and their successful goals then you could have
both you can certainly have both and certainly being spiritual is part of my idea is successful
and uh other people might consider it only you know financial successes at this so it would be
the self-fulfillment of our own comprehension and understanding which is our level of maturity
and of course how old you are uh-huh and you mean at 92 you're going to be more interested
in whether heaven's a reality or not than at 18 right
you
i guess yeah you're right so as well i think it's the hindus that that um they they you know
give up everything at the end of their life and and devote everything to god or i don't know it's
just restricted anybody i i thought everybody did that sort of well yes i mean material things get
rid of things well i don't know if it's material but they what they do do is they do do a lot of
it's they devote the last part of their life to god oh okay yeah so if we all would take those
lessons and devote um you know the first part of your life it's you know you're young and then you
have babies and then you have you know then you go into the to the later part of your life and as
you reach the later part of your life you realize that you're you're spiritual um because it becomes
more important oh yeah
so it would be nice if we could balance that throughout our life rather than just
expecting that to happen at the end yes well i think people are brought up properly uh that
that does happen okay you know as a kid you go to sunday school and uh while your folks are in
church you're at sunday school and then as you get older then finally you get married when you
do that you do that with the priest and the church
and uh it doesn't mean that it's wrong to be non-spiritual or not materialistic i mean to be
materialistic it's not wrong uh that people are not spiritually interested i feel that's just not
an area of their life that karmically is important at this moment it might be in fact quite the
opposite you know quit up put all that praying and get the car washed
okay
let's have let's praying a little more work around here
if you prayed all day instead of cook that have complaints before you know what all right
don't we ever eat around this joint everybody not yet i come on you think
we're just busy praying
i'll have to try that
i'm gonna try that see how that works
when you tell me today we're gonna pray a little more work around here
having meatloaf. Isn't that right? Okay, so yeah that'd be something I'd sit down at
dinner and she says, I didn't get the dinner done. And I'd say, why do you? Because I was
praying we didn't get the meatloaf cooked. Then I'd feel guilty, see, that I'm mad
that you, you know, that I want my meatloaf instead of having you pray. So
that would make me feel materialistic and greedy, that I'm concerned about my
eating instead of her praying. I should be concerned about whether she prays
not whether I eat meatloaf or not. You know, it's funny how human feeling can be so
intricate and circuitous in many ways, seemingly ambivalent, ambiguous, rather.
So would you say that success is
a
just a term that we put on a act or a, how do I want to say, I'm trying to think how to say this,
success is a word that we put to an action. Or an achievement. Or achievement. Or a state of being.
Or a state of being. Worldly or spiritual or intellectual, it could apply to any.
Intellectually you get straight A in school, you did well. Mm-hmm.
Go to church with sincerity in your heart. That would be a fulfillment.
But you brought up the fact that balance is very important between all of them.
Yes, I think extremes otherwise make your prayer sort of quirky.
It's okay to pray all day but somebody's got to shovel the sidewalk, you know what I'm saying?
Yeah.
Uh.
So.
Yeah.
I think that's a good question.
That's a good question.
Well, I don't know.
I think that's a good question.
Yeah.
Well, that's a good question.
as as a teacher would you call yourself successful? Oh successful well I'm happy
I'm successful and then I'm happy that I have a chance to speak spontaneously in
a forthright and honest way that is not stilted and stylized which which often
turns people off on what they consider spiritual but many people are turned off
by anything they hear is spiritual because they expect all this holy roller
stylized not too realistic kind of expression of prayerfulness and
holiness and you know you might say excess being spontaneously joyful and
being spontaneously the reality of that which I am I consider that spiritual
give me a kiss
I didn't think of that it just was I wanted to like say thank you God that you
brought the thought to my mind which I meant to express and I'm very happy to
be able to do that I mean I'm only have this body for a while and I want to use
it to express my understanding of spirituality because it might be a value
to someone else
somebody served it's value to me but it might be helpful to somebody else so as
a more stilted view of it so my view of spirituality is probably less stilted
than some people who tend to be sanctimonious you know you might say
sanctimonious and think that being spiritual is an awkward and difficult
way of life sackcloth and ashes kind of deal mm-hmm not there's any wrong with that.
But as a spiritual teacher you know we've as us we've tried to convey every question
that maybe the spiritual person would ask so that's why we're doing these talks
I think yes we're trying and we're trying to record it and so that if questions arise
that
they will be answered
so we're trying to expand
the understanding
of what's meant by the term
spiritual
or success
a lot of people really dwell on success
I'm not successful unless
I've got a million dollars
in the bank
or I'm not successful unless I get that job
or I'm not successful unless I have that car
so they have their own definitions
and those are all goals
that people set for each other
but you brought up the fact that they need to
balance that
between their spiritual
life and
the monetary
success of life
they will be more successful if they balance it
than if they just
focus on success itself
because just
worldly success
as a 100% focus
tends to turn people off
to a certain extent
you watch them on television
you can tell
they're all about me, me, me, me, me
and that tends to turn you off after a while
and that's one
reason we like comedians
is because comedians tend to make light of their
of the human limitations
to make humorous
what would otherwise be painful
serves a spiritual purpose
I also thought humorous
tended for a long life
and the contribution of humor
to life
because they help us to laugh at ourself
at what otherwise
might be quite painful
and embarrassing
we can take ourselves
Jack Benny can take us
we can take ourselves lightly
I guess that dates me
Jack Benny is he
yeah
yes
is he still alive?
no
oh no
anyway Jack Benny
symbolizes the ultimate of the
the
he's not alive anymore?
no
no?
oh
I didn't know that
so success
Jack Benny's not alive anymore?
no?
so success is
is
is something that
we all work for
we do it with balance
and we achieve our goals
um
does God's will
have anything to do with that?
well I think God's will is like the weather
it influences everything
ok
um both directly and indirectly
I think God's will is that we as human beings fulfill our potentiality
and because the human spirit goes on from one physical lifetime on to another
it grows over a number of physical lifetimes you know
and we call it karma
it needs four or five physical lifetimes
to fulfill a spiritual goal
uh huh
like it?
I feel happy that we went to church
uh
this week
that's an occasion that I
I don't think
in previous years did we go for Ash Wednesday?
I don't remember
I think so
did we?
uh huh
oh ok
uh
well
it's both symbolic on a very deep level
and on another level it's not even necessary you might say
you know what I mean?
so I say to myself
now why in the world do we get up early and go to Ash Wednesday?
to go to church today you see what I'm saying?
uh huh
every year the answer is different
right
uh huh
because you're in a different mood a different decade of life
and the older you get the more you realize that you better be going to church every Sunday
uh huh
the closer you get to being a hundred the more you know it's important you go to church every Sunday
do you feel like we've covered everything you want to say on success?
oh well I could talk all day long about success
you know and as a psychiatrist I uh
that often became important
whether when it's successful in their marriage as a father as a parent
in their children in their physical expressions
financial self expectation is so important
uh yeah
and so in defining success
I hope as we speak today that I'm being as fluent
as possible in fulfilling your questions
so that would be to me success
then if on the way home from here I suddenly think I should have answered it better in a certain area
then I will consider myself successful if I stopped feeling guilty that I didn't answer it better
uh huh
I guess we're going to wrap it up now.
Oh, wrap it up, okay.
So is there anything else you want to say?
Oh, well, I feel myself to be successful that I have you in my life
and that the two of us are sitting here and the camera is focused on us
and therefore that more than just you and myself will be hearing this,
I consider that the fulfillment of success,
that your life is contributing to the life of others.
So to me, success is your life is contributing to the life of others
if nothing else but stirring up the question in their own mind
after they listen to this and they say,
well, what do I consider success?
Yeah, it brings up the question in their life.
So we all grow through the questions that we ask ourselves.
So to the degree that we're helping other people to grow,
I feel my life is a success.
And I thank you for making my life a success.
And I thank you for being in mine.
Thank you, husband.
That'll be a dollar.
Okay.