Um today we're going to be discussing
Um today we're going to be discussing the importance of family and how that
the importance of family and how that
the importance of family and how that affects a person on the path of to
affects a person on the path of to
affects a person on the path of to enlightenment.
enlightenment.
enlightenment. >> Oh yes.
>> Oh yes.
>> Oh yes. >> What um what the characteristics is of
>> What um what the characteristics is of
>> What um what the characteristics is of applying um our spiritual uh importance
applying um our spiritual uh importance
applying um our spiritual uh importance to families
to families
to families uh raising of children. So how
uh raising of children. So how
uh raising of children. So how >> because in many in many quarters it's
>> because in many in many quarters it's
>> because in many in many quarters it's thought that uh the path to
thought that uh the path to
thought that uh the path to enlightenment would negate having a
enlightenment would negate having a
enlightenment would negate having a family and children. You know you'd have
family and children. You know you'd have
family and children. You know you'd have to be single and not associated with
to be single and not associated with
to be single and not associated with anybody.
anybody.
anybody. >> So Karen traditionally they're looked at
>> So Karen traditionally they're looked at
>> So Karen traditionally they're looked at it would be as an impediment to
it would be as an impediment to
it would be as an impediment to enlightenment
enlightenment
enlightenment >> as though being loving and responsible
>> as though being loving and responsible
>> as though being loving and responsible towards wife and children was
towards wife and children was
towards wife and children was >> would hold you back from enlightenment.
>> would hold you back from enlightenment.
>> would hold you back from enlightenment. Well, there was a famous saint who I
Well, there was a famous saint who I
Well, there was a famous saint who I can't remember her name which thing it
can't remember her name which thing it
can't remember her name which thing it was that um actually
was that um actually
was that um actually uh when her calling was she had a
uh when her calling was she had a
uh when her calling was she had a 11year-old boy or 12-year-old boy and he
11year-old boy or 12-year-old boy and he
11year-old boy or 12-year-old boy and he laid down in front of her before she
laid down in front of her before she
laid down in front of her before she went into the convent and she literally
went into the convent and she literally
went into the convent and she literally stepped over him.
stepped over him.
stepped over him. >> Uhhuh.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Uhhuh. >> So this is a you know I guess when the
>> So this is a you know I guess when the
>> So this is a you know I guess when the >> Oh, she's going to go to a higher
>> Oh, she's going to go to a higher
>> Oh, she's going to go to a higher purpose than raising children, right?
purpose than raising children, right?
purpose than raising children, right? >> Oh god.
>> Oh god.
>> Oh god. >> I guess so. She left her child. She left
>> I guess so. She left her child. She left
>> I guess so. She left her child. She left her child and because of the of the you
her child and because of the of the you
her child and because of the of the you know calling.
know calling.
know calling. >> Yeah. Right.
>> Yeah. Right.
>> Yeah. Right. She escaped the child because of the
She escaped the child because of the
She escaped the child because of the calling and suddenly the calling became
calling and suddenly the calling became
calling and suddenly the calling became very attractive to her.
very attractive to her.
very attractive to her. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Other people would think it's she's a
>> Other people would think it's she's a
>> Other people would think it's she's a nut job.
Getting away from the responsibility of
Getting away from the responsibility of being a parent by joining a combat.
being a parent by joining a combat.
being a parent by joining a combat. I mean that's a book sneak out.
be like saying this morning I'll hire
be like saying this morning I'll hire somebody to come in and be interviewed
somebody to come in and be interviewed
somebody to come in and be interviewed in my place so I don't have to be
in my place so I don't have to be
in my place so I don't have to be bothered, you know.
Well, to me it's a copout respon of your
Well, to me it's a copout respon of your one's responsibility.
If you love God and you love your fellow
If you love God and you love your fellow man, then you do so with or without
man, then you do so with or without
man, then you do so with or without children or family, whether you're
children or family, whether you're
children or family, whether you're single or not single,
single or not single,
single or not single, uh
uh
uh it doesn't really play that big a part.
it doesn't really play that big a part.
it doesn't really play that big a part. You can be happy when you're alone going
You can be happy when you're alone going
You can be happy when you're alone going down the road on a bicycle or you can be
down the road on a bicycle or you can be
down the road on a bicycle or you can be happy with a whole bunch of your friends
happy with a whole bunch of your friends
happy with a whole bunch of your friends on bicycles,
on bicycles,
on bicycles, you know, one night better. It's just
you know, one night better. It's just
you know, one night better. It's just different. So would you say then that
different. So would you say then that
different. So would you say then that once one has a family that there there
once one has a family that there there
once one has a family that there there is responsibility there uh and that you
is responsibility there uh and that you
is responsibility there uh and that you can always you still can become
can always you still can become
can always you still can become enlightened but there is responsibility
enlightened but there is responsibility
enlightened but there is responsibility of raising one's children
of raising one's children
of raising one's children >> well responsibility
>> well responsibility
>> well responsibility uh it sounds like a heavy duty drag you
uh it sounds like a heavy duty drag you
uh it sounds like a heavy duty drag you know why don't you just say you know you
know why don't you just say you know you
know why don't you just say you know you you can become enlightened even though
you can become enlightened even though
you can become enlightened even though you have a family and you're raising
you have a family and you're raising
you have a family and you're raising children
children
children that doesn't typify it as a retardant to
that doesn't typify it as a retardant to
that doesn't typify it as a retardant to the process.
the process.
the process. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> It would be a prejudgment to say
>> It would be a prejudgment to say
>> It would be a prejudgment to say burdened by a family.
burdened by a family.
burdened by a family. >> I mean that's already a judgmental.
>> I mean that's already a judgmental.
>> I mean that's already a judgmental. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Yeah. I would just say can you become
>> Yeah. I would just say can you become
>> Yeah. I would just say can you become enlightened even though you have a
enlightened even though you have a
enlightened even though you have a family? Sure. Can you become enlightened
family? Sure. Can you become enlightened
family? Sure. Can you become enlightened even though you have the
even though you have the
even though you have the responsibilities of a family? Of course.
responsibilities of a family? Of course.
responsibilities of a family? Of course. to love your fellow man and love God.
to love your fellow man and love God.
to love your fellow man and love God. Uh a family is not a deterrent.
Uh a family is not a deterrent.
Uh a family is not a deterrent. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> In fact, it would be actually in a way
>> In fact, it would be actually in a way
>> In fact, it would be actually in a way sort of helpful.
sort of helpful.
sort of helpful. >> Okay?
>> Okay?
>> Okay? >> Because lovingness and being loving is
>> Because lovingness and being loving is
>> Because lovingness and being loving is is is your way of life by that time. You
is is your way of life by that time. You
is is your way of life by that time. You love your children, you love your
love your children, you love your
love your children, you love your parents, you love your doggy,
parents, you love your doggy,
parents, you love your doggy, >> you love your kitties,
>> you love your kitties,
>> you love your kitties, >> right? When um does a how does a person
>> right? When um does a how does a person
>> right? When um does a how does a person on the path of enlightenment approach
on the path of enlightenment approach
on the path of enlightenment approach the raising of children?
No different than anything else. To be
No different than anything else. To be kind and loving at all times to be as
kind and loving at all times to be as
kind and loving at all times to be as understanding and put yourself in their
understanding and put yourself in their
understanding and put yourself in their place and try to see things uh from the
place and try to see things uh from the
place and try to see things uh from the other person's experience.
other person's experience.
other person's experience. >> Okay. is that you can anticipate it in
>> Okay. is that you can anticipate it in
>> Okay. is that you can anticipate it in advance.
advance.
advance. You know, if you go into a certain area
You know, if you go into a certain area
You know, if you go into a certain area that they'll feel lost or confused. So,
that they'll feel lost or confused. So,
that they'll feel lost or confused. So, you anticipate that in advance. Don't
you anticipate that in advance. Don't
you anticipate that in advance. Don't you don't be afraid now because we're
you don't be afraid now because we're
you don't be afraid now because we're going to the zoo. When I go around the
going to the zoo. When I go around the
going to the zoo. When I go around the corner, you won't see me for a second.
corner, you won't see me for a second.
corner, you won't see me for a second. That doesn't mean I've gone someplace.
That doesn't mean I've gone someplace.
That doesn't mean I've gone someplace. You're fine. Okay? And the lion won't
You're fine. Okay? And the lion won't
You're fine. Okay? And the lion won't get out of his cage and eat you.
So, um, you would apply the basic
So, um, you would apply the basic principles of,
principles of,
principles of, uh, love and understanding to the
uh, love and understanding to the
uh, love and understanding to the raising of children. It's a little hard
raising of children. It's a little hard
raising of children. It's a little hard to do that when misbehaving, you know,
to do that when misbehaving, you know,
to do that when misbehaving, you know, and everyone's questions, well, how do
and everyone's questions, well, how do
and everyone's questions, well, how do you discipline a child? Um, do you do
you discipline a child? Um, do you do
you discipline a child? Um, do you do you think that um being a parent by
you think that um being a parent by
you think that um being a parent by example
example
example is very good? I mean,
is very good? I mean,
is very good? I mean, >> I I think all of those things together,
>> I I think all of those things together,
>> I I think all of those things together, to be as loving and understanding as
to be as loving and understanding as
to be as loving and understanding as possible,
possible,
possible, to be the best example possible,
to be the best example possible,
to be the best example possible, and to give them positive feedback for
and to give them positive feedback for
and to give them positive feedback for the behaviors that you think are
the behaviors that you think are
the behaviors that you think are constructive,
constructive,
constructive, >> you know, like I I think it's wonderful
>> you know, like I I think it's wonderful
>> you know, like I I think it's wonderful the way you look after your little
the way you look after your little
the way you look after your little sister, you know, when I was a boy. I
sister, you know, when I was a boy. I
sister, you know, when I was a boy. I had a younger sister
had a younger sister
had a younger sister who was an aggravation and she would
who was an aggravation and she would
who was an aggravation and she would misbehave and that would embarrass me.
misbehave and that would embarrass me.
misbehave and that would embarrass me. We'd be in a bus or something. Instead
We'd be in a bus or something. Instead
We'd be in a bus or something. Instead of sitting quietly in her seat, she
of sitting quietly in her seat, she
of sitting quietly in her seat, she would get up and start to walk down the
would get up and start to walk down the
would get up and start to walk down the aisle
and I would have to run down the aisle,
and I would have to run down the aisle, >> stop her
>> stop her
>> stop her >> and get her back to her seat and it
>> and get her back to her seat and it
>> and get her back to her seat and it would embarrass me. I was embarrassed
would embarrass me. I was embarrassed
would embarrass me. I was embarrassed that she was misbehaving. It seems funny
that she was misbehaving. It seems funny
that she was misbehaving. It seems funny now, but at the time it seemed like a
now, but at the time it seemed like a
now, but at the time it seemed like a serious thing.
serious thing.
serious thing. Sitting your seat now and saying don't
Sitting your seat now and saying don't
Sitting your seat now and saying don't get up, you know.
Um, so we so a fam a a parent would be
Um, so we so a fam a a parent would be good to um stress the good things that a
good to um stress the good things that a
good to um stress the good things that a child does and as far as it goes as the
child does and as far as it goes as the
child does and as far as it goes as the bad things that a child does. Uh would
bad things that a child does. Uh would
bad things that a child does. Uh would you say um I mean all children are
you say um I mean all children are
you say um I mean all children are different. Some you can talk to your
different. Some you can talk to your
different. Some you can talk to your balloon in the face and they will don't
balloon in the face and they will don't
balloon in the face and they will don't listen but um it just depends on the
listen but um it just depends on the
listen but um it just depends on the child and the situation. So you would
child and the situation. So you would
child and the situation. So you would say that um I think time out is a good
say that um I think time out is a good
say that um I think time out is a good way to discipline a child when they're
way to discipline a child when they're
way to discipline a child when they're misbehaving.
misbehaving.
misbehaving. >> Well, that's a good Yes. Make them go
>> Well, that's a good Yes. Make them go
>> Well, that's a good Yes. Make them go sit in the corner.
sit in the corner.
sit in the corner. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> I think when I was young you had Yeah.
>> I think when I was young you had Yeah.
>> I think when I was young you had Yeah. If you were bad, you had to go and sit
If you were bad, you had to go and sit
If you were bad, you had to go and sit in the corner and look at the corner,
>> which is super boring. And of course,
>> which is super boring. And of course, the whole minute of not saying anything
the whole minute of not saying anything
the whole minute of not saying anything and looking at a bare wall seems like an
and looking at a bare wall seems like an
and looking at a bare wall seems like an hour. So,
hour. So,
hour. So, >> doesn't take long.
>> doesn't take long.
>> doesn't take long. >> No, within a few minutes, you say, "Now,
>> No, within a few minutes, you say, "Now,
>> No, within a few minutes, you say, "Now, if you keep y doing that, you're going
if you keep y doing that, you're going
if you keep y doing that, you're going to have to go and sit in the corner."
to have to go and sit in the corner."
to have to go and sit in the corner." >> That that would always stop me doing
>> That that would always stop me doing
>> That that would always stop me doing whatever I was doing. So how would you
whatever I was doing. So how would you
whatever I was doing. So how would you say is the best um way to teach children
say is the best um way to teach children
say is the best um way to teach children about spirituality?
about spirituality?
about spirituality? >> Well, I think teaching the value of
>> Well, I think teaching the value of
>> Well, I think teaching the value of love. I think um
love. I think um
love. I think um uh the reverence at which we hold
uh the reverence at which we hold
uh the reverence at which we hold spiritual figures Jesus Christ and
spiritual figures Jesus Christ and
spiritual figures Jesus Christ and saints
saints
saints and how all of society holds God.
and how all of society holds God.
and how all of society holds God. Um, so I believe in teaching children
Um, so I believe in teaching children
Um, so I believe in teaching children from very early on about God and Jesus
from very early on about God and Jesus
from very early on about God and Jesus Christ and saints
Christ and saints
Christ and saints and good persons and the value of going
and good persons and the value of going
and good persons and the value of going to church
to church
to church >> and how we love the clergy, we love the
>> and how we love the clergy, we love the
>> and how we love the clergy, we love the priests and we love the nuns and we love
priests and we love the nuns and we love
priests and we love the nuns and we love the
the
the all those who help the church.
all those who help the church.
all those who help the church. uh the reverence of which society holds
uh the reverence of which society holds
uh the reverence of which society holds uh the spiritual domain.
uh the spiritual domain.
uh the spiritual domain. >> Uh
>> Uh
>> Uh the reverence of which the integrous
the reverence of which the integrous
the reverence of which the integrous members of society hold it hold it.
members of society hold it hold it.
members of society hold it hold it. Other people it's their enemy.
Other people it's their enemy.
Other people it's their enemy. >> Holiness and spirituality and that which
>> Holiness and spirituality and that which
>> Holiness and spirituality and that which is divinity
is the en enemy of people that are uh
is the en enemy of people that are uh anti- good. There are a lot of people
anti- good. There are a lot of people
anti- good. There are a lot of people hate God and hate divinity and hate
hate God and hate divinity and hate
hate God and hate divinity and hate spirituality and they exist in every
spirituality and they exist in every
spirituality and they exist in every religion. They hate Muslims. They hate
religion. They hate Muslims. They hate
religion. They hate Muslims. They hate Christians.
So there's a good deal of hatred gets
So there's a good deal of hatred gets mixed into the religious uh
mixed into the religious uh
mixed into the religious uh sectarianism. Mhm.
sectarianism. Mhm.
sectarianism. Mhm. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> So,
>> So,
>> So, >> which is to me paradoxical,
>> which is to me paradoxical,
>> which is to me paradoxical, >> you know, hate people who picture God in
>> you know, hate people who picture God in
>> you know, hate people who picture God in a different style than you than what you
a different style than you than what you
a different style than you than what you do.
do.
do. >> So, you hate them.
>> It's tragic comic. Tragy comical.
>> It's tragic comic. Tragy comical. >> Um,
>> Um,
>> Um, >> what is the spiritual significance of a
>> what is the spiritual significance of a
>> what is the spiritual significance of a couple choosing not to have children?
couple choosing not to have children?
couple choosing not to have children? not is not necessarily they might do it
not is not necessarily they might do it
not is not necessarily they might do it for spiritual reasons if they
for spiritual reasons if they
for spiritual reasons if they thought that this having the children
thought that this having the children
thought that this having the children was going to interfere with their
was going to interfere with their
was going to interfere with their spiritual design of their life.
spiritual design of their life.
spiritual design of their life. >> Um
>> Um
>> Um but that would be a selection that
but that would be a selection that
but that would be a selection that everybody makes whether to get married
everybody makes whether to get married
everybody makes whether to get married or not in the first place and then
or not in the first place and then
or not in the first place and then whether to have children or not
whether to have children or not
whether to have children or not and the part that spirituality plays in
and the part that spirituality plays in
and the part that spirituality plays in that. Nuns and priests don't have
that. Nuns and priests don't have
that. Nuns and priests don't have children, you know. Well, priests do in
children, you know. Well, priests do in
children, you know. Well, priests do in the Episcopal church. Yeah. Well,
the Episcopal church. Yeah. Well,
the Episcopal church. Yeah. Well, Catholic priests don't.
Catholic priests don't.
Catholic priests don't. Uh so in some churches, uh you can't
Uh so in some churches, uh you can't
Uh so in some churches, uh you can't have a family. In other churches, like
have a family. In other churches, like
have a family. In other churches, like the Episcopal, you can have a family.
the Episcopal, you can have a family.
the Episcopal, you can have a family. So, it's how it's pictured.
So, it's how it's pictured.
So, it's how it's pictured. It can be pictured as a positive
It can be pictured as a positive
It can be pictured as a positive contributor to one's spiritual
contributor to one's spiritual
contributor to one's spiritual dimension
dimension
dimension >> or it could be pictured as retarding it.
>> or it could be pictured as retarding it.
>> or it could be pictured as retarding it. I think it's how you hold it in your
I think it's how you hold it in your
I think it's how you hold it in your mind. I don't think it intrinsically is
mind. I don't think it intrinsically is
mind. I don't think it intrinsically is one way or the other.
one way or the other.
one way or the other. The fact that you're married doesn't
The fact that you're married doesn't
The fact that you're married doesn't your loving God or loving your
your loving God or loving your
your loving God or loving your fellow man. Mhm.
fellow man. Mhm.
fellow man. Mhm. >> Uh so there's nothing intrinsically
>> Uh so there's nothing intrinsically
>> Uh so there's nothing intrinsically anti-spiritual about either celibacy or
anti-spiritual about either celibacy or
anti-spiritual about either celibacy or matrimony.
matrimony.
matrimony. Yeah.
>> Um
>> Um does the does the soul choose to re
does the does the soul choose to re
does the does the soul choose to re incarnate?
incarnate?
incarnate? Well, the the soul is karmically
Well, the the soul is karmically
Well, the the soul is karmically determined
determined
determined um and subject to the vicissitudes of
um and subject to the vicissitudes of
um and subject to the vicissitudes of the karmic consequences of the choices
the karmic consequences of the choices
the karmic consequences of the choices made during this lifetime.
made during this lifetime.
made during this lifetime. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> Uh so when to say whether the soul
>> Uh so when to say whether the soul
>> Uh so when to say whether the soul chooses, did you say?
chooses, did you say?
chooses, did you say? >> Yeah, it says this is a question someone
>> Yeah, it says this is a question someone
>> Yeah, it says this is a question someone wrote in. Does the soul choose to
wrote in. Does the soul choose to
wrote in. Does the soul choose to incarnate?
incarnate?
incarnate? >> Oh, I see.
>> Oh, I see.
>> Oh, I see. I don't technically know the answer to
I don't technically know the answer to
I don't technically know the answer to that. Okay. Is it the soul that makes
that. Okay. Is it the soul that makes
that. Okay. Is it the soul that makes the decision to incarnate?
the decision to incarnate?
the decision to incarnate? >> Uh it depends on what you mean by soul.
>> Uh it depends on what you mean by soul.
>> Uh it depends on what you mean by soul. Consciousness itself if you include all
Consciousness itself if you include all
Consciousness itself if you include all of consciousness then all consciousness
of consciousness then all consciousness
of consciousness then all consciousness isn't involved in a major decision.
isn't involved in a major decision.
isn't involved in a major decision. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> You know be like whether to move to
>> You know be like whether to move to
>> You know be like whether to move to Europe or not. Yeah. That includes all
Europe or not. Yeah. That includes all
Europe or not. Yeah. That includes all kinds of aspects of your life. Mhm.
kinds of aspects of your life. Mhm.
kinds of aspects of your life. Mhm. >> Leaving the familiar for the unfamiliar
>> Leaving the familiar for the unfamiliar
>> Leaving the familiar for the unfamiliar and uh
and uh
and uh >> starting over a new one, new
>> starting over a new one, new
>> starting over a new one, new surroundings and new rules and new
surroundings and new rules and new
surroundings and new rules and new regulations
regulations
regulations be like getting divorced and then
be like getting divorced and then
be like getting divorced and then remarried and then moving to a foreign
remarried and then moving to a foreign
remarried and then moving to a foreign country.
country.
country. >> Okay. Well, do when you when you do
>> Okay. Well, do when you when you do
>> Okay. Well, do when you when you do choose to incarnate, does that mean that
choose to incarnate, does that mean that
choose to incarnate, does that mean that you choose your family and the religion
you choose your family and the religion
you choose your family and the religion and the circumstances to be born into?
and the circumstances to be born into?
and the circumstances to be born into? Or is it that we're learning lessons by
Or is it that we're learning lessons by
Or is it that we're learning lessons by choosing those type of situations?
choosing those type of situations?
choosing those type of situations? >> My my feeling about it there's we'd have
>> My my feeling about it there's we'd have
>> My my feeling about it there's we'd have to use the arm on this. We have it is up
to use the arm on this. We have it is up
to use the arm on this. We have it is up to us. There we go. It is up to us to uh
to us. There we go. It is up to us to uh
to us. There we go. It is up to us to uh make determinations about what is
make determinations about what is
make determinations about what is acceptable, desirable, what is our
acceptable, desirable, what is our
acceptable, desirable, what is our goals.
goals.
goals. Uh I suppose it's like any direction you
Uh I suppose it's like any direction you
Uh I suppose it's like any direction you go in life, you know what your
go in life, you know what your
go in life, you know what your destination is.
destination is.
destination is. and everything else would have to become
and everything else would have to become
and everything else would have to become subservient to that. Uh so you couldn't
subservient to that. Uh so you couldn't
subservient to that. Uh so you couldn't decide to
decide to
decide to um you move east when you're going west.
um you move east when you're going west.
um you move east when you're going west. Is that what you're saying? So what is
Is that what you're saying? So what is
Is that what you're saying? So what is the question again? I'll say it one more
the question again? I'll say it one more
the question again? I'll say it one more time. So I
time. So I
time. So I >> um when we choose to when the when we
>> um when we choose to when the when we
>> um when we choose to when the when we choose
choose
choose >> when the soul choose to reincarnate,
>> when the soul choose to reincarnate,
>> when the soul choose to reincarnate, >> right?
>> right?
>> right? >> Does it have a choice? Does it have a
>> Does it have a choice? Does it have a
>> Does it have a choice? Does it have a choice of family, religion,
choice of family, religion,
choice of family, religion, circumstances or or is that that we are
circumstances or or is that that we are
circumstances or or is that that we are that
that
that >> it has a choice of generalities
>> it has a choice of generalities
>> it has a choice of generalities >> and uh there may be karmic obl karmic
>> and uh there may be karmic obl karmic
>> and uh there may be karmic obl karmic obligations to a specific family. Yeah.
obligations to a specific family. Yeah.
obligations to a specific family. Yeah. The specifics may be karmically
The specifics may be karmically
The specifics may be karmically determined but the generalities are that
determined but the generalities are that
determined but the generalities are that of a total the total consciousness
of a total the total consciousness
of a total the total consciousness itself.
itself.
itself. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Uhhuh. Um so is so why is it that some
>> Uhhuh. Um so is so why is it that some
>> Uhhuh. Um so is so why is it that some people choose a family uh or religion
people choose a family uh or religion
people choose a family uh or religion and then leave that religion? Is it is
and then leave that religion? Is it is
and then leave that religion? Is it is it sort of uh could it be that
it sort of uh could it be that
it sort of uh could it be that karmically in a in a past lifetime that
karmically in a in a past lifetime that
karmically in a in a past lifetime that they had um chosen that religion and now
they had um chosen that religion and now
they had um chosen that religion and now they're undoing that karma or what?
they're undoing that karma or what?
they're undoing that karma or what? >> Yeah, it certainly could be that it
>> Yeah, it certainly could be that it
>> Yeah, it certainly could be that it could be changes that take place during
could be changes that take place during
could be changes that take place during one's adult lifetime.
one's adult lifetime.
one's adult lifetime. So you know some people join a monastery
So you know some people join a monastery
So you know some people join a monastery >> when they're young and idealistic
>> when they're young and idealistic
>> when they're young and idealistic and then they explore what's the uh
and then they explore what's the uh
and then they explore what's the uh spiritual uh value of it and they may
spiritual uh value of it and they may
spiritual uh value of it and they may feel that they've achieved the spiritual
feel that they've achieved the spiritual
feel that they've achieved the spiritual value of uh of it by a certain number of
value of uh of it by a certain number of
value of uh of it by a certain number of years and then realize I've already
years and then realize I've already
years and then realize I've already achieved that spiritual value and there
achieved that spiritual value and there
achieved that spiritual value and there are other things equally important.
are other things equally important.
are other things equally important. >> Mhm. You know, you learn how to be all
>> Mhm. You know, you learn how to be all
>> Mhm. You know, you learn how to be all alone and self-sufficient and all to
alone and self-sufficient and all to
alone and self-sufficient and all to yourself and uh but you also need to
yourself and uh but you also need to
yourself and uh but you also need to learn how to love and be with others in
learn how to love and be with others in
learn how to love and be with others in a family situation as well as an
a family situation as well as an
a family situation as well as an individual. So we in our own natural
individual. So we in our own natural
individual. So we in our own natural lifetime we go through being a single
lifetime we go through being a single
lifetime we go through being a single individual you know as a teenager
individual you know as a teenager
individual you know as a teenager then we get married we have a family
then we get married we have a family
then we get married we have a family then we learn how to become a a parent.
then we learn how to become a a parent.
then we learn how to become a a parent. In the meantime, we learn how to
In the meantime, we learn how to
In the meantime, we learn how to continue to be um the children of our
continue to be um the children of our
continue to be um the children of our own parents who are now grandparents.
own parents who are now grandparents.
own parents who are now grandparents. Then we graduate to being grandparents,
Then we graduate to being grandparents,
Then we graduate to being grandparents, learning how to love generations down.
learning how to love generations down.
learning how to love generations down. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> So you end up loving people older than
>> So you end up loving people older than
>> So you end up loving people older than you are, younger than you are, and then
you are, younger than you are, and then
you are, younger than you are, and then the younger younger ones.
the younger younger ones.
the younger younger ones. >> You're loving maybe four different
>> You're loving maybe four different
>> You're loving maybe four different generations at the same time.
generations at the same time.
generations at the same time. >> Which makes life, I think, fulfilling
>> Which makes life, I think, fulfilling
>> Which makes life, I think, fulfilling and interesting. Well, you know, a lot
and interesting. Well, you know, a lot
and interesting. Well, you know, a lot of us are born into families where um
of us are born into families where um
of us are born into families where um that we we have fa or we have children
that we we have fa or we have children
that we we have fa or we have children that, you know, they're not doing what
that, you know, they're not doing what
that, you know, they're not doing what karmically they should. In other words,
karmically they should. In other words,
karmically they should. In other words, they're
they're
they're >> you know, some people have
>> you know, some people have
>> you know, some people have >> children that some people have children
>> children that some people have children
>> children that some people have children that are,
that are,
that are, >> you know, in prison or, you know, have
>> you know, in prison or, you know, have
>> you know, in prison or, you know, have done crimes.
done crimes.
done crimes. >> Yes. Um, and I think the parents have a
>> Yes. Um, and I think the parents have a
>> Yes. Um, and I think the parents have a tendency to blame themselves for that
tendency to blame themselves for that
tendency to blame themselves for that type of
type of
type of >> I think almost always. Yeah.
>> I think almost always. Yeah.
>> I think almost always. Yeah. >> And so it's hard to write that because
>> And so it's hard to write that because
>> And so it's hard to write that because there the guilt of having a child like
there the guilt of having a child like
there the guilt of having a child like that especially when you're not involved
that especially when you're not involved
that especially when you're not involved with those type of things is is very a
with those type of things is is very a
with those type of things is is very a difficult guilt to carry along. So, what
difficult guilt to carry along. So, what
difficult guilt to carry along. So, what would you I think so.
would you I think so.
would you I think so. >> What would you suggest to a parent that
>> What would you suggest to a parent that
>> What would you suggest to a parent that did have a child that was completely
did have a child that was completely
did have a child that was completely opposite than the belief system that it
opposite than the belief system that it
opposite than the belief system that it was brought up in such as maybe a
was brought up in such as maybe a
was brought up in such as maybe a criminal or someone that How would you
criminal or someone that How would you
criminal or someone that How would you how would you handle that as a parent?
how would you handle that as a parent?
how would you handle that as a parent? >> Well, I would it brings up the whole uh
>> Well, I would it brings up the whole uh
>> Well, I would it brings up the whole uh thing of karma. It has to do with the uh
thing of karma. It has to do with the uh
thing of karma. It has to do with the uh the age at which you are. You know, you
the age at which you are. You know, you
the age at which you are. You know, you may go at age 12 look at things one way
may go at age 12 look at things one way
may go at age 12 look at things one way and at age 13 look at things completely
and at age 13 look at things completely
and at age 13 look at things completely differently,
differently,
differently, >> right?
>> right?
>> right? >> In my own life and around age 12 or
>> In my own life and around age 12 or
>> In my own life and around age 12 or something, I went through a major change
something, I went through a major change
something, I went through a major change about religion and and God and and all
about religion and and God and and all
about religion and and God and and all such things and
such things and
such things and when and then later again shifted back
when and then later again shifted back
when and then later again shifted back again. So you may go through major
again. So you may go through major
again. So you may go through major shifts. So you re you if you associate
shifts. So you re you if you associate
shifts. So you re you if you associate religiosity with child being a child
religiosity with child being a child
religiosity with child being a child then as you grow older you don't want to
then as you grow older you don't want to
then as you grow older you don't want to be a child anymore you want to be grown
be a child anymore you want to be grown
be a child anymore you want to be grown up now so you reject you threw out
up now so you reject you threw out
up now so you reject you threw out religion with things that go with
religion with things that go with
religion with things that go with childhood you know what I mean and then
childhood you know what I mean and then
childhood you know what I mean and then then you later regret that and now you
then you later regret that and now you
then you later regret that and now you read
read
read >> uh
>> uh
>> uh an allegiance to religion but from a
an allegiance to religion but from a
an allegiance to religion but from a different viewpoint not being a good
different viewpoint not being a good
different viewpoint not being a good child but because you see his wisdom and
child but because you see his wisdom and
child but because you see his wisdom and value to society and attractiveness.
value to society and attractiveness.
value to society and attractiveness. >> Well, let's say that you had a you
>> Well, let's say that you had a you
>> Well, let's say that you had a you raised this child that is bad. Um you
raised this child that is bad. Um you
raised this child that is bad. Um you raised this child in a very strong
raised this child in a very strong
raised this child in a very strong religious
religious
religious um
um
um you know and they knew what was right
you know and they knew what was right
you know and they knew what was right and what's wrong but they still chose
and what's wrong but they still chose
and what's wrong but they still chose that path
that path
that path >> to go down.
>> to go down.
>> to go down. >> Yeah. You see that kind of perversity
>> Yeah. You see that kind of perversity
>> Yeah. You see that kind of perversity not all that inferiorly.
not all that inferiorly.
not all that inferiorly. >> Mhm. People who were raised in a very
>> Mhm. People who were raised in a very
>> Mhm. People who were raised in a very decent home with a good religious
decent home with a good religious
decent home with a good religious background and then they suddenly choose
background and then they suddenly choose
background and then they suddenly choose the life of criminality.
the life of criminality.
the life of criminality. >> Often drugs are involved in you know
>> Often drugs are involved in you know
>> Often drugs are involved in you know alcohol and narcotics.
alcohol and narcotics.
alcohol and narcotics. >> You've often said that drugs and alcohol
>> You've often said that drugs and alcohol
>> You've often said that drugs and alcohol lead to the lower astrals coming in.
lead to the lower astrals coming in.
lead to the lower astrals coming in. That's how lower astrals get in is
That's how lower astrals get in is
That's how lower astrals get in is >> drugs and alcohol. So, it's a pathway
>> drugs and alcohol. So, it's a pathway
>> drugs and alcohol. So, it's a pathway for them to come in because normal a lot
for them to come in because normal a lot
for them to come in because normal a lot of times people
of times people
of times people >> um wouldn't do
>> um wouldn't do
>> um wouldn't do >> what they do on drugs and alcohol
>> what they do on drugs and alcohol
>> what they do on drugs and alcohol >> without drugs and alcohol, right?
>> without drugs and alcohol, right?
>> without drugs and alcohol, right? >> And that it's a pathway. So,
>> And that it's a pathway. So,
>> And that it's a pathway. So, >> um then you're dealing with addiction
>> um then you're dealing with addiction
>> um then you're dealing with addiction and other problems that go along that
and other problems that go along that
and other problems that go along that line. Um, but how does a parent as a
line. Um, but how does a parent as a
line. Um, but how does a parent as a parent, how does a parent cope with the
parent, how does a parent cope with the
parent, how does a parent cope with the guilt of a child that is like that?
guilt of a child that is like that?
guilt of a child that is like that? >> Well, you do what you do with I think by
>> Well, you do what you do with I think by
>> Well, you do what you do with I think by seeing that it really is a problem of
seeing that it really is a problem of
seeing that it really is a problem of human nature
human nature
human nature >> and not personalize it so much.
>> and not personalize it so much.
>> and not personalize it so much. >> All right,
>> All right,
>> All right, >> you can be an excellent parent and have
>> you can be an excellent parent and have
>> you can be an excellent parent and have a child that turns out badly. Mhm.
a child that turns out badly. Mhm.
a child that turns out badly. Mhm. >> Well, other than you as a parent, there
>> Well, other than you as a parent, there
>> Well, other than you as a parent, there are many other influences on this child
are many other influences on this child
are many other influences on this child besides yourself.
besides yourself.
besides yourself. And the child has its own karmic
And the child has its own karmic
And the child has its own karmic inheritance.
inheritance.
inheritance. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> So, you take some responsibility, but
>> So, you take some responsibility, but
>> So, you take some responsibility, but not 100%.
not 100%.
not 100%. Uh because you have to give you
Uh because you have to give you
Uh because you have to give you surrendering to God that which is God's.
And so part of it is personal, part of
And so part of it is personal, part of it is impersonal and part of it is
it is impersonal and part of it is
it is impersonal and part of it is karmic and hereditary
karmic and hereditary
karmic and hereditary >> and and certainly societal societal
>> and and certainly societal societal
>> and and certainly societal societal influence.
influence.
influence. In our current life, the media have a
In our current life, the media have a
In our current life, the media have a very very powerful influence on people.
very very powerful influence on people.
very very powerful influence on people. >> The media,
>> The media,
>> The media, you know, tend to dominate human life
you know, tend to dominate human life
you know, tend to dominate human life right now.
right now.
right now. what's on television is more important
what's on television is more important
what's on television is more important than what your parents say or what what
than what your parents say or what what
than what your parents say or what what society thinks.
>> Okay. So in this in your viewpoint
>> Okay. So in this in your viewpoint um the child had a choice of ch of you
um the child had a choice of ch of you
um the child had a choice of ch of you knowing
knowing
knowing right from wrong and they were put in
right from wrong and they were put in
right from wrong and they were put in this position and they chose the wrong
this position and they chose the wrong
this position and they chose the wrong path. But I for me as a parent I would
path. But I for me as a parent I would
path. But I for me as a parent I would feel feel guilt because what could I
feel feel guilt because what could I
feel feel guilt because what could I have not done more you know you carry
have not done more you know you carry
have not done more you know you carry this guilt with you I should have done
this guilt with you I should have done
this guilt with you I should have done more for this child I should have
more for this child I should have
more for this child I should have >> well yeah that's natural it would be
>> well yeah that's natural it would be
>> well yeah that's natural it would be natural to wonder where did I fail
natural to wonder where did I fail
natural to wonder where did I fail >> right
>> right
>> right >> you know I can remember doing things
>> you know I can remember doing things
>> you know I can remember doing things when I was like 12 or 15
when I was like 12 or 15
when I was like 12 or 15 that were uh not in accord with what I
that were uh not in accord with what I
that were uh not in accord with what I was brought up you know
was brought up you know
was brought up you know >> and it was like the willfulness of the
>> and it was like the willfulness of the
>> and it was like the willfulness of the human ego Okay.
human ego Okay.
human ego Okay. >> I think it's just the human ego or even
>> I think it's just the human ego or even
>> I think it's just the human ego or even the animal ego in us. They want to see
the animal ego in us. They want to see
the animal ego in us. They want to see if we can get away with a certain thing.
if we can get away with a certain thing.
if we can get away with a certain thing. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> So really a parent shouldn't carry that
>> So really a parent shouldn't carry that
>> So really a parent shouldn't carry that guilt with them. We should be guiltree.
guilt with them. We should be guiltree.
guilt with them. We should be guiltree. >> It's limited because you could say each
>> It's limited because you could say each
>> It's limited because you could say each of us is only responsible and capable
of us is only responsible and capable
of us is only responsible and capable and reliable up to a certain point
and reliable up to a certain point
and reliable up to a certain point beyond which there are other factors
beyond which there are other factors
beyond which there are other factors unknown.
unknown.
unknown. Can you tell me what the spiritual
Can you tell me what the spiritual
Can you tell me what the spiritual significant would be of being a parent?
significant would be of being a parent?
significant would be of being a parent? There's a lot of people out there that
There's a lot of people out there that
There's a lot of people out there that do don't have children, but there's a
do don't have children, but there's a
do don't have children, but there's a lot What would be the most the most
lot What would be the most the most
lot What would be the most the most significant
significant
significant um
um
um spiritual aspect of being a ch of being
spiritual aspect of being a ch of being
spiritual aspect of being a ch of being a parent? Would it be uh guiding the
a parent? Would it be uh guiding the
a parent? Would it be uh guiding the child or what would you consider being
child or what would you consider being
child or what would you consider being the most significant spiritual
the most significant spiritual
the most significant spiritual significance of being a
significance of being a
significance of being a >> of being a a parent?
>> of being a a parent?
>> of being a a parent? >> Uh I think by example
>> Uh I think by example
>> Uh I think by example >> example
>> example
>> example >> I think example is the best teacher.
>> I think example is the best teacher.
>> I think example is the best teacher. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> That the parents themselves.
>> That the parents themselves.
>> That the parents themselves. So if you don't believe, if you think
So if you don't believe, if you think
So if you don't believe, if you think that eating meat on Fridays is wrong,
that eating meat on Fridays is wrong,
that eating meat on Fridays is wrong, especially during Lent and you live that
especially during Lent and you live that
especially during Lent and you live that way, then the children will grow up with
way, then the children will grow up with
way, then the children will grow up with that feeling to skip, you know, meat
that feeling to skip, you know, meat
that feeling to skip, you know, meat during Lent and and on Fridays
during Lent and and on Fridays
during Lent and and on Fridays and here I am some 70 years later or 80
and here I am some 70 years later or 80
and here I am some 70 years later or 80 years, I don't know what it is that
years, I don't know what it is that
years, I don't know what it is that to eat meat on Friday, Good Friday would
to eat meat on Friday, Good Friday would
to eat meat on Friday, Good Friday would create a sense of guilt in me even now.
create a sense of guilt in me even now.
create a sense of guilt in me even now. And I say, well, intellectually it
And I say, well, intellectually it
And I say, well, intellectually it doesn't make sense.
doesn't make sense.
doesn't make sense. >> But it's not an intellectual matter.
>> But it's not an intellectual matter.
>> But it's not an intellectual matter. It's a matter of reverence
It's a matter of reverence
It's a matter of reverence for certain values and lifestyles and
for certain values and lifestyles and
for certain values and lifestyles and goals.
I'm sure it's not a sin. I don't think
I'm sure it's not a sin. I don't think you go to hell if you meet on Friday.
you go to hell if you meet on Friday.
you go to hell if you meet on Friday. uh but it's uh
uh but it's uh
uh but it's uh a part of one's religious uh
a part of one's religious uh
a part of one's religious uh uh
uh
uh respect for the religion
respect for the religion
respect for the religion >> and uh love for it.
>> and uh love for it.
>> and uh love for it. So I don't eat meat on Fridays and I
So I don't eat meat on Fridays and I
So I don't eat meat on Fridays and I would not even think of eating meat on a
would not even think of eating meat on a
would not even think of eating meat on a good Friday.
good Friday.
good Friday. >> Now that's just my preference,
>> Now that's just my preference,
>> Now that's just my preference, >> right? I I don't think God would throw
>> right? I I don't think God would throw
>> right? I I don't think God would throw me into hell if I ate meat on Friday
me into hell if I ate meat on Friday
me into hell if I ate meat on Friday >> because I don't think it's that
>> because I don't think it's that
>> because I don't think it's that important.
important.
important. But it's a sign of reverence and respect
But it's a sign of reverence and respect
But it's a sign of reverence and respect for one's spiritual
for one's spiritual
for one's spiritual ancestry and culture for one's spiritual
ancestry and culture for one's spiritual
ancestry and culture for one's spiritual religious culture.
religious culture.
religious culture. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Respect for one's religious culture. So,
>> Respect for one's religious culture. So,
>> Respect for one's religious culture. So, for the same reason, we don't, you know,
for the same reason, we don't, you know,
for the same reason, we don't, you know, make loud noises and blow whistles in
make loud noises and blow whistles in
make loud noises and blow whistles in church. It's just out of respect.
church. It's just out of respect.
church. It's just out of respect. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> It's not that you'd be arrested.
>> It's not that you'd be arrested.
>> It's not that you'd be arrested. Not that it's illegal,
Not that it's illegal,
Not that it's illegal, but we wouldn't want to make a loud fuss
but we wouldn't want to make a loud fuss
but we wouldn't want to make a loud fuss in church in the middle of a sermon out
in church in the middle of a sermon out
in church in the middle of a sermon out of sheer respect for our fellow man.
of sheer respect for our fellow man.
of sheer respect for our fellow man. Mhm.
Mhm.
Mhm. >> Um at one point you said that when Bill
>> Um at one point you said that when Bill
>> Um at one point you said that when Bill Wilson was dying, he said um that God
Wilson was dying, he said um that God
Wilson was dying, he said um that God had many houses.
had many houses.
had many houses. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> All right. The question is when this is
>> All right. The question is when this is
>> All right. The question is when this is kind when we die,
kind when we die,
kind when we die, do we go to
do we go to
do we go to that which is like
that which is like
that which is like and or can we you know can we visit
and or can we you know can we visit
and or can we you know can we visit other houses also or do we go to like is
other houses also or do we go to like is
other houses also or do we go to like is like like
like like
like like >> my understanding is that one does have a
>> my understanding is that one does have a
>> my understanding is that one does have a certain liberty to because we have
certain liberty to because we have
certain liberty to because we have different aspects to our personality
different aspects to our personality
different aspects to our personality and to our life and to our friends and
and to our life and to our friends and
and to our life and to our friends and family.
family.
family. And uh he he reported that he had had a
And uh he he reported that he had had a
And uh he he reported that he had had a chance to visit the various aspects
chance to visit the various aspects
chance to visit the various aspects of uh
of uh
of uh >> this is Bill Wilson.
>> this is Bill Wilson.
>> this is Bill Wilson. >> Bill Wilson, the founder of AA was a
>> Bill Wilson, the founder of AA was a
>> Bill Wilson, the founder of AA was a friend of mine when I was younger. And
friend of mine when I was younger. And
friend of mine when I was younger. And Bill said that, you know, my father's
Bill said that, you know, my father's
Bill said that, you know, my father's house has many rooms.
house has many rooms.
house has many rooms. >> Oh, okay. And uh he had had a chance he
>> Oh, okay. And uh he had had a chance he
>> Oh, okay. And uh he had had a chance he would lapse into semiconsciousness
would lapse into semiconsciousness
would lapse into semiconsciousness and visit a realm
and visit a realm
and visit a realm >> and then his consciousness would come
>> and then his consciousness would come
>> and then his consciousness would come back again
back again
back again >> and then he would lapse a little bit in
>> and then he would lapse a little bit in
>> and then he would lapse a little bit in consciousness.
consciousness.
consciousness. And so he said my father's house has
And so he said my father's house has
And so he said my father's house has many rooms meaning there's many uh areas
many rooms meaning there's many uh areas
many rooms meaning there's many uh areas of heaven and levels of heaven in the
of heaven and levels of heaven in the
of heaven and levels of heaven in the afterlife. Mhm.
afterlife. Mhm.
afterlife. Mhm. >> Uh so there's a great uh versatility
>> Uh so there's a great uh versatility
>> Uh so there's a great uh versatility there. Mhm.
there. Mhm.
there. Mhm. >> Yes. As my father's house has many rooms
>> Yes. As my father's house has many rooms
>> Yes. As my father's house has many rooms and mansions.
and mansions.
and mansions. >> So let's say that you were raised in one
>> So let's say that you were raised in one
>> So let's say that you were raised in one religion and you decide to change
religion and you decide to change
religion and you decide to change religions and go to a different
religions and go to a different
religions and go to a different religion.
religion.
religion. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> You're still believing in God in both
>> You're still believing in God in both
>> You're still believing in God in both religions
religions
religions >> or a higher being. But now let's say
>> or a higher being. But now let's say
>> or a higher being. But now let's say that your family was all one religion
that your family was all one religion
that your family was all one religion and you had chosen a different religion.
and you had chosen a different religion.
and you had chosen a different religion. >> Yeah. Different style. So a different
>> Yeah. Different style. So a different
>> Yeah. Different style. So a different style of religious.
style of religious.
style of religious. >> Is there a way of when we go into the
>> Is there a way of when we go into the
>> Is there a way of when we go into the hereafter let's say is there a way of
hereafter let's say is there a way of
hereafter let's say is there a way of is our family still around us? You know
is our family still around us? You know
is our family still around us? You know because you know a lot of these people
because you know a lot of these people
because you know a lot of these people that tr that go pass over they say they
that tr that go pass over they say they
that tr that go pass over they say they saw all their family there that have
saw all their family there that have
saw all their family there that have passed before them you know when they go
passed before them you know when they go
passed before them you know when they go through the
through the
through the >> that's very common that's very common
>> that's very common that's very common
>> that's very common that's very common >> so um they are around us no matter what
>> so um they are around us no matter what
>> so um they are around us no matter what >> their soul their souls are around and um
>> their soul their souls are around and um
>> their soul their souls are around and um that's a very common commonly to report
that's a very common commonly to report
that's a very common commonly to report that your family comes to visit you
that your family comes to visit you
that your family comes to visit you their spirits It's know that you have
their spirits It's know that you have
their spirits It's know that you have arrived and they come to greet you.
arrived and they come to greet you.
arrived and they come to greet you. >> Right?
>> Right?
>> Right? >> So your whole family moves from an
>> So your whole family moves from an
>> So your whole family moves from an earthly dimension to a heavenly is a
earthly dimension to a heavenly is a
earthly dimension to a heavenly is a different dimension.
different dimension.
different dimension. >> Of course less physically dense.
>> Of course less physically dense.
>> Of course less physically dense. But uh
But uh
But uh >> well what if there's people that are not
>> well what if there's people that are not
>> well what if there's people that are not too fond of?
too fond of?
too fond of? >> Right?
>> Right?
>> Right? >> The next question is what if there's
>> The next question is what if there's
>> The next question is what if there's people you're not too fond of? You know,
people you're not too fond of? You know,
people you're not too fond of? You know, do do you sh ass associate with them or
do do you sh ass associate with them or
do do you sh ass associate with them or do you really associate with the ones
do you really associate with the ones
do you really associate with the ones that are
that are
that are >> that would be the decision.
>> that would be the decision.
>> that would be the decision. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Whether you want to overcome that
>> Whether you want to overcome that
>> Whether you want to overcome that aversion,
aversion,
aversion, >> okay,
>> okay,
>> okay, >> and undo a past negation.
>> and undo a past negation.
>> and undo a past negation. >> All right.
>> All right.
>> All right. >> Or you wish to continue it.
>> Or you wish to continue it.
>> Or you wish to continue it. >> I just wondered that as a myself.
>> I just wondered that as a myself.
>> I just wondered that as a myself. >> Yeah. Yeah. You I think you have an
>> Yeah. Yeah. You I think you have an
>> Yeah. Yeah. You I think you have an option.
option.
option. >> Okay. it, you know, is it time to give
>> Okay. it, you know, is it time to give
>> Okay. it, you know, is it time to give up that resentment and forgive the
up that resentment and forgive the
up that resentment and forgive the person and give it up or um were they so
person and give it up or um were they so
person and give it up or um were they so so bad that they don't deserve it?
so bad that they don't deserve it?
so bad that they don't deserve it? >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> And you're never going to speak to them
>> And you're never going to speak to them
>> And you're never going to speak to them again, period.
again, period.
again, period. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> In this dimension or any other
>> In this dimension or any other
>> In this dimension or any other >> um when a couple get a divorce, does
>> um when a couple get a divorce, does
>> um when a couple get a divorce, does that create negative karma?
that create negative karma?
that create negative karma? >> I don't think so. I think I think the
>> I don't think so. I think I think the
>> I don't think so. I think I think the reasons for the divorce are have to do
reasons for the divorce are have to do
reasons for the divorce are have to do with the do with it. I don't think the
with the do with it. I don't think the
with the do with it. I don't think the the divorce itself.
the divorce itself.
the divorce itself. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Divorce itself may be you know with them
>> Divorce itself may be you know with them
>> Divorce itself may be you know with them actually
actually
actually there are couples that really if their
there are couples that really if their
there are couples that really if their heads were screwed on tightly would have
heads were screwed on tightly would have
heads were screwed on tightly would have gotten divorced years ago. They seem to
gotten divorced years ago. They seem to
gotten divorced years ago. They seem to hate each other and have a very negative
hate each other and have a very negative
hate each other and have a very negative effect and bring out the worst in each
effect and bring out the worst in each
effect and bring out the worst in each other. And they would do society a great
other. And they would do society a great
other. And they would do society a great favor if they would just please get
favor if they would just please get
favor if they would just please get divorced and stop throwing frying pans
divorced and stop throwing frying pans
divorced and stop throwing frying pans at each other and having the police
at each other and having the police
at each other and having the police arrive every week. Mhm.
>> Um
>> Um I I wanted to know you know some people
I I wanted to know you know some people
I I wanted to know you know some people say uh so all right let's say that it
say uh so all right let's say that it
say uh so all right let's say that it was an amicable
was an amicable
was an amicable divorce.
divorce.
divorce. >> Um and um I'm giving you a what if you
>> Um and um I'm giving you a what if you
>> Um and um I'm giving you a what if you know
know
know >> amicable divorce. Yeah. Yeah.
>> amicable divorce. Yeah. Yeah.
>> amicable divorce. Yeah. Yeah. >> Okay. So
>> Okay. So
>> Okay. So >> they happen all the time.
>> they happen all the time.
>> they happen all the time. >> Yes. And so you know they get married
>> Yes. And so you know they get married
>> Yes. And so you know they get married and they just grow apart. You know
and they just grow apart. You know
and they just grow apart. You know there's nothing.
there's nothing.
there's nothing. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> So
>> So
>> So what is the karma of that? Is it just
what is the karma of that? Is it just
what is the karma of that? Is it just that there?
that there?
that there? >> I don't know if there's anything special
>> I don't know if there's anything special
>> I don't know if there's anything special about it.
about it.
about it. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> It would be like any other choice. You
>> It would be like any other choice. You
>> It would be like any other choice. You try a certain job, you don't like it,
try a certain job, you don't like it,
try a certain job, you don't like it, and you change to a different job.
and you change to a different job.
and you change to a different job. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> People get into relationships they think
>> People get into relationships they think
>> People get into relationships they think are going to work out and they find out
are going to work out and they find out
are going to work out and they find out later on that they don't.
later on that they don't.
later on that they don't. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> Uh-huh.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Uh-huh. >> And people change. I mean
>> And people change. I mean
>> And people change. I mean >> people change with time.
>> people change with time.
>> people change with time. >> Some people grow, some people don't, you
>> Some people grow, some people don't, you
>> Some people grow, some people don't, you know, and uh some people
know, and uh some people
know, and uh some people remain difficult all their life to get
remain difficult all their life to get
remain difficult all their life to get along with. So, you know, it just
along with. So, you know, it just
along with. So, you know, it just depends.
depends.
depends. >> Yeah. Some people get more mellow as
>> Yeah. Some people get more mellow as
>> Yeah. Some people get more mellow as they get older.
they get older.
they get older. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> And so they're canankerous when they're
>> And so they're canankerous when they're
>> And so they're canankerous when they're young, but they're more gentle. So, we
young, but they're more gentle. So, we
young, but they're more gentle. So, we always usually picture older people as
always usually picture older people as
always usually picture older people as more gentle.
more gentle.
more gentle. However, some become cranks and
However, some become cranks and
However, some become cranks and crackpots
>> and weird
>> and weird >> and weird.
>> Okay. What do pets contribute to the
>> Okay. What do pets contribute to the family? I know you like this one.
family? I know you like this one.
family? I know you like this one. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> As a family pet.
>> As a family pet.
>> As a family pet. >> Yeah. Am I a family pet? Oh,
>> Yeah. Am I a family pet? Oh,
>> Yeah. Am I a family pet? Oh, >> I think you are.
>> I think you are.
>> I think you are. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> You're my You're my pet, sweetheart.
>> You're my You're my pet, sweetheart.
>> You're my You're my pet, sweetheart. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Um
>> Um
>> Um >> you're my wifey pet. as a as a what does
>> you're my wifey pet. as a as a what does
>> you're my wifey pet. as a as a what does a family pet contribute to the family?
a family pet contribute to the family?
a family pet contribute to the family? >> Well, a pet contributes
>> Well, a pet contributes
>> Well, a pet contributes I think quite a bit.
I think quite a bit.
I think quite a bit. It's an opportunity for service and
It's an opportunity for service and
It's an opportunity for service and lovingness
lovingness
lovingness >> for exchange of affection.
>> for exchange of affection.
>> for exchange of affection. >> We know statistically
>> We know statistically
>> We know statistically that having a dog extends your lifespan
that having a dog extends your lifespan
that having a dog extends your lifespan by 10 years. I mean that's not a small
by 10 years. I mean that's not a small
by 10 years. I mean that's not a small amount, 10 years. that we know that
amount, 10 years. that we know that
amount, 10 years. that we know that people who own a dog live 10 years
people who own a dog live 10 years
people who own a dog live 10 years longer. 10 years is a long long time.
longer. 10 years is a long long time.
longer. 10 years is a long long time. >> We also know that the effect of having a
>> We also know that the effect of having a
>> We also know that the effect of having a dog um that a dog having a loving owner,
dog um that a dog having a loving owner,
dog um that a dog having a loving owner, the dog's life is extended by one year.
the dog's life is extended by one year.
the dog's life is extended by one year. So that always seemed to me
So that always seemed to me
So that always seemed to me rather impressive.
rather impressive.
rather impressive. Why a dog? Why uh has the dog become so
Why a dog? Why uh has the dog become so
Why a dog? Why uh has the dog become so special?
special?
special? Mhm.
Mhm.
Mhm. >> But in human life, a dog has quite an
>> But in human life, a dog has quite an
>> But in human life, a dog has quite an impact.
impact.
impact. You pardon me for coughing.
You pardon me for coughing.
You pardon me for coughing. >> Um,
>> Um,
>> Um, so it wouldn't have to be necessarily a
so it wouldn't have to be necessarily a
so it wouldn't have to be necessarily a dog. You're just using that as an
dog. You're just using that as an
dog. You're just using that as an example, but I mean any kind of animal,
example, but I mean any kind of animal,
example, but I mean any kind of animal, whether it's a bird or cat or whatever.
whether it's a bird or cat or whatever.
whether it's a bird or cat or whatever. >> I'm thinking of common ones. I think of
>> I'm thinking of common ones. I think of
>> I'm thinking of common ones. I think of any caringness for others for other
any caringness for others for other
any caringness for others for other other living things.
other living things.
other living things. >> People are more evolved to care for
>> People are more evolved to care for
>> People are more evolved to care for >> more evolved animals.
>> more evolved animals.
>> more evolved animals. >> I think they're evolved if they care for
>> I think they're evolved if they care for
>> I think they're evolved if they care for plants.
plants.
plants. >> I think it's uh more loving to care for
>> I think it's uh more loving to care for
>> I think it's uh more loving to care for an ivy plant hanging from the ceiling on
an ivy plant hanging from the ceiling on
an ivy plant hanging from the ceiling on a on a on a chain.
a on a on a chain.
a on a on a chain. >> Yeah. And having to bleach up and water
>> Yeah. And having to bleach up and water
>> Yeah. And having to bleach up and water it every day. So that caringness and
it every day. So that caringness and
it every day. So that caringness and lovingness for your surroundings
lovingness for your surroundings
lovingness for your surroundings uh including plant life and even your
uh including plant life and even your
uh including plant life and even your love for the inner uh life for instance
love for the inner uh life for instance
love for the inner uh life for instance whether to take care of the sofa and and
whether to take care of the sofa and and
whether to take care of the sofa and and see that it's plumped up or whether and
see that it's plumped up or whether and
see that it's plumped up or whether and vacuumed and or whether it's neglected
vacuumed and or whether it's neglected
vacuumed and or whether it's neglected and allowed to get flat and dirty and
and allowed to get flat and dirty and
and allowed to get flat and dirty and dusty. Does um do you think that um
dusty. Does um do you think that um
dusty. Does um do you think that um animals give help give children
animals give help give children
animals give help give children responsibility you know to for that love
responsibility you know to for that love
responsibility you know to for that love they can transfer that love to their
they can transfer that love to their
they can transfer that love to their animals? Does that is that a good
animals? Does that is that a good
animals? Does that is that a good teaching tool? I think it's a wonderful
teaching tool? I think it's a wonderful
teaching tool? I think it's a wonderful teaching tool. And I think
teaching tool. And I think
teaching tool. And I think one of the best things you can do is is
one of the best things you can do is is
one of the best things you can do is is have your children own a pet and be
have your children own a pet and be
have your children own a pet and be responsible.
responsible.
responsible. >> So they learn how to be responsible for
>> So they learn how to be responsible for
>> So they learn how to be responsible for the life and welfare and happiness of
the life and welfare and happiness of
the life and welfare and happiness of others and they become less less
others and they become less less
others and they become less less self-centered.
self-centered.
self-centered. >> I think a child who grows up owning and
>> I think a child who grows up owning and
>> I think a child who grows up owning and caring for a dog ends up far ahead of a
caring for a dog ends up far ahead of a
caring for a dog ends up far ahead of a child who misses that opportunity.
child who misses that opportunity.
child who misses that opportunity. Then that'd be a dog, could be a kitty
Then that'd be a dog, could be a kitty
Then that'd be a dog, could be a kitty or anything, but a dog is more
or anything, but a dog is more
or anything, but a dog is more responsive quickly to the human touch
responsive quickly to the human touch
responsive quickly to the human touch and attention.
and attention.
and attention. So owning a dog extends your life 10
So owning a dog extends your life 10
So owning a dog extends your life 10 years.
years.
years. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> And loving the dog extends the dog
>> And loving the dog extends the dog
>> And loving the dog extends the dog doubles the dog's life. I think that's
doubles the dog's life. I think that's
doubles the dog's life. I think that's rather profound kind of impact and
rather profound kind of impact and
rather profound kind of impact and importance, significance,
importance, significance,
importance, significance, >> one everybody should really look at it
>> one everybody should really look at it
>> one everybody should really look at it sometime in their life. I wonder what
sometime in their life. I wonder what
sometime in their life. I wonder what that means and does that apply to me and
>> um let's say that you have a family
>> um let's say that you have a family member that is um below 200 be below
member that is um below 200 be below
member that is um below 200 be below integrity.
integrity.
integrity. >> Um what is the how is the best way to
>> Um what is the how is the best way to
>> Um what is the how is the best way to handle that?
handle that?
handle that? I mean, you know, you can pick your
I mean, you know, you can pick your
I mean, you know, you can pick your friends, but you can't pick your family.
friends, but you can't pick your family.
friends, but you can't pick your family. You know, you're born into it. So, uh,
You know, you're born into it. So, uh,
You know, you're born into it. So, uh, how how can you
how how can you
how how can you >> what is the best way to handle a family
>> what is the best way to handle a family
>> what is the best way to handle a family member that is below 200 or below the
member that is below 200 or below the
member that is below 200 or below the line of integrity?
line of integrity?
line of integrity? Well, we we we are the local
Well, we we we are the local
Well, we we we are the local representative of society then to them
representative of society then to them
representative of society then to them and so we're going to do whatever
and so we're going to do whatever
and so we're going to do whatever society would dictate.
society would dictate.
society would dictate. There are, you know, points at which
There are, you know, points at which
There are, you know, points at which they have to call in the police, you
they have to call in the police, you
they have to call in the police, you know, actually,
know, actually,
know, actually, >> right,
>> right,
>> right, >> there are raging children who you have
>> there are raging children who you have
>> there are raging children who you have to actually lock up in a room till they
to actually lock up in a room till they
to actually lock up in a room till they stop screaming, etc.
stop screaming, etc.
stop screaming, etc. So I think it presses our
So I think it presses our
So I think it presses our uh ingenuity.
uh ingenuity.
uh ingenuity. So many of these pressures
So many of these pressures
So many of these pressures really are pressures on our ingenuity
really are pressures on our ingenuity
really are pressures on our ingenuity and our humanness and human capacity to
and our humanness and human capacity to
and our humanness and human capacity to become creative
become creative
become creative and to suddenly grow in an area that had
and to suddenly grow in an area that had
and to suddenly grow in an area that had been unsuspected before. Sometimes a
been unsuspected before. Sometimes a
been unsuspected before. Sometimes a certain character trait or positive
certain character trait or positive
certain character trait or positive trait doesn't show up until there's a
trait doesn't show up until there's a
trait doesn't show up until there's a need for it. I remember people during
need for it. I remember people during
need for it. I remember people during the war that uh it never showed any kind
the war that uh it never showed any kind
the war that uh it never showed any kind of compassion or concern for others.
of compassion or concern for others.
of compassion or concern for others. But then when the shooting started and
But then when the shooting started and
But then when the shooting started and people started to die, suddenly they
people started to die, suddenly they
people started to die, suddenly they became saintly. I mean, they would risk
became saintly. I mean, they would risk
became saintly. I mean, they would risk their life to save their brother and
their life to save their brother and
their life to save their brother and >> guy would get a bullet in him out on the
>> guy would get a bullet in him out on the
>> guy would get a bullet in him out on the deck and he'd go out where where he
deck and he'd go out where where he
deck and he'd go out where where he could have gotten killed by gun machine
could have gotten killed by gun machine
could have gotten killed by gun machine gun fire and risk risk it to save his
gun fire and risk risk it to save his
gun fire and risk risk it to save his buddy.
buddy.
buddy. And uh so great acts of bravery
And uh so great acts of bravery
And uh so great acts of bravery appeared in people who had never shown
appeared in people who had never shown
appeared in people who had never shown anything in the way of courage before.
anything in the way of courage before.
anything in the way of courage before. M
M
M >> so if you have a person below 200 uh or
>> so if you have a person below 200 uh or
>> so if you have a person below 200 uh or below the line of integrity, how do you
below the line of integrity, how do you
below the line of integrity, how do you handle it?
handle it?
handle it? >> You you bring them up like you would a
>> You you bring them up like you would a
>> You you bring them up like you would a weward child, showing them right and
weward child, showing them right and
weward child, showing them right and wrong and you doing it by example and
wrong and you doing it by example and
wrong and you doing it by example and rewarding good behavior and
rewarding good behavior and
rewarding good behavior and withholding uh rewards from bad
withholding uh rewards from bad
withholding uh rewards from bad behaviors.
behaviors.
behaviors. You do it like you do with a
You do it like you do with a
You do it like you do with a child.
So um would let's say that it's not a
So um would let's say that it's not a child that it is a sibling would you
child that it is a sibling would you
child that it is a sibling would you isolate yourself from them or what would
isolate yourself from them or what would
isolate yourself from them or what would be the best way
be the best way
be the best way >> that would depend on the family
>> that would depend on the family
>> that would depend on the family circumstances
circumstances
circumstances but you you could very well isolate
but you you could very well isolate
but you you could very well isolate yourself from that sibling
yourself from that sibling
yourself from that sibling >> and say so long as you're doing that I'm
>> and say so long as you're doing that I'm
>> and say so long as you're doing that I'm not going to speak to you.
not going to speak to you.
not going to speak to you. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> And you can't play with my toys either.
>> And you can't play with my toys either.
>> And you can't play with my toys either. Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. >> And you can't ride my bicycle.
>> And you can't ride my bicycle.
>> And you can't ride my bicycle. >> All right. So, all right. Let's say that
>> All right. So, all right. Let's say that
>> All right. So, all right. Let's say that you have a sibling that is
you have a sibling that is
you have a sibling that is >> below integrity and uh
>> below integrity and uh
>> below integrity and uh and let's say they go out and get drunk.
and let's say they go out and get drunk.
and let's say they go out and get drunk. I'm giving you for instances because I'm
I'm giving you for instances because I'm
I'm giving you for instances because I'm trying to come up with
trying to come up with
trying to come up with >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> what other people might have in their
>> what other people might have in their
>> what other people might have in their life. So, let's say you have a sibling
life. So, let's say you have a sibling
life. So, let's say you have a sibling that goes out and gets drunk and they
that goes out and gets drunk and they
that goes out and gets drunk and they always come to you to fix everything
always come to you to fix everything
always come to you to fix everything because there's fixers out there. I won.
because there's fixers out there. I won.
because there's fixers out there. I won. >> Yeah. So, you tell them Yeah. that
>> Yeah. So, you tell them Yeah. that
>> Yeah. So, you tell them Yeah. that there's a limit to your fixing this.
there's a limit to your fixing this.
there's a limit to your fixing this. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> And then if they do that again, you
>> And then if they do that again, you
>> And then if they do that again, you won't clean it up after them.
won't clean it up after them.
won't clean it up after them. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> If you never spill another quart of beer
>> If you never spill another quart of beer
>> If you never spill another quart of beer on the floor, you'll have to sap it up
on the floor, you'll have to sap it up
on the floor, you'll have to sap it up yourself. I'm not going to get out the
yourself. I'm not going to get out the
yourself. I'm not going to get out the the mop.
the mop.
the mop. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> You have to draw lines and limits of
>> You have to draw lines and limits of
>> You have to draw lines and limits of behaviors.
behaviors.
behaviors. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> Just as society in general does. Society
>> Just as society in general does. Society
>> Just as society in general does. Society draws lines and limits. They'll tolerate
draws lines and limits. They'll tolerate
draws lines and limits. They'll tolerate misbehavior up to a certain point and
misbehavior up to a certain point and
misbehavior up to a certain point and beyond that point they call the police.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Uhhuh. >> So isolating yourself is one tool to use
>> So isolating yourself is one tool to use
>> So isolating yourself is one tool to use and setting an example is another tool.
and setting an example is another tool.
and setting an example is another tool. Uh is there any more tools that you can
Uh is there any more tools that you can
Uh is there any more tools that you can give us that
give us that
give us that >> those are the ones most commonly used is
>> those are the ones most commonly used is
>> those are the ones most commonly used is example and reward and punishment. You
example and reward and punishment. You
example and reward and punishment. You know, you give a reward for good
know, you give a reward for good
know, you give a reward for good behavior
behavior
behavior and a punishment for bad behavior or you
and a punishment for bad behavior or you
and a punishment for bad behavior or you withhold something.
withhold something.
withhold something. >> So like our doggy, if she behaves, we
>> So like our doggy, if she behaves, we
>> So like our doggy, if she behaves, we give her a cookie. And if she
give her a cookie. And if she
give her a cookie. And if she misbehaves, we don't give her a cookie.
misbehaves, we don't give her a cookie.
misbehaves, we don't give her a cookie. You don't get a cookie.
You don't get a cookie.
You don't get a cookie. >> Right.
>> Right.
>> Right. >> So a good deal of our doggy's behavior
>> So a good deal of our doggy's behavior
>> So a good deal of our doggy's behavior can throw with a cookie.
Um, how does a parent teach a child
Um, how does a parent teach a child about spiritual reality without
about spiritual reality without
about spiritual reality without programming them into a specific belief
programming them into a specific belief
programming them into a specific belief system?
system?
system? >> It it would be very hard to do. You
>> It it would be very hard to do. You
>> It it would be very hard to do. You would have to take the abstract
would have to take the abstract
would have to take the abstract s you know the overall significance of a
s you know the overall significance of a
s you know the overall significance of a certain religious rule and try to show
certain religious rule and try to show
certain religious rule and try to show the wisdom of it. So in other words, you
the wisdom of it. So in other words, you
the wisdom of it. So in other words, you would say, let's just give an example.
would say, let's just give an example.
would say, let's just give an example. Um
Um
Um >> certain certain doctrines.
>> certain certain doctrines.
>> certain certain doctrines. >> Yeah, let's just give an example. You
>> Yeah, let's just give an example. You
>> Yeah, let's just give an example. You either, you know, such as um you raise
either, you know, such as um you raise
either, you know, such as um you raise the child in whatever belief system that
the child in whatever belief system that
the child in whatever belief system that you have, whether it's Catholic, Pro,
you have, whether it's Catholic, Pro,
you have, whether it's Catholic, Pro, Protestant, Buddhism, whatever, but you
Protestant, Buddhism, whatever, but you
Protestant, Buddhism, whatever, but you you raise that child in that belief
you raise that child in that belief
you raise that child in that belief system. All right? Um you set the
system. All right? Um you set the
system. All right? Um you set the example for them. And
example for them. And
example for them. And um how do you instit
>> how do you instill um karmic merit into
>> how do you instill um karmic merit into them? You know that
them? You know that
them? You know that >> well you you don't instill it.
>> well you you don't instill it.
>> well you you don't instill it. >> You you set the rules and you you set
>> You you set the rules and you you set
>> You you set the rules and you you set the uh the realities that are
the uh the realities that are
the uh the realities that are represented by their choices.
represented by their choices.
represented by their choices. >> Okay. And then they themselves, you
>> Okay. And then they themselves, you
>> Okay. And then they themselves, you know, make the choices
know, make the choices
know, make the choices >> to either uh uh be in accord with
>> to either uh uh be in accord with
>> to either uh uh be in accord with certain teachings or to dispute them. In
certain teachings or to dispute them. In
certain teachings or to dispute them. In my own lifetime, I went from religiosity
my own lifetime, I went from religiosity
my own lifetime, I went from religiosity to hyper religiosity
to hyper religiosity
to hyper religiosity to atheism to skepticism,
to atheism to skepticism,
to atheism to skepticism, then back to spiritual reality.
then back to spiritual reality.
then back to spiritual reality. And um there were things learned in each
And um there were things learned in each
And um there were things learned in each one each one uh
one each one uh
one each one uh you know when I decided didn't want to
you know when I decided didn't want to
you know when I decided didn't want to go to church anymore and we would meet
go to church anymore and we would meet
go to church anymore and we would meet on Fridays or something I didn't drop
on Fridays or something I didn't drop
on Fridays or something I didn't drop over with lightning nothing really
over with lightning nothing really
over with lightning nothing really happened
happened
happened I you know had made a decision
I you know had made a decision
I you know had made a decision >> so by doing
>> so by doing
>> so by doing >> to be an episcopelian of a certain
>> to be an episcopelian of a certain
>> to be an episcopelian of a certain dimension or you could be a Catholic or
dimension or you could be a Catholic or
dimension or you could be a Catholic or a Protestant or you could be stop going
a Protestant or you could be stop going
a Protestant or you could be stop going to church and I'm not a churchgoer
to church and I'm not a churchgoer
to church and I'm not a churchgoer anymore, but I live a moral be moral
anymore, but I live a moral be moral
anymore, but I live a moral be moral life. You know, you don't have to go to
life. You know, you don't have to go to
life. You know, you don't have to go to church to lead a moral life.
You say worship God as you understand
You say worship God as you understand him.
there's a question I had here and I
there's a question I had here and I can't think of it. Um
can't think of it. Um
can't think of it. Um do parents um
do parents um
do parents um so the parent is to set the example for
so the parent is to set the example for
so the parent is to set the example for a child and it is up to the child to
a child and it is up to the child to
a child and it is up to the child to make the choice.
make the choice.
make the choice. >> The child doesn't when you say make a
>> The child doesn't when you say make a
>> The child doesn't when you say make a choice you're presuming a real free
choice you're presuming a real free
choice you're presuming a real free will.
will.
will. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> They don't really have that degree of
>> They don't really have that degree of
>> They don't really have that degree of free will yet.
free will yet.
free will yet. >> Okay. They're still really under the
>> Okay. They're still really under the
>> Okay. They're still really under the imperative of their parents' wishes and
imperative of their parents' wishes and
imperative of their parents' wishes and desires and love and not love, approval
desires and love and not love, approval
desires and love and not love, approval and disapproval.
and disapproval.
and disapproval. They have some latitude but not a lot.
They have some latitude but not a lot.
They have some latitude but not a lot. But as they get older and older, more
But as they get older and older, more
But as they get older and older, more independent, they have greater and
independent, they have greater and
independent, they have greater and greater latitude
greater latitude
greater latitude and finally they can reach the point
and finally they can reach the point
and finally they can reach the point where they tell you they don't believe
where they tell you they don't believe
where they tell you they don't believe in going in God and they don't believe
in going in God and they don't believe
in going in God and they don't believe in going to church anymore and become go
in going to church anymore and become go
in going to church anymore and become go from devout to atheist.
from devout to atheist.
from devout to atheist. If a child is um doing their parents
If a child is um doing their parents
If a child is um doing their parents crazy,
crazy,
crazy, >> if a child is acting below 200
>> if a child is acting below 200
>> if a child is acting below 200 um how do you correct them or how do you
um how do you correct them or how do you
um how do you correct them or how do you say well do you tell them that was
say well do you tell them that was
say well do you tell them that was that's not a a spiritual way to look at
that's not a a spiritual way to look at
that's not a a spiritual way to look at that or how do you cor how do what do
that or how do you cor how do what do
that or how do you cor how do what do you say
you say
you say >> well you know you're going back to basic
>> well you know you're going back to basic
>> well you know you're going back to basic right and wrong
right and wrong
right and wrong >> basic right and wrong. And then the
>> basic right and wrong. And then the
>> basic right and wrong. And then the wrongs are of a serious degree of uh
wrongs are of a serious degree of uh
wrongs are of a serious degree of uh seriousness and severity and
seriousness and severity and
seriousness and severity and consequence.
consequence.
consequence. And you can warn them that beyond a
And you can warn them that beyond a
And you can warn them that beyond a certain point, you can be doing great
certain point, you can be doing great
certain point, you can be doing great harm to your soul and your spirit.
harm to your soul and your spirit.
harm to your soul and your spirit. >> And it can have grave consequences.
>> And it can have grave consequences.
>> And it can have grave consequences. And it will certainly have grave
And it will certainly have grave
And it will certainly have grave consequences when you leave the body.
consequences when you leave the body.
consequences when you leave the body. Whether you go to heaven or hell is
Whether you go to heaven or hell is
Whether you go to heaven or hell is pretty, you know, pretty much something
pretty, you know, pretty much something
pretty, you know, pretty much something that you have decided yourself by your
that you have decided yourself by your
that you have decided yourself by your own your own be choices and behaviors.
own your own be choices and behaviors.
own your own be choices and behaviors. >> Whether to love your fellow man or to
>> Whether to love your fellow man or to
>> Whether to love your fellow man or to hate him is a very major choice. So we
hate him is a very major choice. So we
hate him is a very major choice. So we we think of people in other religions
we think of people in other religions
we think of people in other religions uh some of which are greatly intolerant
uh some of which are greatly intolerant
uh some of which are greatly intolerant and will kill people just because they
and will kill people just because they
and will kill people just because they belong to a different religion.
belong to a different religion.
belong to a different religion. U in my view it is to be tolerant of all
U in my view it is to be tolerant of all
U in my view it is to be tolerant of all religions
because each one believes what they
because each one believes what they believe for reasons beyond
believe for reasons beyond
believe for reasons beyond >> their own choosing.
>> their own choosing.
>> their own choosing. >> Few people chose who their parents would
>> Few people chose who their parents would
>> Few people chose who their parents would be before they got born. So most people
be before they got born. So most people
be before they got born. So most people are whatever religion they really they
are whatever religion they really they
are whatever religion they really they are is because of the family that they
are is because of the family that they
are is because of the family that they happen to be born into and the culture
happen to be born into and the culture
happen to be born into and the culture and the country and the time.
and the country and the time.
and the country and the time. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> What kind of role do grandparents play?
>> You get the more interesting that
>> You get the more interesting that question gets. Yeah.
question gets. Yeah.
question gets. Yeah. No, I I I think they serve a great uh
No, I I I think they serve a great uh
No, I I I think they serve a great uh they're the great levelers, the great uh
they're the great levelers, the great uh
they're the great levelers, the great uh peacemakers.
peacemakers.
peacemakers. Um the unconditionally loving person
Um the unconditionally loving person
Um the unconditionally loving person and they can also be the disciplinarian
and they can also be the disciplinarian
and they can also be the disciplinarian where the parents have failed to
where the parents have failed to
where the parents have failed to correct. You know,
correct. You know,
correct. You know, >> the grandparent can jump in and say, you
>> the grandparent can jump in and say, you
>> the grandparent can jump in and say, you know, you should have taught so and so
know, you should have taught so and so
know, you should have taught so and so >> to be more respectful to their elders.
>> to be more respectful to their elders.
>> to be more respectful to their elders. I know you had wonderful grandparents
I know you had wonderful grandparents
I know you had wonderful grandparents and so did I growing up. They were just
and so did I growing up. They were just
and so did I growing up. They were just >> Yeah. It was fortunate. Yeah.
>> Yeah. It was fortunate. Yeah.
>> Yeah. It was fortunate. Yeah. >> Yeah. They were just absolutely I
>> Yeah. They were just absolutely I
>> Yeah. They were just absolutely I couldn't ask for better grandparents.
couldn't ask for better grandparents.
couldn't ask for better grandparents. >> I do. Like I have very good memories of
>> I do. Like I have very good memories of
>> I do. Like I have very good memories of them.
them.
them. >> Yeah. Uhhuh.
>> Yeah. Uhhuh.
>> Yeah. Uhhuh. >> And you know they you know they were
>> And you know they you know they were
>> And you know they you know they were just wonderful. You know the overnight
just wonderful. You know the overnight
just wonderful. You know the overnight staying overnight at their house and
staying overnight at their house and
staying overnight at their house and everything. Still remember that. It was
everything. Still remember that. It was
everything. Still remember that. It was very special you know very special to to
very special you know very special to to
very special you know very special to to them.
them.
them. >> Yeah. saying over the weekend that your
>> Yeah. saying over the weekend that your
>> Yeah. saying over the weekend that your grandparents were
grandparents were
grandparents were >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> It would seem like a great idea and
>> It would seem like a great idea and
>> It would seem like a great idea and you'd be all excited about it.
you'd be all excited about it.
you'd be all excited about it. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> And then in the middle of the night you
>> And then in the middle of the night you
>> And then in the middle of the night you get homesick.
get homesick.
get homesick. >> I wish you'd gone home with your parents
>> I wish you'd gone home with your parents
>> I wish you'd gone home with your parents instead of staying with your
instead of staying with your
instead of staying with your grandparents.
grandparents.
grandparents. >> I don't know. I never got homesick in my
>> I don't know. I never got homesick in my
>> I don't know. I never got homesick in my grandparents. They were just super It
grandparents. They were just super It
grandparents. They were just super It was fun. I mean,
was fun. I mean,
was fun. I mean, >> yeah.
>> yeah.
>> yeah. >> Uh they were just great. So,
>> Uh they were just great. So,
>> Uh they were just great. So, >> you know, my grandfather was always so
>> you know, my grandfather was always so
>> you know, my grandfather was always so funny.
funny.
funny. He was really a great sense of humor.
He was really a great sense of humor.
He was really a great sense of humor. >> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. >> Yeah. Just wonderful memories of him.
>> Yeah. Just wonderful memories of him.
>> Yeah. Just wonderful memories of him. >> So grandparents should in as a
>> So grandparents should in as a
>> So grandparents should in as a grandparent we probably should install
grandparent we probably should install
grandparent we probably should install memories of into uh so that our
memories of into uh so that our
memories of into uh so that our grandchildren have an idea of what it's
grandchildren have an idea of what it's
grandchildren have an idea of what it's like to be grandparents.
like to be grandparents.
like to be grandparents. >> Generation to generation. Yes. Uhhuh.
>> Generation to generation. Yes. Uhhuh.
>> Generation to generation. Yes. Uhhuh. >> Uhhuh.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Uhhuh. >> Yeah. You're supposed to be the
>> Yeah. You're supposed to be the
>> Yeah. You're supposed to be the superarent by the time you're a
superarent by the time you're a
superarent by the time you're a grandparent.
grandparent.
grandparent. >> Yeah. You're supposed to have learned
>> Yeah. You're supposed to have learned
>> Yeah. You're supposed to have learned all the lessons of parenting
all the lessons of parenting
all the lessons of parenting >> and become a master of them all. Uhhuh.
>> and become a master of them all. Uhhuh.
>> and become a master of them all. Uhhuh. >> How to be gracious and
>> How to be gracious and
>> How to be gracious and convincing and rewarding at the same
convincing and rewarding at the same
convincing and rewarding at the same time.
time.
time. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> Set limits,
>> Set limits,
>> Set limits, >> right?
>> right?
>> right? >> How to set limits. Mhm.
>> Two cookies is enough.
>> Two cookies is enough. >> Yeah. Yeah. That's kind of thing.
>> Yeah. Yeah. That's kind of thing.
>> Yeah. Yeah. That's kind of thing. >> Draw the line. the third cookie.
>> Um here's a here's a question that's
>> Um here's a here's a question that's very good. It says um
very good. It says um
very good. It says um this particular student is um
this particular student is um
this particular student is um spiritually devoted while the spouse is
spiritually devoted while the spouse is
spiritually devoted while the spouse is not necessarily spir spiritually
not necessarily spir spiritually
not necessarily spir spiritually devoted.
devoted.
devoted. >> Yeah, that's not uncommon.
>> Yeah, that's not uncommon.
>> Yeah, that's not uncommon. >> Um
>> Um
>> Um >> how do you you know you still love your
>> how do you you know you still love your
>> how do you you know you still love your spouse, but how would you say would be
spouse, but how would you say would be
spouse, but how would you say would be the best way to approach that? uh
the best way to approach that? uh
the best way to approach that? uh situation,
situation,
situation, >> but you just accept that that one parent
>> but you just accept that that one parent
>> but you just accept that that one parent may know how to drive a car and the
may know how to drive a car and the
may know how to drive a car and the other one doesn't,
other one doesn't,
other one doesn't, >> right?
>> right?
>> right? >> So, you don't have to get a divorce over
>> So, you don't have to get a divorce over
>> So, you don't have to get a divorce over it. You know what I'm saying?
it. You know what I'm saying?
it. You know what I'm saying? >> Uh one parent really loves going to
>> Uh one parent really loves going to
>> Uh one parent really loves going to church and the other's bored with it,
church and the other's bored with it,
church and the other's bored with it, doesn't want to go.
doesn't want to go.
doesn't want to go. >> So, each one, like anything in marriage,
>> So, each one, like anything in marriage,
>> So, each one, like anything in marriage, there certain degrees of freedom.
there certain degrees of freedom.
there certain degrees of freedom. >> And then there's limits beyond which you
>> And then there's limits beyond which you
>> And then there's limits beyond which you wouldn't want to go under any
wouldn't want to go under any
wouldn't want to go under any circumstances,
circumstances,
circumstances, >> right?
>> right?
>> right? So if one wants to go to church and the
So if one wants to go to church and the
So if one wants to go to church and the other doesn't, the one who wants to is
other doesn't, the one who wants to is
other doesn't, the one who wants to is free to do so,
free to do so,
free to do so, >> right? Without any without
>> right? Without any without
>> right? Without any without >> Yeah. And the one who doesn't want to
>> Yeah. And the one who doesn't want to
>> Yeah. And the one who doesn't want to can discourage it and say, well,
can discourage it and say, well,
can discourage it and say, well, you know, and then give good examples of
you know, and then give good examples of
you know, and then give good examples of why it is worthless or not of any
why it is worthless or not of any
why it is worthless or not of any benefit or something
benefit or something
benefit or something uh or become skeptical about it. Mhm.
uh or become skeptical about it. Mhm.
uh or become skeptical about it. Mhm. >> But those are phases uh you know that
>> But those are phases uh you know that
>> But those are phases uh you know that most people go through. One part of
most people go through. One part of
most people go through. One part of their life they're quite religious,
their life they're quite religious,
their life they're quite religious, another they're not. If they got young
another they're not. If they got young
another they're not. If they got young children just born, they're not so
children just born, they're not so
children just born, they're not so likely to be
likely to be
likely to be observant on Sunday morning.
observant on Sunday morning.
observant on Sunday morning. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> And as they get older, they see that
>> And as they get older, they see that
>> And as they get older, they see that sooner or later you're going to have to
sooner or later you're going to have to
sooner or later you're going to have to go to either heaven or hell. And you
go to either heaven or hell. And you
go to either heaven or hell. And you better start deciding which or what.
better start deciding which or what.
better start deciding which or what. And that may deter a lot of negative
And that may deter a lot of negative
And that may deter a lot of negative behavior.
behavior.
behavior. >> So actually if you're in a relationship
>> So actually if you're in a relationship
>> So actually if you're in a relationship like that, the best thing is to say, you
like that, the best thing is to say, you
like that, the best thing is to say, you know, well, that's your choice not to go
know, well, that's your choice not to go
know, well, that's your choice not to go to church, but I I I would like to go,
to church, but I I I would like to go,
to church, but I I I would like to go, so I'm going this Sunday, you know,
so I'm going this Sunday, you know,
so I'm going this Sunday, you know, without any conflict there.
without any conflict there.
without any conflict there. >> So there doesn't need to be conflict
>> So there doesn't need to be conflict
>> So there doesn't need to be conflict about it. I can just say
about it. I can just say
about it. I can just say I really want to go to hear a sermon by
I really want to go to hear a sermon by
I really want to go to hear a sermon by Reverend so and so and uh the other one
Reverend so and so and uh the other one
Reverend so and so and uh the other one doesn't go with me or not.
doesn't go with me or not.
doesn't go with me or not. >> Yeah. Doesn't necessarily have to go.
>> Yeah. Doesn't necessarily have to go.
>> Yeah. Doesn't necessarily have to go. >> But may want to go just out of curiosity
>> But may want to go just out of curiosity
>> But may want to go just out of curiosity to see what your experience is.
to see what your experience is.
to see what your experience is. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> You know, sometimes you're watching
>> You know, sometimes you're watching
>> You know, sometimes you're watching something on television. I don't have
something on television. I don't have
something on television. I don't have any particular interest in it.
any particular interest in it.
any particular interest in it. >> No. But I I I observe it to see what is
>> No. But I I I observe it to see what is
>> No. But I I I observe it to see what is there in that that she finds
there in that that she finds
there in that that she finds interesting.
interesting.
interesting. Uh
Uh
Uh you know what is it that makes it of
you know what is it that makes it of
you know what is it that makes it of value.
value.
value. >> That's what you asked me on several
>> That's what you asked me on several
>> That's what you asked me on several things you know that I think of now.
things you know that I think of now.
things you know that I think of now. >> Yeah. And I try to see what is what is
>> Yeah. And I try to see what is what is
>> Yeah. And I try to see what is what is obser of value
obser of value
obser of value >> in watching that.
>> in watching that.
>> in watching that. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> Sometimes just the amusement of
>> Sometimes just the amusement of
>> Sometimes just the amusement of animation. So you know it's the
animation. So you know it's the
animation. So you know it's the amusement.
amusement.
amusement. Uh mhm or I say what is amusing about
Uh mhm or I say what is amusing about
Uh mhm or I say what is amusing about that or what's interesting about that
that or what's interesting about that
that or what's interesting about that once in a while I'll say to you what do
once in a while I'll say to you what do
once in a while I'll say to you what do you see in that program remember I say
you see in that program remember I say
you see in that program remember I say what in the world do you see in that
what in the world do you see in that
what in the world do you see in that program it's so stupid
>> well sometimes I like to watch TV just
>> well sometimes I like to watch TV just because it's mindless
because it's mindless
because it's mindless >> you know
>> you know
>> you know >> you don't have to think you know
>> you don't have to think you know
>> you don't have to think you know entertain
entertain
entertain >> well that's true yeah Yeah,
>> well that's true yeah Yeah,
>> well that's true yeah Yeah, >> you have a tendency to like the
>> you have a tendency to like the
>> you have a tendency to like the documentaries and news and things like
documentaries and news and things like
documentaries and news and things like this and I like something that's just
this and I like something that's just
this and I like something that's just not mindless because depending on what
not mindless because depending on what
not mindless because depending on what it is.
it is.
it is. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> So, if you were to sum up
>> So, if you were to sum up
>> So, if you were to sum up what family
what family
what family uh how they influence us and what part
uh how they influence us and what part
uh how they influence us and what part they play in our spiritual aspect, what
they play in our spiritual aspect, what
they play in our spiritual aspect, what would you say? I would say they play a
would you say? I would say they play a
would you say? I would say they play a very important part part because they
very important part part because they
very important part part because they set an example.
set an example.
set an example. >> There's a certain conditioning that
>> There's a certain conditioning that
>> There's a certain conditioning that takes place.
takes place.
takes place. >> Uhu
>> Uhu
>> Uhu >> and um a certain sense of right and
>> and um a certain sense of right and
>> and um a certain sense of right and wrong and of greater and lesser value.
wrong and of greater and lesser value.
wrong and of greater and lesser value. >> Uh
>> Uh
>> Uh so it doesn't require agreement on the
so it doesn't require agreement on the
so it doesn't require agreement on the specifics. Mhm.
specifics. Mhm.
specifics. Mhm. >> But the the overall teaching is that
>> But the the overall teaching is that
>> But the the overall teaching is that there are ways of experiencing and
there are ways of experiencing and
there are ways of experiencing and viewing life that have great value to
viewing life that have great value to
viewing life that have great value to yourself and to others.
yourself and to others.
yourself and to others. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> That they're worth respecting and uh
>> That they're worth respecting and uh
>> That they're worth respecting and uh looking into. Mhm.
looking into. Mhm.
looking into. Mhm. And if you haven't been to church, you
And if you haven't been to church, you
And if you haven't been to church, you ought to try it and see if you like it
ought to try it and see if you like it
ought to try it and see if you like it or not.
or not.
or not. >> Some people like the singing of the
>> Some people like the singing of the
>> Some people like the singing of the choir and they go to church because they
choir and they go to church because they
choir and they go to church because they just love singing of the choir.
just love singing of the choir.
just love singing of the choir. So when I when I think back about my
So when I when I think back about my
So when I when I think back about my spiritual upbringing and how it affects
spiritual upbringing and how it affects
spiritual upbringing and how it affects me in you know this day and age or as an
me in you know this day and age or as an
me in you know this day and age or as an adult um I think back and I think that
adult um I think back and I think that
adult um I think back and I think that it it was important to have whether it's
it it was important to have whether it's
it it was important to have whether it's uh whether you actually quote go to
uh whether you actually quote go to
uh whether you actually quote go to church or whether you're you just have
church or whether you're you just have
church or whether you're you just have that time
that time
that time >> of you know teaching your children to
>> of you know teaching your children to
>> of you know teaching your children to pray and that when things get tough.
pray and that when things get tough.
pray and that when things get tough. >> Reverence.
>> Reverence.
>> Reverence. >> Yeah. That you can use that to fall back
>> Yeah. That you can use that to fall back
>> Yeah. That you can use that to fall back on.
on.
on. >> Turning to God and religion and the
>> Turning to God and religion and the
>> Turning to God and religion and the values that they represent of honesty
values that they represent of honesty
values that they represent of honesty and integrity and
and integrity and
and integrity and responsibility
responsibility
responsibility >> because even at this point there's
>> because even at this point there's
>> because even at this point there's there's things that are very um you know
there's things that are very um you know
there's things that are very um you know that family or siblings or parents have
that family or siblings or parents have
that family or siblings or parents have done. And it's to let go of those
done. And it's to let go of those
done. And it's to let go of those resentments that happened because they
resentments that happened because they
resentments that happened because they were doing the best they could at that
were doing the best they could at that
were doing the best they could at that time.
time.
time. >> That's where I always look at it. That
>> That's where I always look at it. That
>> That's where I always look at it. That everybody everybody and it applies to
everybody everybody and it applies to
everybody everybody and it applies to everybody. Everybody's doing about as
everybody. Everybody's doing about as
everybody. Everybody's doing about as good as they can or or if they were able
good as they can or or if they were able
good as they can or or if they were able to do better, they would be
to do better, they would be
to do better, they would be >> right.
>> right.
>> right. >> They would be.
>> They would be.
>> They would be. So if a thief is a thief, he
So if a thief is a thief, he
So if a thief is a thief, he you know, he may try to not be a thief
you know, he may try to not be a thief
you know, he may try to not be a thief and fail. Mhm.
and fail. Mhm.
and fail. Mhm. >> But what we do is expect the people is
>> But what we do is expect the people is
>> But what we do is expect the people is that they set a value a greater than the
that they set a value a greater than the
that they set a value a greater than the one a behavioral pattern
one a behavioral pattern
one a behavioral pattern >> that is better than the one that they
>> that is better than the one that they
>> that is better than the one that they are following.
are following.
are following. We do expect that of people that they
We do expect that of people that they
We do expect that of people that they will show a certain progression.
will show a certain progression.
will show a certain progression. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> You know, if you go to three three times
>> You know, if you go to three three times
>> You know, if you go to three three times to jail for drunkenness,
to jail for drunkenness,
to jail for drunkenness, uh we're pretty disappointed by the
uh we're pretty disappointed by the
uh we're pretty disappointed by the fourth time.
fourth time.
fourth time. uh pretty pretty disappointed that they
uh pretty pretty disappointed that they
uh pretty pretty disappointed that they have repeated it over. Receivism
have repeated it over. Receivism
have repeated it over. Receivism really wears out the you know
really wears out the you know
really wears out the you know forgiveness
forgiveness
forgiveness that you're going to keep doing it over
that you're going to keep doing it over
that you're going to keep doing it over and over.
and over.
and over. >> So really a
>> So really a
>> So really a >> we begin to view it as a mental disorder
>> we begin to view it as a mental disorder
>> we begin to view it as a mental disorder constantly make the same mistake. So
constantly make the same mistake. So
constantly make the same mistake. So what we've learned today is that a
what we've learned today is that a
what we've learned today is that a family does not actually hold you back
family does not actually hold you back
family does not actually hold you back from enlightenment. If you're destined
from enlightenment. If you're destined
from enlightenment. If you're destined to become enlightened, you have become
to become enlightened, you have become
to become enlightened, you have become enlightened.
enlightened.
enlightened. >> That's true.
>> That's true.
>> That's true. >> Whether you have children, whether you
>> Whether you have children, whether you
>> Whether you have children, whether you don't have children, whether your
don't have children, whether your
don't have children, whether your whether family's involved or they're not
whether family's involved or they're not
whether family's involved or they're not involved,
involved,
involved, >> it's we're each on our own path and it's
>> it's we're each on our own path and it's
>> it's we're each on our own path and it's up to us to follow it. I mean, a lot of
up to us to follow it. I mean, a lot of
up to us to follow it. I mean, a lot of people at this time, you know, they want
people at this time, you know, they want
people at this time, you know, they want to become enlightened and they want to
to become enlightened and they want to
to become enlightened and they want to do it now. Well, sometimes enlightenment
do it now. Well, sometimes enlightenment
do it now. Well, sometimes enlightenment doesn't hit until
doesn't hit until
doesn't hit until >> couple of couple of lifetimes later,
>> couple of couple of lifetimes later,
>> couple of couple of lifetimes later, >> right? Or if you're lucky, it does. But
>> right? Or if you're lucky, it does. But
>> right? Or if you're lucky, it does. But I mean, you do have that
I mean, you do have that
I mean, you do have that >> sometimes in your later years, you see
>> sometimes in your later years, you see
>> sometimes in your later years, you see things more clearly than you do when
things more clearly than you do when
things more clearly than you do when you're in the midst of raising your
you're in the midst of raising your
you're in the midst of raising your children and everything.
children and everything.
children and everything. >> Yes, of course. Because you're not
>> Yes, of course. Because you're not
>> Yes, of course. Because you're not distracted,
distracted,
distracted, >> right? and you don't have the same uh
>> right? and you don't have the same uh
>> right? and you don't have the same uh hormones and uh
hormones and uh
hormones and uh energy problems that you do.
energy problems that you do.
energy problems that you do. >> Yeah,
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, >> it's uh easy to give up sex at 80. It's
>> it's uh easy to give up sex at 80. It's
>> it's uh easy to give up sex at 80. It's difficult at 18.
So you would say that family does not
So you would say that family does not interfere with becoming enlightenment.
interfere with becoming enlightenment.
interfere with becoming enlightenment. >> No, I don't think so.
>> No, I don't think so.
>> No, I don't think so. >> Enlightened.
>> Enlightened.
>> Enlightened. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> All right.
>> All right.
>> All right. And as far as it goes as um we have to
And as far as it goes as um we have to
And as far as it goes as um we have to accept them for their good and their bad
accept them for their good and their bad
accept them for their good and their bad and but don't hold any resentments
and but don't hold any resentments
and but don't hold any resentments towards them. I would say everybody is
towards them. I would say everybody is
towards them. I would say everybody is in a in a certain
in a in a certain
in a in a certain point of evolution
point of evolution
point of evolution >> both personal and cultural
>> both personal and cultural
>> both personal and cultural and historical. Uhhuh.
and historical. Uhhuh.
and historical. Uhhuh. >> Okay. All of us are at a certain point
>> Okay. All of us are at a certain point
>> Okay. All of us are at a certain point of evolution historically and culturally
of evolution historically and culturally
of evolution historically and culturally and uh religiously
and uh religiously
and uh religiously and then personally
and then personally
and then personally and then then it goes to the family and
and then then it goes to the family and
and then then it goes to the family and the kind of the family and then where
the kind of the family and then where
the kind of the family and then where you stood in the family whether the
you stood in the family whether the
you stood in the family whether the youngest or the not.
youngest or the not.
youngest or the not. >> So it's e easier for an older child to
>> So it's e easier for an older child to
>> So it's e easier for an older child to behave in a certain way than a younger
behave in a certain way than a younger
behave in a certain way than a younger child. sort of
child. sort of
child. sort of I used to tell my little sister to sit
I used to tell my little sister to sit
I used to tell my little sister to sit down in the bus and she would insist on
down in the bus and she would insist on
down in the bus and she would insist on running up and down the aisle
and I would insist that she stop running
and I would insist that she stop running up and down the aisle and she wouldn't.
up and down the aisle and she wouldn't.
up and down the aisle and she wouldn't. So I was so embarrassed by her behavior
So I was so embarrassed by her behavior
So I was so embarrassed by her behavior I pretended I didn't know her. So I go
I pretended I didn't know her. So I go
I pretended I didn't know her. So I go sit in another sit in another seat and
sit in another sit in another seat and
sit in another sit in another seat and ignore her like it wasn't I I don't know
ignore her like it wasn't I I don't know
ignore her like it wasn't I I don't know who that is. I pay no attention to her.
who that is. I pay no attention to her.
who that is. I pay no attention to her. I was so ashamed of my little sister's
I was so ashamed of my little sister's
I was so ashamed of my little sister's misbehavior.
misbehavior.
misbehavior. >> Well, that's funny.
>> Well, that's funny.
>> Well, that's funny. >> I I pretended she wasn't my sister.
>> I I pretended she wasn't my sister.
>> I I pretended she wasn't my sister. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> I don't know who I don't know who she
>> I don't know who I don't know who she
>> I don't know who I don't know who she is.
>> Well, didn't she say that she used to go
>> Well, didn't she say that she used to go to your grandparents house or something?
to your grandparents house or something?
to your grandparents house or something? There was It was near a church and she'd
There was It was near a church and she'd
There was It was near a church and she'd go to all the funerals. She'd walk down
go to all the funerals. She'd walk down
go to all the funerals. She'd walk down and
and
and >> Oh, my little sister. Yeah. She loved
>> Oh, my little sister. Yeah. She loved
>> Oh, my little sister. Yeah. She loved funerals. And uh and my grandparents
funerals. And uh and my grandparents
funerals. And uh and my grandparents lived right caddy corner from a church.
lived right caddy corner from a church.
lived right caddy corner from a church. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> So there were a lot of funerals, you
>> So there were a lot of funerals, you
>> So there were a lot of funerals, you know, at least one a week and it would
know, at least one a week and it would
know, at least one a week and it would play play. Anyway, all of a sudden my
play play. Anyway, all of a sudden my
play play. Anyway, all of a sudden my little sister would be missing, you
little sister would be missing, you
little sister would be missing, you know, and every time my little sister
know, and every time my little sister
know, and every time my little sister would be missing, I'd go look at the
would be missing, I'd go look at the
would be missing, I'd go look at the front and I'd say, "Uhoh, I bet I bet
front and I'd say, "Uhoh, I bet I bet
front and I'd say, "Uhoh, I bet I bet there's a funeral." Sure enough, my
there's a funeral." Sure enough, my
there's a funeral." Sure enough, my little sister would go caddy corner, be
little sister would go caddy corner, be
little sister would go caddy corner, be part of the crowd and the you know the
part of the crowd and the you know the
part of the crowd and the you know the they're putting people in the various
they're putting people in the various
they're putting people in the various limos to go to the cemetery and my my
limos to go to the cemetery and my my
limos to go to the cemetery and my my little sister would be sitting there on
little sister would be sitting there on
little sister would be sitting there on the on the chair like she was part of
the on the chair like she was part of
the on the chair like she was part of the family. She just loved going to
the family. She just loved going to
the family. She just loved going to funerals.
funerals.
funerals. >> Nobody knew that that'd be dangerous
>> Nobody knew that that'd be dangerous
>> Nobody knew that that'd be dangerous nowadays, but that was funny.
nowadays, but that was funny.
nowadays, but that was funny. >> She loved to go to a funeral.
I never heard of that. I thought that
I never heard of that. I thought that was so funny.
was so funny.
was so funny. >> She thought they were great fun. Of
>> She thought they were great fun. Of
>> She thought they were great fun. Of course,
course,
course, >> all of our families have little quirks.
>> all of our families have little quirks.
>> all of our families have little quirks. >> Yeah. Funny little things. You know what
>> Yeah. Funny little things. You know what
>> Yeah. Funny little things. You know what I mean?
I mean?
I mean? >> Yeah. So, we accept them.
>> Yeah. So, we accept them.
>> Yeah. So, we accept them. >> Yeah. And we try and work around them.
>> Yeah. And we try and work around them.
>> Yeah. And we try and work around them. Yeah. And as a human being
Yeah. And as a human being
Yeah. And as a human being >> and uh we try to forgive them for
>> and uh we try to forgive them for
>> and uh we try to forgive them for what they uh
what they uh
what they uh for problems or
for problems or
for problems or >> we aim for the ideal.
>> we aim for the ideal.
>> we aim for the ideal. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> We aim for the ideal,
>> We aim for the ideal,
>> We aim for the ideal, >> right?
>> right?
>> right? the great great Christian values.
the great great Christian values.
the great great Christian values. >> Forgiveness,
>> Forgiveness,
>> Forgiveness, kindness, love,
kindness, love,
kindness, love, forgiveness, kindness, love, acceptance,
forgiveness, kindness, love, acceptance,
forgiveness, kindness, love, acceptance, and then to serve by example
and then to serve by example
and then to serve by example and to serve others
and to serve others
and to serve others expecting nothing in return.
expecting nothing in return.
expecting nothing in return. And uh to be of service to others is a
And uh to be of service to others is a
And uh to be of service to others is a way of serving God.
way of serving God.
way of serving God. to God and our fellow man.
to God and our fellow man.
to God and our fellow man. >> Well, thank you honey. That was good.
>> Well, thank you honey. That was good.
>> Well, thank you honey. That was good. >> Thank you for asking me such interesting
>> Thank you for asking me such interesting
>> Thank you for asking me such interesting questions.
>> These are questions that are submitted
>> These are questions that are submitted by the
by the
by the >> a lot of some of these are people that
>> a lot of some of these are people that
>> a lot of some of these are people that are are questions that are submitted by
are are questions that are submitted by
are are questions that are submitted by students. Yes,
students. Yes,
students. Yes, >> that's what makes them even more
>> that's what makes them even more
>> that's what makes them even more valuable.
valuable.
valuable. >> They they would like some answers to
>> They they would like some answers to
>> They they would like some answers to Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. >> That makes them even more valuable to
>> That makes them even more valuable to
>> That makes them even more valuable to me.