Today we're going to speak on what is meant by spiritual.
Oh my, that's a tough one.
I know.
Religious is easy.
Religion is easy, but what is meant by spiritual?
Spiritual is the essence of religion.
Right.
Spiritual means the realization that one's reality is beyond the physical,
that it involves other realms.
These other realms have different qualities, non-physicality, non-locality.
To feel the presence of God is so overwhelming, but there's no way of explaining it.
If a person has ever had the experience of the presence of divinity,
it's very hard to explain to them.
But you can attempt.
There's a great feeling of beatitude and beauty,
and you're aware that there is an infinite presence.
The infinite presence becomes overwhelming and dominates all that exists.
And then as one's talking, one realizes that that same spirit is what is speaking through you.
What is speaking through me right now is of divine origin,
the spiritual energy of the ultimate reality.
And I think I'm starting to understand this,
and one way that you can promote our knowledge
is by getting the attention of the divine spirit into the inner world.
That's—
Right.
It's really about the inner world,
and the inner world is a struggle.
So, I would say that it's really a struggle,
and it's a challenge because it's an inner world.
It's a challenge.
But, as Dr. David said,
it's not a problem.
It's a challenge.
You cannot stop your desire
and you cannot stop living your life.
a certain level and incomprehensible to people who calibrate below that level.
There are people who are so anti-spiritual that they are not permeable to spiritual reality.
So there's other ways of communicating with such individuals, but it's not through direct
awareness.
You can do it via a judge and a cop.
Killing your neighbors is wrong and we will put you into jail.
Before we come into this lifetime of incarnate, do we choose the lessons that we have to learn
in this lifetime?
Well, we choose but not in the customary meaning of the term choose, like a this versus a that.
It's more like a climate, like we choose a certain climate, you know.
I choose a wife who is spiritually oriented and capable of comprehending and responding
to spiritual reality without being specific, you know, you didn't have to grow up in a
certain religion or live in a certain place, but we share certain overall major values.
So we may differ about anything.
Okay.
We may differ about individual clouds, but not about the nature of the sky itself.
All right.
I understand.
Okay.
I just wondered because the climate, you know, it's like choosing the climate.
Yes, I think that's exactly correct.
So we've established a climate for our own lives in which spiritual realities have the
top priority.
And they are interactive with our lives.
They are interactive with our daily actions and behaviors and beliefs and thoughts and
speech to varying degrees depending on the circumstances.
For instance, right now we're speaking about it directly because it's appropriate to speak
so directly, but on the way back home again, we will not speak about it so specifically
so directly, but it will still be a dominant presence, even though we're not on the subject,
so we may be talking about the dominant.
Okay.
We may be talking about the dog or the temperature of the thermostat, but it's in an overall
setting which is predominantly spiritual and devoted to infinite peace and the presence
of God as an unspoken awareness.
Here's one that half America does.
What?
How can a spiritual, how can I be spiritual when I struggle with my weight and overeating?
They're not opposite to each other.
Yeah, each of us has our own propensities coming from childhood training and I think
the dominance of certain sensory modalities over other people, the sense of taste is quite
acute and important in their life and the other people is like an appreciative but dutiful
husband.
Mm-hmm.
And I mean like, yeah, I serve whatever is needed.
I serve whatever is served for lunch, you know.
It could be French toast, it could be bacon, it could be a peanut butter sandwich.
And a lot of times when you say to me, you know, what do you want me to make, I'll say,
a peanut butter sandwich is fine.
In other words, I don't want you to go to any trouble, a specific trouble, because I
get sufficient pleasure out of anything you make and a peanut butter sandwich to me is
fantastic.
And other people would say, oh, a peanut butter sandwich, you know what I mean?
Mm-hmm.
It's like they want Swiss steak every day, I guess.
So that, all right, now spirit, as far as it goes, the spiritual student could still
be spiritual without concentrating on their weight loss.
Oh, they wouldn't have anything to do with each other.
You can contextualize the weight problem within spiritual parameters or not.
If you want to make it a spiritual problem, well then, it becomes a spiritual problem.
It becomes a spiritual problem.
I guess so.
Now, of course, in AA and alcoholism, this is a fact, so your drinking problem, at first,
it's just a physiologic addiction and chemical problem.
And then, as you try to get off of it, you find that you can't and you find that you
have become addicted and that now your behavior is not totally within your own control and
now you turn to a higher power.
Mm-hmm.
God, of myself, I am unable to stop drinking despite all my best intentions.
Mm-hmm. So then would you pray? That's how AA got born, you know. So would you pray to
God to see it differently or to... That's, that's what you do. You ask God for help.
I've tried to do it on my own. I've been unable. And you ask God for help. And, and
that's how the, it was that movement to begin, you know, because it was through
the despair, despair. Having tried everything, nothing worked. I have a, I
have a sign in my kitchen that says, inside every fat person is a skinny one,
but I can usually shut her up with cookies.
That is a very funny joke.
That is a very funny joke. That is a very funny joke.
That is a very funny sign. That is a very funny sign.
Yeah.
It is very comical. I like that.
So, you know, you, if you look at it as humorous, I think sometimes that gets you
through not opening that refrigerator door to get something out, so.
Well, you learn, like any behavior, you learn all kinds of tricks along the way, you
learn the things you do, the things that you can't do, what you can do, and the things
that you just have to.
Yeah, it's hard, it's hard.
Yeah, it's hard.
It's hard.
But remember, if you are hungry, you have to be full, so eating eating healthy, creating
a goal, and then you have to eat healthy, so you have to be eating healthy, so you gotta
eat healthy, so your food should be healthy.
I think that is, I think, I think that you get better at eating, you get more energetic
eating, to make sure you don't get that hungry.
Uh huh.
Things that'll satisfy you that, that have no calories, or very few calories, and drinking
a lot of Diet Root Beer, before you have a snack.
Uh huh.
Ha ha ha.
you have three or four things that you have to do as a spiritual person there's there's um
through there's spirituality through selfless service and what are the other ones i can't
remember now selfless service yeah yes that's one of them there's one that's selfless service
and prayer prayer and um prayer selfless service and um there's another one
there's the three whatever it is i can't surrender to a higher power okay i turn my life over to the
care of god as i understand them asking only for knowledge of his will for me and the power to
carry it out yeah so selfless service would be maybe the donation of one's time
to become more spiritual um it might be uh taking time out to pray pray pray or
meditate during the day yes it could be and then the third one would be um asking
um a higher being for guidance so those would be the three main and supporting spiritual
organizations yes by your presence by your actual contribution like money in the
collection
plate or something or service by service to the church okay i know somebody who paints church
bathrooms out of service i mean people say how holy is that well how holy can you get that's
about as holy as you can get painting a church bathroom is about as devotional as i i can think
of you know anybody can go up to communion rail and partake but that uh it's quite different to
devote yourself to
actual service to the church or cleaning the the a lot of them clean the uh garden or the
or the grounds yes whatever service you give to a church is done out of devotion to god
because it takes a lot of people to run an organization it does indeed yeah yeah um
would let me see there was um there was something i was going to ask you here um
when when people do that or when people do that they're not doing it for the church they're doing it
or they when people pray to god do they pray in a way that um what would you can you give us a
prayer to pray to god such as let's say that you're um dealing with your ego on something
that you think things should go this way and they're not so how do you pray to god and ask
the guidance well you you uh
after you're conscious of what is your goal and then to state that goal dear god i ask you to help
me to see this differently okay it's when the one i use perhaps most often yes i've heard you say
that dear god i uh i pray to see this situation differently because you're seeing it in terms of
right and wrong good and bad good and evil and um so you're abstracting instead of saying the
totality generally i find that in in any situation most people are doing about it are doing the best
they're able if they're able to do more they would be they say i could have no that's a hypothetical
in reality you couldn't have because your adrenaline was running at a certain pace your
body temperature was such that there was other vehicles on the road you
couldn't turn off at the last second and some accidents are inevitable because people reflex
time is just you know within a certain matter of a fifth of a second or whatever by the time they
see what's ahead of them it's too late to put on the brake so i think most accidents happen
inadvertently okay so aside from alcohol and those obvious if you had to say one thing that would
bring you closer to a spiritual life what would you say that would be i think the awareness of the
presence of god in other words in my own life i'm aware of the presence of god at all times
that all things all thoughts all actions all decisions everything is done in the presence
of god and there's a conscious awareness of the presence of god
i asked god to help us like right now in the back of my mind i'm asking god please give us guidance
with this interview that we express the things that would be the most helpful and interesting
to the most people because we could come up with something that would be interesting for you and i
but have no general applicability so i ask god to direct our conversation in a manner that would be
most useful to the most people and be of actual service not theoretically but actually i like
words that can come to your mind when you need them just the word god itself i think is probably
the word i use most in prayer yeah a situation comes up and my mind will say dear god i'm calling
god at all times and in all places and becomes you might say dominant or interactive when called
upon to do so would you say that um the one block to becoming enlightened and more spiritual would
you say that's the ego that's generally what we mean by the ego the ego is self-centered egocentric
and uh is not interested in
Ultimate truth or what's good for others or the mankind
The ego is self-serving and and often so at the expense of others
So would you say that when someone holds on to a resentment? It's because they get juice
From knowing that they can hold on to it. Is that what they're getting juice because it kept captivates their
Attention and energy fuel that a given time
And some people thrive on it, you know, some people spend their lifetime
devoted to hatred hatred
There are whole religions who are devoted to nothing but the hatred of other religions
And then they call themselves a religion which always gives me a big
circle funny
Their religion is to hate other religions and to
Condemn people who have other beliefs to hell
I mean and then go yourself a religion what I have a problem with I have a problem with a religion that
Upholds taking another person's life. I just don't understand it. I
Just have a real block there. I don't see how any religion
I don't care what it is how any religion if they really are truly
Believing in God, how can it be oriented that it's okay to take another person's life
well the mind can rationalize
anything
and
You know, there are many religions that are totally anti-religious in the name of religion
You know to hate and kill anybody who belongs to any other religion and do this in the name of God is one of the great
paradoxes of our current
world society
The way we please God is by killing people who don't believe the way we believe
It's so naive you know what even the fifth grader would be?
able to get that daddy, how could you love somebody if you kill them? I mean a fifth grader gets that but there are whole
countries and societies that believe that way I
Mean what five you said to a five-year-old?
The way to love your bunny is to kill it. I mean
So if you call people bunnies instead of kid people
If you picture people as bunnies, then you find they're much easier to love and forgive
Realize that we're all human bunnies
You're my honey bunny. Give me a kiss, baby. Give me a kiss. Give me give me a kiss, baby
You are my honey bunny. Yes, okay
All right, I was just you know, I just it's a paradox it's what it is. It's paradoxical. Yes paradox. That's right
because I just I mean I still can't
understand that that
maybe I'm oh, it's a major enterprise of humanity over the
So kill people who don't believe in God the way you do. So let's say you have this ego and the ego says
That's religious ego. Right? Let's say you have this religious ego and it says I
Am
According to our chart I am in the 500 and you're in the 300s
You know that right there statement is an ego
Well, it could be an accurate
clinical diagnosis
well yeah it isn't the fact it's how you feel about it okay uh so a person in 300 might be
more proud of their level of consciousness than a person in 500 who no longer has given up who
has given up pride right for gratitude but we have we get emails from people every day yeah
of people who say i'm in the 600s oh you know i'm in you know whatever um can you verify this
it's um yeah that's a spiritual what they call spiritual ego yes and uh they use calibration
system that gives them a falsely high uh rating you know 600 uh it's way beyond enlightenment it's
almost divinity you know
okay
and saints don't take out time to write us letters describing how holy they are
this is true but i'm just saying i think that sometimes the ego jumps in there and it sure does
you know uh and when we're discussing today about what is meant by spiritual they should
have this spiritual awareness that by um stating this that they're actually uh not paying attention
to the spiritual side i mean to think that you better than anyone right there is the ego to rate
yourself according to your calibrated level of consciousness but i mean don't you think the ego
steps in there and jumps in and goes oh yeah i'm better yeah no that's the the downside of
calibrating levels of consciousness uh is the idea that a higher number makes you better than other
people it doesn't necessarily no uh if you calibrate it to a higher level of consciousness
at 400 instead of feeling egotistical that you're better than people at 300 you could turn it around
and say it makes you feel depressed that you're not in the 500s you know what i'm saying it's like
being a millionaire is doing it wonderful to poor people i think it's fantastic to people who is a
multi-millionaire that could be worth a million doesn't mean anything the people i grew up with
a certain part of new york city everybody was everybody was a multi-millionaire
everybody's parents were multi-millionaire everybody lived on big estates everybody had
servants it was a so what yeah so what else is new you know it was just common all my friends
were millionaires it didn't mean anything at all um when one is spiritual um do they become more
intuitive the more spiritual you get or i think so yes i think they become more intuitive
to
the non-verbal and the non-discrete the non-defined or are they just more in tune with
that they're more in tune with the field okay yeah they're more in tune with the field so if you're
spiritually aware you know somebody walks into the room you've already picked up a great deal of who
they are and where they're at without anything having been spoken i've already picked up their
energy and you know whether they're up to good or no good or whether they're up to good or no good
good or no good or whether you have to lock the house when you're gone
um what do they have um the 10 commandments um you know thou shall not kill um do not take up
false gods you know uh there's several different ones i can't think of yeah i know i know really
there's 10 or is there 12 commandments there's 10 well the 10 that are in the bible
but um what i'm saying is the 10 commandments um if you live your life but in your spiritual um
life by the 10 commandments yes i isn't that good enough that i mean good enough for what
it would be generally considered in the religious community as sufficient that you've lived by all
god's commandments and you know someday you have to face god and
what can you say you can say i tried to live by all your commandments as i understood them oh lord
and if i was mistaken i asked for forgiveness and if you really screw up you got to go back
and get reborn and redo the whole deal go back to sunday school learning right from wrong
well let's see a lot of people don't value integrity or spiritual integrity it's not a value
if you watch television
you'll see that you know other values are popularity or money or power over others political
power getting votes many things have served have um replaced uh spiritual values
um is there a conflict from being spiritual and being in and making a good living is there a
you know is there any kind of conflict between the two
no
is there any kind of conflict between the two
yeah it's a big and a lot of times it's assumed by naive people that to be spiritual you really
should be poor well and that the rich people have no chance of getting into heaven what is it this
thing a rich person has the biggest chance of getting into heaven as a what is it something the
eye of a needle yeah yeah some do the eye of a needle yeah they don't mean literally so they
mean that the ego of such a person generally
point, that doesn't mean it's impossible, but generally, probably, nine out of ten,
who have become so worldly as to become, you know, super rich and super famous, that their
value, their values would preclude, preclude their spiritual advancement.
Well, we all know that certain spiritual teachers fall into certain, there's certain categories
such as, you know, worship, you know, they want to be worshipped, you know, they want
wealth, they, there's certain...
Oh, they're professional gurus, yeah.
There's certain downfalls of these gurus that will take you down a wrong path.
Ego and money.
Right, and, you know, I'm sure that there's chinks in the armor that everybody's looking
for, you know.
Yes.
There's always going to be something that someone can say.
There's always going to be something that someone can say about any spiritual life.
They do about us.
They do?
Well, there's all kinds of...
Yeah, show me.
There's all kinds of people out there that doubt, so...
Doubt, oh, doubt.
Yeah, and...
Well, they doubt spiritual reality.
Isn't it that you and I, they doubt spiritual reality, or diminish its value, devalue it,
but that's a personal option on their part, and of course, whether you value it or not,
it's important to know that that will likely change over time.
There was a time in my life when I was extremely religious.
Then there was a time in my life when I became a devout atheist.
You know what I mean?
I was devoutly atheistic as I once was devoutly religious.
In both cases, I was worshiping truth, because I thought atheism was truth.
So, to me, truth became the high priority, not the divinity of our creator.
And I grew up with some other adolescents who all scoffed at religion, all scoffed at religion.
They were all atheists, and I was very religious.
So, they would give me a hard time all the time, all the time about it, you know.
So, I learned that...
It was to keep one's religious, personal religious views to one's self,
and maybe share them only with others who have an equal viewpoint.
So, in other words, it's best not to say too much until you figure out what the climate is.
Yes, that's correct.
So, my religiosity would maybe look like a fool to my atheistic friends,
who are just into intellectualism.
And it was funny.
There's many paradoxes, you know.
Do human beings have a personal will, or are we only witnessing the divine will?
We all have a personal will, and that's part of divine will.
Part of divine will is that each one of us has the freedom of a personal will,
by which our own will is free.
By which our own will is free.
By which our own karma is decided, that we are all given freedom of choice.
So, we are all given sort of a great latitude to become that which we intend for ourself,
some of which we can be responsible for, some we can't.
Some we were conditioned before we had a choice, before we remember a choice in this lifetime.
But some...
Some of us, you know, are really living out choices made in prior lifetimes.
You teach that beauty is a shortcut to God.
That what is?
Beauty is a shortcut to God.
From, you know, from music to opera to...
All beauty, all aesthetic.
And it shows appreciation.
You might say beauty is an expression of divinity in a different dimension, you know, than the intellectual.
And then at a certain point of life, you see the beauty of everything that exists.
You see the beauty of all that exists.
Everything that exists is divinity.
You might say that divinity is the requirement for existence.
And then from an absolutist viewpoint,
nothing exists except divinity.
The capacity to exist is already an expression of divinity.
In reality, nothing exists except divinity.
Disguised as an old shoe or a beautiful lily, but still the same.
Aesthetically, we might say one is different than the other,
but existentially, they're both the same.
An old shoe or a lily share the fact that divinity exists.
Someone has asked you to say something about A.A. and Bill Wilson,
since you have a vantage point, you know, of producing his...
what he believed in.
Actually, we've discussed Bill Wilson many times.
Have we?
Yeah.
Okay.
So, would you say that...
I mean, he had...
You saw through him...
very...
very similar experiences of people who...
I mean, we have people that have seen you one time and have gotten sober.
That's true.
Due to the energy, and so, I mean, we have several people that have done that.
Yes.
So, would you say that if they were to go to find some religious person or place, that
that would...
that would help these people that do have a problem with addiction?
Well, addiction is just one of many problems.
Okay.
Consulting a person...
people of advanced spiritual development can be of assistance to anything, including
addictions.
Sometimes, merely one visit with a very powerful spiritual teacher is all that's required,
because you're right on the verge of it, and that addition of the energy of the teacher
is all that's required.
So, I mean, that's...
Yeah.
And then, that mate, the person or the teacher transmits, transmits automatically
to the listener.
The value of hearing of an advanced teacher is that you automatically pick up the energies,
and they become now available to you.
So, once you've been in the presence of a great teacher, that teachers' level of consciousness
is not available to you as an option.
It's an option.
not a necessity, nor would a great teacher want it to be anything other
than an option. To see the beauty of all that exists is obvious to a person who
sees the beauty of all exists. It is not so obvious to a person who sees a dead
rabbit on the road. I agree with him. So when you say that beauty is a shortcut
to God, you're saying that if you can embrace that beauty and understand it
and take it upon you, that you'll feel the presence of God in that particular
moment. One doesn't define it mentally that way. You know, you can be in a state
of beatitude and the word God never goes through your mind. Or one
can be constantly
aware of the presence of God and not go into what the world calls an advanced
state. My present state, for instance, I'm aware of the presence of God constantly.
It's a constant presence without verbalizing it mentally. All that I do,
all that I am, all the decisions that I make, everywhere I may go, whatever I may
do, is
resolved then in the presence of God. In the back of my mind, I talk to God all the
time.
So can you go about your daily tasks and still, you know, be spiritual because you
have God? It's sort of like a split personality. You're doing the dishes and you're doing
the vacuuming and you're doing the dustings, but in the back of your mind, God's always
present.
Well, it's not split. It's more that the awareness of the presence of God envelops
everything inclusively.
Ok.
Within the inclusiveness, are the daily duties of washing the floor, and running
a vacuum cleaner, and talking to friends on the phone.
Ok.
There's also the awareness suddenly that goes on at all times, that one is answerable
to God for one's state of being.
Ok.
allow yourself to be disrupted and angry, etc. If it happens, you apologize to God and
I say, I pray for forgiveness for my humanness and for the predominance of emotionality.
So we can't be in a beatific state at all times and in all places under all circumstances
unless one is in an extremely advanced level in which nothing that happens matters to you
all that much one way or the other, because it lacks an intrinsic reality. It's a phenomena,
but not all phenomena are really a reality. On the other hand, in another level of consciousness,
all phenomena are the expression of reality. Our sitting here and talking to each other this moment
is a phenomena that occurs within the province of divinity, the versatility of divinity to express
itself in multiple ways. One way is you and I sitting here talking about divinity. You and I
sitting here talking about divinity. You and I sitting here talking about divinity.
Mm-hmm.
How many Americans are sitting at breakfast time this morning talking about divinity?
What percentage?
I don't know.
I don't know. Let's ask. Can we ask the arm?
Come on. We can ask the arm. People talking about divinity at breakfast time is more than 10%,
more than 5%, 6%. Maybe 5% of people do talk about divinity.
But that's just like you said that, you know, you can't talk about divinity.
But you can walk down the street and you ask how many people what their goal is and maybe one in a million or more would say my goal is enlightenment.
To become enlightened would be rare, yeah.
Yeah, very uncommon to have that.
Well, it's supposedly, for one thing, too difficult. The ego is so pervasive and dominant and tenacious that the average person has little chance of achieving its goal.
Mm-hmm.
chance of transcending it unless they go off to a seminary and very special circumstances,
disconnect the phone, don't go to the mailbox, don't deal with money, and don't deal with
the banks, forget the stock market, forget the world.
I say you can do both.
You can live in the world and simultaneously be extremely spiritually dedicated.
Well, I think everyone sets it up like, they set it up that if they are a very wealthy
person, they're not spiritual.
Yeah, that's an artificial separation.
Right.
But they, a lot of people believe that, that if there's a, if they're a wealthy person,
they're not spiritual.
And so, I think that a lot of people look-
Well, it's like saying that if they're poor, they more likely would be.
Yeah.
So, a lot of people look at it that way.
A lot of people look then if, you know, you know and I know that you have to be firm with
people sometimes.
So, when you're firm with them, then they say, oh, they're just that way because they
think they can boss anybody around.
You know, it's like the defensive, I've heard it over and over again, people, not about
me, but other people.
Yeah.
I've said that about other people.
So, I'm just saying that, you know, there is a, in the spiritual community, there seems
to be some kind of, you know, if you are well fixed, you can't be spiritual.
Yeah.
There are, there are, many people believe that way, that if you're rich, you can't really
be religious or truly spiritual, and vice versa, that if you were truly spiritual and
truly religious, you wouldn't be poor, because you get off your lazy butt and go and get a
job.
Yeah, that's true.
It's a, you know, it's, it's just, you know, it's an oxymoron, you know, it's like.
Oxymoron, yeah.
Yeah.
How can you be truthful without becoming, without coming across as unkind?
I think it's a matter of a delicacy of expression, consideration for the feelings of others.
Consideration for other people's feelings.
That's the whole idea, really, behind politeness, is to be considerate.
You know, the person doesn't notice they drop something on the rug, and you say to them,
oh, you dropped so-and-so on the rug.
The person wasn't aware of that at the time, so you try to express it in a way that's non-moralistic
or condemnatory.
Yeah.
Because we can be responsible for things that are, that, that have no morality associated
with them.
Mm-hmm.
You know, you can accidentally step on the dog's paw.
You didn't mean to do that.
Yeah.
It doesn't mean you're bad.
All right.
What is the difference between being spiritual and being religious?
Spiritual is more abstract and of a higher dimension than religiosity.
Okay.
Spiritual is of a higher definition.
Religiosity has a very specific meaning.
Spirituality means the value of things that are non-physical and non-necessarily logical
or within the realm of reason, things of a greater value, of a greater dimension.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
You know, the value of human life.
So let's say that-
That's why I don't believe in capital punishment, because there's no way you can excuse it.
You can rationalize it and hope that it will tend to diminish crime.
I don't think it does, but there's no way you can make it abstract.
It's a very concrete, discreet act.
Mm-hmm.
So as far as it goes, as our spiritual being, we would say that to increase one's spiritual
... to increase one's own spiritual beliefs, we would have to be also religious and ...
No, you don't have to be religious.
Okay.
But if you are spiritual, you see the value of our religions.
Mm-hmm.
Because you see that the essence of that religion is really its spirituality ...
... to a higher dimension.
So if you do something, even though it's sort of stupid in a way, but you do it because
your religion requires it, you're doing it out of your reverence for God and the idea
that, you know, it is of service to mankind to be more spiritually inclined and less physical.
Mm-hmm.
Less moralistic.
So if you could say how all of us could become more spiritual, what would you give us as
advice?
I could tell people, first of all, read what is generally called the world's great
spiritual literature, the great classics that have withstood the ... that have gone on for
centuries, the great spiritual classics of all time, because you'll get something out
of reading every single one of them.
Mm-hmm.
It's impossible to read the great spiritual classics of all time without being affected
by what one has just read.
Everyone gets totally affected by it.
Become acquainted with the great spiritual classics.
Mm-hmm.
And that will take you some ... on the path towards becoming more spiritual?
Well, the great spiritual classics will define for you things that you had not defined before.
Mm-hmm.
Point out things that you did not realize the importance of.
Okay.
Well, what would you classify as the great spiritual classics?
The great ... don't ask me that, please.
All right.
Okay.
I would have to think about it.
All right.
I mean, now you want me to go into the realm of thinking.
Right.
The great spiritual classics, the Bhagavad Gita.
The Holy Bible, the New Testament.
Okay.
The Course of Common.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
I was just curious because actually all of us want to become more spiritual.
Not necessarily more religious but more spiritual — — — because that seems to be the goal.
Yes.
That's a goal.
So, you know, all of our followers would like to, you know, become more spiritual.
Yes.
So we can do that through service.
We can do that through donations.
We can do that through reading, actions.
Everything speaks of helpfulness to others, kindness, consideration.
Every act of kindness is a prayer to me.
If I would step on a doggie's paw by accident, which I did,
on the edge of her paw, I apologized to her.
Even though she doesn't understand half the time, you apologized.
She understands love.
Don't get me wrong.
The dog understands love.
And if I step on her paw by accident, and I say,
Kelsey, oh, honey, I'm sorry, I put my arms around her,
the doggie understands that.
Let's ask her out on this side of the camera.
The doggie understands that.
Yep, the doggie understands that.
That that was a mistake.
Right.
I'm sorry.
So if we were to do that, say, to our enemies, the same,
I'm sorry that happened.
Well, we all regretted World War II, that what was necessary was necessary.
You know, I was a minesweeper.
And so you regretted any damage to anybody or any person.
You had to do it because the war was on,
and you didn't have a choice.
And if you refused an order, you'd be court-martialed.
So we had to do things that were, that I'm glad,
there were many things that many of them had to do,
which I was not required to do.
I was very grateful to God.
I said, dear God, I give thanks.
My life was devoted to keeping the crew alive
and getting us through typhoons
and keeping us from being capsized and stuff.
And I thanked many God.
I thanked God then as I thank him now.
But I was not called upon to kill someone else.
So I cannot say what my decision would have been.
You see that man over there?
I want you to shoot him.
You know, where would my allegiance have been
to God which forbid the killing of anybody under anything?
Only under certain circumstances?
Does that apply?
Does it always apply?
Does it never apply?
So I was always grateful that I never had to make that decision.
I was never commanded to kill anyone.
I was commanded to keep us alive.
I had no problem with that.
Keep us going through the great typhoons and all.
So my life was devoted to saving life and not taking it.
So I just consider that a gift that God gave me,
that I never had to pull the trigger
because I don't know what I would have done
if I sighted another human being within the gun sights.
Well, if he was classified as evil,
I guess I would have had to pull the trigger
because he was evil.
So I wasn't killing anything except evil.
Even the world had that trouble with Adolf Hitler.
They didn't know what to do with him.
Yeah.
Right?
So when we say...
What is meant by spiritual?
It is a way of being in the world.
Way of viewing the world.
Overall, contextualizing the world
and its significance and meaning
and the implications for your own individual life.
I consider our talking to each other right now
to be a great privilege.
And I thank God for it.
Thank you, dear Lord,
that we have been...
allowed to have this discourse
in the presence of the public
and to do so with the help of my wife, Susan,
who is very loving and helpful
with all of our spiritual work
and all of its expressions,
as well as our other friends, close friends,
who played such an important part in our lives,
for whom I am very grateful.
Thank you, honey.
Thank you, honey, for thanking me, honey.
Thank you.
You're a great wife, Susan.
And I love you to pieces.
You're adorable.
Okay, is that about good enough?
Was that about an hour?
It was.
Oh, good.
Yay!
Was it?
When we do these 10 Ghosts so fast,
I think 20 minutes has gone by.