Today we're going to be talking about what you are changes the world. So what
does that mean what you are changes the world? Because we all radiate a certain
energy from our own level of consciousness. So the higher your level of
consciousness the more profound effect you have on the world. So a town
goes along a certain way and one person enters this town who's never
been there before of a very high level of consciousness and they find with
research that the crime rate in that town actually goes down. The actual crime
rate goes down because of the presence of that one person. Now let's just test
the arm and ask is that a fact? That is a fact. Resist. Okay so many a town is
merely blessed by the fact that you you know
moved into the neighborhood. Of course the reverse is probably true. One bum does
not wreck a wreck a whole city you know but one that very advanced saintly saint
saintly person does reduce the crime rate and scientific research is
documented that that is actually a fact.
Well you talk about the broken window theory where you know that one building
in a town has a broken window and all of a sudden that whole neighborhood goes
down. Yes. Due to the fact that that broken window theory. It's called
detriment so the neighborhood goes down because of the one broken window. So it's
obvious that if we had one saintly person in the area that the whole
Area would go up for the same reasons
I don't know if that's been proven or not. I know the down downward has been proven
Well, let's ask the arm upward is equally
Demonstrable. Oh, okay
so the best thing that can happen to a community is that a person with a high level of consciousness moves into town and
Then the crime rate goes down. Actually the crime rate goes down. Wow. Okay
do you remember when you first came to town and you said that you were teaching the course of miracles when you first came to
Sedona and that the course of miracles
almost a certain percentage of the population was doing the course of miracles because you had huge groups here when it first came to
town and
They had there was zero crime rate in Sedona at that time. Yes, Sedona had a zero crime rate. Yeah, and
Just the
course
of
Miracles people themselves
Were sufficient to eliminate all crime
There was no crime in Sedona at all zero
So this goes back to what you are changes the world
So that's true when you say it can one person have the effect on the entire world
Let's say Jesus Christ did yeah, okay
I mean
Everybody wants to feel like they you know
This is the old ego speaking. Everybody wants to feel like we because of me the world is changing. So what about that?
I mean
I don't think people who change the world sedum self because to me the world is changing
Well certain people I know would
They have a very high ego. Yeah, but I mean I mean in reality who really are advanced
Probably would never even think of the question
it wouldn't come to their mind
because it's just their normal way of life.
But that's correct.
Statistics show that the crime rate dropped to zero
in Sedona when the Courts of Miracles people
started to teach here.
Crime rate dropped to zero.
The crime rate is still zero.
No, the crime rate has gone up since then?
The crime rate has gone up since then.
Oh, because lots of people who don't calibrate high
moved into town.
Oh, I see.
Okay.
That makes sense.
Okay, you say that divinity is the essence.
All right, let me see what this is.
Divinity is the essence out of which my existence.
You told me that.
One time.
Divinity is the...
Source of my existence.
Yes.
Right.
It is out of the Godhead that all arises.
It is out of the Godhead that all existence arises.
That is a fact.
There you go.
Okay.
So if we held that phrase in mind in our daily lives,
would that help us to achieve
what you want to achieve?
The fact that each and every one of us is valuable
is important.
The realization that you are of value to the community
automatically changes your behavior.
So just to have certain people move into town
was the most beneficial thing that happened to that town.
It's that people of a high calibrated level
have moved into town.
And when they did,
the crime rate dropped to practically zero.
It dropped to zero.
But if we were to make that statement,
divinity is the essence of my existence,
if we were to meditate on that,
would that eventually become who we were or who we are?
Well, it is who you are.
It's just that you don't realize it,
that divinity is the source of your existence.
Without God, none of us would be here.
I know.
There's no discussion today.
You know, it's very difficult for me to think that,
to, I mean, because you,
this would be a good phrase for me to hold in mind
to live my life like that.
In other words, divinity is the existence,
I mean, divinity is the essence of my existence.
I mean, if we say that to ourselves like every morning,
don't you think that,
don't you think that would help us to live our life like?
Like a prayer, yeah.
Like a prayer?
Mm-hmm.
And that we would change the world because of doing that?
Yeah, that would be a fact.
Okay.
Yes.
You could scientifically prove it.
That can be scientifically proven.
Okay.
All right.
I just wanted to clarify that
because I thought that was such a good phrase
and I think that if you did kind of hold that in mind
each morning before you got out of bed,
that it would help you to live your life like that
as a person to where eventually it became a secondary.
It becomes a fact.
It becomes a fact, yeah.
It just becomes a part of who you are.
In the beginning, it's a supposition based on faith
and then it becomes progressively a reality
and then one day you understand the reality behind it all.
Mm-hmm.
All right.
So who I am in spirit would be how we change the world?
Is that what you're saying when you say what you are changes the world?
Is that who you are in spirit, is that what changes the world?
It's the power of the energy that radiates from a divine being,
a more advanced being.
It goes up exponentially so that,
the more we purify ourself and try to be beneficial to the world,
the more we actually become so.
Okay.
The more intention to be of service to the world
and to reduce pain and suffering
and in and of itself, that intention already changes the world.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
So when you talk about the ships floating on the sea
and by...
You don't want to raise...
The ships, you've said that in other lectures.
You don't want to try and raise the ship
because by ourself, if we try and raise the ship, it's impossible.
Yes.
But if we raise the level of the water in which the ship is floating...
There you go.
...that that changes the whole concept.
That's very profound.
Okay.
So that which we become begins to raise the level of the sea
and the sea then lifts the ships
so we all benefit by the saintly person.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
And the more saintly we can become,
the greater service we are to our fellow human being.
Mm-hmm.
So actually, we don't have to be out there in the forefront.
No, we don't have to be beating the drum, ringing the bell.
Just be the most perfect person you can become.
In the name of thee, O Lord,
I pray that my presence is of service to this world.
Amen.
Mm-hmm.
We serve God and our fellow man by becoming all that we can become.
Sometimes, I mean, I've done this myself where I've gone in,
and like you always say, go into a store, smile at the clerk and say,
I want you to have a really good day.
Or, you know, boy, you look really happy today or whatever.
And it makes them just bright.
You know, you made their day by saying it.
Yeah, it's just one remark changes a person's whole day.
That's why I believe in being complimentary to acknowledge people's gift to the world.
You know, I mean, this carpet right here is vacuumed to perfection.
You know, there's no trash on the floor.
There's nothing, you know, I mean, everything is perfect.
So we acknowledge the gift that others have given us
through their preparation for this interview right now.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
We have a nice couch for us to sit on.
The temperature in here is just fine.
And so I am grateful for the way it was set up for our interview, you know.
So if we were to, how, I want to ask you a question.
How do you, like, radiate love to someone who is not loving?
Who is not lovable or loving?
Who is not loving.
How do you radiate love?
And embrace that person when they're not always a loving person?
Oh, well, they don't have to be loving all the time to be lovable.
Even the doggy piddles on the floor once in a while.
That's our fault because we don't let her out.
Yeah.
But we don't blame the dog.
We don't stop loving the dog.
We blame ourselves for our own shortcoming.
So if people are not polite,
appropriate in our, to us,
I always make the presumption that it's something in myself
that they're perhaps reacting to,
of which I am unaware.
That I perhaps have an aversion to some aspect of their life
or their lifestyle or their means of expression.
And so I say, well,
what am I contributing to this overall field of energy?
So whenever we come up against an obstacle,
we should also look within to see if we are creating that obstacle.
See what we could be contributing to it.
Right.
Mm-hmm.
Which, in other words, self-examination is the...
Well, it's the willingness to take responsibility for all that we can.
Right.
Well, people don't like to do that, you know.
Well, I didn't ask them if they liked it.
They don't like to pay taxes either.
But we ought to do it, right?
They'd put you in jail if you don't.
But it's true, you know.
There's so many people out there with negative attitudes and everything.
And I always want...
It's very difficult to be kind, loving, and gracious to people.
I mean, when they're really not very nice.
Oh, I don't think it's difficult.
Well, that's you.
I'm striving towards that, David.
I'm trying to get there.
I'm sort of.
I'm feeling sorry for them if they're not having a better day.
Yeah.
God bless everyone.
And, you know, I always start out with that attitude in the day.
Mm-hmm.
God bless everyone.
And God bless the doggie.
And God bless the canary.
And God bless all of God's creation.
Mm-hmm.
You know, you want to become the kind of a person that your mere presence is beneficial
to the world.
Mm-hmm.
What you have become then contributes and uplifts everyone.
Yes.
Okay.
So then that leads us a little bit into surrender.
All right.
So when you come up against a block, which I call someone who, you know, is rude or obnoxious,
so you have to surrender the fact that they may be having a bad day or you might have
said something that upset them.
They need help, yes.
Yeah.
Well, that's a nice way of putting it but...
Well, when people are mean and nasty and awful, you know, I figure they really need help,
you see.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
Yeah, they do.
And you can actually change them by sending them love.
That's what I wanted to know.
How do you change them?
Thinking of them lovingly.
You think of them lovingly and forgivingly and picture them at their very best.
And they hold that image of them.
And as you do that, you actually lift them.
Let's check the arm with this.
You actually do lift them.
Uh-huh.
You see?
You actually do lift them by seeing their positive values and their contribution to the world.
And I say to myself, well, I'm thankful that person is in the world.
And then it becomes a fact.
It becomes a fact.
Mm-hmm.
So the more loving we are, the more lovable people in society and the world become.
So to love the world, then, is a major contribution.
Love the world and everyone in it.
Well, we have a lot of people that say, I want to change the world or I want to change
this opinion.
Instead of looking at themselves to change, they want to change what's out there.
Well, that's the impact of the media.
Mm-hmm.
Of course, the media give a lot of people enormous power in the public.
So one little person expressing one little idea is now transmitted to millions of people
and actually is changing them.
Mm-hmm.
Actually is changing them.
We watch the news and how the news is handled.
He's already changing the news.
Mm-hmm.
So observing myself, does that change the world?
Observing yourself because you're becoming more self-aware makes you a more beneficial
contributor to the world and society.
When you're aware of your own shortcomings, then you tend to override them and compensate
for them.
Mm-hmm.
So instead of being a sourpuss, you try to put on a smiley face.
All right.
So is someone below 200 capable of inter-inventory?
I call it inter-inventory.
It's an inventory of my self.
So is someone below 200 capable of that?
I think in general, not really.
But with help, they can be taught how to be that way.
We have psychologists who interview prisoners, and many of them start out with absolutely
zero insight or motivation.
But by interaction with that psychologist, who is personally loving and caring, the person
becomes changed.
So without trying to change them, we change others by virtue of what we are and have become
and the way we are with them.
We are already changing them without trying to change them.
If you try to change people, they resist.
So that's force, you know, like power and force.
That's right.
So just be considerate and loving and considerate.
There are a lot of individuals, however, that even under the most terrific conditions are
unable to prove or show benefit.
And they seem to be of a very limited capability.
So in other words, we can't really force anyone to be different.
We just have to pray that they would someday realize their shortcomings?
We do all that we can on their behalf.
And we hold in mind their best interests.
And I picture the person as being what it is that I hold as an ideal.
I picture them as being more loving, more caring, more polite, more considerate.
And by doing that, I influence them to become that way.
Resist.
Oh, okay.
All right.
So merely picturing a person as more loving, more capable, more polite, more efficient,
more intelligent, whatever you want, already influences them because you're not trying
to influence them.
So there's nothing for them to resist.
If you're trying to train them to become a different way, they now will resist that.
So I don't tell them what I'm doing.
I just hold in mind that this person is very lovable, capable of love, and polite, and
seems to be able to handle things.
And by holding that in mind, it actually becomes a fact.
Well, I know that you did that when you were in practice.
You would hold in mind that your patience got better.
Oh, yes.
And you can put that into different aspects of your life, and you're changing the world.
Yes.
I did that as a psychiatrist.
I held in mind a picture of the person and how I felt they were capable of becoming friendly
instead of sour, and mild in manner instead of threatening, etc.
And they became that way.
They became that way.
And they themselves discovered that they were being influenced in that way.
I remember a couple of patients said they had a picture of me and they put it on the
wall.
And when they got into a bad mood or angry or paranoid or whatever, they would go over
and look at my picture.
And right away, they would feel better.
That made me happy that just one image could be beneficial.
It made people more grateful to be alive and appreciated.
Well, I tended to love all my patients.
I didn't tell them that, of course.
But I tended to love them all.
And that played a big part in their getting better.
Resist.
Yeah.
So the reason I had a high recovery rate is because I loved them all.
I wouldn't dare tell them that.
Of course not.
But I used to pray for them and send them love and best wishes.
And picture their best interests, hold their best interests in mind.
And then that would come to pass.
That would come to pass.
So we do the same thing in our personal lives without being necessarily a professional doing
it, some kind of a professional level.
Just on a personal level.
We picture the people we love in the highest level that we can picture them.
Happy and content and satisfied.
Doing well in school and whatever it is.
Getting promotions at work.
So if you were, let's say in our daily work lives, you know, we try and do the very best
we possibly can at the job that we are doing.
So we try and do the very best.
I have found that if you do that and you put in just a little extra effort, that it's usually
recognized.
Yes.
Even a little bit of effort.
People say, well, that couldn't make any difference that you said thank you.
It does.
So when you thank the clerk, thank you for taking care of me at the cash register or
whatever.
When you say thank you, you've changed their day.
You've changed their life.
So every thank you is a blessing in disguise.
Every thank you is a blessing in disguise.
So we make our life thankful to all the people around us who make our life possible.
If it wasn't for the people in the room right now, we wouldn't be able to be speaking and
interviewing and recording this.
So I'm grateful to all the people that are in the room right now without whom we would
not be able to be having this interview.
Thank you.
Dum ta dum dum.
Our bird says that now.
And I always look for Dave in the room when she's saying it.
Dum ta dum dum.
It's cute.
So now that we have taken an inventory of ourselves, how do we correct things when,
you know, it's like a knee-jerk reaction when something happens.
So how do we not respond?
How do we not respond in that knee-jerk reaction since, you know, to lose our temper or do
we pray to see things differently?
Do we, how do you train yourself not to do that?
I think we do all those things.
We train ourselves to see differently.
We ask, we pray to God and ask for help to bring about a change.
Okay.
Accept and surrender to the things we cannot change and encourage to change the things
we can.
Right.
It's part of the 12-step movement, yes.
Pray for knowledge of your will for us and the power to change what we can.
So by changing one's shortcomings in ourselves, that's what really changes the world.
That's what changes the world.
Every little gesture that you can change in yourself reverberates throughout the world.
Okay.
As unlikely as that may seem to reason, but we're not dealing with reason.
We're dealing with energies within the field of consciousness itself, which is a different
realm.
The physical world is one realm.
The vibrational energies in the field of consciousness is a different realm, yes.
We change the world by what we have become and who we are and we thereby become a blessing
to the world.
Instead of bad news.
But you didn't answer my question.
How do you change the knee-jerk reaction where you want to, you know, you know, how do you
change that reaction?
Well, by conscious awareness you already change it.
By conscious awareness is the only way I know it from a practical viewpoint.
Okay.
By awareness that you're short-tempered you automatically become more even.
Evenly tempered because you're now aware that that is a shortcoming in yourself.
So you bite your tongue and don't say anything.
Right?
Yeah.
So you do what you can to become as perfect as you're capable of doing and that way you
improve everyone around you, including yourself.
Yes.
The world benefits.
The whole world benefits by your efforts.
Mm-hmm.
That way you become a blessing to the world instead of bad news.
And you lift the ships that are in the water.
That's very good, yes.
Wow.
But everyone thinks that they have to lift the whole ocean instead of just lifting one
ship.
If you just lift one ship, isn't that ... I mean, everyone wants to save the world, you
know.
So anyway, we all become more realistic the older we get.
We all become more realistic and we are satisfied with having less of an impact.
In other words, the less your own ego is involved, the better because you don't have to be a major
star on television in order to be of value to the world.
Really being more kindly and gentle and polite, considerate.
Mm-hmm.
Would you say that if we followed this and really did a self-inventory and tried to change
ourselves, that would actually work to change the world?
That actually changes the world, yes.
Changing yourself actually changes the world.
Mm-hmm.
The world is not the same if you're polite today.
We benefit the world by what we have become.
And what we have become is based on our intention and our values that we have integrated and
made part of our own self-image.
Mm-hmm.
So, you know, we're dealing in a very ...
...
This is a question I have from someone.
When a person lies, does that affect the efforts they have, wait, let me see.
The effect.
Yeah.
What effect does that have when a person lies?
It throws a negative energy into a field and can be quite disruptive, and therefore I advise
people to avoid it at all costs if possible, because it's often self-defeating.
Okay.
It's self-defeating.
So lying would be considered what, below 200?
Yes.
Mm-hmm.
Right.
It's self-defeating.
Mm-hmm.
And does that affect who you are?
When you lie or tell little, sometimes little white lies are to protect people, you know
what I mean.
Sometimes little white lies are to help people, you know, you don't want to hurt their feelings
so you say a little white lie.
But when you're doing it maliciously, you know, does that?
Yeah.
So the intention gives it the energy field.
Okay.
It isn't just the facts, it's the intention and the whole energy of the surrounding to
the reality.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
That's what I'm saying.
Mm-hmm.
But does that affect who you are?
When you tell a lie or a little white lie or whatever.
That affects who you are.
Yes, indeed it does.
It does tell who, it does affect you.
Yes, it does have a deleterious effect.
Mm-hmm.
Well, that isn't what I wanted to hear.
What you're asking is how can you get, be evil and get away with it.
No.
I'm just saying, no, I'm just saying, yeah, well, yes, I guess I'm saying that.
Yeah.
I mean, yeah, well, yes, I guess I am.
You know, I guess there is a-
Not evil, but you know-
Yes, I-
Less than ideal, let's say.
Yeah.
So, if you, if you were, how do I say, people that are above 200, they still can lie.
Oh, uh-huh.
Yes.
I mean, so, so, I mean, but they do it with a conscience.
They feel guilty about it.
Yeah.
Because if they're under 200, they don't feel guilty about it.
Right.
So, you know, but they can, they still have the capabilities to lie, even though they're
above 200.
Well, yes, but it's a different affair.
All right.
It's a different affair to be conscious of what you're doing-
And not conscious.
Or oblivious, yes.
All right.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
Well, that explains a lot.
I mean, because that, that explains a lot.
Yes, indeed.
Why people, you know, just because they're above 200 doesn't mean they still can't do
something wrong.
They can still do.
They're not, well, they're not holy.
They're not, you know-
Okay.
Right.
They aren't Christ-like.
You know.
But they're not really below 200, even though they-
No.
Yeah.
So, the wide range that includes most people is between 200 and, and the higher numbers,
you know.
Mm-hmm.
Somewhere in between.
Well, we know that the 300 level is usually service, you know, to others.
Uh-huh.
300.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
And the 300, anyone in the 300 range is usually service to others.
Yes.
Uh-huh.
And they usually do service type work, whether it's plumbing, construction-
Or service towards their families.
Towards their families.
Not necessarily occupation.
Right.
Mm-hmm.
But, I mean, they are of service to other people.
Just by who they are, yes.
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
Right.
And then the 400's is usually the intellect.
The intellect comes in more strongly.
Right.
Mm-hmm.
And the 500's is usually loving.
Right.
They're in the, they want to be 540, which is unconditional love.
But unconditional love is really hard to reach.
And so many people are saying that they're, at least from emails I get, that they are
in the 540's, which-
I don't know anybody that says that.
I do.
Oh.
And yet they're not, because their actions aren't there.
The person themselves are not there.
If you're really loving, you don't really care what your calibration is, you know what
I mean?
It's just sort of an academic-
Thank you.
Academic curiosity, but it's not really important.
Yes.
It's not going to make anybody happy, the fact that you calibrated 540.
Right.
The fact that you made them a peanut butter sandwich is going to carry a lot more weight.
Okay.
So, if we, let's say that-
Let's say that we are in the 300's and we want to make it to the 500's.
Can you skip levels?
I don't know, I've never asked that question.
Okay.
I would imagine a major decision, you know, you live a certain way and you come into a
crisis and now you make a major change.
I imagine you could make that decision in a matter of seconds, to be generous or not
generous.
To retaliate or not retaliate.
To choose love instead of hate, that's a fast decision.
So, in other words, some knee-jerk reactions are good.
They don't always have to be bad.
Yeah, they're not necessarily bad, no.
Very often they're a good impulse.
Okay.
So, in changing what you are, changes the world.
What you are changes the world, right?
Yeah.
It changes the world.
So, how would you say we should live that in our everyday life?
Every incense of every day, your behavior and the way you are experiencing the world
is being influenced by your level of consciousness all the time.
It's either you are not thinking about it as a clinical fact, but it is an existential
fact, that at all times you're influencing what's around you unwittingly.
Absolutely.
either wittingly or unwittingly.
The more advanced you are in your own level of consciousness,
the more you become aware of what your influence is
on the world around you.
And you stop blaming the world.
If the world seems a little less than perfect today,
you stop being critical about that.
I mean, that's the limitation of the human existence.
The limitation of human existence itself is intrinsic.
Psychological, emotional, sociologically,
financially, educationally,
all these facets contribute then to the effective totality
of who we are and how we affect the world.
Some people lift the level of vibration of everyone in the room
by merely walking into the room, their mere presence.
In the party circuit, this is known,
certain people, if you immediately have them at your party,
it's going to be successful.
All you have to do is have them at your party
and that's all that's necessary.
That's how people vie to invite people of that nature.
They radiate a certain energy that uplifts everybody in the room.
Certain people are invited to your party,
the party will be a success.
Is that what you call a party animal?
Yeah, that's something different.
That's something different.
No, there are people that are truly, truly beneficial
to any collection of people together.
They have an uplifting effect on others.
So that's what we all strive to be within ourselves,
to be of such a nature that merely your presence
is uplifting to everyone in the room
and to the benefit of the humanity itself.
Yes.
Kindliness and gentleness and lovingness.
See, even a dog can tell that difference.
A dog senses right away a loving, caring, gentle, safe person
and it senses one that is not fulfilled above.
It's more on guard and it keeps one eye open
and keeps an eye on you.
The dog keeps an eye on you.
Better watch what you're up to.
Would you say that when Jesus died for us,
our sins on the cross,
or, yes,
when Jesus died on the cross for our sins,
would you say that that was the time that the world changed?
Would that be, by him dying on the cross,
do you think that he actually, you know, he was a savior?
Historically, it is stated as such, yes.
Yes.
Died as the savior of mankind.
Okay.
Yes.
So, at that time, he did help to elevate the world by his demise?
Profoundly, his sacrifice.
Because you wouldn't have salvation without...
There we are, yes.
I mean, you've stated that Jesus died for our salvation.
Yes.
That's why he is Jesus the Christ.
So, we're all grateful as Christians
for the sacrifice.
For the sacrifice of Jesus Christ on behalf of mankind.
On behalf of mankind itself.
Okay.
Is a person's consciousness,
does that affect,
what effect does that have on the world?
One's personal consciousness.
What would that effect be on the world?
Well, we sort of answered that.
Yeah, we did.
Yeah.
The more people you have interaction with.
Okay.
So, a miserable person living all alone
is going to have less effect than a miserable person
who is a major television personality.
I'm trying to look and see if there's any questions
that I need to...
that I have here.
Give me a minute.
Okay, here's a good one.
How do I change what I am?
what you are cannot be changed okay how you are what you are can be changed okay so so what i am
can't be changed well what you know me depending on what you're talking about physical mental
spiritual all right emotional of course everybody uh you know psychotherapy psychoanalysis group
therapy consciousness raising programs are all aimed at lifting us and making us more
aware and more loving and more helpful and more beneficial to others yes
mm-hmm okay so if we take a mental inventory of how we are in the world would that change the
world that does already change the world yes
because
because everybody's consciousness is interconnected you might say
in some minimal degree to everybody else's so everyone who takes responsibility
for the way they are in the world and their degree of lovingness and upliftingness
is already changing the world by just taking responsibility for it
to see that you're playing a part in it already changes
uh already changes that so when i have that knee-jerk reaction that i just want to smash
someone
all right so if i change that reaction that will change that's right who i am which changes the
world that's the way it works mm-hmm darn it the better we get the better we get because the better
we get the better we are and the better we are the better we get
yeah it's it's hard to do that though you know you have to i mean especially when you want to do you
I mean, you would like to be able to say, to be that person that sits back and says,
oh, I'm glad to see you feel that way.
You know, you want to go, hmm.
It's kind of like that joke someone gave me, you know.
I meditate, I burn candles, and something else, what is it?
I meditate, burn candles, and drink green tea, and I still want to smack someone.
That's funny, yeah.
I know, I have that on my refrigerator.
That's funny.
So, you know.
We laugh at ourselves.
So laughing at ourselves is a sign of emotional maturity.
To detach from yourself, be able to laugh at yourself, laugh at your own foibles,
be self-forgiving for your limitations, accept the fact you're not perfect,
and that you're just...
that you're not just human, but that you're lovable and worthwhile,
and so your self-regard increases when you accept your limitations
as part of being inherent to the human condition itself.
So if you were to give us a...
condense all this into one thing on...
as to what we should do to improve ourselves, what would that be?
To be as loving as possible.
Loving and forgiving and caring as possible.
Even though we make mistakes.
Yes, even though you make mistakes.
We have to forgive ourselves for that.
That's right.
So we try to be the best person we can in all circumstances,
and of course we will fall short,
but our motivation is, you know, correct.
You may forget the speedometer and get over the speed limit a few miles,
but then a little...
a little way down the road, you suddenly can pull yourself back and say,
hey, I'm picking up speed, I better slow down.
So self-awareness, then, is the guide that we turn to.
In the end, we turn to ourself anyway.
You turn to yourself.
It isn't just what others say, it's what others say affects us
that gives them the power to influence our lives.
If we don't care about what they think, it would have no effect.
So caring about others, then, is the best way to achieve happiness
for yourself and everyone around you.
That way your life becomes a gift to the world.
So you...
In an overall field, you can say to yourself,
how am I being of gift to the world, to my family, to my neighbors,
to the world in general?
Am I a detriment to the world or a gift to the world?
A detriment or a gift?
So it would be through prayer, actions, service, thoughts,
that you become this person who changes the world and changes yourself.
That's the way it works.
Because what we become subtly influences the world.
What we say we are can be refuted,
but what we actually are actually does change the world.
Let's see.
What we actually are actually changes the world.
It's good to know.
So it's important to be kindly to the animals in the woods.
It's important to be kindly to the field, to the tree, and to the bushes.
So our kindness radiates out into the world.
Our kindness.
The best thing we can do for the woods is to love it and appreciate it.
And it's very exciting.
And then you find that there's a hidden love in that existence.
As you're busy walking through the woods all by yourself,
loving the beauty and the leaves falling in the fall,
and you hear the rustling and the incredible beauty,
all of a sudden a sort of a thrill shoots through you.
You realize that your lovingness of nature is partly why it is what it is.
It's because you are part of nature.
So it's not you and nature.
It's you as nature.
And you realize that you are part of nature.
And that your love is benefiting all the trees and bushes and everything around you.
So your love actually does nourish the world.
Your love nourishes the world.
Therefore, instead of minimizing that, you know,
appreciate the fact that who you are is influencing the world for the better or for worse.
And in the end, we're answerable for that.
Are the trees glad to see me today or not?
I want the trees to be glad to see me.
There's an old duck walking through the woods there.
Let's see.
And the trees say, oh, goody.
There you go.
So it's not just ego.
It's a fact of nature.
All right.
So it's a fact of nature.
Nature.
The totality is conscious and aware of what is in its presence for the better or for worse.
So that nature shudders at the presence of the evil doer.
Resist.
There you go.
Nature shudders at the presence of certain people.
Wow.
Wouldn't that be awful to be a person that even nature is scared of you?
Oh, dear.
No, I spent a lot of time walking through woods by myself.
And I was always aware of the beauty and the fact that nature was conscious of my presence somehow.
And I always sent love to the trees and the bushes and radiated my appreciation.
And of course, in the end, all of that is divinity.
So what you're doing is what you're catching onto is the divinity of the existence.
The divinity of the existence of life itself.
And the feedback then tends to increase that value.
So you're alive, but you're not only alive, but you're glad that you're alive.
Lots of people drag themselves through life and they don't seem to be very glad that they're alive.
They're glad that they're alive.
So when you say be as loving and kind.
Be as loving and kind to everything and respect its existence.
Yes, that's right.
You're actually saying that is what you want to become.
And that is actually changing the world.
I was thinking of the story of that little woman who was black, I think.
Very small, little 70-year-old lady.
Right.
Who refused to give up her seat.
Yeah.
On the bus.
And, you know, anyway.
I always think of the effect that she had.
That one action.
That she would not go to the back of the bus.
And that little lady who weighed, I forget how many pounds she weighed.
Yeah.
A very small little lady who didn't weigh hardly anything.
You know, profoundly changed society and the world.
And how they look at things, yeah.
Yes.
So if we love ourself, we realize that we are of importance.
So there's sort of a soothing.
A pseudo-humbleness.
Oh, I'm nobody.
I don't really amount to anything.
The truth of it is that who you are and how you are that is profoundly affecting.
And it's not grandiosity or egotism.
In fact, it's humility that allows you to say, yes, who I am and how I am that does
have an effect on the world and take responsibility for it.
So, thank you.
Thank you.
And so, we'll be doing these little what we call fireside chats this year.
Oh.
And we'll have hopefully another two.
This year.
So we'll be happy that we're condensing our material down to where I think that it'll
be good for our followers to be able to look at it.
Oh, well that'll be fun.
Yes.
That'll be fun.
Thank you very much.
Okay.