Let's
Let's go
Let's go on
Let's go on to
Let's go on to Mr.
Let's go on to Mr. Chiron.
Let's go on to Mr. Chiron. Can
Let's go on to Mr. Chiron. Can we
Let's go on to Mr. Chiron. Can we have
permission
permission to
Let's go on to Mr. Chiron. Can we have
permission to do
permission to do Mr.
Let's go on to Mr. Chiron. Can we have
permission to do Mr. Chiron
permission to do Mr. Chiron in
Let's go on to Mr. Chiron. Can we have
permission to do Mr. Chiron in this
group
group at
group at this
group at this time?
God
God help
group at this time?
God help us
God help us all.
group at this time?
God help us all. Mr.
God help us all. Mr. Chiron
group at this time?
God help us all. Mr. Chiron is
God help us all. Mr. Chiron is over
group at this time?
God help us all. Mr. Chiron is over 200.
He
He says,
He says, "Uhuh.
He says, "Uhuh. Mr.
He says, "Uhuh. Mr. Chiron
He says, "Uhuh. Mr. Chiron is
He says, "Uhuh. Mr. Chiron is over
He says, "Uhuh. Mr. Chiron is over 175,
180,
180, 185,
He says, "Uhuh. Mr. Chiron is over 175,
180, 185, 190."
180, 185, 190." Oh.
He says, "Uhuh. Mr. Chiron is over 175,
180, 185, 190." Oh. Oh.
180, 185, 190." Oh. Oh. So,
He says, "Uhuh. Mr. Chiron is over 175,
180, 185, 190." Oh. Oh. So, thank
180, 185, 190." Oh. Oh. So, thank you.
So,
So, that's
So, that's a
So, that's a little
So, that's a little bit
So, that's a little bit of
So, that's a little bit of a
So, that's a little bit of a reversal
over
over what
So, that's a little bit of a reversal
over what it
over what it used
So, that's a little bit of a reversal
over what it used to
over what it used to be.
So, that's a little bit of a reversal
over what it used to be. I
over what it used to be. I think
So, that's a little bit of a reversal
over what it used to be. I think Chiron
used
used to
used to be
used to be high
used to be high and
used to be high and came
used to be high and came down
used to be high and came down and
used to be high and came down and Arafat
was
was barely
used to be high and came down and Arafat
was barely down
was barely down and
used to be high and came down and Arafat
was barely down and has
was barely down and has come
used to be high and came down and Arafat
was barely down and has come up.
was barely down and has come up. That's
fact.
Okay.
Okay. Chiron
fact.
Okay. Chiron was
Okay. Chiron was once
fact.
Okay. Chiron was once higher
Okay. Chiron was once higher resistance
and
and has
and has now
and has now come
and has now come down
and has now come down resist.
and has now come down resist. And
and has now come down resist. And Arafat
was
was once
and has now come down resist. And Arafat
was once lower
was once lower and
and has now come down resist. And Arafat
was once lower and has
was once lower and has now
and has now come down resist. And Arafat
was once lower and has now come
was once lower and has now come up
resistance.
resistance. Yeah,
resistance. Yeah, you've
resistance. Yeah, you've got
resistance. Yeah, you've got a
resistance. Yeah, you've got a oddball
crisscross
crisscross there
in
in which
in which u
one
one has
in which u
one has come
one has come down
in which u
one has come down in
one has come down in order
in which u
one has come down in order to
one has come down in order to win
in which u
one has come down in order to win and
the
the other
the other one
the other one is
the other one is coming
the other one is coming up
the other one is coming up in
the other one is coming up in order
the other one is coming up in order to
survive.
survive. I
the other one is coming up in order to
survive. I think
survive. I think in
the other one is coming up in order to
survive. I think in Arafat
survive. I think in Arafat realizes
unless
unless he
unless he owns
unless he owns integrity,
unless he owns integrity, he's
unless he owns integrity, he's a
unless he owns integrity, he's a dead
duck.
duck. And
unless he owns integrity, he's a dead
duck. And I
duck. And I think
unless he owns integrity, he's a dead
duck. And I think he
duck. And I think he realizes
unless he owns integrity, he's a dead
duck. And I think he realizes that
duck. And I think he realizes that it's
not
not Palestine
not Palestine or
not Palestine or or
not Palestine or or himself
not Palestine or or himself his
political
political self
not Palestine or or himself his
political self that's
political self that's at
not Palestine or or himself his
political self that's at risk.
political self that's at risk. It's
integrity
integrity itself.
integrity itself. I
integrity itself. I think
integrity itself. I think it's
intuitively
intuitively dawning
integrity itself. I think it's
intuitively dawning on
intuitively dawning on him
integrity itself. I think it's
intuitively dawning on him that
intuitively dawning on him that unless
he
he owns
he owns the
he owns the power
he owns the power of
he owns the power of integrity,
he owns the power of integrity, he's
he owns the power of integrity, he's a
goner.
That's
That's a
That's a fact.
That's a fact. Yeah.
That's a fact. Yeah. By
That's a fact. Yeah. By God,
That's a fact. Yeah. By God, he
That's a fact. Yeah. By God, he is
getting
getting it.
That's a fact. Yeah. By God, he is
getting it. So
getting it. So all
That's a fact. Yeah. By God, he is
getting it. So all the
getting it. So all the people
That's a fact. Yeah. By God, he is
getting it. So all the people praying
for
for it,
for it, it's
for it, it's working.
for it, it's working. [laughter]
Somebody's
Somebody's hearing
for it, it's working. [laughter]
Somebody's hearing it.
Somebody's hearing it. You
for it, it's working. [laughter]
Somebody's hearing it. You know,
Somebody's hearing it. You know, the
first
first one
first one that
first one that really
first one that really regains
first one that really regains integrity
is
is going
first one that really regains integrity
is going to
is going to win
first one that really regains integrity
is going to win and
is going to win and win
first one that really regains integrity
is going to win and win the
is going to win and win the respect
first one that really regains integrity
is going to win and win the respect of
the
the world
the world and
the world and the
the world and the backing
the world and the backing of
the world and the backing of the
the world and the backing of the world.
Whichever
Whichever one
the world and the backing of the world.
Whichever one finally
Whichever one finally comes
the world and the backing of the world.
Whichever one finally comes out
Whichever one finally comes out with
integrity
integrity is
integrity is going
integrity is going to
integrity is going to win.
integrity is going to win. Okay.
So
So that's
integrity is going to win. Okay.
So that's Arafat
So that's Arafat and
integrity is going to win. Okay.
So that's Arafat and Chin
So that's Arafat and Chin Yogananda.
integrity is going to win. Okay.
So that's Arafat and Chin Yogananda. We
had
had calibrated
had calibrated him
had calibrated him before
had calibrated him before was
had calibrated him before was at
had calibrated him before was at 550.
He
He would
had calibrated him before was at 550.
He would therefore
He would therefore be
had calibrated him before was at 550.
He would therefore be the
He would therefore be the perfect
spiritual
spiritual teacher.
spiritual teacher. Let's
spiritual teacher. Let's say
spiritual teacher. Let's say all
spiritual
spiritual teachers
spiritual teacher. Let's say all
spiritual teachers are
spiritual teachers are good
spiritual teacher. Let's say all
spiritual teachers are good for
spiritual teachers are good for wherever
you're
you're at.
you're at. See
you're at. See if
you're at. See if this
you're at. See if this guy
you're at. See if this guy tells
you're at. See if this guy tells you
it's
it's wrong
you're at. See if this guy tells you
it's wrong to
it's wrong to chap
you're at. See if this guy tells you
it's wrong to chap up
it's wrong to chap up infidels.
you're at. See if this guy tells you
it's wrong to chap up infidels. That's
it's wrong to chap up infidels. That's a
danger
danger advance.
danger advance. So
danger advance. So he's
danger advance. So he's a
danger advance. So he's a very
danger advance. So he's a very good
danger advance. So he's a very good guru
till
till there.
danger advance. So he's a very good guru
till there. You
till there. You understand
danger advance. So he's a very good guru
till there. You understand what
till there. You understand what I'm
saying?
550 is
550 is the
saying?
550 is the classical
550 is the classical guru
saying?
550 is the classical guru in
550 is the classical guru in our
saying?
550 is the classical guru in our in
550 is the classical guru in our in our
world.
world. Um,
world. Um, these
world. Um, these are
world. Um, these are people
world. Um, these are people that
world. Um, these are people that are
unconditionally
unconditionally loving.
world. Um, these are people that are
unconditionally loving. What
unconditionally loving. What would
world. Um, these are people that are
unconditionally loving. What would we
say
say he
say he was
say he was 550?
say he was 550? Yeah.
say he was 550? Yeah. 550.
say he was 550? Yeah. 550. 540
say he was 550? Yeah. 550. 540 is
unconditional
unconditional love.
Anything
Anything that
Anything that runs
Anything that runs 540
Anything that runs 540 and
Anything that runs 540 and and
Anything that runs 540 and and up
Anything that runs 540 and and up is
certainly
uh
uh worthy
uh worthy of
uh worthy of great
uh worthy of great respect.
uh worthy of great respect. And
uh
uh as
uh worthy of great respect. And
uh as we
uh as we said,
uh worthy of great respect. And
uh as we said, the
uh as we said, the 12step
uh worthy of great respect. And
uh as we said, the 12step groups
uh as we said, the 12step groups are
540.
They
They represent
540.
They represent the
They represent the pure
540.
They represent the pure essence
They represent the pure essence of
spirituality.
Uh
Uh that
spirituality.
Uh that which
Uh that which has
spirituality.
Uh that which has no
Uh that which has no opinion
spirituality.
Uh that which has no opinion on
Uh that which has no opinion on external
issues
issues tells
issues tells you
issues tells you right
issues tells you right away
issues tells you right away that
issues tells you right away that it's
not
not corruptible.
issues tells you right away that it's
not corruptible. There's
not corruptible. There's no
issues tells you right away that it's
not corruptible. There's no no
not corruptible. There's no no opinions
on
on outside
on outside issues.
Anything
Anything that
on outside issues.
Anything that has
Anything that has no
on outside issues.
Anything that has no opinions
Anything that has no opinions on
on outside issues.
Anything that has no opinions on outside
issues
issues can't
issues can't be
issues can't be bought
issues can't be bought or
issues can't be bought or sold,
issues can't be bought or sold, can
issues can't be bought or sold, can it?
Because
Because there's
issues can't be bought or sold, can it?
Because there's no
Because there's no lever
issues can't be bought or sold, can it?
Because there's no lever out
Because there's no lever out there
issues can't be bought or sold, can it?
Because there's no lever out there to
grab
grab them
grab them by.
grab them by. [laughter]
They
They don't
grab them by. [laughter]
They don't care
They don't care what
grab them by. [laughter]
They don't care what you
They don't care what you think
grab them by. [laughter]
They don't care what you think of
They don't care what you think of them.
They
They don't
They don't need
They don't need your
They don't need your post.
They don't need your post. They
They don't need your post. They don't
need
need your
They don't need your post. They don't
need your money.
need your money. They
They don't need your post. They don't
need your money. They can
need your money. They can just
They don't need your post. They don't
need your money. They can just be
need your money. They can just be who
they
they are.
they are. Yes.
Does
Does your
they are. Yes.
Does your man
Does your man still
they are. Yes.
Does your man still fight
Does your man still fight with
they are. Yes.
Does your man still fight with you?
>> Um,
>> Um, that
>> Um, that I'm
>> Um, that I'm not
>> Um, that I'm not going
>> Um, that I'm not going to
>> Um, that I'm not going to ask
>> Um, that I'm not going to ask because
you're
you're asking
>> Um, that I'm not going to ask because
you're asking the
you're asking the fate
>> Um, that I'm not going to ask because
you're asking the fate of
you're asking the fate of the
>> Um, that I'm not going to ask because
you're asking the fate of the karmic
fate
fate of
fate of his
fate of his spirit.
fate of his spirit. I
fate of his spirit. I don't
fate of his spirit. I don't know.
As
As of
fate of his spirit. I don't know.
As of being
As of being here
fate of his spirit. I don't know.
As of being here on
As of being here on the
fate of his spirit. I don't know.
As of being here on the planet,
As of being here on the planet, he
calibrated
calibrated 550.
calibrated 550. I
calibrated 550. I presume
calibrated 550. I presume his
calibrated 550. I presume his writings
are
are 550.
I
I presume
I presume that's
I presume that's correct.
As
As I
I presume that's correct.
As I said
As I said before,
I presume that's correct.
As I said before, sometimes
As I said before, sometimes there's
I presume that's correct.
As I said before, sometimes there's a
disparity
disparity between
disparity between the
disparity between the writings
disparity between the writings of
disparity between the writings of a
teacher
teacher and
disparity between the writings of a
teacher and their
teacher and their current
disparity between the writings of a
teacher and their current calibration.
It's
It's because
It's because as
It's because as you
It's because as you evolve,
It's because as you evolve, don't
It's because as you evolve, don't forget
a
a test
It's because as you evolve, don't forget
a test of
a test of that
It's because as you evolve, don't forget
a test of that comes
a test of that comes up
It's because as you evolve, don't forget
a test of that comes up all
a test of that comes up all the
It's because as you evolve, don't forget
a test of that comes up all the time
a test of that comes up all the time and
you
you can
you can buy
you can buy its
you can buy its opposite.
you can buy its opposite. Um
the
the uh
you can buy its opposite. Um
the uh power
the uh power over
you can buy its opposite. Um
the uh power over others.
the uh power over others. I
you can buy its opposite. Um
the uh power over others. I remember
being
being presented
being presented with
being presented with that
being presented with that one
being presented with that one and
being presented with that one and uh
being presented with that one and uh I
forget
forget what
being presented with that one and uh I
forget what that
forget what that level
being presented with that one and uh I
forget what that level was.
forget what that level was. We
calibrated
calibrated it
calibrated it later.
Uh
Uh but
calibrated it later.
Uh but it
Uh but it was
calibrated it later.
Uh but it was really
Uh but it was really infinite.
calibrated it later.
Uh but it was really infinite. I
Uh but it was really infinite. I mean
enormous
enormous power
enormous power unlimited
enormous power unlimited by
enormous power unlimited by any
limitation.
And
And it
And it was
And it was offered.
And it was offered. All
And it was offered. All you
And it was offered. All you had
And it was offered. All you had to
And it was offered. All you had to do
was
was say
And it was offered. All you had to do
was say yes
was say yes to
And it was offered. All you had to do
was say yes to it.
was say yes to it. And
And it was offered. All you had to do
was say yes to it. And u
was say yes to it. And u so
And it was offered. All you had to do
was say yes to it. And u so the
in
in the
in the book
in the book I'm
in the book I'm finishing
in the book I'm finishing now
in the book I'm finishing now I
in the book I'm finishing now I feel
responsible
responsible as
in the book I'm finishing now I feel
responsible as a
responsible as a spiritual
in the book I'm finishing now I feel
responsible as a spiritual educator
teacher
teacher or
teacher or whatever
teacher or whatever you
teacher or whatever you want
teacher or whatever you want to
teacher or whatever you want to call
teacher or whatever you want to call it
to
to forewarn
teacher or whatever you want to call it
to forewarn people
to forewarn people that
teacher or whatever you want to call it
to forewarn people that as
to forewarn people that as you
teacher or whatever you want to call it
to forewarn people that as you grow
to forewarn people that as you grow up
that
that which
that which is
that which is luciferic
that which is luciferic is
that which is luciferic is waiting
that which is luciferic is waiting for
you.
Uh
Uh it's
Uh it's waiting
Uh it's waiting for
Uh it's waiting for you
Uh it's waiting for you and
Uh it's waiting for you and when
Uh it's waiting for you and when you
Uh it's waiting for you and when you get
there
there then
Uh it's waiting for you and when you get
there then it
there then it heads
Uh it's waiting for you and when you get
there then it heads for
there then it heads for you.
Uh it's waiting for you and when you get
there then it heads for you. It's
there then it heads for you. It's like
the
the media
the media doesn't
the media doesn't bite
the media doesn't bite you
the media doesn't bite you until
the media doesn't bite you until you
become
become a
the media doesn't bite you until you
become a celebrity.
become a celebrity. You
the media doesn't bite you until you
become a celebrity. You know
become a celebrity. You know what
the media doesn't bite you until you
become a celebrity. You know what I
mean?
You're
You're not
mean?
You're not you're
You're not you're not
mean?
You're not you're not influencing
You're not you're not influencing enough
people.
people. But
people. But when
people. But when you
people. But when you start
people. But when you start getting
people. But when you start getting up
there
there now,
people. But when you start getting up
there now, the
there now, the sniper's
people. But when you start getting up
there now, the sniper's bullet
there now, the sniper's bullet starts
getting
getting aimed
getting aimed at
getting aimed at you.
getting aimed at you. So
getting aimed at you. So um
getting aimed at you. So um I
getting aimed at you. So um I feel
getting aimed at you. So um I feel it's
a
a responsibility
getting aimed at you. So um I feel it's
a responsibility to
a responsibility to educate
getting aimed at you. So um I feel it's
a responsibility to educate student
about
about that
about that that
about that that as
about that that as you
about that that as you evolve
about that that as you evolve that
about that that as you evolve that which
would
would deny
about that that as you evolve that which
would deny the
would deny the reality
about that that as you evolve that which
would deny the reality of
would deny the reality of what
about that that as you evolve that which
would deny the reality of what you
would deny the reality of what you have
uh
uh realized
uh realized as
uh realized as truth
uh realized as truth becomes
uh realized as truth becomes challenged
and
and it's
uh realized as truth becomes challenged
and it's done
and it's done cleverly.
uh realized as truth becomes challenged
and it's done cleverly. I
and it's done cleverly. I think
uh realized as truth becomes challenged
and it's done cleverly. I think I
and it's done cleverly. I think I wrote
it
it rather
it rather specifically
it rather specifically in
it rather specifically in the
it rather specifically in the book
it rather specifically in the book I'm
finishing
finishing now.
it rather specifically in the book I'm
finishing now. I
finishing now. I remember
it rather specifically in the book I'm
finishing now. I remember it
finishing now. I remember it at
at
at about
at about 8:50
at about 8:50 or
at about 8:50 or so
at about 8:50 or so comes
at about 8:50 or so comes in
the
the realization
at about 8:50 or so comes in
the realization out
the realization out of
at about 8:50 or so comes in
the realization out of nowhere.
the realization out of nowhere. It's
at about 8:50 or so comes in
the realization out of nowhere. It's not
via
via a
via a person.
via a person. No
via a person. No spiritual
via a person. No spiritual truth
via a person. No spiritual truth comes
from
from other
via a person. No spiritual truth comes
from other beings.
from other beings. You
via a person. No spiritual truth comes
from other beings. You don't
from other beings. You don't you
via a person. No spiritual truth comes
from other beings. You don't you know
you
you don't
you don't know
you don't know what
you don't know what you
you don't know what you know
you don't know what you know cuz
you don't know what you know cuz that
told
told me
you don't know what you know cuz that
told me or
told me or some
you don't know what you know cuz that
told me or some spirit
told me or some spirit ascended
spiritual
spiritual master
spiritual master told
spiritual master told you
spiritual master told you that
spiritual master told you that it's
spiritual master told you that it's a
realization
realization of
spiritual master told you that it's a
realization of that
realization of that which
spiritual master told you that it's a
realization of that which you
realization of that which you are.
spiritual master told you that it's a
realization of that which you are. So
then
then suddenly
then suddenly in
then suddenly in the
then suddenly in the purity
then suddenly in the purity of
then suddenly in the purity of that
incredible
incredible space
comes
comes the
knowingness.
knowingness. It
comes the
knowingness. It comes
knowingness. It comes out
comes the
knowingness. It comes out of
knowingness. It comes out of like
comes the
knowingness. It comes out of like a
nonverbal
nonverbal realization.
Now
Now that
nonverbal realization.
Now that you
Now that you are
nonverbal realization.
Now that you are beyond
Now that you are beyond personal
nonverbal realization.
Now that you are beyond personal karma
and
and there
and there is
and there is no
and there is no arbitrary
and there is no arbitrary god
to
to punish
and there is no arbitrary god
to punish you
to punish you in
and there is no arbitrary god
to punish you in as
to punish you in as much
and there is no arbitrary god
to punish you in as much as
to punish you in as much as there
and there is no arbitrary god
to punish you in as much as there is
to punish you in as much as there is no
payment
payment and
payment and no
payment and no no
payment and no no consequences
payment and no no consequences to
anything
anything you
payment and no no consequences to
anything you do,
anything you do, think
payment and no no consequences to
anything you do, think or
anything you do, think or say,
payment and no no consequences to
anything you do, think or say, you
anything you do, think or say, you are
free
free to
free to have
free to have absolute
free to have absolute power
free to have absolute power over
free to have absolute power over others.
And
And that
free to have absolute power over others.
And that is
And that is the
free to have absolute power over others.
And that is the ultimate
And that is the ultimate luciferic.
free to have absolute power over others.
And that is the ultimate luciferic. And
of
of course
of course that's
of course that's one
of course that's one is
of course that's one is apparently
brought
brought down
of course that's one is apparently
brought down a
brought down a number
of course that's one is apparently
brought down a number of
brought down a number of teachers.
The
The other
The other defect
The other defect that
The other defect that the
The other defect that the luciferic
offers
offers on
The other defect that the luciferic
offers on the
offers on the way
The other defect that the luciferic
offers on the way up
offers on the way up is
The other defect that the luciferic
offers on the way up is um
offers on the way up is um to
The other defect that the luciferic
offers on the way up is um to see
offers on the way up is um to see love
as
as a
as a trap.
Now
Now remember
as a trap.
Now remember that
Now remember that that's
as a trap.
Now remember that that's a
Now remember that that's a very
as a trap.
Now remember that that's a very specific
one
one that
one that as
one that as you
one that as you go
one that as you go up
one that as you go up higher
one that as you go up higher and
one that as you go up higher and higher
lucifer
lucifer will
one that as you go up higher and higher
lucifer will come
lucifer will come to
one that as you go up higher and higher
lucifer will come to you
lucifer will come to you either
one that as you go up higher and higher
lucifer will come to you either in
lucifer will come to you either in the
form
form of
form of a
form of a person
form of a person a
form of a person a teacher
form of a person a teacher or
form of a person a teacher or an
form of a person a teacher or an entity
coming
coming through
form of a person a teacher or an entity
coming through somebody
coming through somebody you're
form of a person a teacher or an entity
coming through somebody you're talking
to
to will
to will say
to will say don't
to will say don't you
to will say don't you see
to will say don't you see that
to will say don't you see that love
to will say don't you see that love is
just
just a
to will say don't you see that love is
just a trap
and
and they
and they will
and they will sometimes
and they will sometimes use
and they will sometimes use the
and they will sometimes use the Buddha's
description
description of
and they will sometimes use the Buddha's
description of the
description of the ultimate
and they will sometimes use the Buddha's
description of the ultimate reality
description of the ultimate reality is
void
void to
void to verify
void to verify it
void to verify it and
void to verify it and back
void to verify it and back it
void to verify it and back it up.
No,
No, it's
void to verify it and back it up.
No, it's not
No, it's not love
void to verify it and back it up.
No, it's not love that's
No, it's not love that's a
void to verify it and back it up.
No, it's not love that's a limitation
No, it's not love that's a limitation to
the
the realization
the realization of
the realization of the
the realization of the infinite
the realization of the infinite reality.
It's
It's the
the realization of the infinite reality.
It's the attachment
It's the attachment to
the realization of the infinite reality.
It's the attachment to it.
None
None of
None of these
None of these things
None of these things have
None of these things have any
None of these things have any power
within
within themsself.
None of these things have any power
within themsself. All
within themsself. All the
None of these things have any power
within themsself. All the things
within themsself. All the things we're
scared
scared about
scared about and
scared about and thought
scared about and thought about
scared about and thought about through
all
all spiritual
scared about and thought about through
all spiritual and
all spiritual and religious
scared about and thought about through
all spiritual and religious instruction.
It
It isn't
It isn't the
It isn't the thing
It isn't the thing themselves.
It isn't the thing themselves. It's
It isn't the thing themselves. It's our
attachment
attachment to
It isn't the thing themselves. It's our
attachment to it.
attachment to it. Is
It isn't the thing themselves. It's our
attachment to it. Is money
attachment to it. Is money and
It isn't the thing themselves. It's our
attachment to it. Is money and sex
attachment to it. Is money and sex a
great
great limitation
great limitation to
great limitation to spiritual
great limitation to spiritual evolution?
Well,
Well, Ramach
great limitation to spiritual evolution?
Well, Ramach Krishna
Well, Ramach Krishna said
great limitation to spiritual evolution?
Well, Ramach Krishna said so.
Well, Ramach Krishna said so. and
great limitation to spiritual evolution?
Well, Ramach Krishna said so. and young
men.
men. It's
men. It's such
men. It's such a
men. It's such a problem
men. It's such a problem that
men. It's such a problem that he
men. It's such a problem that he forbid
it.
it. You
men. It's such a problem that he forbid
it. You weren't
it. You weren't allowed
men. It's such a problem that he forbid
it. You weren't allowed to
it. You weren't allowed to even
men. It's such a problem that he forbid
it. You weren't allowed to even touch
money.
money. Money
money. Money and
money. Money and sex
money. Money and sex were
money. Money and sex were the
money. Money and sex were the two
money. Money and sex were the two traps
within
within a
money. Money and sex were the two traps
within a certain
within a certain limited
money. Money and sex were the two traps
within a certain limited context.
within a certain limited context. That's
so
so in
so in a
so in a broader
so in a broader context.
so in a broader context. No,
so in a broader context. No, it's
so in a broader context. No, it's the
attachment
attachment to
so in a broader context. No, it's the
attachment to them.
attachment to them. A
so in a broader context. No, it's the
attachment to them. A free
attachment to them. A free being
so in a broader context. No, it's the
attachment to them. A free being can
attachment to them. A free being can go
to
to the
to the casino,
to the casino, win
to the casino, win or
to the casino, win or lose,
to the casino, win or lose, and
to the casino, win or lose, and walk
away
away untouched.
to the casino, win or lose, and walk
away untouched. Huh?
Untouched.
Because
Because the
Untouched.
Because the reality
Because the reality is
Untouched.
Because the reality is not
Because the reality is not involved
Untouched.
Because the reality is not involved in
it.
it. No,
it. No, it's
it. No, it's the
it. No, it's the attachment
it. No, it's the attachment to
it. No, it's the attachment to love
it. No, it's the attachment to love and
money.
money. It's
it. No, it's the attachment to love and
money. It's the
money. It's the attachment
it. No, it's the attachment to love and
money. It's the attachment to
money. It's the attachment to power.
it. No, it's the attachment to love and
money. It's the attachment to power. So
I
I saw
I saw the
I saw the luciferic.
I saw the luciferic. What
I saw the luciferic. What the
I saw the luciferic. What the luciferic
is
is is
I saw the luciferic. What the luciferic
is is the
is is the temptation
to
to own
to own the
to own the power
to own the power of
to own the power of God
to own the power of God and
to own the power of God and but
to own the power of God and but not
to own the power of God and but not the
love
love of
to own the power of God and but not the
love of God.
You
You see
You see because
You see because the
You see because the love
You see because the love of
You see because the love of God
You see because the love of God that
which
which divinity
You see because the love of God that
which divinity is
which divinity is both
You see because the love of God that
which divinity is both power
which divinity is both power and
and
and love.
If
If you
and love.
If you negate
If you negate the
and love.
If you negate the reality
If you negate the reality of
and love.
If you negate the reality of the
If you negate the reality of the love
then
then you
then you have
then you have nothing
then you have nothing but
then you have nothing but power
then you have nothing but power over
others.
And
And the
And the next
And the next question
And the next question to
And the next question to the
And the next question to the luciferic,
they
they haven't
And the next question to the luciferic,
they haven't tried
they haven't tried it
And the next question to the luciferic,
they haven't tried it since
they haven't tried it since because
And the next question to the luciferic,
they haven't tried it since because I
beat
beat him
beat him beat
beat him beat his
beat him beat his ass.
[laughter]
The
The next
The next thing
The next thing to
The next thing to the
The next thing to the luciferic
The next thing to the luciferic is
The next thing to the luciferic is that
what
what what
The next thing to the luciferic is that
what what is
what what is your
The next thing to the luciferic is that
what what is your attachment
what what is your attachment to
The next thing to the luciferic is that
what what is your attachment to power,
buddy?
buddy? [laughter]
Now
Now that
buddy? [laughter]
Now that you
Now that you have
buddy? [laughter]
Now that you have no
Now that you have no karmic
buddy? [laughter]
Now that you have no karmic consequences
to
to pay,
to pay, now
to pay, now that
to pay, now that there's
to pay, now that there's no
to pay, now that there's no arbitrary
God
God waiting
to pay, now that there's no arbitrary
God waiting up
God waiting up there
to pay, now that there's no arbitrary
God waiting up there from
God waiting up there from the
to pay, now that there's no arbitrary
God waiting up there from the Old
Testament
Testament to
Testament to beat
Testament to beat the
Testament to beat the chops
Testament to beat the chops off
Testament to beat the chops off you,
Testament to beat the chops off you, you
know,
know, why
Testament to beat the chops off you, you
know, why don't
know, why don't you
Testament to beat the chops off you, you
know, why don't you just
know, why don't you just do
Testament to beat the chops off you, you
know, why don't you just do whatever
you're
you're going
you're going to
you're going to do?
you're going to do? Forget
you're going to do? Forget about
conscience.
conscience. There's
you're going to do? Forget about
conscience. There's no
conscience. There's no payment
you're going to do? Forget about
conscience. There's no payment can
conscience. There's no payment can be
extracted
extracted by
extracted by anyone.
All
All power
extracted by anyone.
All power is
All power is yours.
extracted by anyone.
All power is yours. That's
All power is yours. That's what
extracted by anyone.
All power is yours. That's what it's
said.
Jesus
Jesus got
said.
Jesus got the
Jesus got the same
said.
Jesus got the same deal
Jesus got the same deal in
said.
Jesus got the same deal in the
Jesus got the same deal in the garden
said.
Jesus got the same deal in the garden of
these
these seminary.
Jesus
Jesus got
these seminary.
Jesus got the
Jesus got the same
these seminary.
Jesus got the same presentation,
Jesus got the same presentation, didn't
he?
he? He
he? He work
he? He work kneel
he? He work kneel down
he? He work kneel down and
he? He work kneel down and worship
he? He work kneel down and worship me
all
all powers.
So
So the
So the answer
So the answer to
So the answer to that
So the answer to that luciferic
So the answer to that luciferic demon
because
because you'll
So the answer to that luciferic demon
because you'll get
because you'll get him
So the answer to that luciferic demon
because you'll get him if
because you'll get him if you're
So the answer to that luciferic demon
because you'll get him if you're moving
towards
towards enlightenment.
towards enlightenment. He
towards enlightenment. He waiting
towards enlightenment. He waiting for
you
and
and teachers
and teachers have
and teachers have failed
and teachers have failed to
and teachers have failed to prepare
their
their students
and teachers have failed to prepare
their students with
their students with what
and teachers have failed to prepare
their students with what the
their students with what the what
and teachers have failed to prepare
their students with what the what the
answer
answer is
answer is to
answer is to the
answer is to the naive
answer is to the naive mind.
answer is to the naive mind. It
answer is to the naive mind. It sounds
very
very convincing.
answer is to the naive mind. It sounds
very convincing. It
very convincing. It comes
answer is to the naive mind. It sounds
very convincing. It comes from
very convincing. It comes from very
answer is to the naive mind. It sounds
very convincing. It comes from very high
feeling
feeling authority.
feeling authority. This
feeling authority. This amazing
realization
realization and
feeling authority. This amazing
realization and You
realization and You have
feeling authority. This amazing
realization and You have no
consequences.
consequences. There's
consequences. There's nothing
consequences. There's nothing unknown
consequences. There's nothing unknown to
be
be answerable
consequences. There's nothing unknown to
be answerable to
be answerable to for.
You're
You're beyond
You're beyond human
You're beyond human karma.
All
All power
You're beyond human karma.
All power is
All power is yours.
All
All power
All power is
All power is yours.
And
And if
All power is yours.
And if you
And if you stop
All power is yours.
And if you stop at
And if you stop at that
All power is yours.
And if you stop at that point,
And if you stop at that point, you
become
become a
become a prince
become a prince in
become a prince in the
become a prince in the luciferic
become a prince in the luciferic realm.
And
And the
become a prince in the luciferic realm.
And the question
And the question to
become a prince in the luciferic realm.
And the question to that
And the question to that demon
become a prince in the luciferic realm.
And the question to that demon is
And the question to that demon is this.
Of
what
what good
Of
what good is
what good is your
Of
what good is your power?
what good is your power? Of
Of
what good is your power? Of what
what good is your power? Of what use?
Are
Are you
Are you still
Are you still attached
Are you still attached to
Are you still attached to power?
What
What do
Are you still attached to power?
What do you
What do you want
Are you still attached to power?
What do you want with
What do you want with power?
I
I remember
I remember one
I remember one time
I remember one time somebody
I remember one time somebody hated
I remember one time somebody hated me
very
very intensely
which
which I
which I picked
which I picked up
which I picked up on
which I picked up on the
inner.
inner. It
which I picked up on the
inner. It was
inner. It was reported
which I picked up on the
inner. It was reported via
inner. It was reported via dream
which I picked up on the
inner. It was reported via dream from
somebody
somebody else
somebody else that
somebody else that this
somebody else that this energy
somebody else that this energy hated
somebody else that this energy hated me.
And
And uh
somebody else that this energy hated me.
And uh this
And uh this is
somebody else that this energy hated me.
And uh this is when
And uh this is when I
somebody else that this energy hated me.
And uh this is when I was
And uh this is when I was a
somebody else that this energy hated me.
And uh this is when I was a celebrity
And uh this is when I was a celebrity in
a
a different
a different realm,
a different realm, you
a different realm, you know,
a different realm, you know, in
a different realm, you know, in New
York.
York. I
a different realm, you know, in New
York. I had
York. I had the
a different realm, you know, in New
York. I had the biggest
York. I had the biggest practice
a different realm, you know, in New
York. I had the biggest practice in
York. I had the biggest practice in the
world,
world, in
world, in the
world, in the country
world, in the country and
world, in the country and all
world, in the country and all this.
world, in the country and all this. This
guy
guy hated
world, in the country and all this. This
guy hated me
guy hated me and
world, in the country and all this. This
guy hated me and I
guy hated me and I said,
world, in the country and all this. This
guy hated me and I said, "What
guy hated me and I said, "What does
world, in the country and all this. This
guy hated me and I said, "What does he
hate
hate me
hate me for?"
hate me for?" He
hate me for?" He envious
hate me for?" He envious your
hate me for?" He envious your power.
hate me for?" He envious your power. I
power?
power? What
hate me for?" He envious your power. I
power? What power?
I
I treat
I treat lots
I treat lots and
I treat lots and lots
I treat lots and lots of
I treat lots and lots of sick
I treat lots and lots of sick people.
What
What What
I treat lots and lots of sick people.
What What is
What What is he
I treat lots and lots of sick people.
What What is he talking
What What is he talking about?
A
A projection
A projection from
A projection from his
A projection from his own
A projection from his own unconscious,
A projection from his own unconscious, I
guess.
guess. Because
A projection from his own unconscious, I
guess. Because if
guess. Because if you
A projection from his own unconscious, I
guess. Because if you contextualize
things
things in
things in terms
things in terms of
things in terms of power,
things in terms of power, then
things in terms of power, then you
things in terms of power, then you see
that
that as
things in terms of power, then you see
that as power.
If
If a
If a million
If a million people
If a million people go,
If a million people go, does
If a million people go, does that
If a million people go, does that give
you
you power?
It
It doesn't
It doesn't change
It doesn't change who
It doesn't change who you
It doesn't change who you are
It doesn't change who you are one
It doesn't change who you are one iota.
You
You know
It doesn't change who you are one iota.
You know what
You know what we
It doesn't change who you are one iota.
You know what we were
You know what we were talking
It doesn't change who you are one iota.
You know what we were talking about
women
women before.
You
You see
women before.
You see what
You see what is
what
what is
is
is the
what is
is the magnificence
is the magnificence of
what is
is the magnificence of the
is the magnificence of the woman
what is
is the magnificence of the woman is
is the magnificence of the woman is the
divinity
divinity within
divinity within her
divinity within her womanhood.
divinity within her womanhood. It's
divinity within her womanhood. It's not
her
her womanhood
divinity within her womanhood. It's not
her womanhood per
her womanhood per se,
divinity within her womanhood. It's not
her womanhood per se, but
her womanhood per se, but the
divinity within her womanhood. It's not
her womanhood per se, but the divinity
expressing
expressing itself
expressing itself in
expressing itself in this
expressing itself in this particular
case
case as
expressing itself in this particular
case as femininity.
case as femininity. And
expressing itself in this particular
case as femininity. And when
case as femininity. And when we
expressing itself in this particular
case as femininity. And when we get
case as femininity. And when we get to
father's
father's day,
father's day, [laughter]
expressing
expressing itself
father's day, [laughter]
expressing itself as
expressing itself as masculinity.
father's day, [laughter]
expressing itself as masculinity. You
see,
see, those
see, those are
see, those are just
see, those are just the
see, those are just the world
see, those are just the world of
see, those are just the world of form.
It's
It's only
see, those are just the world of form.
It's only how
It's only how it
see, those are just the world of form.
It's only how it looks
It's only how it looks from
see, those are just the world of form.
It's only how it looks from a
It's only how it looks from a viewpoint
of
of perception.
of perception. The
of perception. The viewpoint
of perception. The viewpoint of
perception.
And
And as
And as consciousness
And as consciousness evolves,
And as consciousness evolves, it
transcends
transcends gender.
And as consciousness evolves, it
transcends gender. You
transcends gender. You know
And as consciousness evolves, it
transcends gender. You know that
transcends gender. You know that which
you
you are
you are has
you are has no
you are has no limitations
you are has no limitations such
you are has no limitations such as
gender
gender anyway.
All
All right.
All right. So
All right. So you've
All right. So you've already
All right. So you've already got
All right. So you've already got the
answer
answer to
All right. So you've already got the
answer to the
answer to the ultimate.
All right. So you've already got the
answer to the ultimate. The
answer to the ultimate. The one
All right. So you've already got the
answer to the ultimate. The one is
answer to the ultimate. The one is the
challenge
challenge to
challenge to love
challenge to love to
challenge to love to sacrifice
challenge to love to sacrifice love
challenge to love to sacrifice love for
gain
gain and
challenge to love to sacrifice love for
gain and power
gain and power over
challenge to love to sacrifice love for
gain and power over others
gain and power over others and
manipulation
manipulation sexual
manipulation sexual satisfaction
manipulation sexual satisfaction or
whatever.
The
The other
The other great
The other great temptation
is
is the
The other great temptation
is the luc
is the luc luciferica.
The
The teaching
The teaching that
The teaching that love
The teaching that love is
The teaching that love is an
The teaching that love is an attachment
and
and a
The teaching that love is an attachment
and a limitation
and a limitation and
The teaching that love is an attachment
and a limitation and a
and a limitation and a block
The teaching that love is an attachment
and a limitation and a block to
enlightenment
is
is a
enlightenment
is a major
is a major error.
We
We have
We have permission
We have permission to
We have permission to ask
We have permission to ask that
We have permission to ask that is
We have permission to ask that is a
statement
statement of
We have permission to ask that is a
statement of fact.
statement of fact. Is
We have permission to ask that is a
statement of fact. Is it
statement of fact. Is it that
We have permission to ask that is a
statement of fact. Is it that is
statement of fact. Is it that is a
statement
statement of
statement of fact
statement of fact and
statement of fact and you
statement of fact and you see
statement of fact and you see the
authority
authority background
statement of fact and you see the
authority background of
authority background of it
statement of fact and you see the
authority background of it is
authority background of it is the
misinterpretation
misinterpretation of
misinterpretation of the
misinterpretation of the Buddha
misinterpretation of the Buddha teaching
of
of u
misinterpretation of the Buddha teaching
of u the
of u the ultimate
misinterpretation of the Buddha teaching
of u the ultimate reality
of u the ultimate reality as
misinterpretation of the Buddha teaching
of u the ultimate reality as void.
Void
Void is
Void is nothingness.
What
What the
Void is nothingness.
What the Buddha
What the Buddha meant
Void is nothingness.
What the Buddha meant was
What the Buddha meant was no
Void is nothingness.
What the Buddha meant was no thingness.
Nothingness
Nothingness beyond
Nothingness beyond form.
Nothingness beyond form. What
Nothingness beyond form. What the
Nothingness beyond form. What the Buddha
said
said was
Nothingness beyond form. What the Buddha
said was that
said was that the
Nothingness beyond form. What the Buddha
said was that the ultimate
said was that the ultimate truth
Nothingness beyond form. What the Buddha
said was that the ultimate truth is
said was that the ultimate truth is the
unmanifest.
Beyond
Beyond form
is
is just
is just beyond
is just beyond form.
That's
That's different.
If
If the
If the void
If the void was
If the void was the
If the void was the absolute
If the void was the absolute reality,
there'd
there'd be
If the void was the absolute reality,
there'd be nobody
there'd be nobody to
If the void was the absolute reality,
there'd be nobody to tell
there'd be nobody to tell you
If the void was the absolute reality,
there'd be nobody to tell you about
there'd be nobody to tell you about it,
wouldn't
wouldn't there?
wouldn't there? [laughter]
First
First of
wouldn't there? [laughter]
First of all,
First of all, they'd
wouldn't there? [laughter]
First of all, they'd have
First of all, they'd have nothing
wouldn't there? [laughter]
First of all, they'd have nothing to
First of all, they'd have nothing to say
and
and there'd
and there'd be
and there'd be no
and there'd be no one
and there'd be no one there
and there'd be no one there to
and there'd be no one there to say
and there'd be no one there to say it.
The
The ego
and there'd be no one there to say it.
The ego will
The ego will create
and there'd be no one there to say it.
The ego will create a
The ego will create a feeling
and there'd be no one there to say it.
The ego will create a feeling of
oblivion
oblivion and
oblivion and you
oblivion and you go
oblivion and you go into
oblivion and you go into oblivion
because
because oblivion
oblivion and you go into oblivion
because oblivion is
because oblivion is not
oblivion and you go into oblivion
because oblivion is not the
because oblivion is not the same
oblivion and you go into oblivion
because oblivion is not the same as
because oblivion is not the same as the
ultimate
ultimate reality.
ultimate reality. You
ultimate reality. You can't
ultimate reality. You can't stay
ultimate reality. You can't stay there
and
and you
ultimate reality. You can't stay there
and you come
and you come out
ultimate reality. You can't stay there
and you come out of
and you come out of oblivion
ultimate reality. You can't stay there
and you come out of oblivion and
and you come out of oblivion and you
find
find yourself
find yourself three
find yourself three years
find yourself three years old
find yourself three years old in
find yourself three years old in a
little
little cart.
find yourself three years old in a
little cart. [laughter]
Shocked
Shocked to
Shocked to discover
Shocked to discover that
Shocked to discover that you
Shocked to discover that you have
Shocked to discover that you have a
Shocked to discover that you have a body
again.
People
People ask
People ask me
People ask me about
People ask me about the
People ask me about the various
religions
religions in
People ask me about the various
religions in the
religions in the world.
People ask me about the various
religions in the world. So
religions in the world. So far
People ask me about the various
religions in the world. So far the
religions in the world. So far the the
Buddhists
Buddhists have
Buddhists have uh
maintained
maintained the
Buddhists have uh
maintained the strictest
maintained the strictest purest.
Buddhists have uh
maintained the strictest purest. The
maintained the strictest purest. The m
the
the Buddhists
the Buddhists have
the Buddhists have maintained
the Buddhists have maintained the
highest
highest teaching.
the Buddhists have maintained the
highest teaching. People
highest teaching. People ask
the Buddhists have maintained the
highest teaching. People ask what's
highest teaching. People ask what's the
highest
highest teaching?
highest teaching? I
highest teaching? I think
highest teaching? I think uh
highest teaching? I think uh classic
Buddhism
the
the highest
the highest teaching
the highest teaching is
the highest teaching is classic
the highest teaching is classic Buddhism
is
is yeah
the highest teaching is classic Buddhism
is yeah classic
is yeah classic Buddhism
the highest teaching is classic Buddhism
is yeah classic Buddhism is
is yeah classic Buddhism is pretty
the highest teaching is classic Buddhism
is yeah classic Buddhism is pretty much
it
it hasn't
it hasn't sold
it hasn't sold out
it hasn't sold out for
it hasn't sold out for u
it hasn't sold out for u political
it hasn't sold out for u political gain
control
control political
it hasn't sold out for u political gain
control political power
control political power see
it hasn't sold out for u political gain
control political power see what
happened
happened with
happened with Christianity
happened with Christianity is
happened with Christianity is it
happened with Christianity is it got
sold
sold out
happened with Christianity is it got
sold out uh
sold out uh peace
happened with Christianity is it got
sold out uh peace me
sold out uh peace me all
happened with Christianity is it got
sold out uh peace me all doled
sold out uh peace me all doled out
happened with Christianity is it got
sold out uh peace me all doled out to
the
the various
the various rulers
the various rulers and
the various rulers and emperors
the various rulers and emperors and
various
various things
so
so far
so far Buddhism
so far Buddhism has
so far Buddhism has avoided
so far Buddhism has avoided God
so far Buddhism has avoided God I
so far Buddhism has avoided God I don't
know
know where
so far Buddhism has avoided God I don't
know where Hinduism
know where Hinduism is
so far Buddhism has avoided God I don't
know where Hinduism is currently.
know where Hinduism is currently. Let's
just
just see
just see where
just see where the
just see where the world
just see where the world is
just see where the world is at
currently.
Uh
Uh well,
Uh well, of
Uh well, of course,
Uh well, of course, you
Uh well, of course, you have
Uh well, of course, you have to
Uh well, of course, you have to be
Uh well, of course, you have to be quite
definite
definite how
Uh well, of course, you have to be quite
definite how you
definite how you express
Uh well, of course, you have to be quite
definite how you express this.
Uh
Uh current
Uh current Protest
Uh current Protest Protestantism
Uh current Protest Protestantism as
Uh current Protest Protestantism as it
is
is practiced
Uh current Protest Protestantism as it
is practiced in
is practiced in America.
Uh current Protest Protestantism as it
is practiced in America. Protestantism
in
in a
in a as
in a as a
in a as a general
in a as a general is
in a as a general is over
in a as a general is over 485,
in a as a general is over 485, 490,
in a as a general is over 485, 490, 495,
500,
500, 505.
Let
Let me
Let me write
Let me write this
Let me write this down.
Let me write this down. Protestantism
505 as
505 as of
Let me write this down. Protestantism
505 as of today.
Um
Protestantism
consciousness
consciousness level
consciousness level of
consciousness level of it
consciousness level of it is
consciousness level of it is falling
resist
rising
rising resist
it's
it's becoming
rising resist
it's becoming secularized
it's becoming secularized progressive.
Oh
Oh I
Oh I see
Oh I see it's
Oh I see it's destroyed
Oh I see it's destroyed by
secularization
secularization here.
Oh I see it's destroyed by
secularization here. All
secularization here. All right.
Oh I see it's destroyed by
secularization here. All right. So
secularization here. All right. So what
happens
happens is
happens is as
happens is as a
happens is as a religion
happens is as a religion gets
happens is as a religion gets older
happens is as a religion gets older is
it
it begins
happens is as a religion gets older is
it begins to
it begins to get
happens is as a religion gets older is
it begins to get secularized
it begins to get secularized by
happens is as a religion gets older is
it begins to get secularized by the
civilization
uh
uh uh
civilization
uh uh by
uh uh by the
civilization
uh uh by the civilization
uh uh by the civilization in
civilization
uh uh by the civilization in which
uh uh by the civilization in which it
finds
finds itself.
Um
Um you
finds itself.
Um you know
Um you know financial
finds itself.
Um you know financial considerations
Um you know financial considerations it
takes
takes money
takes money to
takes money to build
takes money to build churches
takes money to build churches and
takes money to build churches and you
got
got to
takes money to build churches and you
got to build
got to build a
takes money to build churches and you
got to build a congregation
got to build a congregation and
everything
everything costs
everything costs money.
everything costs money. You
everything costs money. You got
everything costs money. You got to
everything costs money. You got to have
insurance.
insurance. You
everything costs money. You got to have
insurance. You know what
insurance. You know what I
everything costs money. You got to have
insurance. You know what I mean?
Especially
Especially if
Especially if you're
Especially if you're a
Especially if you're a prison.
Imagine
Imagine the
Especially if you're a prison.
Imagine the malpractice
Imagine the malpractice insurance.
talking
talking about
talking about doctors.
talking about doctors. Yeah.
talking about doctors. Yeah. Jeez.
Uh
so
so of
so of the
so of the world's
so of the world's current
so of the world's current religion
so of the world's current religion let's
say
say well
so of the world's current religion let's
say well let's
say well let's ask
so of the world's current religion let's
say well let's ask for
say well let's ask for current
so of the world's current religion let's
say well let's ask for current we
say well let's ask for current we ask
so of the world's current religion let's
say well let's ask for current we ask we
can
can ask
can ask about
can ask about Hinduism
can ask about Hinduism is
can ask about Hinduism is Hinduism
can ask about Hinduism is Hinduism is
practiced
practiced um
can ask about Hinduism is Hinduism is
practiced um in
practiced um in its
can ask about Hinduism is Hinduism is
practiced um in its most
practiced um in its most pristine
can ask about Hinduism is Hinduism is
practiced um in its most pristine level
in
in India
in India currently
in India currently is
in India currently is over
in India currently is over 500
in India currently is over 500 is
in India currently is over 500 is 560
by
by 80
by 80 580
by 80 580 Hinduism
by 80 580 Hinduism ism
by 80 580 Hinduism ism at
by 80 580 Hinduism ism at its
by 80 580 Hinduism ism at its best
by 80 580 Hinduism ism at its best in
current
current India
current India comes
current India comes out
current India comes out of
current India comes out of 575.
current India comes out of 575. Hope
somebody's
somebody's writing
current India comes out of 575. Hope
somebody's writing this
somebody's writing this down
current India comes out of 575. Hope
somebody's writing this down because
afterwards
afterwards I
afterwards I don't
afterwards I don't remember
afterwards I don't remember any
afterwards I don't remember any of
afterwards I don't remember any of this.
Um
Hinduism
Hinduism you
Hinduism you were
Hinduism you were going
Hinduism you were going to
Hinduism you were going to ask
Hinduism you were going to ask about
Islam.
Islam. Islam
uh
uh as
uh as currently
uh as currently practiced
uh as currently practiced in
uh as currently practiced in the
uh as currently practiced in the Arabic
world
world uh
uh as currently practiced in the Arabic
world uh calibrates
world uh calibrates over
uh as currently practiced in the Arabic
world uh calibrates over 200
world uh calibrates over 200 resist.
uh as currently practiced in the Arabic
world uh calibrates over 200 resist. No
Islam
Islam has
Islam has just
Islam has just been
Islam has just been destroyed.
Destroyed.
uh
uh Christianity,
uh Christianity, Catholicism.
uh Christianity, Catholicism. Okay.
Catholicism
Catholicism in
uh Christianity, Catholicism. Okay.
Catholicism in the
Catholicism in the current
uh Christianity, Catholicism. Okay.
Catholicism in the current world
exclusive
exclusive of
priestly
priestly events
exclusive of
priestly events is
priestly events is over
exclusive of
priestly events is over 500
priestly events is over 500 510.
Catholicism
at
at its
Catholicism
at its best,
at its best, at
Catholicism
at its best, at its
at its best, at its pristine
Catholicism
at its best, at its pristine best
at its best, at its pristine best in
current
current America
current America is
current America is over
current America is over 510.
It's
It's over
current America is over 510.
It's over 509.
It's over 509. It's
current America is over 510.
It's over 509. It's about
It's over 509. It's about 510.
current America is over 510.
It's over 509. It's about 510. 50
It's over 509. It's about 510. 50 it's
over
over 505
over 505 506
it's
it's loving
over 505 506
it's loving it's
it's loving it's loving
over 505 506
it's loving it's loving but
it's loving it's loving but it
over 505 506
it's loving it's loving but it has
it's loving it's loving but it has lost
its
its pristine
its pristine don't
its pristine don't forget
its pristine don't forget in
its pristine don't forget in the
beginning
beginning it
its pristine don't forget in the
beginning it was
beginning it was a
its pristine don't forget in the
beginning it was a thousand
uh
uh at
uh at the
uh at the time
uh at the time of
uh at the time of Christ
uh at the time of Christ Christianity
was
was a thousand
uh at the time of Christ Christianity
was a thousand so
was a thousand so it's
uh at the time of Christ Christianity
was a thousand so it's come
was a thousand so it's come down
considerably
Islam
Islam has
considerably
Islam has come
Islam has come down
considerably
Islam has come down considerably
Hinduism
Hinduism still
Hinduism still maintains
Hinduism still maintains it
Hinduism still maintains it what
Hinduism still maintains it what do
Hinduism still maintains it what do we
say
say 575
Hinduism still maintains it what do we
say 575 that's
say 575 that's very
Hinduism still maintains it what do we
say 575 that's very high
say 575 that's very high 575
and
It's
It's close
and
It's close to
It's close to enlightenment
and
It's close to enlightenment at
It's close to enlightenment at 600.
and
It's close to enlightenment at 600. Wow.
And
And Buddhism
And Buddhism has
And Buddhism has declined
And Buddhism has declined the
And Buddhism has declined the least.
Let's
Let's see
And Buddhism has declined the least.
Let's see what
Let's see what Buddhism
And Buddhism has declined the least.
Let's see what Buddhism is
Let's see what Buddhism is at
And Buddhism has declined the least.
Let's see what Buddhism is at currently.
>> Let's
>> Let's see.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, I'll
>> Let's see.
>> Yeah, I'll have
>> Yeah, I'll have to.
>> Yes,
>> Yes, I'll
>> Yes, I'll define
>> Yes, I'll define classically.
Um,
Um, okay.
Uh,
Uh, the
Uh, the vehicle
Uh, the vehicle uh
Uh, the vehicle uh Henana,
we
we have
Uh, the vehicle uh Henana,
we have permission
we have permission to
Uh, the vehicle uh Henana,
we have permission to ask
we have permission to ask about
Uh, the vehicle uh Henana,
we have permission to ask about Henana.
Hinana
Hinana calibrates
Hinana calibrates over
Hinana calibrates over 800
Hinana calibrates over 800 850.
Hinana calibrates over 800 850. Sorry.
Hana
Hana Buddhism
Hinana calibrates over 800 850. Sorry.
Hana Buddhism is
Hana Buddhism is practiced
Hinana calibrates over 800 850. Sorry.
Hana Buddhism is practiced today
calibrates
calibrates over
calibrates over 850
860 870
860 870 870
calibrates over 850
860 870 870 Okay,
860 870 870 Okay, we
calibrates over 850
860 870 870 Okay, we got
860 870 870 Okay, we got 870.
calibrates over 850
860 870 870 Okay, we got 870. Somebody
put
put that
put that down.
put that down. Uh
Mahana,
which
which includes
which includes Zen
which includes Zen calibrates
which includes Zen calibrates over
which includes Zen calibrates over 850,
860,
860, 865.
Did
Did we
Did we get
Did we get 860
Did we get 860 for
Did we get 860 for both
Did we get 860 for both of
Did we get 860 for both of them?
>> Somebody's
>> Somebody's writing
Did we get 860 for both of them?
>> Somebody's writing it
>> Somebody's writing it down.
Did we get 860 for both of them?
>> Somebody's writing it down. Huh?
>> 870.
>> 870. Let's
>> 870. Let's do
>> 870. Let's do it
>> 870. Let's do it again.
>> 870. Let's do it again. Hinana
>> 870. Let's do it again. Hinana and
Mahayana
Mahayana are
>> 870. Let's do it again. Hinana and
Mahayana are almost
Mahayana are almost identical
>> 870. Let's do it again. Hinana and
Mahayana are almost identical as
Mahayana are almost identical as far
>> 870. Let's do it again. Hinana and
Mahayana are almost identical as far as
calibrated
calibrated level
calibrated level consciousness
resistance.
resistance. Yeah,
calibrated level consciousness
resistance. Yeah, they're
resistance. Yeah, they're almost
identical.
identical. One
identical. One is
identical. One is the
identical. One is the lesser
identical. One is the lesser vehicle,
one
one is
identical. One is the lesser vehicle,
one is the
one is the greater
identical. One is the lesser vehicle,
one is the greater vehicle.
Uh
lotus
lotus land
Uh
lotus land Buddhism
lotus land Buddhism is
Uh
lotus land Buddhism is something
lotus land Buddhism is something else.
Let's
Let's do
Let's do lotus
Let's do lotus land.
Let's do lotus land. Lotus
Let's do lotus land. Lotus land
Let's do lotus land. Lotus land is
Let's do lotus land. Lotus land is the
closest
closest to
Let's do lotus land. Lotus land is the
closest to Christianity.
closest to Christianity. We
Let's do lotus land. Lotus land is the
closest to Christianity. We have
permission
permission to
permission to do
permission to do lotus
permission to do lotus land
permission to do lotus land in
permission to do lotus land in front
permission to do lotus land in front of
this
this audience.
permission to do lotus land in front of
this audience. Resist
this audience. Resist lotus
permission to do lotus land in front of
this audience. Resist lotus land.
this audience. Resist lotus land. We
have
have permission
have permission in
have permission in front
have permission in front of
have permission in front of this
audience.
audience. Resist.
Uh,
Uh, it's
Uh, it's over
Uh, it's over 550,
Uh, it's over 550, 580,
Uh, it's over 550, 580, 590,
Uh, it's over 550, 580, 590, 600.
Lotus
Lotus land
Uh, it's over 550, 580, 590, 600.
Lotus land is
Lotus land is right
Uh, it's over 550, 580, 590, 600.
Lotus land is right at
Lotus land is right at 600.
Uh, it's over 550, 580, 590, 600.
Lotus land is right at 600. Resist.
Yeah,
Yeah, I
Yeah, I would
Yeah, I would suspect
Yeah, I would suspect so.
Lotus
Lotus land
Yeah, I would suspect so.
Lotus land is
Lotus land is right
Yeah, I would suspect so.
Lotus land is right at
Lotus land is right at 600.
Lotus
Lotus land
Lotus land is
Lotus land is the
Lotus land is the Buddha
Lotus land is the Buddha of
Lotus land is the Buddha of salvation
Lotus land is the Buddha of salvation in
which
which the
Lotus land is the Buddha of salvation in
which the Buddha
which the Buddha becomes
Lotus land is the Buddha of salvation in
which the Buddha becomes the
which the Buddha becomes the savior.
It's
It's the
It's the equivalent
It's the equivalent of
It's the equivalent of Christianity.
The
The rad
It's the equivalent of Christianity.
The rad the
The rad the radical
spiritual
spiritual the
spiritual the spiritual
spiritual the spiritual realist
spiritual the spiritual realist you
might
might say
[laughter]
this
this the
[laughter]
this the spiritual
this the spiritual teacher
[laughter]
this the spiritual teacher has
this the spiritual teacher has been
kicked
kicked around
kicked around throughout
kicked around throughout the
kicked around throughout the centuries
realizes
that
that in
that in this
that in this world
that in this world which
that in this world which calibrated
that in this world which calibrated less
than
than 190
that in this world which calibrated less
than 190 over
than 190 over the
that in this world which calibrated less
than 190 over the many
than 190 over the many centuries
that
that the
that the best
that the best you
that the best you could
that the best you could hope
that the best you could hope for
that the best you could hope for was
that the best you could hope for was to
reach
reach unconditional
that the best you could hope for was to
reach unconditional love
don't
don't forget
don't forget in
don't forget in a
don't forget in a world
don't forget in a world that's
don't forget in a world that's dominated
by
by hatred
don't forget in a world that's dominated
by hatred love
by hatred love I
don't forget in a world that's dominated
by hatred love I mean
by hatred love I mean hatred
don't forget in a world that's dominated
by hatred love I mean hatred anger
Starvation,
Starvation, war,
Starvation, war, killing,
Starvation, war, killing, rape,
Starvation, war, killing, rape, suicide.
500 is
500 is almost
Starvation, war, killing, rape, suicide.
500 is almost astronomical.
Almost
Almost astronomical.
So
So in
So in a
So in a way
So in a way Jesus
So in a way Jesus Christ
the
the lotus
So in a way Jesus Christ
the lotus land
the lotus land Buddhist
So in a way Jesus Christ
the lotus land Buddhist the
the lotus land Buddhist the Buddha
So in a way Jesus Christ
the lotus land Buddhist the Buddha of
salvation
uh
uh the
salvation
uh the great
uh the great savior
salvation
uh the great savior is
uh the great savior is saying
salvation
uh the great savior is saying aim
uh the great savior is saying aim for
500 or
500 or 540
500 or 540 and
500 or 540 and from
500 or 540 and from there
500 or 540 and from there on
500 or 540 and from there on you
500 or 540 and from there on you don't
have
have to
500 or 540 and from there on you don't
have to worry
have to worry let's
500 or 540 and from there on you don't
have to worry let's see
have to worry let's see if
500 or 540 and from there on you don't
have to worry let's see if that's
have to worry let's see if that's true
you
you get
you get to
you get to 540
you get to 540 you
you get to 540 you won't
you get to 540 you won't have
you get to 540 you won't have to
you get to 540 you won't have to worry
[laughter]
you
you get
you get the
you get the unconditional
you get the unconditional love
you get the unconditional love you
you get the unconditional love you won't
have
have to
you get the unconditional love you won't
have to worry
>> speak
Native
Native American
>> I
>> I did
>> I did uh
>> I did uh the
>> I did uh the Native
>> I did uh the Native American.
>> I did uh the Native American. See
>> I did uh the Native American. See the
Native
Native American
>> I did uh the Native American. See the
Native American was
Native American was a
>> I did uh the Native American. See the
Native American was a monotheist.
Native American was a monotheist. Said
it
it said
it said the
it said the history
it said the history of
it said the history of religion
it said the history of religion will
tell
tell you
it said the history of religion will
tell you the
tell you the first
it said the history of religion will
tell you the first monotheists
tell you the first monotheists were
it said the history of religion will
tell you the first monotheists were in
ancient
ancient Egypt.
ancient Egypt. U
ancient Egypt. U the
ancient Egypt. U the sun
ancient Egypt. U the sun god
ancient Egypt. U the sun god a
ancient Egypt. U the sun god a kenan
wasn't
wasn't it?
ancient Egypt. U the sun god a kenan
wasn't it? EA
wasn't it? EA econom
ancient Egypt. U the sun god a kenan
wasn't it? EA econom econ
wasn't it? EA econom econ somebody
was
was the
was the for
was the for was
was the for was the
was the for was the launching
was the for was the launching of
monotheism
monotheism for
was the for was the launching of
monotheism for the
monotheism for the first
was the for was the launching of
monotheism for the first time
monotheism for the first time about
was the for was the launching of
monotheism for the first time about 500
BC
or
or 5,000
BC
or 5,000 BC
or 5,000 BC somewhere
BC
or 5,000 BC somewhere around
or 5,000 BC somewhere around there
[laughter]
[sighs and gasps]
somewhere
somewhere around
somewhere around there.
somewhere around there. What
somewhere around there. What was
somewhere around there. What was her
question?
>> What
>> What was
>> What was their
>> What was their question?
>> Oh,
>> Oh, a
>> What was their question?
>> Oh, a Native
>> Oh, a Native American.
>> What was their question?
>> Oh, a Native American. Yes.
>> Oh, a Native American. Yes. All
>> What was their question?
>> Oh, a Native American. Yes. All right.
So
So the
So the great
So the great accomplishment
So the great accomplishment there
So the great accomplishment there was
the
the pagan
So the great accomplishment there was
the pagan tribes
uh
and
and the
uh
and the reason
and the reason ancient
uh
and the reason ancient Egypt
and the reason ancient Egypt rejected
that
that particular
uh
uh ruler
that particular
uh ruler is
uh ruler is he
that particular
uh ruler is he brought
uh ruler is he brought in
that particular
uh ruler is he brought in monotheism
just
just like
just like in
uh
uh later
just like in
uh later Roman
uh later Roman culture
just like in
uh later Roman culture there
uh later Roman culture there were
just like in
uh later Roman culture there were many
gods
gods numerous
gods numerous gods.
gods numerous gods. So
gods numerous gods. So we
gods numerous gods. So we say
gods numerous gods. So we say primitive
religion
religion tended
gods numerous gods. So we say primitive
religion tended to
religion tended to have
gods numerous gods. So we say primitive
religion tended to have numerous
religion tended to have numerous gods,
gods numerous gods. So we say primitive
religion tended to have numerous gods, a
pantheon
pantheon of
pantheon of gods
pantheon of gods which
pantheon of gods which still
pantheon of gods which still exist
pantheon of gods which still exist to
this
this day
pantheon of gods which still exist to
this day uh
this day uh in
pantheon of gods which still exist to
this day uh in Hinduism.
this day uh in Hinduism. Each
pantheon of gods which still exist to
this day uh in Hinduism. Each one
this day uh in Hinduism. Each one you
might
might say
might say are
might say are subdivisions
might say are subdivisions of
might say are subdivisions of deity
divided
divided into
might say are subdivisions of deity
divided into various
divided into various representations.
What
What was
What was the
What was the question?
>> Oh,
>> Oh, Native
What was the question?
>> Oh, Native American.
>> Oh, Native American. Yes.
What was the question?
>> Oh, Native American. Yes. All
>> Oh, Native American. Yes. All right.
What was the question?
>> Oh, Native American. Yes. All right. So
the
the Native
the Native American,
the Native American, you
the Native American, you see,
the Native American, you see, was
the Native American, you see, was into
monotheism.
Of
Of course,
Of course, we
Of course, we don't
Of course, we don't know
Of course, we don't know how
Of course, we don't know how far
Of course, we don't know how far back
their
their history
Of course, we don't know how far back
their history is,
their history is, what
Of course, we don't know how far back
their history is, what their
their history is, what their teachings
were
were back
were back that
were back that far.
were back that far. Ancient
were back that far. Ancient Egypt,
were back that far. Ancient Egypt, we
still
still have,
were back that far. Ancient Egypt, we
still have, you
still have, you know,
were back that far. Ancient Egypt, we
still have, you know, actually
still have, you know, actually the
writings
writings from
writings from those
writings from those days,
writings from those days, but
writings from those days, but the
writings from those days, but the Native
American
American believed
writings from those days, but the Native
American believed in
American believed in uh
writings from those days, but the Native
American believed in uh the
American believed in uh the great
writings from those days, but the Native
American believed in uh the great spirit
was
was already
was already a
was already a monotheist
actually
actually was
was already a monotheist
actually was a
actually was a monotheist.
was already a monotheist
actually was a monotheist. And
actually was a monotheist. And I
was already a monotheist
actually was a monotheist. And I think
we
we we
we we calibrated
we we calibrated Chief
we we calibrated Chief Detroit
we we calibrated Chief Detroit who's
very
very famous.
we we calibrated Chief Detroit who's
very famous. Anybody
very famous. Anybody here
we we calibrated Chief Detroit who's
very famous. Anybody here familiar
very famous. Anybody here familiar with
the
his
his recitations
the
his recitations of
his recitations of Chief
the
his recitations of Chief Detroit
his recitations of Chief Detroit are
quite
quite profound.
quite profound. All
quite profound. All right.
quite profound. All right. Chief
quite profound. All right. Chief Detroit
who
who is
quite profound. All right. Chief Detroit
who is an
who is an airquay
quite profound. All right. Chief Detroit
who is an airquay uh
who is an airquay uh calibrated
quite profound. All right. Chief Detroit
who is an airquay uh calibrated over
who is an airquay uh calibrated over 700
resists
resists 710
resists 710 720
resists 710 720 730
resists 710 720 730 730
resists 710 720 730 730 that's
resists 710 720 730 730 that's higher
than
than Muhammad
resists 710 720 730 730 that's higher
than Muhammad Muhammad
than Muhammad Muhammad came
resists 710 720 730 730 that's higher
than Muhammad Muhammad came in
than Muhammad Muhammad came in at
resists 710 720 730 730 that's higher
than Muhammad Muhammad came in at 731
so
so that
so that capacity
so that capacity to
so that capacity to realize
so that capacity to realize the
so that capacity to realize the presence
of
of an
so that capacity to realize the presence
of an infinite
infinite
infinite oneness
infinite oneness the
infinite oneness the infinite
infinite oneness the infinite divinity
out
out of
infinite oneness the infinite divinity
out of which
out of which all
infinite oneness the infinite divinity
out of which all of
out of which all of creation
infinite oneness the infinite divinity
out of which all of creation manifests
See,
See, the
See, the Native
See, the Native American
See, the Native American could
See, the Native American could see
See, the Native American could see the
expression
expression of
See, the Native American could see the
expression of divinity
expression of divinity in
See, the Native American could see the
expression of divinity in all
expression of divinity in all things
that
that live.
that live. Brother
that live. Brother elk,
that live. Brother elk, brother
that live. Brother elk, brother Rabbit,
apologizing
apologizing to
u
u the
u the fact
u the fact I've
u the fact I've got
u the fact I've got to
u the fact I've got to knock
u the fact I've got to knock you
u the fact I've got to knock you out
u the fact I've got to knock you out of
body.
See,
See, the
See, the animal
See, the animal doesn't
See, the animal doesn't die
See, the animal doesn't die when
See, the animal doesn't die when you
knock
knock it
See, the animal doesn't die when you
knock it out
knock it out of
See, the animal doesn't die when you
knock it out of body.
knock it out of body. It
See, the animal doesn't die when you
knock it out of body. It just
knock it out of body. It just gets
knocked
knocked out
knocked out of
knocked out of body.
knocked out of body. Let's
knocked out of body. Let's see.
knocked out of body. Let's see. That's
knocked out of body. Let's see. That's a
fact.
fact. It's
knocked out of body. Let's see. That's a
fact. It's just
fact. It's just Yeah,
knocked out of body. Let's see. That's a
fact. It's just Yeah, it
fact. It's just Yeah, it hardly
sometimes
sometimes hardly
sometimes hardly animal
sometimes hardly animal hardly
sometimes hardly animal hardly even
notices
notices it.
sometimes hardly animal hardly even
notices it. The
notices it. The animal
sometimes hardly animal hardly even
notices it. The animal doesn't
notices it. The animal doesn't really
notice
notice it
notice it most
notice it most of
notice it most of the
notice it most of the time.
notice it most of the time. He's
notice it most of the time. He's just
doesn't
doesn't notice
notice it most of the time. He's just
doesn't notice it
doesn't notice it most
notice it most of the time. He's just
doesn't notice it most of
doesn't notice it most of the
notice it most of the time. He's just
doesn't notice it most of the time.
doesn't notice it most of the time. It's
flying
flying around
flying around in
flying around in a
flying around in a little
flying around in a little flies
flying around in a little flies body.
Swat.
Swat. Now
flying around in a little flies body.
Swat. Now it's
Swat. Now it's flying
flying around in a little flies body.
Swat. Now it's flying around
Swat. Now it's flying around in
flying around in a little flies body.
Swat. Now it's flying around in his
little
little atheric
little atheric body.
little atheric body. It
little atheric body. It doesn't
little atheric body. It doesn't even
really
really notice.
little atheric body. It doesn't even
really notice. It
really notice. It comes
little atheric body. It doesn't even
really notice. It comes back
really notice. It comes back in
little atheric body. It doesn't even
really notice. It comes back in through
another
another egg
another egg and
another egg and it's
another egg and it's flying
another egg and it's flying and
another egg and it's flying and it's
another egg and it's flying and it's got
amnesia.
amnesia. It's
another egg and it's flying and it's got
amnesia. It's got
amnesia. It's got amnesia
another egg and it's flying and it's got
amnesia. It's got amnesia for
amnesia. It's got amnesia for that.
another egg and it's flying and it's got
amnesia. It's got amnesia for that. It
doesn't
doesn't even
doesn't even remember
doesn't even remember that
doesn't even remember that it
doesn't even remember that it was
doesn't even remember that it was and
then
then wasn't.
doesn't even remember that it was and
then wasn't. That
then wasn't. That doesn't
doesn't even remember that it was and
then wasn't. That doesn't worry
then wasn't. That doesn't worry worry
about
about not
about not being
about not being because
about not being because it
about not being because it doesn't
remember
remember that
about not being because it doesn't
remember that it
remember that it wasn't.
[laughter]
So
So the
[laughter]
So the Native
So the Native American
[laughter]
So the Native American already
So the Native American already knew
[laughter]
So the Native American already knew that
the
the actually
the actually the
the actually the animal
the actually the animal doesn't
the actually the animal doesn't actually
die.
die. It
the actually the animal doesn't actually
die. It sacrifices
die. It sacrifices this
physical
physical manifestation.
physical manifestation. Now
physical manifestation. Now I
physical manifestation. Now I has
physical manifestation. Now I has to
physical manifestation. Now I has to go
around
around the
physical manifestation. Now I has to go
around the other
around the other side
physical manifestation. Now I has to go
around the other side and
around the other side and wait
physical manifestation. Now I has to go
around the other side and wait to
around the other side and wait to come
back
back again.
back again. And
back again. And so
back again. And so he
back again. And so he says,
back again. And so he says, "Thank
back again. And so he says, "Thank you,
brother,
brother, for
back again. And so he says, "Thank you,
brother, for giving
brother, for giving up
back again. And so he says, "Thank you,
brother, for giving up your
brother, for giving up your physicality
for
for the
for the maintenance
for the maintenance of
for the maintenance of my
for the maintenance of my physicality.
And
And uh
for the maintenance of my physicality.
And uh don't
And uh don't take
for the maintenance of my physicality.
And uh don't take this
And uh don't take this personally,
for the maintenance of my physicality.
And uh don't take this personally, but
And uh don't take this personally, but I
got
got to
got to eat
got to eat you."
got to eat you." [laughter]
[laughter]
All right.
All right. So
All right. So the
All right. So the inlect
All right. So the inlect puts
All right. So the inlect puts that
All right. So the inlect puts that down
as
as what
All right. So the inlect puts that down
as what is
as what is it?
All right. So the inlect puts that down
as what is it? Pantheism
and
and Catholicism.
and Catholicism. It's
and Catholicism. It's a
and Catholicism. It's a it's
and Catholicism. It's a it's a
and Catholicism. It's a it's a it's
and Catholicism. It's a it's a it's an
error
error to
and Catholicism. It's a it's a it's an
error to see
error to see divinity
and Catholicism. It's a it's a it's an
error to see divinity in
error to see divinity in all
and Catholicism. It's a it's a it's an
error to see divinity in all of
error to see divinity in all of nature
and
and all
and all that
and all that exists
and all that exists because
and all that exists because traditional
religion
religion tends
and all that exists because traditional
religion tends to
religion tends to be
and all that exists because traditional
religion tends to be uh
religion tends to be uh seeing
and all that exists because traditional
religion tends to be uh seeing God
religion tends to be uh seeing God as
transcendent.
You
You see
transcendent.
You see the
You see the probably
transcendent.
You see the probably the
You see the probably the reason
transcendent.
You see the probably the reason Buddhism
comes
comes up
comes up so
comes up so high
comes up so high is
comes up so high is because
comes up so high is because the
comes up so high is because the Buddha
taught
taught that
comes up so high is because the Buddha
taught that the
taught that the realization
comes up so high is because the Buddha
taught that the realization of
taught that the realization of the
absolute
absolute truth
by
by whatever
absolute truth
by whatever you
by whatever you call
absolute truth
by whatever you call it
by whatever you call it divinity
absolute truth
by whatever you call it divinity or
by whatever you call it divinity or the
ultimate
ultimate or
ultimate or reality.
He
He called
ultimate or reality.
He called it
He called it the
ultimate or reality.
He called it the Buddha
He called it the Buddha nature
ultimate or reality.
He called it the Buddha nature is
He called it the Buddha nature is merely
to
to realize
to realize that
to realize that which
to realize that which we
to realize that which we talked
to realize that which we talked about
this
this morning
to realize that which we talked about
this morning that
this morning that which
to realize that which we talked about
this morning that which you
this morning that which you really
to realize that which we talked about
this morning that which you really are
that
that instant
that instant right
that instant right before
that instant right before mind
that instant right before mind gets
that instant right before mind gets in
and
and interrupts
that instant right before mind gets in
and interrupts your
and interrupts your awareness
that instant right before mind gets in
and interrupts your awareness of
and interrupts your awareness of who
that instant right before mind gets in
and interrupts your awareness of who you
are.
So
So the
are.
So the Buddha
So the Buddha said
are.
So the Buddha said God
So the Buddha said God is
are.
So the Buddha said God is is
So the Buddha said God is is imminent
imminent
imminent not.
imminent not. So
imminent not. So the
imminent not. So the ultimate
imminent not. So the ultimate divine
divinity
divinity is
imminent not. So the ultimate divine
divinity is both
divinity is both imminent
imminent not. So the ultimate divine
divinity is both imminent within
divinity is both imminent within as
imminent not. So the ultimate divine
divinity is both imminent within as the
self
self with
self with a
self with a capital
self with a capital S
self with a capital S and
self with a capital S and transcendent
as
as the
self with a capital S and transcendent
as the supreme.
as the supreme. When
self with a capital S and transcendent
as the supreme. When Krishna
as the supreme. When Krishna writes
self with a capital S and transcendent
as the supreme. When Krishna writes of
the
the supreme
he
he really
the supreme
he really it's
he really it's really
the supreme
he really it's really meant
he really it's really meant to
the supreme
he really it's really meant to be
he really it's really meant to be not
only
only the
only the supreme
only the supreme transcendent
only the supreme transcendent but
only the supreme transcendent but the
the
the supreme
only the supreme transcendent but the
the supreme imminent
the supreme imminent as
only the supreme transcendent but the
the supreme imminent as the
the supreme imminent as the self
as
as that
as that the
as that the essence
as that the essence of
as that the essence of that
as that the essence of that which
as that the essence of that which you
are.
are. So
as that the essence of that which you
are. So the
are. So the Native
as that the essence of that which you
are. So the Native American
are. So the Native American then
as that the essence of that which you
are. So the Native American then was
quite
quite evolved,
quite evolved, quite
quite evolved, quite evolved
and
and um
quite evolved, quite evolved
and um happily
and um happily didn't
quite evolved, quite evolved
and um happily didn't know
and um happily didn't know he
quite evolved, quite evolved
and um happily didn't know he was
evolved
evolved or
evolved or he
evolved or he would
evolved or he would have
evolved or he would have made
evolved or he would have made a
evolved or he would have made a thing
out
out of
evolved or he would have made a thing
out of it,
out of it, [laughter]
chopped
chopped it
chopped it to
chopped it to pieces.
chopped it to pieces. You
chopped it to pieces. You know
chopped it to pieces. You know what
chopped it to pieces. You know what I'm
saying?
saying? Uh
addiction
addiction is
addiction is a
addiction is a whole
addiction is a whole story
addiction is a whole story in
addiction is a whole story in itself.
addiction is a whole story in itself. I
don't know
don't know if
addiction is a whole story in itself. I
don't know if we
don't know if we have
addiction is a whole story in itself. I
don't know if we have time
don't know if we have time to
addiction is a whole story in itself. I
don't know if we have time to do
addiction.
addiction. We'll
addiction. We'll do
addiction. We'll do addiction
addiction. We'll do addiction then
addiction. We'll do addiction then we'll
break
break again.
addiction. We'll do addiction then we'll
break again. Uh
break again. Uh I
addiction. We'll do addiction then we'll
break again. Uh I did
break again. Uh I did a
addiction. We'll do addiction then we'll
break again. Uh I did a you
break again. Uh I did a you know
probably
probably one
probably one of
probably one of the
probably one of the first
probably one of the first lectures
probably one of the first lectures on
consciousness
consciousness and
probably one of the first lectures on
consciousness and was
consciousness and was on
probably one of the first lectures on
consciousness and was on addiction
consciousness and was on addiction back
in
in the
in the early
in the early 80s.
I
I did
in the early 80s.
I did it
I did it in
in the early 80s.
I did it in California
I did it in California at
in the early 80s.
I did it in California at a
I did it in California at a conference
on
on consciousness
on consciousness and
on consciousness and addiction.
My
My understanding
on consciousness and addiction.
My understanding of
My understanding of addiction
on consciousness and addiction.
My understanding of addiction at
My understanding of addiction at that
time
time was
time was that
time was that you
time was that you see
time was that you see all
time was that you see all this
time was that you see all this stuff
from
from here
time was that you see all this stuff
from here down
from here down is
time was that you see all this stuff
from here down is painful.
Uh
painful
painful as
Uh
painful as compared
painful as compared to
Uh
painful as compared to it's
painful as compared to it's not
Uh
painful as compared to it's not being
there.
Drugs
Drugs drugs
there.
Drugs drugs block
Drugs drugs block out
there.
Drugs drugs block out your
Drugs drugs block out your experiencing
of
of all
of all this
of all this here.
A
A drug
of all this here.
A drug itself
A drug itself only
of all this here.
A drug itself only calibrates
A drug itself only calibrates around
of all this here.
A drug itself only calibrates around 75
or
or 80.
Alcohol
Alcohol calibrates
or 80.
Alcohol calibrates around
Alcohol calibrates around 75.
Drug
Drug calibrate
Drug calibrate around
Drug calibrate around 75
Drug calibrate around 75 to
Drug calibrate around 75 to 80.
Drug calibrate around 75 to 80. See,
Drug calibrate around 75 to 80. See, as
chemicals,
chemicals, these
Drug calibrate around 75 to 80. See, as
chemicals, these chemicals
chemicals, these chemicals just
calibrate
calibrate around
calibrate around 75
calibrate around 75 or
calibrate around 75 or 80.
Uh
the
the awareness
the awareness of
the awareness of the
the awareness of the presence
the awareness of the presence of
God
God within
the awareness of the presence of
God within is
God within is blocked
the awareness of the presence of
God within is blocked by
the
the conversation
the conversation and
the conversation and the
the conversation and the energy
the conversation and the energy fields
of
of the
the conversation and the energy fields
of the ego.
It's
It's like
It's like the
It's like the clouds
It's like the clouds in
It's like the clouds in the
It's like the clouds in the sky
It's like the clouds in the sky block
off
off the
It's like the clouds in the sky block
off the radiance
off the radiance of
It's like the clouds in the sky block
off the radiance of the
off the radiance of the sun.
What
What the
What the drugs
What the drugs do
What the drugs do is
What the drugs do is silence
What the drugs do is silence these
energy
energy fields.
Anesthetize
Anesthetize them.
Anesthetize them. Therefore,
Anesthetize them. Therefore, you
Anesthetize them. Therefore, you only
feel
feel the
Anesthetize them. Therefore, you only
feel the radiance
feel the radiance of
Anesthetize them. Therefore, you only
feel the radiance of the
feel the radiance of the higher
vibrations.
vibrations. Now,
vibrations. Now, all
vibrations. Now, all these
vibrations. Now, all these vibrations
are
are going
vibrations. Now, all these vibrations
are going on
are going on at
vibrations. Now, all these vibrations
are going on at once.
are going on at once. Let's
vibrations. Now, all these vibrations
are going on at once. Let's say
are going on at once. Let's say light
comes
comes through
comes through a
comes through a spectrum.
comes through a spectrum. You
comes through a spectrum. You see
comes through a spectrum. You see the
radiance.
radiance. If
comes through a spectrum. You see the
radiance. If I
radiance. If I block
comes through a spectrum. You see the
radiance. If I block all
radiance. If I block all these
comes through a spectrum. You see the
radiance. If I block all these off
radiance. If I block all these off now
you
you experience
you experience this
you experience this is
you experience this is who
you experience this is who I
you experience this is who I am.
you experience this is who I am. Huh?
The
The experience
you experience this is who I am. Huh?
The experience even
The experience even if
you experience this is who I am. Huh?
The experience even if experienced
The experience even if experienced once
is
is like
is like a
is like a near-death
is like a near-death experience.
is like a near-death experience. The
first
first time
is like a near-death experience. The
first time you
first time you get
is like a near-death experience. The
first time you get high,
first time you get high, you
is like a near-death experience. The
first time you get high, you already
first time you get high, you already got
it.
First
First time
it.
First time you
First time you feel
it.
First time you feel that
First time you feel that lovely,
gorgeous,
gorgeous, I
gorgeous, I love
gorgeous, I love everybody.
gorgeous, I love everybody. Isn't
gorgeous, I love everybody. Isn't life
grand?
Whoa.
You
You got
Whoa.
You got it
You got it right
Whoa.
You got it right now.
You got it right now. Right
Whoa.
You got it right now. Right that
You got it right now. Right that moment.
Anybody
Anybody who
Anybody who doesn't
Anybody who doesn't keep
Anybody who doesn't keep repeating
Anybody who doesn't keep repeating that
must
must be
Anybody who doesn't keep repeating that
must be stupid.
must be stupid. [laughter]
I
I say
I say I'm
I say I'm going
I say I'm going to
I say I'm going to go
I say I'm going to go back
I say I'm going to go back to
I say I'm going to go back to here,
I say I'm going to go back to here, go
to
to the
I say I'm going to go back to here, go
to the office,
to the office, and
I say I'm going to go back to here, go
to the office, and be
to the office, and be poed
I say I'm going to go back to here, go
to the office, and be poed at
to the office, and be poed at my
I say I'm going to go back to here, go
to the office, and be poed at my boss
and
and worry
and worry about
and worry about my
and worry about my What's
and worry about my What's the
and worry about my What's the matter
with
with that
and worry about my What's the matter
with that idiot?
with that idiot? Why
and worry about my What's the matter
with that idiot? Why didn't
with that idiot? Why didn't he
and worry about my What's the matter
with that idiot? Why didn't he just
block
block it
block it off
block it off and
block it off and stay
block it off and stay there?
block it off and stay there? Stay
block it off and stay there? Stay stoned
and
and live
block it off and stay there? Stay stoned
and live there.
and live there. You
block it off and stay there? Stay stoned
and live there. You know
and live there. You know what
block it off and stay there? Stay stoned
and live there. You know what I'm
saying?
That's
That's what
saying?
That's what the
That's what the voice
saying?
That's what the voice within
That's what the voice within says.
saying?
That's what the voice within says. Why
should
should I
should I live
should I live this
should I live this miserable,
should I live this miserable, horrible
life?
life? Have
should I live this miserable, horrible
life? Have a
life? Have a few
should I live this miserable, horrible
life? Have a few beers
life? Have a few beers on
should I live this miserable, horrible
life? Have a few beers on the
life? Have a few beers on the way
should I live this miserable, horrible
life? Have a few beers on the way to
work.
work. Not
work. Not hurting
work. Not hurting anybody.
work. Not hurting anybody. It's
work. Not hurting anybody. It's my
money,
money, right?
[laughter]
Well,
so
so that
so that euphoria
so that euphoria then
so that euphoria then is
so that euphoria then is not
so that euphoria then is not so
so that euphoria then is not so the
so that euphoria then is not so the drug
it
it doesn't
so that euphoria then is not so the drug
it doesn't have
it doesn't have the
so that euphoria then is not so the drug
it doesn't have the capacity
it doesn't have the capacity to
so that euphoria then is not so the drug
it doesn't have the capacity to create
it doesn't have the capacity to create a
high.
high. The
high. The point
high. The point is
high. The point is it
high. The point is it is
high. The point is it is not
high. The point is it is not the
high. The point is it is not the drug
that
that creates
high. The point is it is not the drug
that creates this
that creates this feeling
high. The point is it is not the drug
that creates this feeling of
that creates this feeling of euphoria.
The
The feeling
The feeling of
The feeling of euphoria
The feeling of euphoria is
The feeling of euphoria is the
The feeling of euphoria is the radiance
of
of the
The feeling of euphoria is the radiance
of the self.
Is
Is this
Is this all
Is this all right?
Is this all right? So
Is this all right? So if
Is this all right? So if we
Is this all right? So if we block
Is this all right? So if we block off
the
the negative
Is this all right? So if we block off
the negative energies,
the negative energies, then
Is this all right? So if we block off
the negative energies, then what's
the negative energies, then what's left
is
is the
is the radiance
is the radiance of
is the radiance of the
is the radiance of the self.
is the radiance of the self. You
is the radiance of the self. You feel
high,
high, you
is the radiance of the self. You feel
high, you feel
high, you feel fantastic,
is the radiance of the self. You feel
high, you feel fantastic, you
high, you feel fantastic, you feel
great.
The
The only
great.
The only problem
The only problem is
great.
The only problem is you
The only problem is you didn't
great.
The only problem is you didn't really
transcend
transcend the
transcend the lower
transcend the lower sense
transcend the lower sense of
transcend the lower sense of the
transcend the lower sense of the ego.
You
You only
transcend the lower sense of the ego.
You only temporarily
You only temporarily blocked
transcend the lower sense of the ego.
You only temporarily blocked it
You only temporarily blocked it off.
transcend the lower sense of the ego.
You only temporarily blocked it off. You
found
found a
found a shortcut.
Somehow
Somehow that
found a shortcut.
Somehow that creates
Somehow that creates some
found a shortcut.
Somehow that creates some kind
Somehow that creates some kind of
found a shortcut.
Somehow that creates some kind of a
karmic
karmic debt.
karmic debt. Some
karmic debt. Some kind
karmic debt. Some kind of
karmic debt. Some kind of a
karmic debt. Some kind of a karmic
karmic debt. Some kind of a karmic debt,
right?
right? Uh
karmic debt. Some kind of a karmic debt,
right? Uh somehow
right? Uh somehow that
karmic debt. Some kind of a karmic debt,
right? Uh somehow that creates
right? Uh somehow that creates some
karmic debt. Some kind of a karmic debt,
right? Uh somehow that creates some kind
of
of a
of a karmic
of a karmic debt.
of a karmic debt. You
of a karmic debt. You know,
of a karmic debt. You know, somehow
of a karmic debt. You know, somehow it's
as
as though
of a karmic debt. You know, somehow it's
as though the
as though the money
of a karmic debt. You know, somehow it's
as though the money that
as though the money that you
of a karmic debt. You know, somehow it's
as though the money that you stole
as though the money that you stole you
now
now owe
now owe back
now owe back later
now owe back later with
now owe back later with with
now owe back later with with interest.
Anybody
Anybody has
now owe back later with with interest.
Anybody has gone
Anybody has gone through
now owe back later with with interest.
Anybody has gone through withdrawal
Anybody has gone through withdrawal from
drugs
drugs or
drugs or alcohol
drugs or alcohol knows
drugs or alcohol knows I
drugs or alcohol knows I think
drugs or alcohol knows I think you
drugs or alcohol knows I think you pay
it
it and
drugs or alcohol knows I think you pay
it and with
it and with interest
drugs or alcohol knows I think you pay
it and with interest all
it and with interest all that
drugs or alcohol knows I think you pay
it and with interest all that you
it and with interest all that you stole
you
you might
you might say
you might say uh
you might say uh in
you might say uh in an
you might say uh in an artificial
you might say uh in an artificial manner
uh
now
now you're
now you're not
now you're not allowed
now you're not allowed to
now you're not allowed to touch
now you're not allowed to touch it
now you're not allowed to touch it if
you're
you're going
now you're not allowed to touch it if
you're going to
you're going to recover
now you're not allowed to touch it if
you're going to recover one
you're going to recover one day
now you're not allowed to touch it if
you're going to recover one day at
you're going to recover one day at a
time
time you
time you don't
time you don't have
time you don't have you
time you don't have you can't
time you don't have you can't touch
time you don't have you can't touch any
of
of it.
time you don't have you can't touch any
of it. So
of it. So then
time you don't have you can't touch any
of it. So then what
of it. So then what happens
time you don't have you can't touch any
of it. So then what happens is
of it. So then what happens is the
time you don't have you can't touch any
of it. So then what happens is the way
back
back legitimately
back legitimately is
back legitimately is discovered.
back legitimately is discovered. So
back legitimately is discovered. So the
12 steps
12 steps is
back legitimately is discovered. So the
12 steps is nothing
12 steps is nothing but
back legitimately is discovered. So the
12 steps is nothing but how
12 steps is nothing but how to
back legitimately is discovered. So the
12 steps is nothing but how to come
12 steps is nothing but how to come from
an
an artificially
an artificially induced
an artificially induced euphoria
back
back into
an artificially induced euphoria
back into a
back into a lovingness
an artificially induced euphoria
back into a lovingness which
back into a lovingness which you
an artificially induced euphoria
back into a lovingness which you have
actually
actually become.
actually become. Now
actually become. Now because
actually become. Now because you
actually become. Now because you have
become
become it,
actually become. Now because you have
become it, you
become it, you own
actually become. Now because you have
become it, you own it.
become it, you own it. It's
actually become. Now because you have
become it, you own it. It's no
become it, you own it. It's no longer
vulnerable.
vulnerable. Nobody
vulnerable. Nobody can
vulnerable. Nobody can take
vulnerable. Nobody can take it
vulnerable. Nobody can take it away
vulnerable. Nobody can take it away from
you
because
because lovingness
because lovingness is
because lovingness is a
because lovingness is a condition.
because lovingness is a condition. It's
a
a way
because lovingness is a condition. It's
a way of
a way of being.
because lovingness is a condition. It's
a way of being. It's
a way of being. It's a
because lovingness is a condition. It's
a way of being. It's a way
a way of being. It's a way of
because lovingness is a condition. It's
a way of being. It's a way of being.
a way of being. It's a way of being. And
as
as members
as members of
as members of this
as members of this group
as members of this group know,
as members of this group know, because
there's
there's a
as members of this group know, because
there's a great
there's a great deal
as members of this group know, because
there's a great deal of
there's a great deal of lovingness
as members of this group know, because
there's a great deal of lovingness here
as
as you
as you walk
as you walk through
as you walk through Walmarts,
your
your lovingness
as you walk through Walmarts,
your lovingness goes
your lovingness goes with
as you walk through Walmarts,
your lovingness goes with you.
your lovingness goes with you. And
people
people intuit
people intuit it.
people intuit it. That's
people intuit it. That's why
people intuit it. That's why they
people intuit it. That's why they smile
at
at you
people intuit it. That's why they smile
at you and
at you and and
people intuit it. That's why they smile
at you and and they're
at you and and they're open
people intuit it. That's why they smile
at you and and they're open and
at you and and they're open and very
vulnerable
vulnerable with
vulnerable with you.
vulnerable with you. You
vulnerable with you. You see,
vulnerable with you. You see, what
vulnerable with you. You see, what love
is
is is
vulnerable with you. You see, what love
is is an
is is an openness
vulnerable with you. You see, what love
is is an openness and
is is an openness and a
vulnerable with you. You see, what love
is is an openness and a vulnerability.
Lady,
Lady, I
Lady, I bump
Lady, I bump into
Lady, I bump into her
Lady, I bump into her basket
Lady, I bump into her basket and
Lady, I bump into her basket and she
Lady, I bump into her basket and she was
just
just wide
Lady, I bump into her basket and she was
just wide open,
just wide open, totally
Lady, I bump into her basket and she was
just wide open, totally vulnerable
just wide open, totally vulnerable to
me.
me. You
me. You know,
me. You know, I
me. You know, I could
me. You know, I could have
me. You know, I could have snatched
me. You know, I could have snatched a
person
person running.
me. You know, I could have snatched a
person running. [laughter]
She
She probably
She probably would
She probably would have
She probably would have said
She probably would have said thank
She probably would have said thank you.
How
How can
She probably would have said thank you.
How can we
How can we help
She probably would have said thank you.
How can we help you?
How can we help you? [laughter]
Would
Would you
Would you like
Would you like another
Would you like another person?
Would you like another person? All
right.
Trust.
Trust. Part
Trust. Part of
Trust. Part of love
Trust. Part of love is
Trust. Part of love is trust.
Trust. Part of love is trust. The
Trust. Part of love is trust. The more
loving
loving we
Trust. Part of love is trust. The more
loving we are,
loving we are, the
Trust. Part of love is trust. The more
loving we are, the more
loving we are, the more capable
Trust. Part of love is trust. The more
loving we are, the more capable we
loving we are, the more capable we are
of
of trust.
of trust. So,
all
all right.
of trust. So,
all right. That's
all right. That's the
of trust. So,
all right. That's the way
all right. That's the way we
of trust. So,
all right. That's the way we get
all right. That's the way we get out
of trust. So,
all right. That's the way we get out of
uh
uh the
uh the negative.
uh the negative. Um
so,
so, that's
uh the negative. Um
so, that's the
so, that's the story
uh the negative. Um
so, that's the story on
so, that's the story on addiction
uh the negative. Um
so, that's the story on addiction pretty
much.
much. You
much. You get
much. You get addicted.
much. You get addicted. What
much. You get addicted. What you're
addicted
addicted to
much. You get addicted. What you're
addicted to is
addicted to is this
much. You get addicted. What you're
addicted to is this state.
addicted to is this state. Once
much. You get addicted. What you're
addicted to is this state. Once you
experience
experience this
experience this state,
experience this state, nothing
experience this state, nothing less
experience this state, nothing less than
that
that is
experience this state, nothing less than
that is going
that is going to
experience this state, nothing less than
that is going to ever
that is going to ever do.
experience this state, nothing less than
that is going to ever do. Tell
that is going to ever do. Tell you
near-death
near-death experience.
near-death experience. How
near-death experience. How many
near-death experience. How many people
here
here had
near-death experience. How many people
here had near-death
here had near-death experiences?
near-death experience. How many people
here had near-death experiences? Right?
Nothing
Nothing nothing
Nothing nothing in
Nothing nothing in this
Nothing nothing in this world
Nothing nothing in this world comes
Nothing nothing in this world comes near
it.
it. Uh
Nothing nothing in this world comes near
it. Uh the
it. Uh the longing
Nothing nothing in this world comes near
it. Uh the longing to
it. Uh the longing to return
Nothing nothing in this world comes near
it. Uh the longing to return to
it. Uh the longing to return to that
state
state of
state of awareness,
state of awareness, that
state of awareness, that condition,
state of awareness, that condition, that
presence
presence hangs
state of awareness, that condition, that
presence hangs with
presence hangs with you.
state of awareness, that condition, that
presence hangs with you. And
presence hangs with you. And that's
state of awareness, that condition, that
presence hangs with you. And that's what
the
the addict
the addict has
the addict has to
the addict has to get
the addict has to get off
the addict has to get off of.
the addict has to get off of. And
the addict has to get off of. And that's
why
why recovery
the addict has to get off of. And that's
why recovery is
why recovery is slow,
the addict has to get off of. And that's
why recovery is slow, difficult
why recovery is slow, difficult and
statistically
uh
these
these levels
these levels are
these levels are not
these levels are not necessarily
progressive.
progressive. You
these levels are not necessarily
progressive. You know,
progressive. You know, it's
these levels are not necessarily
progressive. You know, it's not
progressive. You know, it's not like
grade
grade school
grade school and
grade school and then
grade school and then third
grade school and then third grade,
fourth
fourth grade.
grade school and then third grade,
fourth grade. You
fourth grade. You can
grade school and then third grade,
fourth grade. You can make
fourth grade. You can make great
grade school and then third grade,
fourth grade. You can make great leaps
hitting
hitting bottom.
hitting bottom. You
hitting bottom. You know,
hitting bottom. You know, the
hitting bottom. You know, the story
hitting bottom. You know, the story of
addiction
addiction is
hitting bottom. You know, the story of
addiction is to
addiction is to me
hitting bottom. You know, the story of
addiction is to me addiction
addiction is to me addiction is
hitting bottom. You know, the story of
addiction is to me addiction is the
addiction is to me addiction is the fast
way
way to
way to God.
way to God. You
way to God. You either
way to God. You either die
way to God. You either die or
way to God. You either die or you
way to God. You either die or you get
it.
it. [laughter]
Either
Either guy
Either guy or
Either guy or you
Either guy or you did
Either guy or you did it.
Either guy or you did it. So,
Either guy or you did it. So, it's
Either guy or you did it. So, it's like
la
la last
Either guy or you did it. So, it's like
la last gaspers,
la last gaspers, you
Either guy or you did it. So, it's like
la last gaspers, you know,
la last gaspers, you know, you've
Either guy or you did it. So, it's like
la last gaspers, you know, you've been
63 times
63 times on
63 times on this
63 times on this planet
63 times on this planet and
63 times on this planet and you're
getting
getting pretty
63 times on this planet and you're
getting pretty desperate.
Uh,
Uh, the
Uh, the fastest
Uh, the fastest way
Uh, the fastest way either
Uh, the fastest way either makes
Uh, the fastest way either makes or
breaks
breaks you
Uh, the fastest way either makes or
breaks you is
breaks you is addiction.
Uh, the fastest way either makes or
breaks you is addiction. You
breaks you is addiction. You either
Uh, the fastest way either makes or
breaks you is addiction. You either die
in
in sanity
in sanity and
in sanity and agony
in sanity and agony and
in sanity and agony and horrible
in sanity and agony and horrible death
or
or you
in sanity and agony and horrible death
or you transcend
or you transcend it.
in sanity and agony and horrible death
or you transcend it. So,
or you transcend it. So, you
in sanity and agony and horrible death
or you transcend it. So, you can
or you transcend it. So, you can go
in sanity and agony and horrible death
or you transcend it. So, you can go all
the
the way
the way from
the way from down
the way from down here
the way from down here suicidal
the way from down here suicidal suicidal
right
right here
the way from down here suicidal suicidal
right here and
right here and suddenly
the way from down here suicidal suicidal
right here and suddenly go
right here and suddenly go into
a
a presence
a presence infinite
a presence infinite state.
Incredible
Incredible state.
a presence infinite state.
Incredible state. Incredible
Incredible state. Incredible state.
Like
Like the
Like the presence
Like the presence of
Like the presence of God.
Like the presence of God. From
Like the presence of God. From the
depths
depths of
Like the presence of God. From the
depths of hell,
depths of hell, one
Like the presence of God. From the
depths of hell, one can
depths of hell, one can call
Like the presence of God. From the
depths of hell, one can call forth.
If
If there
If there is
If there is a
If there is a God,
If there is a God, I
If there is a God, I ask
If there is a God, I ask him
If there is a God, I ask him to
If there is a God, I ask him to help
If there is a God, I ask him to help me.
Then
Then remember
If there is a God, I ask him to help me.
Then remember nothing
Then remember nothing and
If there is a God, I ask him to help me.
Then remember nothing and suddenly
Then remember nothing and suddenly stand
in
in the
in the infinite
in the infinite presence.
So
So that's
in the infinite presence.
So that's from
So that's from the
in the infinite presence.
So that's from the lower
So that's from the lower depths
in the infinite presence.
So that's from the lower depths of
So that's from the lower depths of hell
to
what
what was
to
what was the
what was the level
to
what was the level of
what was the level of that
to
what was the level of that day?
what was the level of that day? The
level
level of
level of that
level of that day
level of that day was
level of that day was over
level of that day was over 750,
level of that day was over 750, 800,
850,
850, 890,
level of that day was over 750, 800,
850, 890, 900.
It
It was
It was the
It was the ultimate
It was the ultimate from
It was the ultimate from the
It was the ultimate from the depths
It was the ultimate from the depths of
hell
hell to
It was the ultimate from the depths of
hell to the
hell to the presence
It was the ultimate from the depths of
hell to the presence of
hell to the presence of the
It was the ultimate from the depths of
hell to the presence of the infinite.
So
So can
So can you
So can you jump
So can you jump levels?
So can you jump levels? You
So can you jump levels? You bet
So can you jump levels? You bet you
So can you jump levels? You bet you can.
As
As we
So can you jump levels? You bet you can.
As we said,
As we said, you
So can you jump levels? You bet you can.
As we said, you can
As we said, you can go
So can you jump levels? You bet you can.
As we said, you can go from
As we said, you can go from grief,
So can you jump levels? You bet you can.
As we said, you can go from grief, stop
seeing
seeing it
seeing it as
seeing it as loss,
seeing it as loss, feeling
seeing it as loss, feeling sorry
seeing it as loss, feeling sorry for
yourself
yourself and
seeing it as loss, feeling sorry for
yourself and juicing
yourself and juicing it
seeing it as loss, feeling sorry for
yourself and juicing it out
yourself and juicing it out of
seeing it as loss, feeling sorry for
yourself and juicing it out of self-pity
and
and seeing
and seeing it
and seeing it as
and seeing it as freedom.
and seeing it as freedom. Where
and seeing it as freedom. Where is
freedom
freedom up
and seeing it as freedom. Where is
freedom up here?
freedom up here? 200
and seeing it as freedom. Where is
freedom up here? 200 and
freedom up here? 200 and something.
Where
Where is
Where is freedom?
Where is freedom? What
Where is freedom? What happened
Where is freedom? What happened to
Where is freedom? What happened to our
freedom?
freedom? Somebody's
Where is freedom? What happened to our
freedom? Somebody's stolen
freedom? Somebody's stolen our
Where is freedom? What happened to our
freedom? Somebody's stolen our freedom.
[laughter]
I
I want
[laughter]
I want my
I want my freedom
[laughter]
I want my freedom back.
I want my freedom back. Please,
[laughter]
I want my freedom back. Please, where's
my
my freedom?
>> [laughter]
>> I
>> I know
>> I know what
>> I know what I
>> I know what I can
>> I know what I can grieve.
>> I know what I can grieve. I
>> I know what I can grieve. I can
>> I know what I can grieve. I can grieve.
I've
I've lost
>> I know what I can grieve. I can grieve.
I've lost my
I've lost my freedom.
>> I know what I can grieve. I can grieve.
I've lost my freedom. [laughter]
Oh,
Oh, I'm
Oh, I'm safe
Oh, I'm safe with
Oh, I'm safe with attachment
Oh, I'm safe with attachment again.
Oh, I'm safe with attachment again. Oh,
you
you see,
Oh, I'm safe with attachment again. Oh,
you see, [laughter]
if
if you
if you get
if you get attached
if you get attached to
if you get attached to freedom,
if you get attached to freedom, then
if you get attached to freedom, then it
becomes
becomes a
if you get attached to freedom, then it
becomes a compulsion.
becomes a compulsion. You
if you get attached to freedom, then it
becomes a compulsion. You see
becomes a compulsion. You see them
if you get attached to freedom, then it
becomes a compulsion. You see them out
there.
there. You
there. You see
there. You see them
there. You see them out
there. You see them out there
there. You see them out there on
motorcycles
motorcycles all
there. You see them out there on
motorcycles all day
motorcycles all day long.
there. You see them out there on
motorcycles all day long. Tattoos,
motorcycles all day long. Tattoos, hair
flying,
flying, I'm
flying, I'm free.
[laughter]
I
I mean,
I mean, they're
I mean, they're hooked
I mean, they're hooked on
I mean, they're hooked on it.
I mean, they're hooked on it. You
I mean, they're hooked on it. You know
what
what I
I mean, they're hooked on it. You know
what I mean?
what I mean? They're
I mean, they're hooked on it. You know
what I mean? They're like
what I mean? They're like addicted
I mean, they're hooked on it. You know
what I mean? They're like addicted to
it.
it. You
it. You take
it. You take away
it. You take away his
it. You take away his Harley
it. You take away his Harley and
it. You take away his Harley and he
thinks
thinks suicide.
We
We told
We told you
We told you last
We told you last time,
We told you last time, nobody
We told you last time, nobody ever
shoots
shoots a
We told you last time, nobody ever
shoots a Harley-Davidson
shoots a Harley-Davidson by
We told you last time, nobody ever
shoots a Harley-Davidson by mistake.
shoots a Harley-Davidson by mistake. You
know,
know, children,
know, children, family
know, children, family members,
ex-wives,
ex-wives, mother-in-laws
know, children, family members,
ex-wives, mother-in-laws shot
ex-wives, mother-in-laws shot all
know, children, family members,
ex-wives, mother-in-laws shot all the
time
time by
time by accident,
time by accident, but
time by accident, but never
Harley-Davidson.
Harley-Davidson. [laughter]
So,
So, you
So, you can
So, you can get
So, you can get addicted
So, you can get addicted to
So, you can get addicted to even
freedom,
freedom, right?
So, you can get addicted to even
freedom, right? It's
freedom, right? It's a
So, you can get addicted to even
freedom, right? It's a compulsion
freedom, right? It's a compulsion to
never
never get
never get a
never get a job,
never get a job, never
never get a job, never put
never get a job, never put a
never get a job, never put a tie
never get a job, never put a tie on.
never get a job, never put a tie on. You
get
get like
never get a job, never put a tie on. You
get like hooked
get like hooked on
never get a job, never put a tie on. You
get like hooked on it.
get like hooked on it. You
never get a job, never put a tie on. You
get like hooked on it. You know
get like hooked on it. You know what
never get a job, never put a tie on. You
get like hooked on it. You know what I'm
saying?
saying? You
saying? You got
saying? You got run
saying? You got run by
saying? You got run by it.
All right.
All right. So,
saying? You got run by it.
All right. So, we
All right. So, we can
saying? You got run by it.
All right. So, we can bypass
All right. So, we can bypass levels.
There
There is
There is a
There is a a
There is a a relic
There is a a relic around.
There is a a relic around. Let's
There is a a relic around. Let's ask
There is a a relic around. Let's ask if
we
we can
There is a a relic around. Let's ask if
we can ask
we can ask about
There is a a relic around. Let's ask if
we can ask about this
we can ask about this relic.
There is a a relic around. Let's ask if
we can ask about this relic. I
we can ask about this relic. I don't
know
know anything
know anything about
know anything about this
know anything about this relic.
know anything about this relic. I
know anything about this relic. I only
heard
heard that
know anything about this relic. I only
heard that there
heard that there is
know anything about this relic. I only
heard that there is a
heard that there is a relic
know anything about this relic. I only
heard that there is a relic around.
There
There is
There is a
There is a relic
There is a relic around.
There is a relic around. Resist.
There is a relic around. Resist. This
There is a relic around. Resist. This is
a
a genuine
There is a relic around. Resist. This is
a genuine relic
a genuine relic resist.
There is a relic around. Resist. This is
a genuine relic resist. You
a genuine relic resist. You have
permission
permission to
permission to ask
permission to ask about
permission to ask about this
permission to ask about this relic
resist.
This
This is
This is a
This is a genuine
This is a genuine real
This is a genuine real relic.
This is a genuine real relic. It
This is a genuine real relic. It is.
This is a genuine real relic. It is. It
has
has the
This is a genuine real relic. It is. It
has the vibration
within
within it
within it of
within it of its
within it of its original
within it of its original owner.
within it of its original owner. It
within it of its original owner. It is
okay.
okay. Oh,
within it of its original owner. It is
okay. Oh, I
okay. Oh, I get
within it of its original owner. It is
okay. Oh, I get what
okay. Oh, I get what it
within it of its original owner. It is
okay. Oh, I get what it is.
okay. Oh, I get what it is. Okay.
within it of its original owner. It is
okay. Oh, I get what it is. Okay. It's
over
over 800,
over 800, 850,
over 800, 850, 860,
over 800, 850, 860, 870,
over 800, 850, 860, 870, 890.
It's
It's energy
over 800, 850, 860, 870, 890.
It's energy of
It's energy of this.
over 800, 850, 860, 870, 890.
It's energy of this. The
It's energy of this. The only
over 800, 850, 860, 870, 890.
It's energy of this. The only energy
within
within this
within this relic
within this relic is
within this relic is over
within this relic is over 890,
within this relic is over 890, 900,
within this relic is over 890, 900, 920.
Okay,
Okay, this
within this relic is over 890, 900, 920.
Okay, this uh
Okay, this uh there's
within this relic is over 890, 900, 920.
Okay, this uh there's a
Okay, this uh there's a relic
within this relic is over 890, 900, 920.
Okay, this uh there's a relic somewhere.
I
I don't
I don't know
I don't know where
I don't know where it
I don't know where it is.
Well,
Well, I'm
I don't know where it is.
Well, I'm going
Well, I'm going to
I don't know where it is.
Well, I'm going to go
Well, I'm going to go visit
I don't know where it is.
Well, I'm going to go visit that.
Well, I'm going to go visit that. I
don't
don't know
don't know about
don't know about you,
don't know about you, but
don't know about you, but [laughter]
I
I just
don't know about you, but [laughter]
I just want
I just want to
don't know about you, but [laughter]
I just want to touch
I just want to touch my
don't know about you, but [laughter]
I just want to touch my little
I just want to touch my little toe
don't know about you, but [laughter]
I just want to touch my little toe to
that
that 920
that 920 and
photograph
photograph it,
that 920 and
photograph it, maybe.
All
All right.
All right. So,
All right. So, that's
All right. So, that's something
All right. So, that's something I've
never
never asked
All right. So, that's something I've
never asked before.
never asked before. H
the
the spiritual
the spiritual energy
the spiritual energy can
the spiritual energy can persist
the spiritual energy can persist in
the spiritual energy can persist in the
physical
physical body
the spiritual energy can persist in the
physical body even
physical body even after
the spiritual energy can persist in the
physical body even after physical
physical body even after physical death
resist.
resist. It
resist. It only
resist. It only does
resist. It only does so
resist. It only does so in
resist. It only does so in evolved
enlightened
enlightened beings
resist. It only does so in evolved
enlightened beings resist
enlightened beings resist it
resist. It only does so in evolved
enlightened beings resist it does
enlightened beings resist it does so
resist. It only does so in evolved
enlightened beings resist it does so in
the
the average
the average human
the average human being
the average human being resist.
Oh
Oh and
the average human being resist.
Oh and the
Oh and the enlightened
the average human being resist.
Oh and the enlightened being
Oh and the enlightened being the
the average human being resist.
Oh and the enlightened being the remains
are
are special.
are special. Huh.
That's
That's strange
are special. Huh.
That's strange isn't
That's strange isn't it?
are special. Huh.
That's strange isn't it? Realize
That's strange isn't it? Realize that.
>> I'm
>> I'm going
>> I'm going to
>> I'm going to stuff
>> I'm going to stuff you.
[laughter]
There's
There's karmic
There's karmic merit
There's karmic merit in
There's karmic merit in uh
There's karmic merit in uh visiting
There's karmic merit in uh visiting a
relic.
relic. Is
There's karmic merit in uh visiting a
relic. Is it
relic. Is it the
There's karmic merit in uh visiting a
relic. Is it the karmic
relic. Is it the karmic merit
arises
arises from
the
the reverence
arises from
the reverence from
the reverence from the
arises from
the reverence from the presence
the reverence from the presence within
resist?
Oh,
Oh, I
resist?
Oh, I see.
Oh, I see. The
resist?
Oh, I see. The karmic
Oh, I see. The karmic merit
resist?
Oh, I see. The karmic merit arises
Oh, I see. The karmic merit arises from
really
really the
really the reverence
really the reverence for
really the reverence for God
really the reverence for God is
represented
represented by
really the reverence for God is
represented by the
represented by the energy
really the reverence for God is
represented by the energy of
represented by the energy of the
really the reverence for God is
represented by the energy of the relic
resistance.
resistance. Okay.
resistance. Okay. The
resistance. Okay. The karmic
benefit
benefit arises
resistance. Okay. The karmic
benefit arises from
benefit arises from the
resistance. Okay. The karmic
benefit arises from the energy
benefit arises from the energy of
resistance. Okay. The karmic
benefit arises from the energy of the
relic
relic itself
relic itself as
relic itself as a
relic itself as a physicality
resistance.
They
They both
there's
there's a
They both
there's a value
there's a value to
They both
there's a value to visiting
there's a value to visiting relics
folks.
folks. Hate
folks. Hate to
folks. Hate to tell
folks. Hate to tell you
folks. Hate to tell you that
[laughter]
I
I mean
I mean travel
I mean travel restrictions
I mean travel restrictions being
I mean travel restrictions being what
they
they are
I mean travel restrictions being what
they are today.
they are today. Uh
I mean travel restrictions being what
they are today. Uh going
they are today. Uh going through
I mean travel restrictions being what
they are today. Uh going through you
know
know you
know you getting
know you getting one
know you getting one your
know you getting one your bag
know you getting one your bag saying
know you getting one your bag saying we
got
got to
know you getting one your bag saying we
got to check
got to check you
know you getting one your bag saying we
got to check you out
got to check you out for
know you getting one your bag saying we
got to check you out for relics
got to check you out for relics boy.
[laughter]
He's
He's carrying
[laughter]
He's carrying a
He's carrying a relic
[laughter]
He's carrying a relic in
He's carrying a relic in his
[laughter]
He's carrying a relic in his pocket.
Bring
Bring it
Bring it take
Bring it take him
Bring it take him aside
Bring it take him aside for
Bring it take him aside for his
[laughter]
the
the date
the date of
the date of death
the date of death we
the date of death we said
the date of death we said before
the date of death we said before is
the date of death we said before is is
already
already set
the date of death we said before is is
already set at
already set at the
the date of death we said before is is
already set at the time
already set at the time of
the date of death we said before is is
already set at the time of the
already set at the time of the time
the date of death we said before is is
already set at the time of the time of
birth.
birth. The
birth. The date
birth. The date of
birth. The date of death
birth. The date of death is
birth. The date of death is already
birth. The date of death is already set.
Uh
Uh the
birth. The date of death is already set.
Uh the question
Uh the question was
birth. The date of death is already set.
Uh the question was is
Uh the question was is that
birth. The date of death is already set.
Uh the question was is that date
Uh the question was is that date like
birth. The date of death is already set.
Uh the question was is that date like in
written
written in
written in cement
written in cement resist
written in cement resist is
written in cement resist is that
written in cement resist is that date
like
like equivalent
written in cement resist is that date
like equivalent of
like equivalent of written
written in cement resist is that date
like equivalent of written in
like equivalent of written in cement
resist
do
do we
resist
do we have
do we have other
resist
do we have other options
do we have other options resist
no
no you
no you don't
no you don't really
no you don't really oh
no you don't really oh you
no you don't really oh you think
no you don't really oh you think you
no you don't really oh you think you did
well
well I
no you don't really oh you think you did
well I don't
well I don't have
no you don't really oh you think you did
well I don't have to
well I don't have to feel
no you don't really oh you think you did
well I don't have to feel bad
well I don't have to feel bad about
no you don't really oh you think you did
well I don't have to feel bad about that
one
one anymore
one anymore now
[laughter]
I
I had
I had the
I had the opportunity
I had the opportunity didn't
I had the opportunity didn't take
I had the opportunity didn't take it
after
after year
I had the opportunity didn't take it
after year years
after year years after
I had the opportunity didn't take it
after year years after I
after year years after I said
I had the opportunity didn't take it
after year years after I said what
after year years after I said what an
idiot
idiot you
idiot you were
idiot you were man
idiot you were man you
idiot you were man you There
idiot you were man you There you
idiot you were man you There you were
idiot you were man you There you were in
that
that infinite
idiot you were man you There you were in
that infinite presence
that infinite presence one
idiot you were man you There you were in
that infinite presence one one
that infinite presence one one with
idiot you were man you There you were in
that infinite presence one one with the
infinite
infinite lovingness
infinite lovingness of
infinite lovingness of the
infinite lovingness of the universe
infinite lovingness of the universe and
you
you said
infinite lovingness of the universe and
you said I'm
you said I'm going
infinite lovingness of the universe and
you said I'm going back
you said I'm going back in
infinite lovingness of the universe and
you said I'm going back in the
you said I'm going back in the body.
What
What a
What a stupid
What a stupid idiot.
I
I thought
What a stupid idiot.
I thought we'd
I thought we'd resume
What a stupid idiot.
I thought we'd resume because
I thought we'd resume because we
What a stupid idiot.
I thought we'd resume because we do
I thought we'd resume because we do have
sort
sort of
sort of a
sort of a special
occasion
occasion in
sort of a special
occasion in Sedona
occasion in Sedona today
sort of a special
occasion in Sedona today that
occasion in Sedona today that might
sort of a special
occasion in Sedona today that might bear
considering
considering the
considering the questions
considering the questions we
considering the questions we asked
before.
Uh
we
we got
Uh
we got that
we got that the
Uh
we got that the relics
we got that the relics did
Uh
we got that the relics did uh
we got that the relics did uh let's
Uh
we got that the relics did uh let's re
let's
let's redo
let's redo it
the
the relics
let's redo it
the relics that
the relics that are
let's redo it
the relics that are spoken
the relics that are spoken of
let's redo it
the relics that are spoken of are
genuine
genuine resist
genuine resist it's
genuine resist it's worthwhile
genuine resist it's worthwhile for
genuine resist it's worthwhile for us
genuine resist it's worthwhile for us to
visit
visit them
genuine resist it's worthwhile for us to
visit them resist
visit them resist wow
genuine resist it's worthwhile for us to
visit them resist wow there's
visit them resist wow there's a
genuine resist it's worthwhile for us to
visit them resist wow there's a karmic
merit
merit in
merit in so
merit in so doing
merit in so doing resist
merit in so doing resist huh
the
the there
merit in so doing resist huh
the there is
the there is an
merit in so doing resist huh
the there is an energy
the there is an energy that
merit in so doing resist huh
the there is an energy that radiates
from
from them
from them resist
which
which is
from them resist
which is over
which is over 800
from them resist
which is over 800 900
which is over 800 900 950
from them resist
which is over 800 900 950 960
which is over 800 900 950 960 16.
>> Wow.
>> Wow. Ah.
>> Wow. Ah. All right.
>> Wow. Ah. All right. We
>> Wow. Ah. All right. We get
>> Wow. Ah. All right. We get we
>> Wow. Ah. All right. We get we get
>> Wow. Ah. All right. We get we get that
this
this is
>> Wow. Ah. All right. We get we get that
this is a
this is a rather
>> Wow. Ah. All right. We get we get that
this is a rather unique
this is a rather unique occasion.
>> Wow. Ah. All right. We get we get that
this is a rather unique occasion. These
Krishna
sorry
sorry these
Krishna
sorry these relics
sorry these relics which
Krishna
sorry these relics which are
sorry these relics which are present
Krishna
sorry these relics which are present in
Sedona
Sedona uh
Sedona uh will
Sedona uh will only
Sedona uh will only be
Sedona uh will only be visitable
Sedona uh will only be visitable for
Sedona uh will only be visitable for the
rest
rest of
Sedona uh will only be visitable for the
rest of the
rest of the day.
Sedona uh will only be visitable for the
rest of the day. I
rest of the day. I thought
Sedona uh will only be visitable for the
rest of the day. I thought what
rest of the day. I thought what we
Sedona uh will only be visitable for the
rest of the day. I thought what we might
do
do is
do is break
do is break early.
do is break early. I'll
do is break early. I'll tell
do is break early. I'll tell you
do is break early. I'll tell you how
do is break early. I'll tell you how to
get
get there.
do is break early. I'll tell you how to
get there. And
get there. And those
do is break early. I'll tell you how to
get there. And those of
get there. And those of you
do is break early. I'll tell you how to
get there. And those of you who
get there. And those of you who wish
do is break early. I'll tell you how to
get there. And those of you who wish to,
we
we might
we might visit
we might visit the
we might visit the the
we might visit the the relics
we might visit the the relics because
the
the alternative
we might visit the the relics because
the alternative is
the alternative is to
we might visit the the relics because
the alternative is to spend
the alternative is to spend 14
we might visit the the relics because
the alternative is to spend 14 hours
flying
flying over
flying over to
flying over to Asia
flying over to Asia [laughter]
flying over to Asia [laughter] to
flying over to Asia [laughter] to visit
which
which I
flying over to Asia [laughter] to visit
which I have
which I have done.
flying over to Asia [laughter] to visit
which I have done. I'll
which I have done. I'll tell
flying over to Asia [laughter] to visit
which I have done. I'll tell you
which I have done. I'll tell you from
here
here to
here to Korea
here to Korea is
here to Korea is a
here to Korea is a long
here to Korea is a long way.
>> I
>> I miss
here to Korea is a long way.
>> I miss going
>> I miss going this
here to Korea is a long way.
>> I miss going this year.
>> I miss going this year. Um,
here to Korea is a long way.
>> I miss going this year. Um, all
>> I miss going this year. Um, all right.
So
So we
So we have
So we have these
So we have these uh
So we have these uh uh
So we have these uh uh it
So we have these uh uh it says
So we have these uh uh it says that
So we have these uh uh it says that they
are
are genuine
um
that
that it
um
that it is
that it is of
um
that it is of karmic
that it is of karmic merit
um
that it is of karmic merit to
that it is of karmic merit to merely
visit
visit them
visit them that
visit them that they
visit them that they do
visit them that they do create
visit them that they do create benefit
beneficience
beneficience of
visit them that they do create benefit
beneficience of their
beneficience of their own
and
and of
and of course
and of course the
and of course the willingness
and of course the willingness to
acknowledge
what
what would
what would we
what would we say
what would we say uh
what would we say uh the
what would we say uh the value
what would we say uh the value of
divinity
divinity and
what would we say uh the value of
divinity and whatever
divinity and whatever its
what would we say uh the value of
divinity and whatever its expression
divinity and whatever its expression is
a
a karmic
a karmic merit
a karmic merit that
a karmic merit that comes
a karmic merit that comes from
a karmic merit that comes from within
your
your own
a karmic merit that comes from within
your own spiritual
self.
self. Um,
self. Um, and
self. Um, and so
self. Um, and so we
self. Um, and so we thought
self. Um, and so we thought we
self. Um, and so we thought we might
break
break early
self. Um, and so we thought we might
break early and
break early and go
self. Um, and so we thought we might
break early and go visit
break early and go visit the
self. Um, and so we thought we might
break early and go visit the u
break early and go visit the u the
relics.
They're
They're on
relics.
They're on display
They're on display until
relics.
They're on display until 5:00.
They're on display until 5:00. Then
relics.
They're on display until 5:00. Then at
5:00,
5:00, the
5:00, the Buddhist
5:00, the Buddhist community
5:00, the Buddhist community here,
5:00, the Buddhist community here, which
is
is represented
5:00, the Buddhist community here, which
is represented by
is represented by our
5:00, the Buddhist community here, which
is represented by our wonderful
is represented by our wonderful uh
videographer,
and
and there's
videographer,
and there's a
and there's a strong
videographer,
and there's a strong Buddhist
and there's a strong Buddhist community
here.
here. Uh
here. Uh anyway,
here. Uh anyway, they
here. Uh anyway, they have
somehow
somehow gotten
here. Uh anyway, they have
somehow gotten these
somehow gotten these assembled
here. Uh anyway, they have
somehow gotten these assembled relics
here.
here. Anything
here. Anything Calvary
here. Anything Calvary is
here. Anything Calvary is that
here. Anything Calvary is that high
here. Anything Calvary is that high is
worth
worth a
here. Anything Calvary is that high is
worth a visit.
worth a visit. So
here. Anything Calvary is that high is
worth a visit. So I
worth a visit. So I thought
here. Anything Calvary is that high is
worth a visit. So I thought we
worth a visit. So I thought we might
break
break early.
break early. I'll
break early. I'll tell
break early. I'll tell you
break early. I'll tell you where
break early. I'll tell you where it
break early. I'll tell you where it is.
You
You go
break early. I'll tell you where it is.
You go out
You go out West
break early. I'll tell you where it is.
You go out West Sedona.
But
But I
But I thought
But I thought it
But I thought it might
But I thought it might be
But I thought it might be fun.
But I thought it might be fun. We
But I thought it might be fun. We just
go
go visit
But I thought it might be fun. We just
go visit these
go visit these relics.
But I thought it might be fun. We just
go visit these relics. Uh
go visit these relics. Uh using
kinesiology,
kinesiology, we
kinesiology, we can
kinesiology, we can calibrate
kinesiology, we can calibrate the
kinesiology, we can calibrate the merit,
the
the worthwhile,
kinesiology, we can calibrate the merit,
the worthwhile, the
the worthwhile, the impact
kinesiology, we can calibrate the merit,
the worthwhile, the impact it
the worthwhile, the impact it would
kinesiology, we can calibrate the merit,
the worthwhile, the impact it would have
on
on our
on our own
on our own spiritual
on our own spiritual growth
on our own spiritual growth or
worthwhileness
worthwhileness of
on our own spiritual growth or
worthwhileness of it.
worthwhileness of it. and
on our own spiritual growth or
worthwhileness of it. and we'll
worthwhileness of it. and we'll take
on our own spiritual growth or
worthwhileness of it. and we'll take a
democratic
democratic vote.
democratic vote. We'll
democratic vote. We'll go.
democratic vote. We'll go. There
[laughter]
[laughter] you
democratic vote. We'll go. There
[laughter] you go.
[cheering]
There's
There's true
[cheering]
There's true democracy
There's true democracy for
[cheering]
There's true democracy for you.
>> My
>> My votes
>> My votes are
>> My votes are all
>> My votes are all and
>> My votes are all and yours
>> My votes are all and yours are
>> My votes are all and yours are none.
Okay.
>> What'
>> What' you
>> What' you say?
>> The
>> The directions.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, yes.
>> Uh
>> Uh it's
>> Oh, yes.
>> Uh it's a
>> Uh it's a rare
>> Oh, yes.
>> Uh it's a rare opportunity
>> Uh it's a rare opportunity and
>> Oh, yes.
>> Uh it's a rare opportunity and of
>> Uh it's a rare opportunity and of course
it's
it's in
it's in it's
it's in it's aligned
it's in it's aligned with
it's in it's aligned with our
it's in it's aligned with our purpose.
Our
Our purpose
it's in it's aligned with our purpose.
Our purpose is
Our purpose is to
it's in it's aligned with our purpose.
Our purpose is to evolve
Our purpose is to evolve spiritually.
And
And when
And when we
And when we get
And when we get on
And when we get on the
And when we get on the other
And when we get on the other side,
we'll
we'll say
And when we get on the other side,
we'll say to
we'll say to him,
And when we get on the other side,
we'll say to him, "And
we'll say to him, "And we
And when we get on the other side,
we'll say to him, "And we did
we'll say to him, "And we did visit
And when we get on the other side,
we'll say to him, "And we did visit your
relics."
relics." [laughter]
Yeah.
Yeah. Again,
relics." [laughter]
Yeah. Again, he's
Yeah. Again, he's at
relics." [laughter]
Yeah. Again, he's at the
Yeah. Again, he's at the door.
relics." [laughter]
Yeah. Again, he's at the door. He
Yeah. Again, he's at the door. He said,
"Did
"Did you
"Did you visit
"Did you visit my
"Did you visit my relics
"Did you visit my relics when
"Did you visit my relics when you
"Did you visit my relics when you had
"Did you visit my relics when you had an
opportunity?"
opportunity?" No.
Never
Never turned
Never turned down
Never turned down a
Never turned down a relic.
Never turned down a relic. I've
Never turned down a relic. I've never
visited
visited a
Never turned down a relic. I've never
visited a relic
visited a relic before,
Never turned down a relic. I've never
visited a relic before, and
visited a relic before, and I
Never turned down a relic. I've never
visited a relic before, and I never
visited a relic before, and I never gave
it
it serious
it serious consideration
it serious consideration until
it serious consideration until we
calibrated
calibrated it.
it serious consideration until we
calibrated it. And
calibrated it. And uh
it serious consideration until we
calibrated it. And uh now
calibrated it. And uh now the
it serious consideration until we
calibrated it. And uh now the integrity
of
of this
of this um
oh
oh and
of this um
oh and therefore
oh and therefore the
of this um
oh and therefore the intent
oh and therefore the intent it's
integrity.
integrity. All
integrity. All right.
integrity. All right. So
integrity. All right. So the
integrity. All right. So the integrity
see
see the
integrity. All right. So the integrity
see the integrity
see the integrity is
integrity. All right. So the integrity
see the integrity is in
see the integrity is in the
integrity. All right. So the integrity
see the integrity is in the intention
but
but what
but what is
but what is the
but what is the intention
but what is the intention to
but what is the intention to acknowledge
divinity
divinity in
but what is the intention to acknowledge
divinity in whatever
divinity in whatever its
but what is the intention to acknowledge
divinity in whatever its representative
form.
form. We
form. We did
form. We did it
form. We did it this
form. We did it this morning
form. We did it this morning using
form. We did it this morning using women
as
as an
form. We did it this morning using women
as an example.
as an example. We
form. We did it this morning using women
as an example. We didn't
as an example. We didn't mean
form. We did it this morning using women
as an example. We didn't mean to
as an example. We didn't mean to use
form. We did it this morning using women
as an example. We didn't mean to use it
as
as women
as women visav
as women visav men.
as women visav men. You
as women visav men. You see
as women visav men. You see the
as women visav men. You see the ego
tends
tends to
as women visav men. You see the ego
tends to see
tends to see that
as women visav men. You see the ego
tends to see that as
tends to see that as a
as women visav men. You see the ego
tends to see that as a separation.
You're
You're just
You're just naming
You're just naming mankind
You're just naming mankind by
You're just naming mankind by that
You're just naming mankind by that name.
Uh
Uh mankind
You're just naming mankind by that name.
Uh mankind is
Uh mankind is uh
You're just naming mankind by that name.
Uh mankind is uh also
Uh mankind is uh also by
You're just naming mankind by that name.
Uh mankind is uh also by the
Uh mankind is uh also by the name
You're just naming mankind by that name.
Uh mankind is uh also by the name of
man.
man. It's
man. It's w
man. It's w man.
man. It's w man. Woman
man. It's w man. Woman man
man. It's w man. Woman man woman.
man. It's w man. Woman man woman. Man
man. It's w man. Woman man woman. Man is
part
part of
man. It's w man. Woman man woman. Man is
part of woman.
part of woman. Right.
man. It's w man. Woman man woman. Man is
part of woman. Right. [laughter]
Or
Or is
Or is woman
Or is woman in
Or is woman in addition
Or is woman in addition on
Or is woman in addition on the
Or is woman in addition on the man?
Or is woman in addition on the man? He
stuck
stuck a
Or is woman in addition on the man? He
stuck a wool
stuck a wool in
Or is woman in addition on the man? He
stuck a wool in front
stuck a wool in front of
Or is woman in addition on the man? He
stuck a wool in front of men
[laughter]
and
and got
[laughter]
and got women.
All right.
All right. So
All right. So anyway,
All right. So anyway, that's
All right. So anyway, that's all
political
political boiling
to
to to
to to see
to to see the
to to see the divinity
to to see the divinity within
to to see the divinity within all
to to see the divinity within all that
exists.
exists. Well,
to to see the divinity within all that
exists. Well, the
exists. Well, the divinity,
the
the existence
the existence of
the existence of divinity
the existence of divinity within
the existence of divinity within certain
aspects
aspects of
the existence of divinity within certain
aspects of life
aspects of life or
the existence of divinity within certain
aspects of life or certain
aspects of life or certain gurus,
the existence of divinity within certain
aspects of life or certain gurus, pieces
of
of consciousness
of consciousness that
of consciousness that speak
of consciousness that speak to
of consciousness that speak to you,
of consciousness that speak to you, etc.
It's
It's just
of consciousness that speak to you, etc.
It's just that
It's just that they're
of consciousness that speak to you, etc.
It's just that they're more
recognizable.
recognizable. You
recognizable. You see
recognizable. You see that
recognizable. You see that same
recognizable. You see that same divinity
is
is within
recognizable. You see that same divinity
is within all
is within all that
recognizable. You see that same divinity
is within all that exists.
is within all that exists. It
recognizable. You see that same divinity
is within all that exists. It is
is within all that exists. It is not
possible
possible for
possible for anything
possible for anything to
possible for anything to exist
possible for anything to exist unless
possible for anything to exist unless it
comes
comes out
possible for anything to exist unless it
comes out of
comes out of creation.
possible for anything to exist unless it
comes out of creation. All
comes out of creation. All that
possible for anything to exist unless it
comes out of creation. All that comes
out
out of
out of creation
then
has
has within
has within it
has within it the
has within it the essence
has within it the essence of
has within it the essence of divinity
has within it the essence of divinity or
it
it could
has within it the essence of divinity or
it could not
it could not be
anything
anything to
anything to be.
So
in
in deciding
in deciding to
in deciding to go
in deciding to go over
in deciding to go over and
in deciding to go over and visit
in deciding to go over and visit the
relic
relic then
in deciding to go over and visit the
relic then we
relic then we take
in deciding to go over and visit the
relic then we take take
relic then we take take advantage
in deciding to go over and visit the
relic then we take take advantage of
relic then we take take advantage of a
rare
rare opportunity.
Uh
Uh we
rare opportunity.
Uh we give
Uh we give thanks
rare opportunity.
Uh we give thanks to
Uh we give thanks to the
rare opportunity.
Uh we give thanks to the Buddhist
community
community for
community for making
community for making it
community for making it available
community for making it available to
community for making it available to us
and
and we
community for making it available to us
and we give
and we give recognition
community for making it available to us
and we give recognition to
and we give recognition to the
community for making it available to us
and we give recognition to the value
and we give recognition to the value of
the
the our
the our own
the our own research
the our own research methods
the our own research methods to
the our own research methods to discern
the
the true
the our own research methods to discern
the true from
the true from the
the our own research methods to discern
the true from the false.
the true from the false. I'm
the our own research methods to discern
the true from the false. I'm sure
there's
there's all
there's all kinds
there's all kinds of
there's all kinds of false
there's all kinds of false relics
there's all kinds of false relics all
over
over the
there's all kinds of false relics all
over the world.
And
And if
And if you
And if you go
And if you go to
And if you go to South
And if you go to South America,
And if you go to South America, many
And if you go to South America, many of
these
these things
And if you go to South America, many of
these things are
these things are for
And if you go to South America, many of
these things are for sale.
these things are for sale. You
And if you go to South America, many of
these things are for sale. You know,
pre-Colombian
pre-Colombian stuff
pre-Colombian stuff is
pre-Colombian stuff is for
pre-Colombian stuff is for sale
everywhere
everywhere on
pre-Colombian stuff is for sale
everywhere on every
everywhere on every street
pre-Colombian stuff is for sale
everywhere on every street corner.
everywhere on every street corner. You
as
as soon
as soon as
as soon as you
as soon as you get
as soon as you get off
as soon as you get off the
as soon as you get off the airplane,
pre-colian
pre-colian art.
as soon as you get off the airplane,
pre-colian art. [laughter]
And
And uh
And uh it
And uh it makes
And uh it makes your
And uh it makes your arm
And uh it makes your arm go
And uh it makes your arm go weak.
And uh it makes your arm go weak. That's
the
the only
And uh it makes your arm go weak. That's
the only difference.
Pre-colian
Pre-colian art
Pre-colian art that
Pre-colian art that makes
Pre-colian art that makes your
Pre-colian art that makes your arm
Pre-colian art that makes your arm go
strong
strong costs
Pre-colian art that makes your arm go
strong costs a
strong costs a lot
Pre-colian art that makes your arm go
strong costs a lot more
strong costs a lot more than
Pre-colian art that makes your arm go
strong costs a lot more than that
strong costs a lot more than that which
makes
makes you
makes you go
makes you go weak.
makes you go weak. I'll
makes you go weak. I'll tell
makes you go weak. I'll tell you.
All
All right.
makes you go weak. I'll tell you.
All right. So,
All right. So, we've
makes you go weak. I'll tell you.
All right. So, we've got
All right. So, we've got some
interesting
interesting questions.
interesting questions. I
interesting questions. I want
interesting questions. I want to
interesting questions. I want to finish
them.
them. So,
interesting questions. I want to finish
them. So, if
them. So, if their
interesting questions. I want to finish
them. So, if their exhibit
them. So, if their exhibit is
interesting questions. I want to finish
them. So, if their exhibit is until
them. So, if their exhibit is until 5,
if
if we
if we leave
if we leave here
if we leave here at
if we leave here at 4:00,
if we leave here at 4:00, that
if we leave here at 4:00, that would
give
give us
if we leave here at 4:00, that would
give us plenty
give us plenty of
if we leave here at 4:00, that would
give us plenty of time
give us plenty of time and
if we leave here at 4:00, that would
give us plenty of time and pretty
give us plenty of time and pretty things
are
are pretty
are pretty much
are pretty much cleaned
are pretty much cleaned up.
are pretty much cleaned up. I
are pretty much cleaned up. I just
thought
thought it'd
are pretty much cleaned up. I just
thought it'd be
thought it'd be fun
are pretty much cleaned up. I just
thought it'd be fun to
thought it'd be fun to move
are pretty much cleaned up. I just
thought it'd be fun to move us
thought it'd be fun to move us as
are pretty much cleaned up. I just
thought it'd be fun to move us as a
group,
group, you
group, you know,
group, you know, to
group, you know, to a
group, you know, to a different
group, you know, to a different uh
context
context and
group, you know, to a different uh
context and um
context and um acknowledge
group, you know, to a different uh
context and um acknowledge uh
context and um acknowledge uh the
Buddhist
Buddhist community
Buddhist community here,
Buddhist community here, which
Buddhist community here, which in
Buddhist community here, which in itself
is
is a
Buddhist community here, which in itself
is a a
is a a good
Buddhist community here, which in itself
is a a good thing
is a a good thing to
Buddhist community here, which in itself
is a a good thing to do.
is a a good thing to do. Huh.
Buddhist community here, which in itself
is a a good thing to do. Huh. We
is a a good thing to do. Huh. We saw
that
that Buddhism
that Buddhism had
that Buddhism had declined
that Buddhism had declined the
that Buddhism had declined the least
that Buddhism had declined the least of
all
all the
that Buddhism had declined the least of
all the world's
all the world's religions.
that Buddhism had declined the least of
all the world's religions. very
interestingly
uh
uh because
interestingly
uh because it
uh because it stuck
interestingly
uh because it stuck to
uh because it stuck to its
interestingly
uh because it stuck to its own
spirituality
spirituality rather
spirituality rather than
spirituality rather than getting
involved
involved in
spirituality rather than getting
involved in local
involved in local politics.
spirituality rather than getting
involved in local politics. What
happened
happened to
happened to most
happened to most religions
happened to most religions I
happened to most religions I think
happened to most religions I think is
that
that they
happened to most religions I think is
that they got
that they got invaded
happened to most religions I think is
that they got invaded by
that they got invaded by the
happened to most religions I think is
that they got invaded by the local
politics
politics to
politics to get
politics to get the
politics to get the church
politics to get the church to
politics to get the church to align
itself
itself with
politics to get the church to align
itself with this
itself with this regime
politics to get the church to align
itself with this regime versus
itself with this regime versus the
politics to get the church to align
itself with this regime versus the house
of
of Hapsburg
of Hapsburg versus
of Hapsburg versus the
of Hapsburg versus the house
of Hapsburg versus the house of
something
something or
of Hapsburg versus the house of
something or other
something or other of
of Hapsburg versus the house of
something or other of course
something or other of course is
of Hapsburg versus the house of
something or other of course is what
costed
costed a
costed a lot
costed a lot of
costed a lot of its
costed a lot of its uh
uh
uh believability.
costed a lot of its uh
uh believability. So,
uh believability. So, I
costed a lot of its uh
uh believability. So, I think
uh believability. So, I think we've
answered
answered most
answered most of
answered most of the
answered most of the most
answered most of the most of
answered most of the most of the
questions
questions that
answered most of the most of the
questions that we
questions that we had
answered most of the most of the
questions that we had on
questions that we had on top
answered most of the most of the
questions that we had on top of
questions that we had on top of the
list.
list. I
list. I want
list. I want to
list. I want to make
list. I want to make sure
um
um we're
list. I want to make sure
um we're often
um we're often asked
list. I want to make sure
um we're often asked about
um we're often asked about Joel
Goldsmith
Goldsmith and
Goldsmith and we've
Goldsmith and we've done
Goldsmith and we've done him
Goldsmith and we've done him many
Goldsmith and we've done him many times.
You
You see,
Goldsmith and we've done him many times.
You see, there's
You see, there's many
Goldsmith and we've done him many times.
You see, there's many spiritual
You see, there's many spiritual teachers
that
that are
that are in
that are in the
that are in the high
that are in the high 400s.
that are in the high 400s. Joel
Goldsmith
Goldsmith is
that are in the high 400s. Joel
Goldsmith is in
Goldsmith is in the
that are in the high 400s. Joel
Goldsmith is in the high
Goldsmith is in the high 400s,
that are in the high 400s. Joel
Goldsmith is in the high 400s, 490,
Goldsmith is in the high 400s, 490, 495,
500.
500. Bill
500. Bill Goldmith's
500. Bill Goldmith's writings
500. Bill Goldmith's writings are
500. Bill Goldmith's writings are over
495.
His
His writings
His writings are
His writings are over
His writings are over 500.
His writings are over 500. His
His writings are over 500. His writings
are
are about
His writings are over 500. His writings
are about 495
are about 495 results.
His writings are over 500. His writings
are about 495 results. Okay,
are about 495 results. Okay, that
His writings are over 500. His writings
are about 495 results. Okay, that so
he's
he's taking
he's taking you
he's taking you as
he's taking you as far
he's taking you as far as
he's taking you as far as the
he's taking you as far as the intellect
can
can take
he's taking you as far as the intellect
can take you
can take you in
he's taking you as far as the intellect
can take you in the
can take you in the understanding
he's taking you as far as the intellect
can take you in the understanding of
can take you in the understanding of of
truth.
truth. The
truth. The teachers
truth. The teachers in
truth. The teachers in the
truth. The teachers in the high
truth. The teachers in the high 400s
truth. The teachers in the high 400s are
often
often very
truth. The teachers in the high 400s are
often very excellent
often very excellent because
truth. The teachers in the high 400s are
often very excellent because they
often very excellent because they have
mastered
mastered the
mastered the knowledge
mastered
mastered the knowledge and
mastered the knowledge and of
mastered
mastered the knowledge and of course
spiritual
searchers
searchers very
spiritual
searchers very are
searchers very are very
spiritual
searchers very are very often
searchers very are very often in
spiritual
searchers very are very often in the
400s
400s and
400s and the
400s and the air
400s and the air addition
400s and the air addition that
400s and the air addition that comes
400s and the air addition that comes in
the
the high
400s and the air addition that comes in
the high 400s
the high 400s is
400s and the air addition that comes in
the high 400s is what
the high 400s is what springs
400s and the air addition that comes in
the high 400s is what springs you
the high 400s is what springs you into
the
the 500s.
the 500s. How
the 500s. How do
the 500s. How do you
the 500s. How do you get
the 500s. How do you get out
the 500s. How do you get out of
the 500s. How do you get out of the
400s?
400s? Because
the 500s. How do you get out of the
400s? Because you
400s? Because you learn
the 500s. How do you get out of the
400s? Because you learn within
400s? Because you learn within the
the 500s. How do you get out of the
400s? Because you learn within the 400s
the
the world
the world of
the world of the
the world of the intellect
that
that the
the world of the intellect
that the intellect
that the intellect is
the world of the intellect
that the intellect is not
that the intellect is not going
the world of the intellect
that the intellect is not going to
that the intellect is not going to give
you
you the
you the answer.
So
So the
you the answer.
So the greatest
So the greatest fruit
you the answer.
So the greatest fruit that
So the greatest fruit that the
you the answer.
So the greatest fruit that the intellect
can
can give
can give you
can give you is
can give you is I
can give you is I ain't
can give you is I ain't what
can give you is I ain't what you're
looking
looking for.
can give you is I ain't what you're
looking for. Whoa.
looking for. Whoa. [laughter]
Because
Because all
Because all society
Because all society thinks
Because all society thinks all
Because all society thinks all you
Because all society thinks all you got
to
to do
Because all society thinks all you got
to do is
to do is read
Because all society thinks all you got
to do is read another
to do is read another book
Because all society thinks all you got
to do is read another book and
to do is read another book and take
another
another course
another course and
another course and you'll
another course and you'll get
another course and you'll get there.
uh
uh Nissa
another course and you'll get there.
uh Nissa Gada
uh Nissa Gada Maharaj's
another course and you'll get there.
uh Nissa Gada Maharaj's level
consciousness
consciousness on
consciousness on the
consciousness on the earth
consciousness on the earth was
consciousness on the earth was over
consciousness on the earth was over 700
conscious
conscious the
consciousness on the earth was over 700
conscious the book
conscious the book I
consciousness on the earth was over 700
conscious the book I am
conscious the book I am that
consciousness on the earth was over 700
conscious the book I am that I
conscious the book I am that I think
consciousness on the earth was over 700
conscious the book I am that I think is
uh
other
other books
other books really
other books really are
other books really are in
other books really are in the
other books really are in the high
other books really are in the high 400s.
Um
Um somebody
other books really are in the high 400s.
Um somebody asked
Um somebody asked me
other books really are in the high 400s.
Um somebody asked me what
Um somebody asked me what love
other books really are in the high 400s.
Um somebody asked me what love is.
Um somebody asked me what love is. Well,
okay.
Um,
as
as as
as as commonly
as as commonly understood,
as as commonly understood, love
as as commonly understood, love is
as as commonly understood, love is an
emotion
emotion and
as as commonly understood, love is an
emotion and this
emotion and this emotion
as as commonly understood, love is an
emotion and this emotion goes
emotion and this emotion goes from
as as commonly understood, love is an
emotion and this emotion goes from here
to
to there.
Love
Love is
to there.
Love is something
Love is something you
to there.
Love is something you give,
Love is something you give, something
to there.
Love is something you give, something is
love
love is
love is something
love is something you
love is something you get.
love is something you get. Consequently,
love
love is
love is something you get. Consequently,
love is something
love is something you
love is something you get. Consequently,
love is something you can
love is something you can lose.
Uh,
therefore,
therefore, love
Uh,
therefore, love is
therefore, love is valitional.
It's
It's conditional.
Uh
there's
there's a
there's a famous
there's a famous cowboy
there's a famous cowboy song.
there's a famous cowboy song. I
there's a famous cowboy song. I just
don't
don't love
there's a famous cowboy song. I just
don't love you
don't love you anymore.
there's a famous cowboy song. I just
don't love you anymore. [laughter]
Sorry
Sorry babe,
Sorry babe, but
Sorry babe, but [laughter]
just
just ain't
Sorry babe, but [laughter]
just ain't got
just ain't got that
Sorry babe, but [laughter]
just ain't got that old
just ain't got that old feeling
Sorry babe, but [laughter]
just ain't got that old feeling for
just ain't got that old feeling for you
the
the way
the way I
the way I used
the way I used to.
Love
Love is
the way I used to.
Love is also
Love is also something
the way I used to.
Love is also something that's
Love is also something that's deserved.
You
You have
You have to
You have to earn
You have to earn love.
You have to earn love. You
You have to earn love. You have
You have to earn love. You have to
You have to earn love. You have to pay
for
for love.
It's
It's like
It's like a
It's like a commodity,
It's like a commodity, a
It's like a commodity, a very
It's like a commodity, a very pleasant
one
one and
It's like a commodity, a very pleasant
one and highly
one and highly regarded.
uh
uh but
uh but it's
uh but it's lossable.
It
It goes
uh but it's lossable.
It goes from
It goes from here
uh but it's lossable.
It goes from here to
It goes from here to there
uh but it's lossable.
It goes from here to there and
It goes from here to there and therefore
it's
it's subject
it's subject to
it's subject to dissolution
and
and vulnerable
it's subject to dissolution
and vulnerable to
and vulnerable to attack
is
is something
is something that
is something that people
is something that people fear
is something that people fear the
is something that people fear the loss
of
of etc.
>> So
>> So what
>> So what is
>> So what is love
>> So what is love actually?
>> So what is love actually? Well,
as
as those
>> So what is love actually? Well,
as those of
as those of you
>> So what is love actually? Well,
as those of you who've
as those of you who've gone
>> So what is love actually? Well,
as those of you who've gone into
as those of you who've gone into really
high
high spaces
high spaces know
high spaces know that
high spaces know that love,
the
the love
high spaces know that love,
the love they're
the love they're talking
high spaces know that love,
the love they're talking about
the love they're talking about is
high spaces know that love,
the love they're talking about is really
about
about up
about up here.
about up here. Love
about up here. Love is
about up here. Love is a
about up here. Love is a way
about up here. Love is a way of
about up here. Love is a way of being.
It's
It's a
about up here. Love is a way of being.
It's a way,
It's a way, it's
about up here. Love is a way of being.
It's a way, it's a
It's a way, it's a way
about up here. Love is a way of being.
It's a way, it's a way of
It's a way, it's a way of being
about up here. Love is a way of being.
It's a way, it's a way of being with
It's a way, it's a way of being with the
world.
The
The condition
world.
The condition of
The condition of lovingness
world.
The condition of lovingness prevails
as
as a
as a permanency
as a permanency because
as a permanency because it's
as a permanency because it's what
as a permanency because it's what and
it's
it's what
as a permanency because it's what and
it's what you
it's what you are.
as a permanency because it's what and
it's what you are. It's
it's what you are. It's what
as a permanency because it's what and
it's what you are. It's what you
it's what you are. It's what you become.
The
The willingness
The willingness to
The willingness to be
The willingness to be friendly
The willingness to be friendly in
Walmarts
Walmarts is
The willingness to be friendly in
Walmarts is because
Walmarts is because you're
The willingness to be friendly in
Walmarts is because you're a
Walmarts is because you're a loving
being.
being. It's
being. It's coming
being. It's coming from
being. It's coming from your
being. It's coming from your lovingness.
Doesn't
Doesn't depend
being. It's coming from your lovingness.
Doesn't depend on
Doesn't depend on whether
being. It's coming from your lovingness.
Doesn't depend on whether this
Doesn't depend on whether this lady
being. It's coming from your lovingness.
Doesn't depend on whether this lady with
her
her basket
her basket smiles
her basket smiles you
her basket smiles you or
her basket smiles you or appreciates
her basket smiles you or appreciates it.
It's
It's just
her basket smiles you or appreciates it.
It's just who
It's just who you
her basket smiles you or appreciates it.
It's just who you are.
It's just who you are. And
her basket smiles you or appreciates it.
It's just who you are. And it's
It's just who you are. And it's who
her basket smiles you or appreciates it.
It's just who you are. And it's who you
are
are in
are in all
times,
times, places,
are in all
times, places, and
times, places, and conditions.
are in all
times, places, and conditions. It
doesn't
doesn't change.
doesn't change. Uh
doesn't change. Uh it's
doesn't change. Uh it's not
doesn't change. Uh it's not given.
doesn't change. Uh it's not given. It's
not
not lost.
doesn't change. Uh it's not given. It's
not lost. It's
not lost. It's not
doesn't change. Uh it's not given. It's
not lost. It's not taken
not lost. It's not taken away.
doesn't change. Uh it's not given. It's
not lost. It's not taken away. It's
not lost. It's not taken away. It's not
something
something you
something you earn.
something you earn. It's
something you earn. It's what
something you earn. It's what you've
become.
become. Similar
something you earn. It's what you've
become. Similar to
become. Similar to generosity.
Generosity
Generosity is
Generosity is a
Generosity is a way
Generosity is a way of
Generosity is a way of being
Generosity is a way of being in
Generosity is a way of being in the
world.
world. It
Generosity is a way of being in the
world. It doesn't
world. It doesn't have
Generosity is a way of being in the
world. It doesn't have to
world. It doesn't have to do
Generosity is a way of being in the
world. It doesn't have to do with
world. It doesn't have to do with money.
Generosity
Generosity has
Generosity has to
Generosity has to do
Generosity has to do with
Generosity has to do with the
willingness
willingness to
Generosity has to do with the
willingness to be
willingness to be open
Generosity has to do with the
willingness to be open and
willingness to be open and share
Generosity has to do with the
willingness to be open and share what
you
you are
you are with
you are with life
you are with life for
what?
what? For
you are with life for
what? For the
what? For the good
you are with life for
what? For the good of
what? For the good of life
you are with life for
what? For the good of life itself
what? For the good of life itself only
because
because of
because of that's
because of that's what
because of that's what you
because of that's what you are.
because of that's what you are. It's
because
because that's
because of that's what you are. It's
because that's where
because that's where you
because of that's what you are. It's
because that's where you become.
because that's where you become. You
automatically
you
you automatically
uh
uh appreciate
uh appreciate life
uh appreciate life and
uh appreciate life and all
uh appreciate life and all its
expressions.
You
You know what
You know what I
You know what I mean?
You know what I mean? You
You know what I mean? You drive
You know what I mean? You drive along
You know what I mean? You drive along a
country
country road.
You know what I mean? You drive along a
country road. The
country road. The place
You know what I mean? You drive along a
country road. The place I
country road. The place I go
You know what I mean? You drive along a
country road. The place I go to
country road. The place I go to the
girls
girls ranch
girls ranch three
girls ranch three mornings
girls ranch three mornings a
girls ranch three mornings a week
girls ranch three mornings a week where
I'm
I'm chief
girls ranch three mornings a week where
I'm chief of
I'm chief of staff.
girls ranch three mornings a week where
I'm chief of staff. Got
I'm chief of staff. Got 55
girls ranch three mornings a week where
I'm chief of staff. Got 55 girls
I'm chief of staff. Got 55 girls there
and
and all
and all conditions
and all conditions of
and all conditions of disarray.
and all conditions of disarray. I'll
tell
tell you.
and all conditions of disarray. I'll
tell you. Anyway,
tell you. Anyway, on
and all conditions of disarray. I'll
tell you. Anyway, on the
tell you. Anyway, on the way
and all conditions of disarray. I'll
tell you. Anyway, on the way there,
there's
there's a
there's a bunch
there's a bunch of
there's a bunch of periodically
there's a bunch of periodically there's
a
a bunch
there's a bunch of periodically there's
a bunch of
a bunch of cows,
there's a bunch of periodically there's
a bunch of cows, you
a bunch of cows, you know,
there's a bunch of periodically there's
a bunch of cows, you know, bunch
a bunch of cows, you know, bunch of
cattle
cattle there
cattle there and
cattle there and you
cattle there and you can't
cattle there and you can't help
cattle there and you can't help but
cattle there and you can't help but stop
and
and love
cattle there and you can't help but stop
and love and
and love and the
cattle there and you can't help but stop
and love and the cows
and love and the cows look
cattle there and you can't help but stop
and love and the cows look at
and love and the cows look at you
cattle there and you can't help but stop
and love and the cows look at you like
this.
this. [laughter]
I
I mean,
this. [laughter]
I mean, I
I mean, I say
this. [laughter]
I mean, I say this
I mean, I say this morning,
this. [laughter]
I mean, I say this morning, I'm
I mean, I say this morning, I'm not
going
going to
going to stop
going to stop with
going to stop with the
going to stop with the cows
going to stop with the cows at
going to stop with the cows at 8:00
already.
already. But
going to stop with the cows at 8:00
already. But then
already. But then the
going to stop with the cows at 8:00
already. But then the cow's
already. But then the cow's standing
there
there and
there and she
there and she looks
there and she looks at
there and she looks at me
there and she looks at me like
there and she looks at me like that
there and she looks at me like that and
you
you just
there and she looks at me like that and
you just have
you just have to
there and she looks at me like that and
you just have to be
you just have to be with
there and she looks at me like that and
you just have to be with the
you just have to be with the cow
there and she looks at me like that and
you just have to be with the cow because
she's
she's life
she's life expressing
she's life expressing itself
uh
uh in
she's life expressing itself
uh in that
uh in that beautiful
she's life expressing itself
uh in that beautiful way
uh in that beautiful way that
she's life expressing itself
uh in that beautiful way that a
uh in that beautiful way that a cow
she's life expressing itself
uh in that beautiful way that a cow is.
You
You know,
You know, a
You know, a cow
You know, a cow just
You know, a cow just a
You know, a cow just a beautiful
creature
creature being
You know, a cow just a beautiful
creature being what
creature being what it
You know, a cow just a beautiful
creature being what it is.
creature being what it is. You
You know, a cow just a beautiful
creature being what it is. You know
creature being what it is. You know what
I'm
I'm saying?
I'm saying? And
I'm saying? And there's
I'm saying? And there's the
I'm saying? And there's the little
calves
calves there
I'm saying? And there's the little
calves there being
calves there being what
I'm saying? And there's the little
calves there being what they
calves there being what they are.
I'm saying? And there's the little
calves there being what they are. And
calves there being what they are. And of
course,
course, you
course, you know,
course, you know, they're
course, you know, they're going
course, you know, they're going to
course, you know, they're going to get
eaten
eaten someday.
[laughter]
You
You can
[laughter]
You can even
You can even say,
[laughter]
You can even say, "I'm
You can even say, "I'm going
[laughter]
You can even say, "I'm going to
You can even say, "I'm going to love
eating
eating you
eating you sometime,
eating you sometime, baby."
eating you sometime, baby." You
eating you sometime, baby." You know
[laughter]
why
why is
why is the
why is the cow
why is the cow there?
Well,
Well, if
why is the cow there?
Well, if you
Well, if you didn't
why is the cow there?
Well, if you didn't eat
Well, if you didn't eat meat,
why is the cow there?
Well, if you didn't eat meat, there
wouldn't
wouldn't be
wouldn't be any
wouldn't be any cows.
wouldn't be any cows. Do
wouldn't be any cows. Do you
wouldn't be any cows. Do you realize
that?
If
If everybody
If everybody gives
If everybody gives up
If everybody gives up eating
If everybody gives up eating meat,
If everybody gives up eating meat, cows
will
will disappear.
If everybody gives up eating meat, cows
will disappear. Who's
will disappear. Who's going
If everybody gives up eating meat, cows
will disappear. Who's going to
will disappear. Who's going to raise
them?
them? Who's
them? Who's going
them? Who's going to
them? Who's going to feed
them? Who's going to feed them?
them? Who's going to feed them? Who's
going
going to
them? Who's going to feed them? Who's
going to go
going to go to
them? Who's going to feed them? Who's
going to go to all
going to go to all that
them? Who's going to feed them? Who's
going to go to all that work
going to go to all that work for
them? Who's going to feed them? Who's
going to go to all that work for what?
Right?
The
The eating
Right?
The eating of
The eating of cows
Right?
The eating of cows then
The eating of cows then means
Right?
The eating of cows then means that
millions
millions of
millions of cows
millions of cows come
millions of cows come into
millions of cows come into experiencing
life.
When
When they
When they get
When they get put
When they get put to
When they get put to sleep,
When they get put to sleep, they
instantly
instantly disappear
When they get put to sleep, they
instantly disappear on
instantly disappear on the
When they get put to sleep, they
instantly disappear on the other
instantly disappear on the other side.
They
They come
They come back
They come back as
They come back as another
They come back as another cow
They come back as another cow again.
[laughter]
It's
It's all
It's all the
It's all the same
It's all the same cow.
It's all the same cow. Let's
It's all the same cow. Let's see
It's all the same cow. Let's see if
that's
that's true.
Generically
Generically speaking,
Generically speaking, it's
Generically speaking, it's all
Generically speaking, it's all the
Generically speaking, it's all the same
cow.
cow. It's
Generically speaking, it's all the same
cow. It's all
cow. It's all the
Generically speaking, it's all the same
cow. It's all the same
cow. It's all the same cow.
[laughter]
Why
Why do
[laughter]
Why do we
Why do we say
[laughter]
Why do we say that?
Why do we say that? Because
[laughter]
Why do we say that? Because the
consciousness
consciousness of
consciousness of We
consciousness of We did
consciousness of We did it
consciousness of We did it on
consciousness of We did it on our
consciousness of We did it on our orange
kitty.
All
All orange
All orange kitties
All orange kitties are
All orange kitties are the
All orange kitties are the same
All orange kitties are the same orange
kitty.
Yes,
we
we said
Yes,
we said that
we said that evolution
Yes,
we said that evolution as
we said that evolution as it
Yes,
we said that evolution as it appears
we said that evolution as it appears in
physicality
physicality is
physicality is the
physicality is the reflection
physicality is the reflection of
physicality is the reflection of that
which
which has
physicality is the reflection of that
which has occurred
which has occurred on
physicality is the reflection of that
which has occurred on the
which has occurred on the level
physicality is the reflection of that
which has occurred on the level of
consciousness.
consciousness. It's
consciousness. It's on
consciousness. It's on the
consciousness. It's on the level
consciousness. It's on the level of
consciousness
consciousness that
consciousness. It's on the level of
consciousness that form
consciousness that form evolves
consciousness. It's on the level of
consciousness that form evolves into
consciousness that form evolves into the
forms
forms that
forms that we
forms that we see
forms that we see as
forms that we see as life
forms that we see as life on
forms that we see as life on earth.
The
The form
forms that we see as life on earth.
The form can
The form can then
forms that we see as life on earth.
The form can then be
The form can then be optionally
energized
energized by
energized by energies
energized by energies on
energized by energies on the
energized by energies on the other
energized by energies on the other side.
You
You might
energized by energies on the other side.
You might would
You might would say
energized by energies on the other side.
You might would say for
You might would say for speech
energized by energies on the other side.
You might would say for speech on
You might would say for speech on the
other
other side
other side can
other side can opt
other side can opt to
other side can opt to be
other side can opt to be the
other side can opt to be the life
other side can opt to be the life energy
within
within that
other side can opt to be the life energy
within that form.
That
That form
That form has
That form has a
That form has a central
That form has a central you
That form has a central you remember
That form has a central you remember in
power
power versus
That form has a central you remember in
power versus force
power versus force we
That form has a central you remember in
power versus force we talked
power versus force we talked about
attractor
attractor fields
attractor fields in
attractor fields in the
attractor fields in the nonlinear
attractor fields in the nonlinear domain
of
of what
attractor fields in the nonlinear domain
of what appears
of what appears as
attractor fields in the nonlinear domain
of what appears as chaos.
of what appears as chaos. what
attractor fields in the nonlinear domain
of what appears as chaos. what appears
as
as chaos.
as chaos. Multiple
as chaos. Multiple orange
as chaos. Multiple orange kitties
as chaos. Multiple orange kitties all
over
over the
as chaos. Multiple orange kitties all
over the planet.
over the planet. There
as chaos. Multiple orange kitties all
over the planet. There is
over the planet. There is a
as chaos. Multiple orange kitties all
over the planet. There is a central
attractor
attractor field
attractor field of
attractor field of orange
attractor field of orange kittiness.
We
We could
attractor field of orange kittiness.
We could even
We could even draw
attractor field of orange kittiness.
We could even draw if
We could even draw if we
attractor field of orange kittiness.
We could even draw if we had
We could even draw if we had a
attractor field of orange kittiness.
We could even draw if we had a computer.
There's
There's an
There's an attractor
There's an attractor field.
Nature
Nature draws
There's an attractor field.
Nature draws attractor
Nature draws attractor fields
There's an attractor field.
Nature draws attractor fields for
Nature draws attractor fields for you
all
all the
all the time.
all the time. All
all the time. All you
all the time. All you have
all the time. All you have to
all the time. All you have to do
all the time. All you have to do is
all the time. All you have to do is fly
in
in a
all the time. All you have to do is fly
in a plane
in a plane and
all the time. All you have to do is fly
in a plane and look
in a plane and look at
all the time. All you have to do is fly
in a plane and look at the
in a plane and look at the formation
all the time. All you have to do is fly
in a plane and look at the formation of
the
the earth
the earth below
the earth below you
the earth below you and
the earth below you and the
the earth below you and the vegetation.
But
But as
the earth below you and the vegetation.
But as you
But as you watch
the earth below you and the vegetation.
But as you watch um
But as you watch um the
the earth below you and the vegetation.
But as you watch um the there's
But as you watch um the there's a
beautiful
beautiful series
beautiful series of
beautiful series of uh
beautiful series of uh videos
beautiful series of uh videos on
beautiful series of uh videos on right
now
now or
beautiful series of uh videos on right
now or TVs
now or TVs on
beautiful series of uh videos on right
now or TVs on now
now or TVs on now called
beautiful series of uh videos on right
now or TVs on now called the
now or TVs on now called the Deep
beautiful series of uh videos on right
now or TVs on now called the Deep Blue.
What
What is
What is it?
What is it? Deep
What is it? Deep Blue.
What is it? Deep Blue. Yeah.
Underwater.
Underwater. A
What is it? Deep Blue. Yeah.
Underwater. A magnificent
Underwater. A magnificent series
What is it? Deep Blue. Yeah.
Underwater. A magnificent series on
Underwater. A magnificent series on the
History
History Channel.
History Channel. I
History Channel. I think
History Channel. I think it's
History Channel. I think it's a
Discovery
Discovery Channel.
History Channel. I think it's a
Discovery Channel. Anyway,
Discovery Channel. Anyway, incredible
History Channel. I think it's a
Discovery Channel. Anyway, incredible be
the
the incredible
the incredible beauty
the incredible beauty at
the incredible beauty at the
the incredible beauty at the depth
the incredible beauty at the depth of
the
the sea.
the incredible beauty at the depth of
the sea. Stunning
the sea. Stunning creatures.
So
So stunningly
So stunningly beautiful.
So stunningly beautiful. You
So stunningly beautiful. You just
So stunningly beautiful. You just suck
in
in your
So stunningly beautiful. You just suck
in your breath.
in your breath. You
So stunningly beautiful. You just suck
in your breath. You go.
in your breath. You go. That's
So stunningly beautiful. You just suck
in your breath. You go. That's existing
5,000
5,000 ft
5,000 ft down
5,000 ft down in
5,000 ft down in the
5,000 ft down in the dark.
5,000 ft down in the dark. Woo!
5,000 ft down in the dark. Woo! Gorgeous
radiance.
radiance. Beautiful.
5,000 ft down in the dark. Woo! Gorgeous
radiance. Beautiful. But
radiance. Beautiful. But you
5,000 ft down in the dark. Woo! Gorgeous
radiance. Beautiful. But you see
radiance. Beautiful. But you see the
schools
schools of
schools of fish
schools of fish feeling
schools of fish feeling as
schools of fish feeling as though
they're
they're worn
schools of fish feeling as though
they're worn like
they're worn like this.
You
You see
You see the
You see the whole
You see the whole tens
You see the whole tens of
You see the whole tens of thousands
You see the whole tens of thousands of
fish
fish all
You see the whole tens of thousands of
fish all in
fish all in the
You see the whole tens of thousands of
fish all in the design
fish all in the design like
You see the whole tens of thousands of
fish all in the design like this.
fish all in the design like this. You
see
see the
see the same
see the same thing
see the same thing with
see the same thing with the
see the same thing with the birds
see the same thing with the birds taking
off.
off. They
see the same thing with the birds taking
off. They all
off. They all like
see the same thing with the birds taking
off. They all like this.
off. They all like this. Well,
see the same thing with the birds taking
off. They all like this. Well, the
presumption
presumption of
presumption of the
presumption of the ego
presumption of the ego which
presumption of the ego which believes
presumption of the ego which believes in
causality
causality is
presumption of the ego which believes in
causality is that
causality is that this
presumption of the ego which believes in
causality is that this bird
causality is that this bird is
presumption of the ego which believes in
causality is that this bird is flying
like
like like
like like a
like like a squadron
like like a squadron of
like like a squadron of fighters
like like a squadron of fighters this
many
many feet
like like a squadron of fighters this
many feet from
many feet from this
like like a squadron of fighters this
many feet from this one.
many feet from this one. It
like like a squadron of fighters this
many feet from this one. It thinks
many feet from this one. It thinks that
these
these birds
these birds are
these birds are following
these birds are following this
these birds are following this birds
and
and being
these birds are following this birds
and being causing
and being causing these.
these birds are following this birds
and being causing these. So
and being causing these. So actually
what's
what's happening
what's happening these
what's happening these birds
what's happening these birds are
what's happening these birds are not
following
following each
what's happening these birds are not
following each other
following each other at
what's happening these birds are not
following each other at all.
following each other at all. These
what's happening these birds are not
following each other at all. These birds
are
are being
are being controlled
are being controlled by
are being controlled by an
are being controlled by an attractor
field
field in
are being controlled by an attractor
field in the
field in the visible
are being controlled by an attractor
field in the visible domain.
Each
Each bird
Each bird is
Each bird is uniquely
Each bird is uniquely controlled
Each bird is uniquely controlled by
Each bird is uniquely controlled by the
same
same attractor
Each bird is uniquely controlled by the
same attractor field
same attractor field and
Each bird is uniquely controlled by the
same attractor field and that's
same attractor field and that's why
Each bird is uniquely controlled by the
same attractor field and that's why they
line
line up.
line up. They're
line up. They're not
line up. They're not following
line up. They're not following each
other
other at
line up. They're not following each
other at all.
So
So when
So when you
So when you see
So when you see the
So when you see the birds
So when you see the birds feeling
So when you see the birds feeling like
that,
that, that's
So when you see the birds feeling like
that, that's the
that, that's the demonstration
So when you see the birds feeling like
that, that's the demonstration of
that, that's the demonstration of the
attractor
attractor field
attractor field which
attractor field which is
attractor field which is in
attractor field which is in the
invisible
invisible domain
attractor field which is in the
invisible domain becoming
invisible domain becoming manifest
attractor field which is in the
invisible domain becoming manifest in
invisible domain becoming manifest in a
flock
flock of
flock of birds
flock of birds in
flock of birds in flight.
[clears throat]
That's
That's stunningly
That's stunningly obvious
That's stunningly obvious in
That's stunningly obvious in this
series.
series. is
That's stunningly obvious in this
series. is the
series. is the deep
That's stunningly obvious in this
series. is the deep blue.
series. is the deep blue. You
That's stunningly obvious in this
series. is the deep blue. You see
series. is the deep blue. You see um
That's stunningly obvious in this
series. is the deep blue. You see um 5
million
million minnows
million minnows all
million minnows all turning
million minnows all turning as
million minnows all turning as one
million minnows all turning as one and
the
the shine
million minnows all turning as one and
the shine of
the shine of light
million minnows all turning as one and
the shine of light as
the shine of light as they
million minnows all turning as one and
the shine of light as they swing.
the shine of light as they swing. They
swing
swing like
swing like one
swing like one one
swing like one one being
swing like one one being one
swing like one one being one being
swing like one one being one being and
thousands
thousands and
swing like one one being one being and
thousands and thousands
thousands and thousands of
swing like one one being one being and
thousands and thousands of bodies
simultaneously.
simultaneously. That's
simultaneously. That's the
simultaneously. That's the attractive
field.
The
The animal
The animal gods
The animal gods of
The animal gods of the
The animal gods of the Native
The animal gods of the Native Americans,
the
the many
The animal gods of the Native Americans,
the many gods
the many gods of
The animal gods of the Native Americans,
the many gods of the
the many gods of the Hindu
The animal gods of the Native Americans,
the many gods of the Hindu pantheon
all
all represent
all represent to
all represent to me
um
um symbolic
those
those are
those are the
those are the attractor
those are the attractor fields.
those are the attractor fields. In
those are the attractor fields. In other
words,
there
there is
there is central
there is central to
there is central to all
there is central to all orange
there is central to all orange kittiness
the
the essence
there is central to all orange kittiness
the essence of
the essence of that
there is central to all orange kittiness
the essence of that which
the essence of that which makes
there is central to all orange kittiness
the essence of that which makes orange
kittiness
kittiness and
kittiness and it
kittiness and it radiates
kittiness and it radiates out
kittiness and it radiates out what
kittiness and it radiates out what looks
to
to perception
kittiness and it radiates out what looks
to perception as
to perception as individual
kittiness and it radiates out what looks
to perception as individual separate
orange
orange kitties.
orange kitties. But
orange kitties. But there's
orange kitties. But there's only
orange kitties. But there's only one
orange
orange kittiness
orange kitties. But there's only one
orange kittiness that's
orange kittiness that's radiating
orange kitties. But there's only one
orange kittiness that's radiating out.
You
You understand
You understand what
You understand what I'm
You understand what I'm saying?
So
So the
You understand what I'm saying?
So the essence
So the essence of
You understand what I'm saying?
So the essence of each
So the essence of each genus
You understand what I'm saying?
So the essence of each genus and
So the essence of each genus and species
then
then exists
then exists on
then exists on the
then exists on the invisible
then exists on the invisible domain
then exists on the invisible domain and
actualizes
actualizes within
then exists on the invisible domain and
actualizes within the
actualizes within the physical.
What
What I
What I what
What I what I
What I what I said
What I what I said is
What I what I said is true
What I what I said is true is
there
there is
What I what I said is true is
there is one
there is one orange
What I what I said is true is
there is one orange kitty.
there is one orange kitty. Is
What I what I said is true is
there is one orange kitty. Is there
there is one orange kitty. Is there is
one
one orange
one orange kitty.
The
The reason
one orange kitty.
The reason I
The reason I know
one orange kitty.
The reason I know this
The reason I know this is
one orange kitty.
The reason I know this is I've
The reason I know this is I've had
one orange kitty.
The reason I know this is I've had a
whole
whole series
whole series of
whole series of orange
whole series of orange kitties
whole series of orange kitties and
whole series of orange kitties and it's
always
always the
whole series of orange kitties and it's
always the same
always the same kitty.
whole series of orange kitties and it's
always the same kitty. [laughter]
I
I mean,
I mean, in
I mean, in orange
I mean, in orange kitty's
I mean, in orange kitty's nature
I mean, in orange kitty's nature is
I mean, in orange kitty's nature is the
same.
same. You
I mean, in orange kitty's nature is the
same. You ever
same. You ever notice
I mean, in orange kitty's nature is the
same. You ever notice that?
same. You ever notice that? Doberman
pinchers.
pinchers. They're
pinchers. They're all
pinchers. They're all the
pinchers. They're all the same,
pinchers. They're all the same, you
know.
know. So
pinchers. They're all the same, you
know. So we
know. So we love
pinchers. They're all the same, you
know. So we love each
know. So we love each species
pinchers. They're all the same, you
know. So we love each species and
know. So we love each species and and
genus
genus because
genus because it
genus because it represents
genus because it represents in
physicality
certain
certain characteristics
certain characteristics that
certain characteristics that we've
certain characteristics that we've come
to
to love
certain characteristics that we've come
to love and
to love and appreciate.
>> That
>> That goes
>> That goes for
>> That goes for the
>> That goes for the animal
>> That goes for the animal kingdom.
>> That goes for the animal kingdom. But
does
does that
>> That goes for the animal kingdom. But
does that go
does that go with
>> That goes for the animal kingdom. But
does that go with the
does that go with the human?
>> Oh,
>> Oh, you
>> Oh, you would
>> Oh, you would ask
>> Oh, you would ask such
>> Oh, you would ask such a
>> Oh, you would ask such a question,
wouldn't
wouldn't you?
[laughter]
Oh
Oh my
[laughter]
Oh my goodness.
Oh my goodness. I
[laughter]
Oh my goodness. I don't
Oh my goodness. I don't know.
Turn
Turn out
Turn out the
Turn out the lights.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh
>> Uh this
>> Uh this is
>> Uh this is a
>> Uh this is a valid
>> Uh this is a valid question
>> Uh this is a valid question resist.
It's
It's an
>> Uh this is a valid question resist.
It's an answerable
It's an answerable question
>> Uh this is a valid question resist.
It's an answerable question resist.
It's an answerable question resist. It's
not
not an
not an answerable
not an answerable question.
not an answerable question. [laughter]
I
I think
not an answerable question. [laughter]
I think because
I think because of
not an answerable question. [laughter]
I think because of individual
I think because of individual karma
not an answerable question. [laughter]
I think because of individual karma in
the
the condition
the condition of
the condition of the
the condition of the human
the condition of the human we
the condition of the human we have
individual
individual karma
the condition of the human we have
individual karma resist.
individual karma resist. Yeah.
the condition of the human we have
individual karma resist. Yeah. So
individual karma resist. Yeah. So we
don't
don't represent
don't represent a
>> uh
>> uh a
don't represent a
>> uh a group
>> uh a group uh
don't represent a
>> uh a group uh the
>> uh a group uh the manifestation
don't represent a
>> uh a group uh the manifestation of
otherwise
otherwise there
otherwise there would
otherwise there would be
otherwise there would be like
otherwise there would be like one
otherwise there would be like one human
being
being and
otherwise there would be like one human
being and we
being and we would
otherwise there would be like one human
being and we would all
being and we would all radiate
otherwise there would be like one human
being and we would all radiate out
being and we would all radiate out the
sameness
sameness the
sameness the sameness
but
but what
sameness the sameness
but what we
but what we radiate
sameness the sameness
but what we radiate mainly
but what we radiate mainly is
sameness the sameness
but what we radiate mainly is difference
right
right there's
right there's the
right there's the sameness
right there's the sameness to
right there's the sameness to our
essence
essence but
right there's the sameness to our
essence but a
essence but a difference
um
could
could be
um
could be the
could be the different
um
could be the different races
could be the different races maybe
represent
represent do
represent do perhaps
represent do perhaps different
represent do perhaps different races
represent
represent sort
represent do perhaps different races
represent sort sort
represent sort sort of
represent do perhaps different races
represent sort sort of a
represent sort sort of a coalition
represent do perhaps different races
represent sort sort of a coalition of
energies
energies resist.
energies resist. No,
energies resist. No, they
energies resist. No, they don't
energies resist. No, they don't even.
energies resist. No, they don't even. So
humanness
humanness is
energies resist. No, they don't even. So
humanness is an
humanness is an individual
energies resist. No, they don't even. So
humanness is an individual karma
humanness is an individual karma resist.
>> Orange
>> Orange kittiness
>> Orange kittiness is
>> Orange kittiness is a
>> Orange kittiness is a group
>> Orange kittiness is a group karma
resist.
resist. Well,
>> Orange kittiness is a group karma
resist. Well, that's
resist. Well, that's there's
>> Orange kittiness is a group karma
resist. Well, that's there's certain
spiritual
spiritual teachings
spiritual teachings that
spiritual teachings that animals
spiritual teachings that animals share
spiritual teachings that animals share a
group
group karma
spiritual teachings that animals share a
group karma whereas
group karma whereas mankind
spiritual teachings that animals share a
group karma whereas mankind share
group karma whereas mankind share has
individual
individual karmas.
individual karmas. So
individual karmas. So the
individual karmas. So the orange
individual karmas. So the orange kitties
then
then have
individual karmas. So the orange kitties
then have a
then have a group
individual karmas. So the orange kitties
then have a group orange
then have a group orange kittiness
karma.
karma. [laughter]
They
They have
karma. [laughter]
They have a
They have a pretty
karma. [laughter]
They have a pretty good
They have a pretty good pretty
karma. [laughter]
They have a pretty good pretty good
karma.
>> We
>> We have
karma.
>> We have permission
>> We have permission to
karma.
>> We have permission to ask
>> We have permission to ask that
karma.
>> We have permission to ask that humans
have
have the
have the capacity
have the capacity to
have the capacity to reincarnate
have the capacity to reincarnate in
subhuman
subhuman forms.
have the capacity to reincarnate in
subhuman forms. He
subhuman forms. He says
have the capacity to reincarnate in
subhuman forms. He says no.
subhuman forms. He says no. I've
have the capacity to reincarnate in
subhuman forms. He says no. I've asked
that
that before.
that before. We
that before. We always
that before. We always get
that before. We always get no.
that before. We always get no. So
that before. We always get no. So you
don't
don't have
that before. We always get no. So you
don't have to
don't have to worry
that before. We always get no. So you
don't have to worry about
don't have to worry about coming
that before. We always get no. So you
don't have to worry about coming back
don't have to worry about coming back as
a
a frog.
Only
Only a
a frog.
Only a frog
Only a frog gets
a frog.
Only a frog gets to
Only a frog gets to come
a frog.
Only a frog gets to come back
Only a frog gets to come back as
a frog.
Only a frog gets to come back as a
Only a frog gets to come back as a frog.
[laughter]
All
All right.
What
What was
What was the
What was the reason
What was the reason we
What was the reason we got
What was the reason we got out
What was the reason we got out of
What was the reason we got out of this?
Anyway,
[laughter]
this
this asks
[laughter]
this asks the
this asks the purpose
[laughter]
this asks the purpose of
this asks the purpose of enlightenment.
Well,
Well, is
Well, is the
Well, is the highest
Well, is the highest level
Well, is the highest level of
enlightenment
enlightenment the
Well, is the highest level of
enlightenment the desire
enlightenment the desire to
Well, is the highest level of
enlightenment the desire to help
enlightenment the desire to help others
become
become enlightened?
become enlightened? Um
become enlightened? Um you
become enlightened? Um you might
become enlightened? Um you might say
become enlightened? Um you might say so
if
if that
become enlightened? Um you might say so
if that but
if that but that
become enlightened? Um you might say so
if that but that that
if that but that that again
become enlightened? Um you might say so
if that but that that again is
if that but that that again is a
become enlightened? Um you might say so
if that but that that again is a program
that
that is
that is rejected
that is rejected on
that is rejected on the
that is rejected on the condition.
that is rejected on the condition. The
condition
condition only
that is rejected on the condition. The
condition only is
condition only is what
that is rejected on the condition. The
condition only is what it
condition only is what it is.
Uh
it
it is
Uh
it is what
it is what it
Uh
it is what it is
it is what it is to
Uh
it is what it is to the
it is what it is to the world
Uh
it is what it is to the world because
because
because it
because it is
because it is that
because it is that it's
because it is that it's similar
because it is that it's similar to
because it is that it's similar to the
question
question about
because it is that it's similar to the
question about uh
question about uh loving
because it is that it's similar to the
question about uh loving lovingness.
You
You see
You see you
You see you don't
You see you don't you're
You see you don't you're not
You see you don't you're not loving
You see you don't you're not loving in
in
in order
You see you don't you're not loving in
in order to
in order to anything.
You
You understand
You understand what
You understand what I'm
You understand what I'm saying?
You understand what I'm saying? You're
not
not once
You understand what I'm saying? You're
not once a
not once a person
You understand what I'm saying? You're
not once a person becomes
not once a person becomes loving
You understand what I'm saying? You're
not once a person becomes loving there
is
is no
is no purpose
is no purpose to
is no purpose to that
is no purpose to that lovingness.
is no purpose to that lovingness. It's
just
just what
is no purpose to that lovingness. It's
just what they
just what they are.
is no purpose to that lovingness. It's
just what they are. They
just what they are. They become
is no purpose to that lovingness. It's
just what they are. They become that.
So
So you're
So you're not
So you're not that
So you're not that lovingness
So you're not that lovingness doesn't
like
like present
So you're not that lovingness doesn't
like present itself
like present itself in
So you're not that lovingness doesn't
like present itself in Walmarts
like present itself in Walmarts in
So you're not that lovingness doesn't
like present itself in Walmarts in order
to
to make
to make other
to make other shoppers
to make other shoppers happy
to make other shoppers happy or
to make other shoppers happy or for
to make other shoppers happy or for any
other
other reason.
to make other shoppers happy or for any
other reason. It's
other reason. It's just
to make other shoppers happy or for any
other reason. It's just who
other reason. It's just who you
to make other shoppers happy or for any
other reason. It's just who you are.
other reason. It's just who you are. And
who
who you
who you are
who you are turns
who you are turns some
who you are turns some people
who you are turns some people on
who you are turns some people on and
probably
probably makes
who you are turns some people on and
probably makes other
probably makes other people
who you are turns some people on and
probably makes other people hate
probably makes other people hate you.
[laughter]
Lots
Lots of
[laughter]
Lots of people
Lots of people hate
[laughter]
Lots of people hate love.
Lots of people hate love. is
[laughter]
Lots of people hate love. is there
Lots of people hate love. is there were
countries
countries in
countries in the
countries in the world
countries in the world in
countries in the world in which
countries in the world in which it
countries in the world in which it was
illegal.
illegal. You
countries in the world in which it was
illegal. You know,
illegal. You know, Cambodia
countries in the world in which it was
illegal. You know, Cambodia was
illegal. You know, Cambodia was one
countries in the world in which it was
illegal. You know, Cambodia was one of
them.
them. Remember
them. Remember Paul
them. Remember Paul taught
them. Remember Paul taught you
them. Remember Paul taught you put
them. Remember Paul taught you put to
death
death if
them. Remember Paul taught you put to
death if you
death if you display
them. Remember Paul taught you put to
death if you display affection
death if you display affection and
lovingness
lovingness in
lovingness in public.
lovingness in public. It's
lovingness in public. It's suitable
lovingness in public. It's suitable for
execution.
execution. So,
a
a Japanese
a Japanese warrior
a Japanese warrior and
a Japanese warrior and then
a Japanese warrior and then king
a Japanese warrior and then king who
showed
showed lovingness
a Japanese warrior and then king who
showed lovingness towards
showed lovingness towards his
a Japanese warrior and then king who
showed lovingness towards his captive,
I'm
I'm sure
I'm sure would
I'm sure would may
I'm sure would may have
I'm sure would may have been
I'm sure would may have been gotten
himself
himself bayoneted
I'm sure would may have been gotten
himself bayoneted on
himself bayoneted on the
I'm sure would may have been gotten
himself bayoneted on the spot
himself bayoneted on the spot for
for
for insubordination.
Nikki
Nikki What's
for insubordination.
Nikki What's the
Nikki What's the Is
for insubordination.
Nikki What's the Is there
Nikki What's the Is there a
for insubordination.
Nikki What's the Is there a correlation
between
between intelligence
between intelligence and
between intelligence and consciousness?
>> I
>> I never
between intelligence and consciousness?
>> I never asked
>> I never asked that
between intelligence and consciousness?
>> I never asked that before.
>> I never asked that before. You
between intelligence and consciousness?
>> I never asked that before. You mean
>> I never asked that before. You mean like
IQ?
>> IQ.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, there
>> Yeah, there is
>> Yeah, there is some
>> Yeah, there is some correlation,
meaningful
meaningful correlation
>> Yeah, there is some correlation,
meaningful correlation between
meaningful correlation between IQ
>> Yeah, there is some correlation,
meaningful correlation between IQ and
consciousness
consciousness resist.
consciousness resist. No,
you
you can
consciousness resist. No,
you can be
you can be have
consciousness resist. No,
you can be have an
you can be have an IQ
consciousness resist. No,
you can be have an IQ and
you can be have an IQ and be
consciousness resist. No,
you can be have an IQ and be very
stupid.
You
You can
stupid.
You can be
You can be very
stupid.
You can be very stupid
You can be very stupid and
stupid.
You can be very stupid and be
You can be very stupid and be very
beneficial
beneficial to
beneficial to the
beneficial to the world,
beneficial to the world, you
beneficial to the world, you know.
So,
So, no,
beneficial to the world, you know.
So, no, apparently
So, no, apparently not.
beneficial to the world, you know.
So, no, apparently not. It's
So, no, apparently not. It's just
beneficial to the world, you know.
So, no, apparently not. It's just some
people
people are
people are built
people are built more
people are built more muscular.
people are built more muscular. Somebody
came
came up
people are built more muscular. Somebody
came up today
came up today and
people are built more muscular. Somebody
came up today and he
came up today and he to
people are built more muscular. Somebody
came up today and he to me
came up today and he to me he
people are built more muscular. Somebody
came up today and he to me he was
came up today and he to me he was the
perfect
perfect misamore.
perfect misamore. You
perfect misamore. You know what
perfect misamore. You know what I
perfect misamore. You know what I mean?
He
He had
perfect misamore. You know what I mean?
He had like
He had like muscles
perfect misamore. You know what I mean?
He had like muscles and
He had like muscles and bone.
perfect misamore. You know what I mean?
He had like muscles and bone. You
probably
probably lift
probably lift 100
probably lift 100 pounds
probably lift 100 pounds like,
probably lift 100 pounds like, you
probably lift 100 pounds like, you know,
[laughter]
I
I was
I was born
an
an ectomorph.
I was born
an ectomorph. You
an ectomorph. You know,
lifting
lifting anything
lifting anything over
lifting anything over 50
lifting anything over 50 pounds
lifting anything over 50 pounds has
always
always been
lifting anything over 50 pounds has
always been a
always been a struggle
lifting anything over 50 pounds has
always been a struggle my
always been a struggle my whole
lifting anything over 50 pounds has
always been a struggle my whole life.
Uh,
Uh, and
Uh, and I
Uh, and I always
Uh, and I always tell
Uh, and I always tell people
Uh, and I always tell people people
Uh, and I always tell people people are
born
born sematypes,
Uh, and I always tell people people are
born sematypes, endomorph.
born sematypes, endomorph. This
Uh, and I always tell people people are
born sematypes, endomorph. This is
born sematypes, endomorph. This is off
the
the subject.
the subject. Endomorph,
the subject. Endomorph, misamorph,
the subject. Endomorph, misamorph, and
ectomorph.
And
And endomorph
And endomorph tends
And endomorph tends to
And endomorph tends to be
And endomorph tends to be chunky.
Tends
Tends to
And endomorph tends to be chunky.
Tends to be
Tends to be very
And endomorph tends to be chunky.
Tends to be very family
Tends to be very family oriented.
And endomorph tends to be chunky.
Tends to be very family oriented. Got
Tends to be very family oriented. Got to
have
have family
have family around
have family around you.
Values
Values family,
have family around you.
Values family, homelessness,
domestic
domestic domesticity,
and
and dieting
domestic domesticity,
and dieting probably
and dieting probably isn't
domestic domesticity,
and dieting probably isn't going
and dieting probably isn't going to
domestic domesticity,
and dieting probably isn't going to do
any
any good
any good at
any good at all.
any good at all. [laughter]
If
If you
any good at all. [laughter]
If you look
If you look at
any good at all. [laughter]
If you look at a
If you look at a candy
any good at all. [laughter]
If you look at a candy bar,
If you look at a candy bar, you
any good at all. [laughter]
If you look at a candy bar, you gain
If you look at a candy bar, you gain a
half
half a
half a pound.
half a pound. So,
uh,
uh, they
half a pound. So,
uh, they have
uh, they have a
half a pound. So,
uh, they have a wonderful
uh, they have a wonderful digestive
tract.
tract. The
tract. The misamomorph
tract. The misamomorph tends
tract. The misamomorph tends to
tract. The misamomorph tends to be
tract. The misamomorph tends to be more
muscular
muscular and,
tract. The misamomorph tends to be more
muscular and, um,
muscular and, um, capable
tract. The misamomorph tends to be more
muscular and, um, capable of
muscular and, um, capable of sports.
And
And the,
And the, uh,
And the, uh, the
And the, uh, the misomorph,
And the, uh, the misomorph, as
And the, uh, the misomorph, as they
And the, uh, the misomorph, as they get
older,
older, if
And the, uh, the misomorph, as they get
older, if they
older, if they sit
And the, uh, the misomorph, as they get
older, if they sit in
older, if they sit in front
And the, uh, the misomorph, as they get
older, if they sit in front of
older, if they sit in front of the
And the, uh, the misomorph, as they get
older, if they sit in front of the TV
and
and drink
and drink beer,
and drink beer, they're
and drink beer, they're going
and drink beer, they're going to
and drink beer, they're going to put
and drink beer, they're going to put it
on.
on. But
and drink beer, they're going to put it
on. But if
on. But if the
and drink beer, they're going to put it
on. But if the misamomorph
on. But if the misamomorph cuts
and drink beer, they're going to put it
on. But if the misamomorph cuts down
their
their diet
their diet and
their diet and exercises,
their diet and exercises, they
their diet and exercises, they will
their diet and exercises, they will lose
weight.
weight. So
their diet and exercises, they will lose
weight. So the
weight. So the misomorph
their diet and exercises, they will lose
weight. So the misomorph can
weight. So the misomorph can either
their diet and exercises, they will lose
weight. So the misomorph can either gain
or
or lose
or lose weight.
or lose weight. The
or lose weight. The endomorph
or lose weight. The endomorph is
or lose weight. The endomorph is going
to
to stay
or lose weight. The endomorph is going
to stay on
to stay on diet
or lose weight. The endomorph is going
to stay on diet pills,
to stay on diet pills, but
or lose weight. The endomorph is going
to stay on diet pills, but they
to stay on diet pills, but they aren't
going to
going to really
going to really take
going to really take much
going to really take much of the
going to really take much of the weight
off.
off. Not
going to really take much of the weight
off. Not going
off. Not going to
going to really take much of the weight
off. Not going to change
off. Not going to change your
going to really take much of the weight
off. Not going to change your lifestyle
anyway.
anyway. The
anyway. The ectomorph
anyway. The ectomorph is
anyway. The ectomorph is skinny
anyway. The ectomorph is skinny and
neurotic
neurotic and
anyway. The ectomorph is skinny and
neurotic and [laughter]
who's
who's that
who's that that
who's that that actor
who's that that actor that's
who's that that actor that's that
typifies
typifies the
>> Woody
>> Woody typifies
>> Woody typifies the
>> Woody typifies the ectomorph.
>> Woody typifies the ectomorph. Yeah.
>> Woody typifies the ectomorph. Yeah. thin
and
and wiry
>> Woody typifies the ectomorph. Yeah. thin
and wiry and
and wiry and somewhat
>> Woody typifies the ectomorph. Yeah. thin
and wiry and somewhat nervous
and wiry and somewhat nervous and
neurotic
neurotic and
neurotic and prone
neurotic and prone to
neurotic and prone to nervous
neurotic and prone to nervous breakdowns
and
and [laughter]
never
never going
never going to
never going to gain
never going to gain weight.
never going to gain weight. And
never going to gain weight. And uh
eating
eating too
never going to gain weight. And uh
eating too much
eating too much just
never going to gain weight. And uh
eating too much just makes
eating too much just makes him
never going to gain weight. And uh
eating too much just makes him throw
eating too much just makes him throw up.
He
He doesn't
He doesn't gain
He doesn't gain weight.
He doesn't gain weight. [laughter]
So
So we
He doesn't gain weight. [laughter]
So we sort
So we sort of
He doesn't gain weight. [laughter]
So we sort of accept
So we sort of accept our
He doesn't gain weight. [laughter]
So we sort of accept our fate,
So we sort of accept our fate, you
He doesn't gain weight. [laughter]
So we sort of accept our fate, you might
say.
say. If
say. If you're
say. If you're an
say. If you're an endomorph,
say. If you're an endomorph, quit
struggling
struggling with
say. If you're an endomorph, quit
struggling with it.
struggling with it. Become
say. If you're an endomorph, quit
struggling with it. Become the
struggling with it. Become the happy,
jolly,
jolly, fat
jolly, fat person
jolly, fat person everybody
jolly, fat person everybody loves.
If
If you're
jolly, fat person everybody loves.
If you're a
If you're a misamorph,
jolly, fat person everybody loves.
If you're a misamorph, be
If you're a misamorph, be sure
jolly, fat person everybody loves.
If you're a misamorph, be sure and
If you're a misamorph, be sure and diet
and
and exercise
and exercise to
and exercise to gain
and exercise to gain weight.
and exercise to gain weight. And
and exercise to gain weight. And if
you're
you're an
and exercise to gain weight. And if
you're an ectomorph,
you're an ectomorph, you're
and exercise to gain weight. And if
you're an ectomorph, you're too
you're an ectomorph, you're too neurotic
to
to worry
to worry about
to worry about it
to worry about it anyway.
to worry about it anyway. So
to worry about it anyway. So [laughter]
now
now [clears throat]
you
you can't
you can't you
you can't you can't
you can't you can't rate
you can't you can't rate anything.
you can't you can't rate anything. You
can't
can't rate
you can't you can't rate anything. You
can't rate anything
can't rate anything up
you can't you can't rate anything. You
can't rate anything up and
can't rate anything up and down
you can't you can't rate anything. You
can't rate anything up and down the
scale.
scale. You
scale. You can
scale. You can only
scale. You can only know
scale. You can only know where
scale. You can only know where it
scale. You can only know where it is.
Many
Many of
scale. You can only know where it is.
Many of the
Many of the world's
scale. You can only know where it is.
Many of the world's best
Many of the world's best spiritual
teachers
teachers are
teachers are in
teachers are in the
teachers are in the four
teachers are in the four high
teachers are in the four high 400s.
They
They are
teachers are in the four high 400s.
They are more
They are more capable
teachers are in the four high 400s.
They are more capable of
They are more capable of expressing,
verbalizing,
verbalizing, making
verbalizing, making comprehensible
verbalizing, making comprehensible and
understandable
the
the word
the word spiritual
the word spiritual truth
the word spiritual truth than
the word spiritual truth than people
the word spiritual truth than people in
the
the 800s.
the word spiritual truth than people in
the 800s. Let's
the 800s. Let's say
most
most people
most people in
most people in the
most people in the 800s
most people in the 800s are
most people in the 800s are totally
unintelligible.
[laughter]
Most
Most of
[laughter]
Most of them
Most of them stay
[laughter]
Most of them stay home.
Most of them stay home. You
[laughter]
Most of them stay home. You never
Most of them stay home. You never see
them
them in
them in public.
First
First of
them in public.
First of all,
First of all, there's
them in public.
First of all, there's nothing
First of all, there's nothing to
them in public.
First of all, there's nothing to say.
[laughter]
That's
That's quite
[laughter]
That's quite a
That's quite a roadblock
[laughter]
That's quite a roadblock to
That's quite a roadblock to begin
[laughter]
That's quite a roadblock to begin with.
Take
Take you
Take you 20,
Take you 20, 30
Take you 20, 30 years
Take you 20, 30 years to
Take you 20, 30 years to figure
Take you 20, 30 years to figure what
you're
you're going
Take you 20, 30 years to figure what
you're going to
you're going to say
Take you 20, 30 years to figure what
you're going to say about
you're going to say about all
Take you 20, 30 years to figure what
you're going to say about all this.
There's
There's nothing
There's nothing to
There's nothing to say
There's nothing to say about
There's nothing to say about it.
Most
Most spiritual
There's nothing to say about it.
Most spiritual teachers
Most spiritual teachers of
There's nothing to say about it.
Most spiritual teachers of a
Most spiritual teachers of a very
advanced
advanced enlightenment
advanced enlightenment are
advanced enlightenment are not
necessarily
necessarily good
advanced enlightenment are not
necessarily good teachers
necessarily good teachers any
advanced enlightenment are not
necessarily good teachers any more
necessarily good teachers any more than
Padreski
Padreski was
Padreski was a
Padreski was a great
Padreski was a great piano
Padreski was a great piano teacher.
Najinski
Najinski was
Padreski was a great piano teacher.
Najinski was probably
Najinski was probably a
Padreski was a great piano teacher.
Najinski was probably a very
Najinski was probably a very lousy
ballet
ballet teacher.
ballet teacher. You
ballet teacher. You know what
ballet teacher. You know what I'm
saying?
saying? The
ballet teacher. You know what I'm
saying? The fact
saying? The fact that
ballet teacher. You know what I'm
saying? The fact that you're
saying? The fact that you're a
ballet teacher. You know what I'm
saying? The fact that you're a great
musician
musician doesn't
musician doesn't make
musician doesn't make you
musician doesn't make you a
musician doesn't make you a great
teacher.
The
The best
The best teachers
The best teachers of
The best teachers of good
The best teachers of good musicians
The best teachers of good musicians are
themselves,
themselves, not
The best teachers of good musicians are
themselves, not genius
themselves, not genius musicians.
Otherwise,
Otherwise, they'd
Otherwise, they'd be
Otherwise, they'd be on
Otherwise, they'd be on the
Otherwise, they'd be on the road.
[laughter]
I
in
in childhood
I
in childhood the
in childhood the great
I
in childhood the great spirit
in childhood the great spirit artistic
merit
merit was
merit was greatly
merit was greatly appreciated
merit was greatly appreciated by
merit was greatly appreciated by the
family.
family. We
merit was greatly appreciated by the
family. We traveled
family. We traveled endless
merit was greatly appreciated by the
family. We traveled endless miles
family. We traveled endless miles to
merit was greatly appreciated by the
family. We traveled endless miles to see
Jinsky
Jinsky or
any
any of
Jinsky or
any of the
any of the great
Jinsky or
any of the great performers
any of the great performers of
Jinsky or
any of the great performers of the
any of the great performers of the day
and
and my
and my grandfather
and my grandfather on
and my grandfather on my
and my grandfather on my mother's
and my grandfather on my mother's side
knew
knew a
and my grandfather on my mother's side
knew a lot
knew a lot of
and my grandfather on my mother's side
knew a lot of them
knew a lot of them personally
and my grandfather on my mother's side
knew a lot of them personally and
knew a lot of them personally and uh
many
many of
many of them
many of them were
many of them were great
many of them were great virtuosos
many of them were great virtuosos but
many of them were great virtuosos but as
teachers
teachers forget
many of them were great virtuosos but as
teachers forget it
teachers forget it make
many of them were great virtuosos but as
teachers forget it make one
teachers forget it make one mistake
many of them were great virtuosos but as
teachers forget it make one mistake get
out
out of
out of here
out of here I
out of here I can't
out of here I can't stand
out of here I can't stand it
out of here I can't stand it you
out of here I can't stand it you stupid
idiot
lousy
lousy teachers
lousy teachers all
lousy teachers all right
lousy teachers all right so
lousy teachers all right so a
lousy teachers all right so a great
teacher
teacher very
lousy teachers all right so a great
teacher very often
teacher very often the
lousy teachers all right so a great
teacher very often the high
teacher very often the high 400s
lousy teachers all right so a great
teacher very often the high 400s these
these
these are
these are often
these are often the
these are often the most
these are often the most aryodite
teachers.
teachers. They
these are often the most aryodite
teachers. They are
teachers. They are the
these are often the most aryodite
teachers. They are the most
teachers. They are the most erodite
teachers.
teachers. They
teachers. They uh
teachers. They uh can
teachers. They uh can compare
teachers. They uh can compare the
world's
world's literature,
teachers. They uh can compare the
world's literature, cite
world's literature, cite all
teachers. They uh can compare the
world's literature, cite all the
references
references that
references that reinforce
references that reinforce and
references that reinforce and confirm
each
each other.
So
So they
So they are
So they are great
So they are great clarifiers,
So they are great clarifiers, great
clarifiers
clarifiers of
So they are great clarifiers, great
clarifiers of sphere
clarifiers of sphere of
So they are great clarifiers, great
clarifiers of sphere of the
clarifiers of sphere of the truth.
So they are great clarifiers, great
clarifiers of sphere of the truth. So
you
you can't
you can't say
you can't say that
you can't say that a
you can't say that a teacher
you can't say that a teacher at
you can't say that a teacher at 540
you can't say that a teacher at 540 is
better
better than
you can't say that a teacher at 540 is
better than a
better than a teacher
you can't say that a teacher at 540 is
better than a teacher at
better than a teacher at 480.
you can't say that a teacher at 540 is
better than a teacher at 480. They're
different.
different. They're
different. They're teaching
different. They're teaching different
things.
things. The
different. They're teaching different
things. The higher
things. The higher one
different. They're teaching different
things. The higher one goes
things. The higher one goes up
different. They're teaching different
things. The higher one goes up the
scale,
scale, the
scale, the more
scale, the more it
scale, the more it is
scale, the more it is that
scale, the more it is that the
scale, the more it is that the presence
of
of that
scale, the more it is that the presence
of that which
of that which you
scale, the more it is that the presence
of that which you are
of that which you are itself
scale, the more it is that the presence
of that which you are itself has
of that which you are itself has the
transformative
transformative effect
transformative effect rather
transformative effect rather than
verbatim
verbatim the
transformative effect rather than
verbatim the wording
verbatim the wording the
transformative effect rather than
verbatim the wording the wording.
So
there
there are
So
there are some
there are some beings
So
there are some beings in
there are some beings in whose
So
there are some beings in whose presence
one
one feels
one feels an
one feels an elevation
one feels an elevation of
one feels an elevation of consciousness
but
but they're
one feels an elevation of consciousness
but they're writing
verbal
verbal fluency.
verbal fluency. They're
verbal fluency. They're not
verbal fluency. They're not great
writers
writers and
verbal fluency. They're not great
writers and there's
writers and there's great
verbal fluency. They're not great
writers and there's great writers
writers and there's great writers who
have
have the
have the data
have the data down
have the data down pat.
Um
Um they're
have the data down pat.
Um they're interesting
Um they're interesting but
have the data down pat.
Um they're interesting but you
Um they're interesting but you don't
exactly
exactly go
exactly go into
exactly go into a
exactly go into a state
exactly go into a state of
exactly go into a state of somat
exactly go into a state of somat in
exactly go into a state of somat in the
presency.
So
So one
So one is
So one is not
So one is not better
So one is not better than
So one is not better than the
So one is not better than the other.
They
They serve
So one is not better than the other.
They serve different
They serve different purposes.
Very
Very often
Very often when
Very often when you
Very often when you go
Very often when you go with
Very often when you go with the
Very often when you go with the way
Very often when you go with the way of
the
the heart
Very often when you go with the way of
the heart which
the heart which we'll
Very often when you go with the way of
the heart which we'll talk
the heart which we'll talk more
Very often when you go with the way of
the heart which we'll talk more about
the heart which we'll talk more about at
a
a later
a later date
a later date you
a later date you can
a later date you can bypass
a later date you can bypass and
a later date you can bypass and shoot
all
all the
a later date you can bypass and shoot
all the way
all the way up
because
because love
because love bypasses
because love bypasses the
because love bypasses the intellect
altogether.
altogether. You
because love bypasses the intellect
altogether. You understand?
altogether. You understand? Love
because love bypasses the intellect
altogether. You understand? Love takes
you
you to
you to 500
you to 500 and
you to 500 and it's
you to 500 and it's beyond
you to 500 and it's beyond reason.
you to 500 and it's beyond reason. It's
beyond
beyond reason.
you to 500 and it's beyond reason. It's
beyond reason. Somebody
beyond reason. Somebody says
you to 500 and it's beyond reason. It's
beyond reason. Somebody says why
beyond reason. Somebody says why do
you to 500 and it's beyond reason. It's
beyond reason. Somebody says why do you
love
love that
love that person
love that person thing
love that person thing but
you
you can't
love that person thing but
you can't give
you can't give any
love that person thing but
you can't give any reason
you can't give any reason why
love that person thing but
you can't give any reason why can't
you can't give any reason why can't give
any
any reason
certain
certain music
any reason
certain music instantly
certain music instantly tr
any reason
certain music instantly tr you
certain music instantly tr you instantly
transcend
transcend who's
transcend who's who's
transcend who's who's that
transcend who's who's that newest
transcend who's who's that newest tape
we
we have
transcend who's who's that newest tape
we have right
we have right right
transcend who's who's that newest tape
we have right right now
we have right right now CD
>> let
>> let me
>> let me just
>> let me just calibrate
>> let me just calibrate what
>> let me just calibrate what he's
>> let me just calibrate what he's at
>> let me just calibrate what he's at the
music
music I'm
>> let me just calibrate what he's at the
music I'm thinking
music I'm thinking of
>> let me just calibrate what he's at the
music I'm thinking of now
music I'm thinking of now calibrates
over
over 500
over 500 520
over 500 520 530
over 500 520 530 540
over 500 520 530 540 550
over 500 520 530 540 550 560
over 500 520 530 540 550 560 570
over 500 520 530 540 550 560 570 My
over 500 520 530 540 550 560 570 My god,
he's
he's way
over 500 520 530 540 550 560 570 My god,
he's way up
he's way up there.
over 500 520 530 540 550 560 570 My god,
he's way up there. What's
he's way up there. What's his
over 500 520 530 540 550 560 570 My god,
he's way up there. What's his name?
he's way up there. What's his name? The
music
music I'm
music I'm thinking
music I'm thinking about
music I'm thinking about calibrates
music I'm thinking about calibrates at
560.
>> Andrea
>> Andrea Andrea.
>> Andre
>> Andre Belli.
>> Andrea Andrea.
>> Andre Belli. Right.
>> Andre Belli. Right. Correct.
>> Andrea Andrea.
>> Andre Belli. Right. Correct. All right.
So,
So, you
So, you see
So, you see what
So, you see what the
So, you see what the space
So, you see what the space you
So, you see what the space you go
So, you see what the space you go into
as
as you
So, you see what the space you go into
as you listen
as you listen to
So, you see what the space you go into
as you listen to that
as you listen to that music.
If
If the
If the way
If the way of
If the way of the
If the way of the pathway
If the way of the pathway of
If the way of the pathway of the
If the way of the pathway of the heart
is
is open
If the way of the pathway of the heart
is open in
is open in you
If the way of the pathway of the heart
is open in you tends
is open in you tends to
If the way of the pathway of the heart
is open in you tends to bring
is open in you tends to bring tears.
That's
That's why
That's why it's
That's why it's not
That's why it's not good
That's why it's not good to
That's why it's not good to drive
[laughter]
[laughter] to.
It's
[laughter]
It's bad
It's bad music
[laughter]
It's bad music to
It's bad music to drive
[laughter]
It's bad music to drive to
It's bad music to drive to because
[laughter]
It's bad music to drive to because you
lose
lose all
lose all interest
lose all interest in
lose all interest in going
lose all interest in going anywhere
lose all interest in going anywhere for
anything
anything about
lose all interest in going anywhere for
anything about anything.
I
I mean,
I mean, everything
I mean, everything is
I mean, everything is totally
I mean, everything is totally incomplete
right
right now.
I mean, everything is totally incomplete
right now. Where
right now. Where is
I mean, everything is totally incomplete
right now. Where is there
right now. Where is there to
I mean, everything is totally incomplete
right now. Where is there to go
right now. Where is there to go for
what?
what? You
what? You know what
what? You know what I
what? You know what I mean?
what? You know what I mean? [laughter]
That's
That's his
what? You know what I mean? [laughter]
That's his name.
That's his name. Five.
what? You know what I mean? [laughter]
That's his name. Five. What
That's his name. Five. What was
what? You know what I mean? [laughter]
That's his name. Five. What was he
>> way
>> way up
>> way up there?
>> way up there? Okay.
>> way up there? Okay. So,
>> way up there? Okay. So, artistic
>> way up there? Okay. So, artistic the
that
that that
>> way up there? Okay. So, artistic the
that that which
that that which is
>> way up there? Okay. So, artistic the
that that which is great
that that which is great beauty.
>> way up there? Okay. So, artistic the
that that which is great beauty. The
great
great cathedrals
great cathedrals of
great cathedrals of the
great cathedrals of the world,
great cathedrals of the world, you
great cathedrals of the world, you know,
calibrate
calibrate around
great cathedrals of the world, you know,
calibrate around 700
calibrate around 700 chart.
Uh
Uh you
Uh you go
Uh you go into
Uh you go into a
Uh you go into a cathedral
Uh you go into a cathedral like
Uh you go into a cathedral like chart,
you
you can't
Uh you go into a cathedral like chart,
you can't stop
you can't stop crying.
Uh you go into a cathedral like chart,
you can't stop crying. It's
you can't stop crying. It's just
Uh you go into a cathedral like chart,
you can't stop crying. It's just just
overwhelming.
overwhelming. And
some
some of
overwhelming. And
some of the
some of the great
overwhelming. And
some of the great cathedrals
some of the great cathedrals I've
overwhelming. And
some of the great cathedrals I've been
in,
in, uh,
in, uh, they
in, uh, they just
in, uh, they just overwhelm
in, uh, they just overwhelm you.
in, uh, they just overwhelm you. All
thought
thought stops.
in, uh, they just overwhelm you. All
thought stops. The
thought stops. The joy
in, uh, they just overwhelm you. All
thought stops. The joy of
thought stops. The joy of beauty
in, uh, they just overwhelm you. All
thought stops. The joy of beauty comes
up
up and
you
you can't
up and
you can't function
you can't function in
up and
you can't function in that
you can't function in that state.
up and
you can't function in that state. I've
noticed
noticed there's
noticed there's no
noticed there's no graffiti
noticed there's no graffiti in
noticed there's no graffiti in the
noticed there's no graffiti in the great
cathedrals
cathedrals of
noticed there's no graffiti in the great
cathedrals of the
cathedrals of the world.
noticed there's no graffiti in the great
cathedrals of the world. Isn't
cathedrals of the world. Isn't that
interesting?
interesting? Because
interesting? Because that
interesting? Because that which
interesting? Because that which hates
beauty
beauty is
interesting? Because that which hates
beauty is the
beauty is the source
interesting? Because that which hates
beauty is the source of
beauty is the source of graffiti.
Graffiti
Graffiti usually
Graffiti usually uh
Graffiti usually uh desecrates
Graffiti usually uh desecrates that
which
which is
Graffiti usually uh desecrates that
which is let's
which is let's see
Graffiti usually uh desecrates that
which is let's see what
which is let's see what does
Graffiti usually uh desecrates that
which is let's see what does it
desecrate
desecrate it
desecrate it usually
desecrate it usually desecrates
desecrate it usually desecrates that
which
which is
desecrate it usually desecrates that
which is below
which is below 200
desecrate it usually desecrates that
which is below 200 resist
which is below 200 resist desecrates
that
that which
that which is
that which is about
that which is about 190
that which is about 190 resist
graffiti
graffiti is
that which is about 190 resist
graffiti is usually
graffiti is usually used
that which is about 190 resist
graffiti is usually used to
graffiti is usually used to desecrate
that
that which
that which is
that which is above
that which is above 190
that which is above 190 192
that which is above 190 192 195
okay
okay so
that which is above 190 192 195
okay so anything
okay so anything calibrates
that which is above 190 192 195
okay so anything calibrates around
okay so anything calibrates around 195
tends
tends to
tends to pull
tends to pull forth
tends to pull forth graffiti
tends to pull forth graffiti to
tends to pull forth graffiti to face
tends to pull forth graffiti to face it.
Huh?
At
At 500,
At 500, even
At 500, even the
At 500, even the weirdest
even
even the
At 500, even the weirdest
even the weirdest
even the weirdest person
doesn't
doesn't have
doesn't have what
doesn't have what it
doesn't have what it takes.
So
So great
doesn't have what it takes.
So great beauty
So great beauty then
doesn't have what it takes.
So great beauty then overwhelms
So great beauty then overwhelms people,
sets
sets them
sets them back
sets them back into
sets them back into the
sets them back into the reality
sets them back into the reality of
sets them back into the reality of the
self
self out
sets them back into the reality of the
self out of
self out of which
sets them back into the reality of the
self out of which such
self out of which such thinkingness
sets them back into the reality of the
self out of which such thinkingness does
not
not arise.
not arise. With
not arise. With the
not arise. With the exception
not arise. With the exception of
not arise. With the exception of extreme
madness,
I
I see
I see you
I see you being
I see you being right
I see you being right now.
I see you being right now. Okay.
I see you being right now. Okay. Uh,
we
we have
I see you being right now. Okay. Uh,
we have permission
we have permission to
I see you being right now. Okay. Uh,
we have permission to ask
we have permission to ask about
I see you being right now. Okay. Uh,
we have permission to ask about the
we have permission to ask about the PA
resist.
Uh,
Uh, PA
resist.
Uh, PA calibrates
Uh, PA calibrates over
resist.
Uh, PA calibrates over 550,
Uh, PA calibrates over 550, 580,
resist.
Uh, PA calibrates over 550, 580, 590.
Uh, PA calibrates over 550, 580, 590. PA
calibrates
calibrates at
calibrates at 590.
Now
Now desecrated
calibrates at 590.
Now desecrated the
Now desecrated the PA.
calibrates at 590.
Now desecrated the PA. We
Now desecrated the PA. We have
permission
permission to
permission to calibrate
permission to calibrate it.
permission to calibrate it. Is
permission to calibrate it. Is this
permission to calibrate it. Is this its
level
level was
permission to calibrate it. Is this its
level was over
level was over 60.
level
level was
level was over
level was over 40
level was over 40 45
that
that which
level was over 40 45
that which desecrated
that which desecrated the
level was over 40 45
that which desecrated the piet.
that which desecrated the piet. Remember
when
when the
when the piet
when the piet was
when the piet was attacked
when the piet was attacked the
when the piet was attacked the entity
was
was 4
when the piet was attacked the entity
was 4 40
was 4 40 says
when the piet was attacked the entity
was 4 40 says 45.
was 4 40 says 45. Oh
when the piet was attacked the entity
was 4 40 says 45. Oh boy.
was 4 40 says 45. Oh boy. Still
when the piet was attacked the entity
was 4 40 says 45. Oh boy. Still walking
in
in two
in two feet
in two feet though.
in two feet though. [laughter]
in two feet though. [laughter] 45
uh
uh infuriated
in two feet though. [laughter] 45
uh infuriated probably
uh infuriated probably by
in two feet though. [laughter] 45
uh infuriated probably by the
perfection.
perfection. What
perfection. What did
perfection. What did we
perfection. What did we say
perfection. What did we say the
perfection. What did we say the piano
calibrated
calibrated at?
perfection. What did we say the piano
calibrated at? I
calibrated at? I forget.
>> Anyway,
>> Anyway, way
>> Anyway, way up
>> Anyway, way up there.
>> Anyway, way up there. [clears throat]
So
So that
>> Anyway, way up there. [clears throat]
So that which
So that which is
>> Anyway, way up there. [clears throat]
So that which is incredible
So that which is incredible beauty
uh
uh has
uh has a
uh has a tendency
uh has a tendency to
has
has a
uh has a tendency to
has a tendency
has a tendency to
uh has a tendency to
has a tendency to throw
has a tendency to throw you
uh has a tendency to
has a tendency to throw you back
has a tendency to throw you back into
the
the self
to
to walk
the self
to walk into
to walk into the
the self
to walk into the world's
to walk into the world's great
cathedrals
cathedrals that
cathedrals that have
cathedrals that have been
cathedrals that have been there
cathedrals that have been there for
cathedrals that have been there for a
thousand
thousand years.
The
The incredible
The incredible music,
The incredible music, the
The incredible music, the incense,
The incredible music, the incense, the
beauty
beauty shining
The incredible music, the incense, the
beauty shining forth
beauty shining forth through
The incredible music, the incense, the
beauty shining forth through the
beauty shining forth through the stained
glass
glass windows.
glass windows. Even
glass windows. Even if
glass windows. Even if it's
glass windows. Even if it's not
glass windows. Even if it's not your
religion,
religion, the
glass windows. Even if it's not your
religion, the reverence,
the
the collective
the collective reverence,
the collective reverence, the
the collective reverence, the worship
the collective reverence, the worship of
God
God expressing
the collective reverence, the worship of
God expressing itself
God expressing itself as
the collective reverence, the worship of
God expressing itself as such
God expressing itself as such incredible
beauty
um
um has
beauty
um has an
um has an uplifting
beauty
um has an uplifting experience.
One
One then
One then ascribes
One then ascribes that
One then ascribes that experience
One then ascribes that experience to
One then ascribes that experience to the
out
out there
One then ascribes that experience to the
out there of
out there of the
One then ascribes that experience to the
out there of the cathedral.
out there of the cathedral. No,
One then ascribes that experience to the
out there of the cathedral. No, the
cathedral
lifts
lifts you
cathedral
lifts you to
lifts you to the
cathedral
lifts you to the experience
lifts you to the experience of
cathedral
lifts you to the experience of that
which
which is
which is present
which is present at
which is present at all
which is present at all times
which is present at all times within
yourself.
yourself. But
which is present at all times within
yourself. But you
yourself. But you only
which is present at all times within
yourself. But you only allow
yourself. But you only allow yourself
which is present at all times within
yourself. But you only allow yourself to
experience
experience under
experience under these
experience under these conditions.
experience under these conditions. That
which
which you're
experience under these conditions. That
which you're experiencing
which you're experiencing is
experience under these conditions. That
which you're experiencing is the
presence
presence of
presence of the
presence of the divine
presence of the divine within.
Incredible
Incredible beauty
presence of the divine within.
Incredible beauty then
Incredible beauty then unleashes
the
the dam
the dam in
the dam in which
that
that which
the dam in which
that which is
that which is love,
the dam in which
that which is love, that
that which is love, that which
the dam in which
that which is love, that which is
that which is love, that which is sacred
shines
shines forth.
shines forth. And
shines forth. And that
shines forth. And that radiance
shines forth. And that radiance is
shines forth. And that radiance is what
makes
makes you
shines forth. And that radiance is what
makes you feel
makes you feel like
shines forth. And that radiance is what
makes you feel like crying.
makes you feel like crying. You
shines forth. And that radiance is what
makes you feel like crying. You know,
incredible
incredible beauty
incredible beauty brings
incredible beauty brings a
incredible beauty brings a lump
incredible beauty brings a lump in
incredible beauty brings a lump in your
throat.
Incredible
Incredible beauty
Incredible beauty as
Incredible beauty as it
Incredible beauty as it rises
makes
makes the
Incredible beauty as it rises
makes the hair
makes the hair in
Incredible beauty as it rises
makes the hair in the
makes the hair in the back
Incredible beauty as it rises
makes the hair in the back of
makes the hair in the back of your
Incredible beauty as it rises
makes the hair in the back of your head
stand
stand up
stand up and
stand up and then
stand up and then as
stand up and then as it
stand up and then as it gets
stand up and then as it gets even
higher,
higher, you
stand up and then as it gets even
higher, you can't
higher, you can't stop
stand up and then as it gets even
higher, you can't stop crying.
higher, you can't stop crying. Huh?
stand up and then as it gets even
higher, you can't stop crying. Huh? Is
that
that so?
that so? Those
that so? Those of
that so? Those of you
that so? Those of you who
that so? Those of you who gone
that so? Those of you who gone into
incredibly
incredibly beautiful
that so? Those of you who gone into
incredibly beautiful spaces,
incredibly beautiful spaces, you
that so? Those of you who gone into
incredibly beautiful spaces, you know
that
that you
that you can't
that you can't stop
that you can't stop crying
that you can't stop crying at
that you can't stop crying at a
that you can't stop crying at a certain
level.
level. At
that you can't stop crying at a certain
level. At a
level. At a certain
that you can't stop crying at a certain
level. At a certain level,
level. At a certain level, you
that you can't stop crying at a certain
level. At a certain level, you can't
even
even witness
even witness anything
even witness anything has
even witness anything has to
even witness anything has to do
even witness anything has to do with
love.
love. It
even witness anything has to do with
love. It just
love. It just breaks
even witness anything has to do with
love. It just breaks you
love. It just breaks you up.
even witness anything has to do with
love. It just breaks you up. [laughter]
Little
Little puppy
Little puppy walking
Little puppy walking down
Little puppy walking down the
Little puppy walking down the street,
you
you break
Little puppy walking down the street,
you break out
you break out in
Little puppy walking down the street,
you break out in tears.
I
I mean
I mean it's
I mean it's adorableness
I mean it's adorableness is
I mean it's adorableness is lovableness
and
and you
I mean it's adorableness is lovableness
and you can
and you can see
I mean it's adorableness is lovableness
and you can see what
and you can see what it
I mean it's adorableness is lovableness
and you can see what it means
and you can see what it means to
I mean it's adorableness is lovableness
and you can see what it means to the
owner.
owner. You
owner. You know
owner. You know the
owner. You know the whole
owner. You know the whole space
owner. You know the whole space of
owner. You know the whole space of all
that
that lovingness
owner. You know the whole space of all
that lovingness is
that lovingness is just
owner. You know the whole space of all
that lovingness is just too
that lovingness is just too much.
owner. You know the whole space of all
that lovingness is just too much. It
just
just knocks
just knocks you
just knocks you out.
just knocks you out. So
just knocks you out. So there's
just knocks you out. So there's a
difficult
difficult time
just knocks you out. So there's a
difficult time there.
A
A difficult
A difficult time
A difficult time of
A difficult time of weeping
A difficult time of weeping and
A difficult time of weeping and crying
over
the
the presence
the presence of
the presence of divinity
the presence of divinity as
the presence of divinity as beauty
the presence of divinity as beauty and
love.
It
It says
It says is
It says is consciousness
It says is consciousness a
It says is consciousness a byproduct
It says is consciousness a byproduct of
spirit
spirit entering
dense
dense matter?
dense matter? No.
dense matter? No. No,
dense matter? No. No, it
dense matter? No. No, it is
dense matter? No. No, it is not.
Uh,
Uh, consciousness
dense matter? No. No, it is not.
Uh, consciousness arises
Uh, consciousness arises prior
dense matter? No. No, it is not.
Uh, consciousness arises prior to
matter.
Genesis
Genesis is
matter.
Genesis is pretty
Genesis is pretty pretty
matter.
Genesis is pretty pretty correct
according
according to
according to our
according to our own
according to our own research
according to our own research that
according to our own research that out
of
of what
according to our own research that out
of what appeared
of what appeared as
according to our own research that out
of what appeared as chaos
of what appeared as chaos chaos
according to our own research that out
of what appeared as chaos chaos to
perception
which
which is
perception
which is really
which is really nonform
arose
arose light
arose light as
arose light as consciousness.
The
The power
arose light as consciousness.
The power of
The power of consciousness
arose light as consciousness.
The power of consciousness is
The power of consciousness is such
arose light as consciousness.
The power of consciousness is such that
it
it can
it can Power
it can Power of
it can Power of consciousness
it can Power of consciousness is
it can Power of consciousness is such
that
that it
it can Power of consciousness is such
that it can
that it can initiate
it can Power of consciousness is such
that it can initiate life
that it can initiate life when
it can Power of consciousness is such
that it can initiate life when it
touches
touches matter
and
and that
touches matter
and that matter
and that matter then
touches matter
and that matter then evolves
and that matter then evolves from
touches matter
and that matter then evolves from below
up.
up. So
up. So creation
up. So creation is
up. So creation is from
up. So creation is from above
up. So creation is from above down
and
and then
up. So creation is from above down
and then we
and then we see
up. So creation is from above down
and then we see the
and then we see the evolution
up. So creation is from above down
and then we see the evolution of
and then we see the evolution of life
forms
forms from
forms from the
forms from the bottom
forms from the bottom up
forms from the bottom up from
forms from the bottom up from the
forms from the bottom up from the ooze
to
to us.
forms from the bottom up from the ooze
to us. [laughter]
Then
Then we
Then we can
Then we can look
Then we can look down
Then we can look down on
Then we can look down on the
Then we can look down on the worms.
Then we can look down on the worms. I'm
getting
getting somebody
Then we can look down on the worms. I'm
getting somebody to
getting somebody to look
Then we can look down on the worms. I'm
getting somebody to look that
getting somebody to look that up.
What
What is
What is the
What is the nursing
What is the nursing mind
What is the nursing mind and
consciousness?
consciousness? Consciousness
What is the nursing mind and
consciousness? Consciousness is
consciousness? Consciousness is the
field
which
which supports
field
which supports the
which supports the phenomena
field
which supports the phenomena called
mind.
mind. Consciousness
mind. Consciousness itself
mind. Consciousness itself is
mind. Consciousness itself is without
form.
Without
Without form
just
just before
Without form
just before you
just before you think
Without form
just before you think a
just before you think a thought,
Without form
just before you think a thought, what
you're
you're experiencing
you're experiencing is
you're experiencing is awareness
you're experiencing is awareness which
is
is radiating
you're experiencing is awareness which
is radiating out
is radiating out of
you're experiencing is awareness which
is radiating out of it's
is radiating out of it's an
you're experiencing is awareness which
is radiating out of it's an aspect
is radiating out of it's an aspect of
consciousness.
If
If you
consciousness.
If you want
If you want to,
consciousness.
If you want to, you
If you want to, you can
consciousness.
If you want to, you can watch
If you want to, you can watch and
consciousness.
If you want to, you can watch and see
right
right before
right before every
right before every thought
right before every thought you
right before every thought you have
right before every thought you have an
opportunity.
That
That opportunity
That opportunity presents
That opportunity presents itself
continuously.
It
It lasts
It lasts about
It lasts about 110,000th
It lasts about 110,000th of
It lasts about 110,000th of a
It lasts about 110,000th of a second.
You
You got
It lasts about 110,000th of a second.
You got to
You got to be
It lasts about 110,000th of a second.
You got to be quick.
That
That space
That space is
That space is 110,000
That space is 110,000 of
That space is 110,000 of a
That space is 110,000 of a second
approximately.
approximately. It's
That space is 110,000 of a second
approximately. It's just
approximately. It's just it's
That space is 110,000 of a second
approximately. It's just it's more
approximately. It's just it's more than
that.
that. It's
that. It's just
that. It's just No,
that. It's just No, it's
that. It's just No, it's not
that. It's just No, it's not more
that. It's just No, it's not more than
that.
that. Darn
that. It's just No, it's not more than
that. Darn it.
that. Darn it. It's
that. It's just No, it's not more than
that. Darn it. It's always
that. Darn it. It's always been
that. It's just No, it's not more than
that. Darn it. It's always been like
110,000th
110,000th of
110,000th of a
110,000th of a second.
110,000th of a second. When
110,000th of a second. When we
110,000th of a second. When we say
110,000th of a second. When we say that,
it
it sounds
110,000th of a second. When we say that,
it sounds very
it sounds very very
110,000th of a second. When we say that,
it sounds very very minimal.
it sounds very very minimal. And
110,000th of a second. When we say that,
it sounds very very minimal. And and
it sounds very very minimal. And and who
the
the heck's
the heck's going
the heck's going to
the heck's going to make
the heck's going to make it
the heck's going to make it through
the heck's going to make it through the
crack
crack in
the heck's going to make it through the
crack in 110,000
crack in 110,000 of
the heck's going to make it through the
crack in 110,000 of a
crack in 110,000 of a second?
That's
That's an
That's an only
That's an only temporal
That's an only temporal physical
That's an only temporal physical time.
That
That doesn't
That's an only temporal physical time.
That doesn't sound
That doesn't sound like
That's an only temporal physical time.
That doesn't sound like much.
That doesn't sound like much. But
That's an only temporal physical time.
That doesn't sound like much. But in
that
that space
that space of
that space of that
that space of that 110,000th
that space of that 110,000th of
that space of that 110,000th of a
second,
second, you're
that space of that 110,000th of a
second, you're looking
second, you're looking at
that space of that 110,000th of a
second, you're looking at eternity,
which
which is
which is outside
which is outside of
which is outside of time.
which is outside of time. So
which is outside of time. So you
which is outside of time. So you have
a
a window
which is outside of time. So you have
a window open
a window open to
which is outside of time. So you have
a window open to that
a window open to that which
which is outside of time. So you have
a window open to that which is
a window open to that which is beyond
time,
time, the
time, the infinite
one
one 10,000
time, the infinite
one 10,000 of
one 10,000 of a
time, the infinite
one 10,000 of a second.
one 10,000 of a second. What
time, the infinite
one 10,000 of a second. What does
one 10,000 of a second. What does that
mean?
mean? What
mean? What does
mean? What does that
mean? What does that mean?
mean? What does that mean? It
mean? What does that mean? It means
mean? What does that mean? It means then
you
you become
mean? What does that mean? It means then
you become aware
you become aware of
mean? What does that mean? It means then
you become aware of your
you become aware of your thoughts
mean? What does that mean? It means then
you become aware of your thoughts as
sort
sort of
sort of a
sort of a thingness
sort of a thingness thing.
sort of a thingness thing. It's
sort of a thingness thing. It's sort
sort of a thingness thing. It's sort of
like
like your
sort of a thingness thing. It's sort of
like your thought
like your thought is
sort of a thingness thing. It's sort of
like your thought is a
like your thought is a thing.
sort of a thingness thing. It's sort of
like your thought is a thing. See,
like your thought is a thing. See, right
prior
prior to
prior to this
prior to this thing
prior to this thing occupying
prior to this thing occupying the
prior to this thing occupying the space
of
of your
prior to this thing occupying the space
of your attention
is
is a
is a space.
is a space. If
is a space. If there
is a space. If there wasn't
is a space. If there wasn't an
is a space. If there wasn't an empty
space,
space, the
is a space. If there wasn't an empty
space, the thought
space, the thought would
is a space. If there wasn't an empty
space, the thought would have
space, the thought would have no
is a space. If there wasn't an empty
space, the thought would have no place
to
to present
to present itself.
You
You know
to present itself.
You know what
You know what I'm
to present itself.
You know what I'm saying?
Without
Without a
Without a blank
Without a blank screen,
Without a blank screen, there's
Without a blank screen, there's nothing
for
for a
Without a blank screen, there's nothing
for a thought
for a thought project
Without a blank screen, there's nothing
for a thought project itself
for a thought project itself upon.
with
with a
with a little
with a little self-reflection.
with a little self-reflection. The
with a little self-reflection. The best
place
place to
with a little self-reflection. The best
place to become
place to become enlightened
with a little self-reflection. The best
place to become enlightened is
place to become enlightened is driving,
riding
riding in
riding in a
riding in a taxi
riding in a taxi cab,
riding in a taxi cab, any
riding in a taxi cab, any place,
[laughter]
waiting
waiting in
waiting in the
waiting in the line
waiting in the line at
waiting in the line at the
waiting in the line at the waiting
waiting in the line at the waiting in
the
the line
waiting in the line at the waiting in
the line of
the line of the
waiting in the line at the waiting in
the line of the supermarket.
One's
One's thoughts
One's thoughts go
One's thoughts go by
One's thoughts go by nonchalantly
One's thoughts go by nonchalantly and
suddenly
suddenly one
One's thoughts go by nonchalantly and
suddenly one sees
one
one instant
one instant right
one instant right before
one instant right before the
one instant right before the thought.
That's
That's who
one instant right before the thought.
That's who you
That's who you are.
one instant right before the thought.
That's who you are. And
That's who you are. And you
one instant right before the thought.
That's who you are. And you pull
That's who you are. And you pull back
into
into that
into that nothinkingness
prior
prior to
into that nothinkingness
prior to thought.
It's
It's there
It's there all
It's there all the
It's there all the time.
It's there all the time. It's
It's there all the time. It's there
It's there all the time. It's there all
the
the time.
It's there all the time. It's there all
the time. So
the time. So it's
It's there all the time. It's there all
the time. So it's said
the time. So it's said that
It's there all the time. It's there all
the time. So it's said that the
the time. So it's said that the entryway
into
into enlightenment
into enlightenment is
into enlightenment is in
into enlightenment is in the
into enlightenment is in the instant
into enlightenment is in the instant of
now.
That
That now
That now is
That now is always
That now is always present.
It's
It's all
That now is always present.
It's all it
It's all it only
That now is always present.
It's all it only takes
It's all it only takes a
That now is always present.
It's all it only takes a curiosity
really.
You
You don't
really.
You don't have
You don't have to
fast
fast and
fast and join
fast and join a
fast and join a monastery
fast and join a monastery or
fast and join a monastery or a
fast and join a monastery or a nunnery.
Beat
Beat drums
fast and join a monastery or a nunnery.
Beat drums and
Beat drums and gongs
fast and join a monastery or a nunnery.
Beat drums and gongs and
channel
channel lake.
to
to beat
channel lake.
to beat yourself,
to beat yourself, deprive
channel lake.
to beat yourself, deprive yourself.
Every
Every possible
Every possible instant
Every possible instant of
Every possible instant of now
Every possible instant of now is
Every possible instant of now is forever
present.
Outside
Outside of
Outside of time,
Outside of time, forever
Outside of time, forever is
Outside of time, forever is this
Outside of time, forever is this moment.
So
So you
Outside of time, forever is this moment.
So you really
So you really in
Outside of time, forever is this moment.
So you really in a
So you really in a way
Outside of time, forever is this moment.
So you really in a way have
So you really in a way have forever
Outside of time, forever is this moment.
So you really in a way have forever to
notice
notice this.
notice this. Out
notice this. Out of
notice this. Out of sheer
notice this. Out of sheer curiosity,
forget
forget about
notice this. Out of sheer curiosity,
forget about enlightenment,
forget about enlightenment, forget
notice this. Out of sheer curiosity,
forget about enlightenment, forget about
God,
God, all
God, all that.
Just
Just out
God, all that.
Just out of
Just out of sheer
God, all that.
Just out of sheer curiosity
Just out of sheer curiosity watch
God, all that.
Just out of sheer curiosity watch and
see
that
that each
see
that each thought
that each thought arises
see
that each thought arises in
that each thought arises in an
see
that each thought arises in an empty
space
be
be with
space
be with the
be with the empty
space
be with the empty space
and
and as
and as the
and as the next
and as the next thought
and as the next thought arises
and as the next thought arises the
and as the next thought arises the empty
space
space is
and as the next thought arises the empty
space is there
space is there again
and as the next thought arises the empty
space is there again the
space is there again the empty
and as the next thought arises the empty
space is there again the empty space
presents
presents itself
presents itself continuously
and
and then
presents itself continuously
and then one
and then one sees
I'm
I'm the
I'm the space
I'm the space and
I'm the space and not
I'm the space and not the
I'm the space and not the thought
I'm the space and not the thought it's
simple
simple huh
Any
Any more
Any more questions?
Any more questions? I
Any more questions? I want
Any more questions? I want to
Any more questions? I want to make
Any more questions? I want to make sure
they're
they're all
Any more questions? I want to make sure
they're all answered
they're all answered and
Any more questions? I want to make sure
they're all answered and then
they're all answered and then maybe
we'll
we'll take
we'll take off
we'll take off for
we'll take off for the
we'll take off for the relics,
we'll take off for the relics, which
will
will be
we'll take off for the relics, which
will be a
will be a fun
we'll take off for the relics, which
will be a fun thing
will be a fun thing to
we'll take off for the relics, which
will be a fun thing to do.
will be a fun thing to do. Yes.
>> What
>> What did
>> What did you
>> What did you say?
>> Oh,
>> Oh, yes,
>> What did you say?
>> Oh, yes, indeed.
>> Oh, yes, indeed. Right.
>> What did you say?
>> Oh, yes, indeed. Right. Oh,
>> Oh, yes, indeed. Right. Oh, yeah.
>> What did you say?
>> Oh, yes, indeed. Right. Oh, yeah. I
>> Oh, yes, indeed. Right. Oh, yeah. I hope
someone
someone remembers
someone remembers what
someone remembers what we
someone remembers what we were.
someone remembers what we were. We
someone remembers what we were. We were
433,
I
I think.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. We
I think.
>> Okay. We have
>> Okay. We have permission
I think.
>> Okay. We have permission to
>> Okay. We have permission to calibrate
the
the energy
the energy of
the energy of the
the energy of the group.
the energy of the group. So,
the energy of the group. So, we're
the energy of the group. So, we're 433.
434 435
434 435 436
the energy of the group. So, we're 433.
434 435 436 437
434 435 436 437 438
the energy of the group. So, we're 433.
434 435 436 437 438 439
434 435 436 437 438 439 440
the energy of the group. So, we're 433.
434 435 436 437 438 439 440 Wow
434 435 436 437 438 439 440 Wow 441
the energy of the group. So, we're 433.
434 435 436 437 438 439 440 Wow 441 Holy
went
went up
went up seven
went up seven points
went up seven points 700
went up seven points 700 points
as
as a
went up seven points 700 points
as a group.
As
As a
As a group,
As a group, as
As a group, as we
As a group, as we said,
As a group, as we said, the
As a group, as we said, the average
consciousness
consciousness advances
As a group, as we said, the average
consciousness advances five
consciousness advances five points
As a group, as we said, the average
consciousness advances five points in
consciousness advances five points in a
lifetime.
lifetime. We
lifetime. We went
lifetime. We went up
lifetime. We went up seven
lifetime. We went up seven points
lifetime. We went up seven points in
lifetime. We went up seven points in a
matter
matter of
lifetime. We went up seven points in a
matter of hours,
matter of hours, you
lifetime. We went up seven points in a
matter of hours, you know.
So
So what
So what does
So what does that
So what does that mean?
So what does that mean? It
So what does that mean? It just
So what does that mean? It just means
there's
there's a
So what does that mean? It just means
there's a willingness
there's a willingness to
So what does that mean? It just means
there's a willingness to hold
there's a willingness to hold belief
So what does that mean? It just means
there's a willingness to hold belief in
suspension
and
and allow
suspension
and allow a
and allow a different
suspension
and allow a different energy
and allow a different energy to
recontextualize
recontextualize what
recontextualize what you
recontextualize what you already
recontextualize what you already know.
I
I probably
recontextualize what you already know.
I probably didn't
I probably didn't say
recontextualize what you already know.
I probably didn't say anything
I probably didn't say anything you
haven't
haven't heard
haven't heard before
haven't heard before today.
haven't heard before today. A
haven't heard before today. A few
haven't heard before today. A few unique
things
things perhaps,
but
but the
but the way
but the way in
but the way in which
but the way in which that
but the way in which that is
but the way in which that is held,
but the way in which that is held, the
readiness
readiness of
but the way in which that is held, the
readiness of the
readiness of the field.
So
So to
So to become
So to become enlightened
So to become enlightened is
So to become enlightened is to
So to become enlightened is to see
So to become enlightened is to see that
one
one is
So to become enlightened is to see that
one is the
one is the field
So to become enlightened is to see that
one is the field and
one is the field and not
So to become enlightened is to see that
one is the field and not the
one is the field and not the content
So to become enlightened is to see that
one is the field and not the content of
the
the field.
the field. That's
the field. That's the
the field. That's the only
the field. That's the only difference.
You're
You're the
the field. That's the only difference.
You're the field
You're the field in
the field. That's the only difference.
You're the field in which
You're the field in which the
the field. That's the only difference.
You're the field in which the thought
presents
presents itself
and
and you'll
presents itself
and you'll catch
and you'll catch it
presents itself
and you'll catch it one/10enth
and you'll catch it one/10enth onto
presents itself
and you'll catch it one/10enth onto the
second.
second. You
second. You don't
second. You don't think
second. You don't think that's
second. You don't think that's possible?
Yep.
Yep. Because
second. You don't think that's possible?
Yep. Because if
Yep. Because if you're
second. You don't think that's possible?
Yep. Because if you're watching
Yep. Because if you're watching for
second. You don't think that's possible?
Yep. Because if you're watching for it,
if
if you're
if you're watching
if you're watching for
if you're watching for it,
if you're watching for it, that
if you're watching for it, that tends
if you're watching for it, that tends to
potentiate
potentiate its
if you're watching for it, that tends to
potentiate its appearance.
potentiate its appearance. The
if you're watching for it, that tends to
potentiate its appearance. The one
potentiate its appearance. The one the
minute
minute you
minute you get
minute you get curious
minute you get curious about
minute you get curious about what
minute you get curious about what is
there
there prior
minute you get curious about what is
there prior to
there prior to thought,
minute you get curious about what is
there prior to thought, prior
there prior to thought, prior to
minute you get curious about what is
there prior to thought, prior to mind,
the
the minute
the minute you
the minute you get
the minute you get curious
the minute you get curious about
the minute you get curious about it,
that
that fires
the minute you get curious about it,
that fires off
that fires off the
the minute you get curious about it,
that fires off the quantum
that fires off the quantum potential
the minute you get curious about it,
that fires off the quantum potential for
that
that to
that to present
that to present itself
that to present itself as
that to present itself as a
that to present itself as a reality.
that to present itself as a reality. You
understand
understand what
that to present itself as a reality. You
understand what I'm
understand what I'm saying?
To
To merely
To merely be
To merely be interested,
To merely be interested, curious
To merely be interested, curious about
it,
to
to hold
to hold that
to hold that in
to hold that in mind
to hold that in mind tends
to hold that in mind tends to
to hold that in mind tends to increase
potentiality,
potentiality, the
to hold that in mind tends to increase
potentiality, the likelihood
potentiality, the likelihood of
to hold that in mind tends to increase
potentiality, the likelihood of it
manifesting
manifesting as
manifesting as a
manifesting as a experiential
manifesting as a experiential reality.
Yes.
>> Question
is
is perfect.
changing
changing then
>> if
>> if everything
changing then
>> if everything is
>> if everything is perfect
changing then
>> if everything is perfect what's
>> if everything is perfect what's the
point
point of
point of perfecting
point of perfecting anything
point of perfecting anything because
point of perfecting anything because it
is
is perfect
point of perfecting anything because it
is perfect already
is perfect already that
point of perfecting anything because it
is perfect already that the
is perfect already that the essence
Everything
Everything is
Everything is perfect
Everything is perfect as
Everything is perfect as it
Everything is perfect as it is.
What
What does
Everything is perfect as it is.
What does that
What does that mean?
Nothing
Nothing can
Nothing can be
other
other than
Nothing can be
other than the
other than the perfection
Nothing can be
other than the perfection of
other than the perfection of that
Nothing can be
other than the perfection of that which
it
it is.
it is. That
it is. That has
it is. That has to
it is. That has to do
it is. That has to do with
it is. That has to do with the
a
a thing
it is. That has to do with the
a thing that's
a thing that's very
it is. That has to do with the
a thing that's very hard
a thing that's very hard to
it is. That has to do with the
a thing that's very hard to explain.
Uh
Uh the
Uh the radical
Uh the radical identity
Uh the radical identity of
Uh the radical identity of self
Uh the radical identity of self of
Uh the radical identity of self of that
which
which it
Uh the radical identity of self of that
which it is
which it is with
Uh the radical identity of self of that
which it is with that
which it is with that which
Uh the radical identity of self of that
which it is with that which it
which it is with that which it is
in
in which
in which there
in which there is
in which there is no
absence
absence of
in which there is no
absence of information
absence of information that
in which there is no
absence of information that has
absence of information that has to
in which there is no
absence of information that has to be
projected
projected onto
projected onto it
projected onto it by
projected onto it by the
projected onto it by the observer.
What
What you're
projected onto it by the observer.
What you're asking
What you're asking is
projected onto it by the observer.
What you're asking is easy
What you're asking is easy to
projected onto it by the observer.
What you're asking is easy to see,
difficult
difficult to
difficult to answer
difficult to answer in
difficult to answer in a
difficult to answer in a verbal
difficult to answer in a verbal form.
The
The formula
difficult to answer in a verbal form.
The formula lies
The formula lies a
difficult to answer in a verbal form.
The formula lies a piece
The formula lies a piece of
difficult to answer in a verbal form.
The formula lies a piece of plastic.
It's
It's absolutely
It's absolutely perfect.
It's
It's perfectly
It's perfectly exactly
It's perfectly exactly that
It's perfectly exactly that which
It's perfectly exactly that which it
It's perfectly exactly that which it is.
The
The perfection
It's perfectly exactly that which it is.
The perfection is
The perfection is in
It's perfectly exactly that which it is.
The perfection is in that
The perfection is in that it
It's perfectly exactly that which it is.
The perfection is in that it fulfills
its
its karmic
its karmic destiny
its karmic destiny at
its karmic destiny at all
its karmic destiny at all times.
Absolutely.
It
It has
It has no
It has no destiny
It has no destiny to
It has no destiny to be
It has no destiny to be a
It has no destiny to be a camel.
It has no destiny to be a camel. It'
It has no destiny to be a camel. It' be
an
an imperfect
It has no destiny to be a camel. It' be
an imperfect camel.
But
But it
But it is
But it is not
But it is not an
But it is not an imperfect
But it is not an imperfect piece
But it is not an imperfect piece of
plastic.
It
It would
It would be
It would be imperfect
It would be imperfect in
It would be imperfect in the
It would be imperfect in the eye
It would be imperfect in the eye of
It would be imperfect in the eye of the
groundskeeper
who
who feels
who feels it
who feels it should
who feels it should be
who feels it should be swept
who feels it should be swept away.
But
But that's
who feels it should be swept away.
But that's trying
But that's trying to
who feels it should be swept away.
But that's trying to impose
But that's trying to impose in
who feels it should be swept away.
But that's trying to impose in trying
But that's trying to impose in trying to
impose
impose form
impose form on
impose form on what
impose form on what is.
What
What it
impose form on what is.
What it is
What it is is
impose form on what is.
What it is is the
What it is is the absolute
impose form on what is.
What it is is the absolute perfect
expression
expression of
expression of all
expression of all that
expression of all that it
expression of all that it take
throughout
throughout the
expression of all that it take
throughout the evolution
throughout the evolution of
all
all of
all of time
all of time through
all of time through the
all of time through the invention
all of time through the invention of
plastic
plastic through
all of time through the invention of
plastic through the
plastic through the all
all of time through the invention of
plastic through the all of
plastic through the all of us
all of time through the invention of
plastic through the all of us being
plastic through the all of us being here
through
through the
through the gravity
through the gravity through
through the gravity through the
barometric
barometric pressure
through the gravity through the
barometric pressure for
barometric pressure for the
through the gravity through the
barometric pressure for the for
barometric pressure for the for this
building
building to
building to be
building to be here
building to be here for
building to be here for Sedona
building to be here for Sedona to
building to be here for Sedona to be
founded
founded etc.
building to be here for Sedona to be
founded etc. It
founded etc. It took
building to be here for Sedona to be
founded etc. It took all
founded etc. It took all of
building to be here for Sedona to be
founded etc. It took all of that
founded etc. It took all of that for
this
this divine
this divine piece
this divine piece of
this divine piece of plastic
this divine piece of plastic to
this divine piece of plastic to be
this divine piece of plastic to be where
it
it is.
this divine piece of plastic to be where
it is. [laughter]
You
You You
You You remember
You You remember that
You You remember that movie?
You You remember that movie? It
You You remember that movie? It was
You You remember that movie? It was one
of the
of the funniest
You You remember that movie? It was one
of the funniest movies
of the funniest movies I
You You remember that movie? It was one
of the funniest movies I ever
of the funniest movies I ever saw
You You remember that movie? It was one
of the funniest movies I ever saw which
a
a Coke
a Coke bottle
a Coke bottle falls
a Coke bottle falls from
a Coke bottle falls from a
a Coke bottle falls from a plane
a Coke bottle falls from a plane into
What
What was
a Coke bottle falls from a plane into
What was the
What was the name
a Coke bottle falls from a plane into
What was the name of
What was the name of that
a Coke bottle falls from a plane into
What was the name of that movie?
>> Huh?
>> What
>> What was
>> Huh?
>> What was the
>> What was the name
>> Huh?
>> What was the name of
>> What was the name of that?
>> The
>> The gods
>> The gods must
>> The gods must be
>> The gods must be crazy.
>> The
>> The gods
>> The gods must be crazy.
>> The gods must
>> The gods must be
>> The gods must be crazy.
>> The gods must be crazy. Right.
>> [laughter]
>> The
>> The gods
>> [laughter]
>> The gods must
>> The gods must be
>> [laughter]
>> The gods must be crazy
>> The gods must be crazy is
>> [laughter]
>> The gods must be crazy is one
>> The gods must be crazy is one of
>> [laughter]
>> The gods must be crazy is one of the
>> The gods must be crazy is one of the a
wonderful
wonderful movie
wonderful movie for
wonderful movie for spiritual
wonderful movie for spiritual seekers,
you
you know.
wonderful movie for spiritual seekers,
you know. See,
you know. See, because
wonderful movie for spiritual seekers,
you know. See, because you
you know. See, because you see
wonderful movie for spiritual seekers,
you know. See, because you see how
you know. See, because you see how we
project
project onto
project onto a
project onto a thing
project onto a thing what
project onto a thing what we
project onto a thing what we think
project onto a thing what we think it
is,
is, which
project onto a thing what we think it
is, which has
is, which has nothing
project onto a thing what we think it
is, which has nothing to
is, which has nothing to do
project onto a thing what we think it
is, which has nothing to do with
is, which has nothing to do with what
project onto a thing what we think it
is, which has nothing to do with what it
is,
is, you
is, you know,
is, you know, is
is, you know, is its
is, you know, is its value
is, you know, is its value became
is, you know, is its value became when
two
two people
is, you know, is its value became when
two people wanted
two people wanted the
is, you know, is its value became when
two people wanted the one
two people wanted the one Coke
is, you know, is its value became when
two people wanted the one Coke bottle.
That
That was
That was the
That was the beginning
That was the beginning of
That was the beginning of the
That was the beginning of the breakdown
of
of their
That was the beginning of the breakdown
of their society.
of their society. [laughter]
One
One person
One person had
One person had a
One person had a Coke
One person had a Coke bottle
One person had a Coke bottle and
One person had a Coke bottle and only
one.
one. Uh
One person had a Coke bottle and only
one. Uh oh,
one. Uh oh, now
One person had a Coke bottle and only
one. Uh oh, now everybody
one. Uh oh, now everybody else
One person had a Coke bottle and only
one. Uh oh, now everybody else wanted
the
the Coke
the Coke bottle
the Coke bottle and
the Coke bottle and the
the Coke bottle and the fight
the Coke bottle and the fight started.
Of
Of course,
the Coke bottle and the fight started.
Of course, that's
Of course, that's a
the Coke bottle and the fight started.
Of course, that's a very
Of course, that's a very comical.
the Coke bottle and the fight started.
Of course, that's a very comical. So
perfection
perfection is
perfection is then
perfection is then what
perfection is then what you
perfection is then what you see
perfection is then what you see it
perfection is then what you see it as.
There
There are
perfection is then what you see it as.
There are different
There are different levels
perfection is then what you see it as.
There are different levels of
There are different levels of perfection
because
because they're
because they're really
because they're really all
because they're really all a
because they're really all a definition.
You
You see,
because they're really all a definition.
You see, in
You see, in the
because they're really all a definition.
You see, in the absolute,
the
the word
the word perfection
the word perfection would
the word perfection would be
meaningless.
Just
Just like
Just like the
Just like the word
Just like the word beauty
Just like the word beauty is
Just like the word beauty is meaningless
when
when you
Just like the word beauty is meaningless
when you stand
when you stand there
Just like the word beauty is meaningless
when you stand there looking
when you stand there looking at
Just like the word beauty is meaningless
when you stand there looking at a
sunset.
Incredible.
Incredible. All
sunset.
Incredible. All words
Incredible. All words you
sunset.
Incredible. All words you could
Incredible. All words you could use
would
would be
uh
uh irrelevant.
Everything
Everything is
Everything is perfectly
what
what it
Everything is perfectly
what it is
what it is at
Everything is perfectly
what it is at every
what it is at every moment
Everything is perfectly
what it is at every moment because
what it is at every moment because there
is
is no
is no other
is no other possibility.
Any
Any other
is no other possibility.
Any other possibility
Any other possibility is
is no other possibility.
Any other possibility is an
Any other possibility is an intellectual
positionality.
with
with no
positionality.
with no that
with no that does
positionality.
with no that does not
with no that does not reflect
positionality.
with no that does not reflect any
reality.
Nothing
Nothing can
reality.
Nothing can be
Nothing can be anything
reality.
Nothing can be anything except
Nothing can be anything except that
which
which it
which it is.
which it is. To
which it is. To be
which it is. To be that
which it is. To be that which
which it is. To be that which it
which it is. To be that which it is,
which it is. To be that which it is, it
already
already has
which it is. To be that which it is, it
already has to
already has to be
which it is. To be that which it is, it
already has to be perfectly
already has to be perfectly that
which it is. To be that which it is, it
already has to be perfectly that which
it
it is,
it is, or
it is, or it
it is, or it couldn't
it is, or it couldn't exist
it is, or it couldn't exist at
it is, or it couldn't exist at all.
For
For the
it is, or it couldn't exist at all.
For the evolution
For the evolution of
it is, or it couldn't exist at all.
For the evolution of consciousness
For the evolution of consciousness to
take
take the
take the forms
take the forms that
take the forms that it
take the forms that it takes.
take the forms that it takes. So,
take the forms that it takes. So, as
consciousness
consciousness evolves,
take the forms that it takes. So, as
consciousness evolves, it
consciousness evolves, it takes
take the forms that it takes. So, as
consciousness evolves, it takes these
forms.
forms. Here's
forms. Here's the
forms. Here's the Middle
forms. Here's the Middle East
forms. Here's the Middle East right
here.
here. He's
forms. Here's the Middle East right
here. He's here's
here. He's here's a
forms. Here's the Middle East right
here. He's here's a a
here. He's here's a a Neanderthal
forms. Here's the Middle East right
here. He's here's a a Neanderthal man.
Here's
Here's uh
it
it gets
Here's uh
it gets to
it gets to here
Here's uh
it gets to here from
it gets to here from there.
So
So you
So you can't
So you can't make
So you can't make it
So you can't make it wrong
So you can't make it wrong for
So you can't make it wrong for being
So you can't make it wrong for being in
the
the process
So you can't make it wrong for being in
the process of
the process of getting
So you can't make it wrong for being in
the process of getting here.
the process of getting here. It
So you can't make it wrong for being in
the process of getting here. It isn't
here
here yet.
That
That which
here yet.
That which was
That which was what
here yet.
That which was what it
That which was what it was.
here yet.
That which was what it was. As
That which was what it was. As evolution
became
became more
became more and
became more and more
became more and more conscious.
became more and more conscious. Homo
u
u spiritus
became more and more conscious. Homo
u spiritus is
u spiritus is just
became more and more conscious. Homo
u spiritus is just born.
five
five minutes
five minutes ago.
[laughter]
Spirit
Spirit is
Spirit is is
Spirit is is just
Spirit is is just barely
Spirit is is just barely the
Spirit is is just barely the latest
evolutionary
evolutionary tree
Spirit is is just barely the latest
evolutionary tree of
evolutionary tree of mankind.
It
It doesn't
It doesn't value
It doesn't value the
It doesn't value the physical
It doesn't value the physical and
It doesn't value the physical and the
material
material anymore.
It doesn't value the physical and the
material anymore. It
material anymore. It doesn't
It doesn't value the physical and the
material anymore. It doesn't value
wealth.
wealth. It
wealth. It doesn't
wealth. It doesn't value
wealth. It doesn't value the
wealth. It doesn't value the ego
wealth. It doesn't value the ego come
comes
comes out
wealth. It doesn't value the ego come
comes out of
comes out of the
wealth. It doesn't value the ego come
comes out of the evolution
comes out of the evolution of
wealth. It doesn't value the ego come
comes out of the evolution of animal
consciousness
consciousness and
consciousness and survival.
Homo
Homo spirit
consciousness and survival.
Homo spirit is
Homo spirit is doesn't
consciousness and survival.
Homo spirit is doesn't even
Homo spirit is doesn't even value
consciousness and survival.
Homo spirit is doesn't even value that
anymore.
You
You can
anymore.
You can give
You can give me
anymore.
You can give me $10
You can give me $10 million
anymore.
You can give me $10 million to
You can give me $10 million to do
something
something non-integrous
something non-integrous and
something non-integrous and it
something non-integrous and it would
sound
sound like
something non-integrous and it would
sound like a
sound like a joke,
something non-integrous and it would
sound like a joke, wouldn't
sound like a joke, wouldn't it?
something non-integrous and it would
sound like a joke, wouldn't it? You
sound like a joke, wouldn't it? You can
sell
sell your
sell your soul
sell your soul for
sell your soul for what?
sell your soul for what? That
sell your soul for what? That would
sell your soul for what? That would be
ridiculous
to
to to
to to to
to to to someone
to to to someone who's
to to to someone who's not
to to to someone who's not to
to to to someone who's not to that
level,
level, it
to to to someone who's not to that
level, it would
level, it would be
to to to someone who's not to that
level, it would be a
level, it would be a major
to to to someone who's not to that
level, it would be a major temptation.
You
You understand?
You understand? So,
You understand? So, we've
You understand? So, we've become
You understand? So, we've become a
different
different kind
You understand? So, we've become a
different kind of
different kind of an
You understand? So, we've become a
different kind of an entity.
If
If I
If I say
If I say to
If I say to you,
If I say to you, visiting
If I say to you, visiting a
If I say to you, visiting a relic
If I say to you, visiting a relic will
have
have its
If I say to you, visiting a relic will
have its spiritual
have its spiritual advantage,
If I say to you, visiting a relic will
have its spiritual advantage, we
have its spiritual advantage, we all
say,
say, hey,
say, hey, let's
say, hey, let's go.
If
If it
say, hey, let's go.
If it does
If it does not
say, hey, let's go.
If it does not have
If it does not have a
say, hey, let's go.
If it does not have a spiritual
advantage,
advantage, we
advantage, we wouldn't
advantage, we wouldn't leave,
advantage, we wouldn't leave, would
advantage, we wouldn't leave, would we?
So
So we
advantage, we wouldn't leave, would we?
So we are
So we are brought
advantage, we wouldn't leave, would we?
So we are brought together
So we are brought together by
by
by spiritual
by spiritual intention
that
that which
by spiritual intention
that which sets
that which sets our
by spiritual intention
that which sets our karma.
that which sets our karma. So
by spiritual intention
that which sets our karma. So as
that which sets our karma. So as a
by spiritual intention
that which sets our karma. So as a group
we
we share
we share a
we share a common
we share a common karma.
we share a common karma. people
dedicated
dedicated to
we share a common karma. people
dedicated to spiritual
dedicated to spiritual intention
we share a common karma. people
dedicated to spiritual intention that
dedicated to spiritual intention that is
what
what becomes
what becomes paramount
what becomes paramount surrounds
what becomes paramount surrounds other
objectives
makes
makes people
makes people travel
makes people travel long
makes people travel long distances
makes people travel long distances etc.
So
So the
makes people travel long distances etc.
So the same
So the same drive
makes people travel long distances etc.
So the same drive that
So the same drive that brings
makes people travel long distances etc.
So the same drive that brings us
So the same drive that brings us here
today
today would
today would give
today would give us
today would give us the
today would give us the spiritual
curiosity.
curiosity. What
today would give us the spiritual
curiosity. What is
curiosity. What is it
today would give us the spiritual
curiosity. What is it like
curiosity. What is it like to
today would give us the spiritual
curiosity. What is it like to visit
curiosity. What is it like to visit uh
today would give us the spiritual
curiosity. What is it like to visit uh a
genuine
genuine ancient
genuine ancient spiritual
genuine ancient spiritual relic?
genuine ancient spiritual relic? I
genuine ancient spiritual relic? I don't
know.
know. I've
genuine ancient spiritual relic? I don't
know. I've never
know. I've never visited
genuine ancient spiritual relic? I don't
know. I've never visited one.
[laughter]
So
So spiritual
[laughter]
So spiritual curiosity
So spiritual curiosity then
is
charged
charged up
is
charged up by
charged up by our
is
charged up by our spiritual
charged up by our spiritual commitment.
Will
Will we
Will we all
Will we all see
Will we all see God
Will we all see God as
Will we all see God as we
Will we all see God as we visit
Will we all see God as we visit the
relic?
relic? I
Will we all see God as we visit the
relic? I don't
relic? I don't know.
Will we all see God as we visit the
relic? I don't know. Will
relic? I don't know. Will we
Will we all see God as we visit the
relic? I don't know. Will we all
relic? I don't know. Will we all get
Will we all see God as we visit the
relic? I don't know. Will we all get a
great
great buzz?
great buzz? No.
great buzz? No. I
great buzz? No. I think
great buzz? No. I think we
great buzz? No. I think we all
great buzz? No. I think we all get
great buzz? No. I think we all get a
great
great satisfaction
great buzz? No. I think we all get a
great satisfaction that
great satisfaction that somehow
great buzz? No. I think we all get a
great satisfaction that somehow as
great satisfaction that somehow as a
group
group we
group we acknowledge
group we acknowledge the
group we acknowledge the presence
group we acknowledge the presence of
group we acknowledge the presence of God
as
as it
group we acknowledge the presence of God
as it radiates
as it radiates forth
group we acknowledge the presence of God
as it radiates forth into
as it radiates forth into this
group we acknowledge the presence of God
as it radiates forth into this world
as it radiates forth into this world at
a
a consciousness
a consciousness level
a consciousness level of
a consciousness level of over
a consciousness level of over 900
a consciousness level of over 900 which
is
is a
a consciousness level of over 900 which
is a very
is a very rare
a consciousness level of over 900 which
is a very rare opportunity.
So
So out
So out of
So out of reverence
So out of reverence for
So out of reverence for God,
So out of reverence for God, we
So out of reverence for God, we say
thanks
thanks for
So out of reverence for God, we say
thanks for the
thanks for the opportunity
So out of reverence for God, we say
thanks for the opportunity and
thanks for the opportunity and avail
oursel
oursel of
oursel of probably
oursel of probably once
oursel of probably once in
oursel of probably once in a
oursel of probably once in a lifetime
experience.
experience. How
oursel of probably once in a lifetime
experience. How many
experience. How many here
oursel of probably once in a lifetime
experience. How many here before
experience. How many here before have
had
had a
had a chance
had a chance to
had a chance to visit
had a chance to visit a
had a chance to visit a great
had a chance to visit a great relic?
Couple.
All
All right.
All right. So
All right. So we'll
All right. So we'll quit
All right. So we'll quit here
All right. So we'll quit here for
All right. So we'll quit here for today.
I've
I've tried
All right. So we'll quit here for today.
I've tried to
I've tried to answer
All right. So we'll quit here for today.
I've tried to answer all
I've tried to answer all the
All right. So we'll quit here for today.
I've tried to answer all the questions
I've tried to answer all the questions I
could.
It's
It's been
could.
It's been my
It's been my great
could.
It's been my great pleasure.
It's been my great pleasure. It's
could.
It's been my great pleasure. It's been
my
my pleasure.
>> [applause]